THE HOUSE / 1984
ELECTION SUNDAY
THE POLLING STATIONS ARE CLOSED.
THE CANDIDATES HAVE BEEN CHOSEN.
THE RESULTS ARE BEING TALLIED.
PENTECOST MONDAY
SWEET FANTASY.
FREEDOM AND FRIENDSHIP.
WORKDAY TUESDAY
3000 people in that fieId
are looking for apartments,
out of the 6000
we have for the whole district.
What can you do? I can only make
around 100-120 referrals a year
that are then granted.
You can imagine
how many of the 3000 get left behind.
HOUSING POLICY DEPT.
Hello.
- Hello.
I had to make another appearance.
- Yes. But it's stiIl...
HelIo.
StiII the same?
- Yes.
StiII no senior-friendIy
apartments avaiIabIe.
Yes.
Nothing can be done.
- Nothing can be done.
I keep coming and saying...
I thought now that vacation was over...
But that's why
no more apartments are avaiIabIe.
Yes, I beIieve that.
- We onIy ever have a few.
Okay...
- But we're keeping an eye on your case.
That's the important thing.
- Yes.
... KEEPING AN EYE ON IT.
What changes do we have to make
to your apartment appIication?
None.
None? Everything's the same?
You're an auto painter at Auto-Trans BerIin?
Starting in 1980
you did three years in the NVA.
If it's over then I can erase it.
WeII, now it's '84.
The three years are over.
That's right.
So, is this teIephone number right:
37 64 230?
No.
We've never had a teIephone.
Your work number.
- Oh, okay. Yes.
It couId be your work number.
So...
And you work in two shifts?
You're not eIigibIe for PIan 85 yet,
You Iive in a 4-room apartment
with four peopIe.
THEN I CAN ERASE IT.
Oh, here.
Handwriting was hard to read.
So...
- Yes.
You're stiII a student.
Any changes to your appIication?
There haven't been any changes.
Are you stiII studying at the medicaI schooI?
- No, I'm done.
See, that's a change.
- Yes.
This year, in '84?
- In '84, that's right.
And what do you do now?
- I'm a physicaI therapist.
Where?
- In BerIin Buch.
Is it caIIed ''Buch CIinic''?
What's it caIIed?
It's caIIed...
The address is: BerIin Buch...
I don't want the address,
I want the name of the company.
It must be caIIed ''Buch CIinic''
or something.
Write ''Buch CIinic.''
So, I have your teIephone number.
Do you have a work number?
No.
So...
Do you work in shifts?
No. Not in shifts.
- No.
Not in two shifts, either?
Then we don't have an opportunity
to enroII you in PIan 85 yet.
WE GET RID OF EVERYTHING.
Even oId peopIe get turned away.
That doesn't happen here.
We get rid of everything.
So.
- I wanted to check in again,
see if it was possibIe in the meantime,
and see what kind of chances I have
for the coming year.
As a nurse?
Are you a nurse?
No. I'm studying.
But I work too.
- Weren't you a nurse?
No, I wasn't.
I worked for a year at the rescue center.
Here it says ''faciIity: hospitaI.''
- Yes.
And now I work...
- I'm sweating buckets!
It's hot enough as it is
with aII these Iights.
And I'm working there again.
And how many shifts do you have?
- It's a three- shift system.
Do we have anything in writing for you?
- Yes. That's it, right there.
Where? Oh, this.
- Both sides.
I don't know why it isn't marked.
WeII, as a student
you're out of the running, right?
How much Ionger wiII you study?
- Five more years.
Five more years?
- It's a six-year study program.
What wiII you be then?
- A doctor.
Then you won't work in shifts.
- Oh yes I wiII!
But not in three shifts.
- As I doctor, I wiII.
Patients have to be cared for at night too.
Then you have on-caII duty.
- Yes, on top of that.
So, today it's '84. Then it'II be '89.
You want to study that Iong?
I'm going to try, but Iike I said...
I can't promise you'II get through with that.
SO, TODAY IT'S '84.
For exampIe, because of Leipzig
I'm home every six months
for three weeks with the expo.
We have to rearrange everything,
and I need an office for my books and...
There's no way we can give you
an office as a student.
No, but...
We wish aII students couId have one,
but we can't do that yet.
- Yeah, I know.
You can take it, it's yours.
- I know.
But there's no space.
Our Iiving room...
Like I said,
if your brother appIies when he's 18
and he works in three shifts,
it's quite possibIe
that he'II get pIaced before you do.
That's how it is.
Okay?
Your parents can count on
having you around for a whiIe.
So, there's no way you'II...
Get married in Leipzig.
Then we're rid of you.
Find a professor with high standing.
You never know.
You have to keep a positive attitude.
That was just a joke, just so you know.
- Yeah, I know.
My coIIeague is a bit of a joker.
THAT WAS JUST A JOKE.
We aII make our own choices.
SOCIAL SERVICES DEPT.
So,
I spoke with my coIIeague.
Back then he said
you couId drop by at any time
if you're having probIems
or if you're in troubIe.
I've expIained to you
our IegaI requirements concerning the issue.
I aIso toId you
that because of those requirements,
we can no Ionger offer
any one-time financiaI support.
He agrees compIeteIy.
If you wouId Iike to speak with
my coIIeague again,
you're weIcome to do so.
Based on the sociaI weIfare ordinance,
we are no Ionger abIe to heIp you.
And to be compIeteIy honest,
you didn't find out
about enroIIment today.
You've known for about a year.
And you couId've prepared for that
a IittIe bit.
And if you were a member
of the trade union
you wouId've been eIigibIe
for cuIturaI and sociaI funds.
That argument just doesn't cut it:
''I've known for about a year.''
I had aII sorts of other things to deaI with.
I've got debts...
I started because
I spent that time pretty much
under the poverty Iine,
untiI I got this job
by petitioning and things.
I started with such a huge deficit!
AII I want to know right now:
I just have to accept this, right?
Is this finaI?
You can't heIp me
no matter how dire my situation is?
You know,
my probIems and emergencies...
I don't get to choose them,
they just come.
And I tried to get by on my own!
But now...
I came here as a Iast resort!
But now I'm stuck,
so I thought I'd come back
and see if you couId heIp.
If I'd come six months ago
it wouIdn't have been any different.
But the fact remains that we
aIready heIped with 740 marks.
That was one-time financiaI support
in the sense that
we heIped you very generousIy
because of the troubIe
and probIems you were having.
That was aII handIed
and processed in a normaI manner.
And as I said, our financiaI assets
are exhausted at this point.
We can't do any more.
- So the case is cIosed?
There's no reason for me to come back?
- You couId say that
because you have
a gross saIary of 420 marks,
and the sociaI weIfare Iimit is 230 marks.
If we're being generous, we can accept
up to 260 marks incIuding rent.
And because of our IegaI requirements
for ''one-time financiaI support,''
you wouId be eIigibIe
if you had an income of 230 marks.
That means, in the case of
schooI enroIIment or a youth ceremony,
we couId've given you
one-time financiaI support.
Yes, but those peopIe
aIso receive chiId support
or get support from their parents,
and I don't have any of that.
Or the father actuaIIy heIps out.
- Yes, I know that.
Even if you did receive chiId support
you'd stiII be over the Iimit,
but we don't count chiId support.
You have the right
to fiIe an appeaI against it.
I'II teII you how.
- That won't heIp me.
I don't want to get into that again.
If I'd known that it's no Ionger possibIe...
Then they teII me...
You knew what my saIary was,
you knew that.
I'm getting the furniture,
because I've been Iiving on the fIoor.
You knew aII that and you stiII said:
''We can't provide you with chiId support.
There's no way
to do it IegaIIy,
but nevertheIess, if you have a reaI probIem,
we can do this or that.''
That's why I came here,
and now I know it's not possibIe.
This is the onIy advice I can give you:
due to your current work situation,
you shouId become a member of the FDGB.
Then the next time
you have a financiaI emergency
you can appIy for one-time financiaI support
through the FDGB.
Is there anything eIse we can do?
Because I need to handIe this situation.
It's reaIIy...
I'm behind in every way,
but I don't want it to affect my chiId.
I want her to start schooI
the same way other kids do.
In the end,
aII I care about is the 100 marks.
Can I get it as a Ioan or something?
We'II have to go back down
to my coIIeague.
I can't just decide that on my own.
You'II have to come with me.
- Sure, if it's okay.
Fine.
HANDLED AND PROCESSED
IN A NORMAL MANNER.
Is this your first time here?
- Yes, it is.
Did you bring your documents?
Pension statement, insurance proof?
- Not the insurance proof.
No?
Then show me what you've... Thanks.
You moved apartments?
- Yes.
In the same house?
- In the same house.
How Iarge is the apartment?
How Iarge is your new apartment?
Two rooms that are the same,
and a kitchen...
With an indoor toiIet?
- I now have an indoor toiIet and bath,
which I didn't have before.
Who is your doctor?
- Dr. ...
And you're stiII in the front buiIding?
- Yes.
We don't have a rear buiIding.
Yes, front buiIding.
So...
With indoor toiIet and bath?
- Yes.
I'II give that back to you.
- I had to move on Friday.
You've requested support
in order to buy yourseIf some things.
You have to understand,
because of your pension,
we won't be abIe to grant you
everything you've appIied for.
We can do the foIIowing:
We can grant you one-time financiaI support
in the form of 150 marks.
Then you can buy the things
that you appIied for.
My pension is onIy 350 marks,
and with the move... - Yes, yes.
Others get 270 or 280 marks
and have to
make do with that.
And you just received coaI money from us.
Yes, I did receive that.
OTHERS GET 270 OR 280
AND HAVE TO MAKE DO WITH THAT.
HeIIo.
Just one more citizen
then we're aII done.
A haIf hour, forty-five minutes, okay?
Bye.
What do we have here?
I'm here again
about our daughter's apartment situation.
We have a tiny
three-room apartment.
Five of us Iive there incIuding the infant,
and the son-in-Iaw on the weekends.
And we're supposed to work shifts!
I know aII of that.
That's nothing new.
My daughter is studying in September
and she needs work space.
I don't know how to go on!
WeII, we've got nothing.
We can't offer you anything right now.
I got two apartments Iast week.
It's been this way since February.
- But
we have so few apartments coming in.
It wouId be a Iot easier
to achieve our PIan 84
if we had more apartments.
Your daughter isn't in the pIan
and I can't teII someone in the pIan
''You can't get anything because
it's her turn to get something.''
We said ''outside the pIan,''
but I have to foIIow the pIan first.
My pIan is the Iaw, and I have to execute it.
Then we deaI with the rest.
But how do our chances Iook?
- WeII, it Iooks bad.
But that's not going to heIp us.
No, it won't,
but it doesn't heIp me either.
I spent the whoIe day
taIking with peopIe who are in the pIan
and they're surprised,
reaIIy surprised,
and they have to accept the fact
that it's August
and they stiII haven't received an offer.
But,
I mean, it's no way to Iive!
No three-month-oId baby
shouId have to Iive in a Iiving room.
It sIeeps and things
in the middIe of everything eIse.
In the kitchen...
We can't eat or anything!
MY PLAN IS THE LAW.
THEN WE DEAL WITH THE REST.
It can't go on Iike this!
I can't heIp you.
PRESENTATION WEDNESDAY
Yesterday was okay.
Not every day is Iike that.
I mean, you're here...
We had 62 citizens come in,
I did in any case.
That's okay.
Sometimes we have even more.
,And it aII went reIativeIy businessIike.
The two or three who I thought
wouId fIip out a bit,
didn't end up fIipping out.
So it was okay.
I tend to do weII on Tuesdays anyway.
I'm stiII spunky.
INTERNAL AFFAIRS DEPT.
InternaI Dept., BerIin Mitte CounciI.
Good morning.
Yes, InternaI Affairs,
BerIin Mitte CounciI.
HeIIo. I caIIed yesterday.
Was it you I spoke with
about this person being discharged?
Was he discharged?
Did you give him an appointment
between 10 and 11:30
here at the counciI?
That's great,
because he isn't here yet.
I thought maybe
he wasn't abIe to get away at this time.
7:30. Okay, thank you.
Then he'II be...
I see.
Thank you.
Then he'II be in Iater.
Yes.
Yes, that happens.
Okay, thanks.
Good bye.
He was discharged at 7:30
and he signed
saying he'd come to InternaI before 11:30.
Now we have to wait and see
if he comes or not.
PIease give me the documents.
Come here, pIease.
PIease take a seat.
So, you Iive here in Mitte?
- Yes, with my mother.
Is your mother Ms. ...?
- Yes.
That's your onIy residence?
Then why are you
stiII registered in PrenzIauer Berg?
I Iived with my brother for a whiIe.
I registered there
to keep everything orderIy.
I was there for two months.
But my sister-in-Iaw
is the kind of woman
that's hard to get aIong with.
We pretty much can't stand each other.
She's got her kids there.
What she's doing isn't right.
When did you
move back in with your mother?
In ApriI.
Of '84?
- This year, yes.
But...
- I tried to sign the house register
as a visitor at first,
and I went to the station
and wanted to register myseIf.
My mother made a statement
saying I had a right to enter the apartment.
I aIso had a new Iock put in
because she Iost her key.
At your mother's?
- Yes.
She was robbed once
on the street at night.
They took her ID,
her key and everything.
She got her ID back,
but not the key to the apartment,
or for the courtyard
because it's border area.
It's border area?
- It's border area.
I can get into the apartment,
but not into the courtyard.
But you don't have...
You need authorization.
I spoke with this coIIeague.
He's the...
What does he do?
He's househoId management.
And he's a photographer too.
He's got a photo studio in the back.
A few peopIe took off recentIy.
It was on the news yesterday.
I wanted to come yesterday,
but I was with my brother-in-Iaw.
It was his birthday.
I thought it was onIy 2 pm.
I thought I'd go
congratuIate him,
and then come here.
I wanted to come
to keep everything orderIy.
Yes, so...
- But it was aIready 5:30 pm
and then it was too Iate.
If it's border area
you are onIy aIIowed to be there
with poIice authorization.
WeII, Iast night, around 10 or so,
after 10,
I met the other coIIeague.
And he made an appointment for me
at 10 AM today at Station 14.
I was there on time
but he had something to do.
He wasn't there yet.
Then I waited
and we came here together.
I wouId've come aIone too.
WeII, you were summoned a few times.
Once.
- Yes, and why didn't you come?
It was for yesterday.
Yesterday?
- Yes.
You have it in there somewhere.
It was for June 16th.
- No.
Yes, you were summoned for June 16th.
You know,
our maiIbox doesn't cIose.
WeII, you have to make sure it cIoses.
That's your responsibiIity as a tenant,
or your mother's responsibiIity
to make sure no one takes your maiI.
Yes.
That actuaIIy happened a few times.
That's your responsibiIity,
you're in charge of that.
WeII, I'II have to buy a new one.
You have to register
at your mother's apartment again.
I'II check if it's reaIIy border area,
Brunnenstrasse 143.
It's three houses from the border.
WeII...
It's not Iike I'm going
to jump over the WaII or something.
RegardIess, you need authorization
from the PeopIe's PoIice Force to be there,
and authorization from this counciI.
And you'd give me authorization?
- No, I can't give it to you.
Another coIIeague wouId give it to you.
You have to appIy.
Where?
- With the coIIeague in room 415.
He Iives in my house, right?
- No.
But a person with this name Iives there.
- He doesn't Iive there.
He Iives in our house.
But not this Person.
I'm sure of it.
You wouId know.
So, and how is it going with work?
I've aIways tried to find work,
and I worked in Operncafé
for a Iump sum.
I'm going to go back there
and see if they'II insure me,
if they'II give me saIary work.
And then I'II come here on Tuesday
and say, ''Look, I've got work.''
Your Iast job was from January 1st...
No, from... Yes...
From when?
From October 1st, 1982 to the 30th...
I can't make it out.
- September.
September 30th, 1983.
- Yes.
You've had no work since September.
What are you Iiving on?
I aIways worked for a Iump sum.
- Where?
That's a good question.
House BerIin.
Then...
- For how Iong?
Fourteen days.
House BerIin,
then Operncafé at some point.
First I was at Operncafé,
but then I worked at what-do-you-caII-it...
... THE COSMETIC COMBINE.
- Yes.
Why were you absent from work
without an excuse?
The man that I was Iiving with
cheated on me with his ex-wife.
And I hate it when he does that.
- I see.
So you just didn't come in to work?
I wanted to take a vacation.
I caIIed, we had a phone,
and taIked with the person in charge.
I asked her if I couId take a vacation
because I had some probIems.
She said, ''You're shop steward
and fiIIing in for the foreman. You can't.''
That's what they said.
- So you just stayed home?
No, I went here and...
My son came with me.
And we both taIked with her
about the probIem.
Then I went back to work and...
When was that?
It was in JuIy.
Yes, then from JuIy 4th to the 11th,
and then from JuIy 18th to the 20th.
AND THEN THREE MORE DAYS...
Are you singIe? Divorced?
- Yes. - SingIe?
With one son?
- Yes.
Where is he now?
- At a juveniIe detention center.
Do you have any physicaI Iimitations?
HeaIth probIems?
Not that I know of.
You can do aII types of work, right?
As Iong as it's not too tough,
I can handIe it.
But I can't reaIIy do precision work.
Do you wear gIasses?
- Yes.
Do you have them with you?
- No, not yet.
Are they Iost?
- I don't have any.
You never had any?
- No.
But, what kind of work
wouId you Iike to do?
My first choice wouId be in a kitchen.
Or as a porter.
I've worked as a porter before.
I worked Iate and night shifts
and Iots of overtime.
I made good money.
Then I met a man,
but I went kept working anyway.
Are you a drinker?
- No!
None?
- I drank a IittIe yesterday
because I was at a party.
But I usuaIIy don't drink.
AbsoIuteIy nothing?
- Nope.
And you don't go to bars?
- No. Oh God, not aIone!
No.
I don't take men home either.
I onIy have one man
and he's from Stuttgart.
But that's not iIIegaI.
Okay.
And you want to cross over
to be with him, right?
I'd have to be married first.
Not before.
And get rid of my debts.
- What kind of debts?
I stiII owe
the Youth WeIfare Office money.
I don't know.
I can't teII you for sure.
I'II have to check on that.
YOU WANT TO CROSS OVER
TO BE WITH HIM. WHAT KIND OF DEBTS?
I bet it was hard to keep a straight face.
Yeah, when she said...
What was it? That her boyfriend
cheated on her with his ex-wife.
Can I have another cigarette?
I'm...
... aII out.
But if she doesn't drink aIcohoI,
ORDER THURSDAY
then I'm a monkey's uncIe.
Youth WeIfare Department.
Youth SociaI Workers.
I'm sure you can imagine
why we need to taIk today.
This is about you.
Why were you asked to come here today?
Because I did something stupid?
- What stupid thing did you do?
I went into the ceIIar.
- In which one?
What?
- Into which ceIIar?
In your house, the neighbor's house?
- In our house.
How many ceIIars were there?
I was in one.
What about the others
that were there?
I was in another ceIIar too,
but I didn't take anything from it.
What did you take out of the ceIIar?
- Two aquariums.
What did you want with them?
Do you Iike animaIs?
WeII, at first.
But I'm not interested in them anymore.
I gave them to my sister.
Did you get the aquariums for her?
No, but I gave them to her anyway,
because I didn't want them anymore.
Do you have other pets at home?
My sister and I have two.
- What kind of pets?
A bird and a guinea pig.
- Who takes care of them?
My sister.
- Why don't you take care of them?
WeII, sometimes I feed them,
but cIeaning up after them...
What are you interested in?
I start a Iot of things,
and then I give up on them.
You assess yourseIf very criticaIIy.
We've taIked about that a Iot.
What kinds of things have you started?
- Swimming, crafts.
What eIse?
YOU ASSESS YOURSELF CRITICALLY.
Moved to 7th grade.
Behavior: B, effort: C, tidiness...
Why did you give yourseIf a D in tidiness?
WeII, I'm sIoppy.
I mean, I forget most things.
Is art your favorite subject?
That's why you chose the art work group?
- Yes.
And what did we say
we're going to do in September?
Improve.
My mother and I want to sit down together.
What wouId you Iike to improve?
Your behavior or grades?
WeII get rid of aII the Ds
and the Cs too if it's possibIe.
If we get rid of the Ds
then we'II be pretty weII off.
Yeah, but I might have some Cs
in my other subjects,
where I used to have Bs
and then I'd have the same average.
You know, when we taIk
you seen pretty responsibIe to me.
I'm sure you and your mother
had a IittIe taIk before
about aII these probIems.
Do you often do the types of things
that the PeopIe's PoIice Force toId us about?
Yes, once. I mean, severaI times.
And what did you do?
I stoIe money.
- From home?
And other pIaces.
- From who? Friends?
My mother's best friend
and a schooI friend.
Why did that happen?
How much is your aIIowance?
I don't have one.
But I do get something.
I ask Mommy
if I want to go somewhere
Iike to the rec. center,
and she gives it to me.
What about coIIecting scrap?
Lots of kids earn their aIIowance
by coIIecting scrap,
in a compIeteIy honest way.
- That's too easy for the young man.
If you were in the 9th or 10th grade
then I'd understand that.
Those boys are too vain
to be seen with bags of bottIes
and newspapers.
But the 7th grade is actuaIIy an age
where kids reaIIy Iike coIIecting scrap.
What's your routine Iike
after you get home from schooI.
Not a hoIiday Iike today,
but a schooI day. What's your routine?
When I get home...
WeII, for the Iast six months,
I get home, bring down the garbage paiIs,
dry them...
Not aIways, but often.
Then I go downstairs,
instead of doing my homework.
And is your sister as Iazy as you are?
- No.
Is she more responsibIe than you?
- Yeah, I'd say so.
Is she oIder or younger?
- OIder.
How oId is your sister.
- Thirteen. We're twins.
WeII, that shouId spur you on.
As a twin sister...
Are you in the same grade?
How are your sister's grades?
Better. Her average is about a B+,
I think.
So, what do you pIan to change,
besides improving your grades?
Your free time.
How do you want to change your free time?
Can you do it aIone?
I can, if I want to.
So you didn't want to for 13 years,
or for the Iast 6 schooI years,
is that it?
I have IittIe streaks.
Sometimes I want to, sometimes I don't.
SO YOU DIDN'T WANT TO
FOR THE LAST 13 YEARS?
On September 4th,
I want a seIf-assessment.
Even though you don't Iike writing.
IncIude what you
pIan to do in the new year.
And then we'II check your progress reguIarIy.
Got it?
Next week on your own, without Mommy.
Wait outside a moment.
I want to taIk to your mother
for a moment.
You can take that aIong.
ActuaIIy it's Iike this:
we usuaIIy don't get invoIved
with petty crimes.
But you probabIy toId...
the criminaI poIice
that these probIems happen often.
Yes.
- And that's why the comrades asked
that we taIk to you
and see if you need some heIp,
and see how we can heIp you.
I don't Iike that.
I went to our IocaI poIiceman myseIf
and asked for heIp,
and he gossiped
to everybody on the bIock about it.
He's sworn to secrecy too.
I was Iooking for heIp,
but I'm not going back there again.
Of course not.
I'm disappointed in him.
I went there and the peopIe
said things Iike:
''Aw, Iook! The robber famiIy!''
Or... I mean, I'm aIone.
WeII, that couId aIso
have to do with the others.
He's gone downhiII
since he's been
hanging around those two boys.
And...
that takes its toII.
I'm pretty exhausted.
I mean,
I've got a job with a Iot of responsibiIity.
What do you do?
- I'm a managing cIerk at Möve.
Yeah, so...
And I made a huge mistake.
My daughter...
I didn't Iike boys.
I aIways put my daughter first.
I can't make that right in one year's time.
You know?
I didn't Iike boys.
And...
I aIways Iooked for fauIts,
onIy saw fauIts in him.
But not with my daughter.
And he's...
I'd say that my son
is outrageousIy sensitive.
My daughter bears a grudge,
but he doesn't.
That's a big difference.
If you've come to reaIize
that you're aIso to bIame...
I'm trying to set it right,
but I can't do that over night.
... then we can fix it a IittIe at a time.
- I think...
I'm to bIame for a Iot of it, yes.
I even admit that.
- At this point Iet's say
that your son wiII report in reguIarIy.
If that doesn't work out,
the other possibiIity
is that he speak with a psychoIogist,
or that a voIunteer care worker
visits him at home.
I'd have no probIem with that.
Maybe it's better.
He probabIy thinks
this is just another warning.
But I don't want him to be...
But you can't be too hard on him.
I probabIy aIready did that.
I was too hard on him.
I'm pretty strict with him.
Try to praise him more,
even for IittIe things.
He's aII thumbs.
- Then find a way to Iook past that!
My God, there are so many men that...
- Yeah, but for craft projects...
He comes and says: ''Show me how to knit.''
It drives me nuts!
He's Iike a girI somehow.
- Yeah...
But you Iike girIs.
- Yeah, but not if he's a boy!
You have to get over that.
Praise him more, even for IittIe things.
Give him aIIowance.
He just buys candy with it
and then it's gone.
The money's gone!
- So the one mark a week is gone.
SOLIDARITY FRIDAY.
He has to get a reguIar aIIowance.
1 10 going once! 1 10 going twice!
1 15, 120...
Please, please!
Everyone participating, raise your hands!
120 going once! 120 going twice!
120 going three times!
Congratulations!
That's sure to be a unique contribution
to the trophy collection.
120 marks for solidarity.
Thank you very much.
Now something completely different.
A vase for the new apartment.
35!
And 21, 25!
42!
42 going once! 42 going twice! 45!
45 going twice!
45 going once! 45 going twice!
47!
40 going twice! 40 going three times!
Thank you! Moving right along!
FINANCIAL STATEMENTS
DISTRICT BERLIN-MITTE.
YOUTH QUESTIONS.
FINANCES.
EULOGIES.
WORK SCHEDULE.
HEALTH CARE.
WEDDING SATURDAY
Dear Ms. Radke, dear Mr. BaIser,
I've aIready introduced myseIf to you,
but I'd Iike to warmIy weIcome you
in behaIf of the
BerIin Mitte District CounciI.
DearIy beIoved,
we have gathered here today
to seaI your friendship
and Iove for one another
in the bond of matrimony.
With this step you take on
new and quite nice tasks:
You promise to trust and heIp each other,
to be there for each other unseIfishIy,
to share both happiness
and sorrow with each other,
to abandon seIfish wishes.
These are quaIities
that create an enduring bond
between man and wife.
In our country marriage and the famiIy
are under speciaI protection.
AII sociaI conditions were created
so that the famiIy you wish to start
with your marriage today
can deveIop into a true Iife partnership.
Dear Ms. Radke, dear Mr. BaIser,
I wouId Iike to say that the happiness
of your marriage wiII onIy endure
if you both contribute to it.
For not onIy are you man and wife
before the Iaw,
more importantIy
you are Iife partners and friends.
Your wedding day, September 1, 1984,
is aIso the InternationaI Day of Peace.
On a day Iike today
it shouId be cIear to you
that your active participation
is necessary to withhoId this peace.
RecentIy I read
a few Iines in the newspaper.
Maybe you
have some thoughts about them too.
It was written:
''The shining dream of great peace
is buried within our desires.
When its quiet voice is heard
we feeI peace,
and it is more than a feeIing, a desire.
Peace is more than everything in the worId.
Our hearts cannot beat without peace.''
So, dear Ms. Radke, dear Mr. BaIser,
before marriage
many exciting days and hours are spent.
Perhaps that was your experience?
Why not use your wedding
as an opportunity
to refIect for a minute?
Why not take a minute
to remember how you met,
or to think back
on the happy hours you've aIready shared?
You must know that marriage and famiIy
are more than just friendship and Iove.
And that the Iove between a man and a woman
must be preserved
in a wide variety of Iife situations.
Once I read something
from Theodor Fontane who cIaimed
that Iove can be sustained
by smaII courtesies.
But you know,
in this day and age we know fuII weII
that it takes a Iot more than that.
From my own experience
I couId add
that reIationships do not aIways stay the same.
They change simpIy due to the fact
that we change over the years.
And we often hear
that passion fades over the years.
There is some truth to that.
But at the same time I'd Iike to assert
that cIoseness shouId not.
By that I mean
that we shouId respect our partner,
understand him,
and make sure he feeIs
that his happiness and weII-being
are of great importance to you.
Yes, this wiII create heaIthy homes
which in turn give each partner
strength and enthusiasm.
For this reason one shouId go to try,
spurred on by the fundamentaIs
of sociaIist moraIs and ethics,
not to focus onIy on individuaI needs.
AIways be in baIance
with the tasks and interests of the society.
On this, your wedding day, you wiII be
showered with many words of congratuIations.
I hope and wish for you
that you master your Iife together
as open, joyfuI young peopIe.
Yet it is very important
that your personaI dreams come true.
Dear Ms. Radke, dear Mr. BaIser,
I wouId Iike to end our very short meeting
with a poem.
This is a poem
written by HeImut PreissIer.
He wrote:
''I want to Iive with you,
hope that Iuck wins out.
Though we sureIy
wiII have cause for worry,
after a hard day, make the evening good.
Torture me not with questions!
Give not reproach but courage!
Search not, when we argue,
for the bIame!
Find tenderness,
for Iove needs patience.''
Dear Ms. Radke, dear Mr. BaIser,
you have come here today
to say something as weII.
To speak a cIear, distinct ''yes,''
when I ask each of you in turn
if you are wiIIing to enter into
the bond of matrimony with each other.
And when I cIearIy and distinctIy
hear that from you both
then I'd Iike to say that
that is the proof
that you both Iove each other very much.
Dear Ms. Radke, dear Mr. BaIser,
may I now ask you
to stand.
Do you, Gerd BaIser,
take Petra Radke as you wife,
and accept the surname
you both seIected: BaIser?
Yes.
- Thanks.
And now your statement.
Do you, Petra Radke, aIso take
Gerd BaIser as your husband,
and accept the surname
you both seIected: BaIser?
Yes.
I many now caII you Mr. and Mrs. BaIser.
You have both given your word of consent,
and I confirmed that with my signature.
You are hereby,
under the Iaw
of our German Democratic RepubIic,
now a married-coupIe.
If you'd Iike to seaI that with a kiss,
we'd be happy to watch.
So, now we come to an end.
You must be given the proof
of the marriage we just performed,
the BaIser FamiIy Book
with two marriage certificates.
I have added the other documents.
This is the proof.
You carry the fIowers.
I now present you with the book,
many wishes for a happy future
and my experience:
one must work hard for Iove.
I wish that for you.
CongratuIations, Ms. BaIser.
I wish you both a IoveIy day
despite the rain.
So, if the photographer wouId be so kind?
WouId you Iike to take more photos,
or is that enough?
I don't know.
Maybe we couId do more outside...
But it's raining outside.
I say we shouId make them...
Or is your car outside?
- Then we'll do it outside.
Okay, good.
Then we'II say goodbye.
All the best to you again.
And have a nice stay here in Berlin.
Subtitles:
Barabas