My God, it's full of stars!
Neatness! It's a good quality.
You'll make someone a fine wife!
You are Dr. Heywood FIoyd?
Who the hell are you?
I'm Moisevitch.
I'm here to talk about your problem.
Really?
What problem's that?
You were chairman
of the National Council on Astronautics.
Now you are a schoolteacher.
This was by your own choice?
ChancelIor of the university.
It pays better. What do you care?
You were responsible
for the Discovery mission.
It was a failure.
Someone had to be blamed,
so it was you.
You like being a teacher?
I don't think I like you.
I just read your final report
on what happened to Discovery.
You left a good number of Ioose edges.
-Ends.
-Ioose ends, yes. Thank you.
A good number of questions...
...have remained unanswered.
You just read that report?
Took you this Iong to steal our secrets?
How Iong does it take for your people
to steal ours?
Same amount of time.
This is very bad for my asthma.
You think you could
meet me halfway?
Maybe.
It doesn't take a very smart man
to appreciate...
...the risk that I am taking
by being here with you, Dr. FIoyd.
And you are a smart man.
This is a very bad business...
...in Central America.
Very bad.
Ships, other planes buzzing around
each other like angry hornets.
Very bad.
We didn't start it.
We are scientists, you and I, Dr. FIoyd.
Our governments are enemies.
We are not.
Why don't you just try saying
what's on your mind?
I want to play a game with you, Dr. FIoyd.
-I don't have any time for games.
-This is a good game.
It's called '"The Truth.'"
For two minutes, I will tell only the truth.
And so will you.
Two minutes?
Two minutes.
Make it a minute and a half.
One minute and three quarters.
You start.
We know you are building
the Discovery Two...
...to go back to Jupiter to find out
what happened to your men up there.
Also to examine the large monolith.
You know that we are building
the Alexei Leonov to also go up there.
I thought you were gonna call it the Titov.
We changed last month.
People fall out of favor.
The Leonov will reach Discovery
almost a year...
...before you are ready.
My government feels it's very important
that we should get there first.
It's a distinction that will Iook splendid
on the front page of Pravda.
What other value it has, I don't know.
One minute ten.
Why are you telling me this?
Because there are things we need to know.
Otherwise, the same thing that
you let happen to your people up there...
...could happen to ours,
and we would accomplish nothing.
-I have about one minute left?
-About.
The small monolith
you brought back from the moon....
Your government has been very selfish
and stupid in keeping it to yourselves.
You never let us examine it.
What have you found out about it?
Nothing.
It's impenetrable.
We've tried lasers, nuclear detonators.
Nothing worked.
Forty-five seconds.
The monolith near Jupiter,
it is the same?
It's even larger.
And the computer on board the Discovery...
...the HAL-9000, can it be reactivated?
Yes.
-By us?
-By you?
It would take three to four months.
You're not familiar with the system.
And Ionger than that
to comprehend the data.
I thought so.
Thirty seconds.
Here we have our quandary.
We are going to get there first...
...yet you have the knowledge
to make the trip work.
How much more time do I have?
You just got yourself an extension.
How could you convince your people
to alIow Americans to go on the flight?
It won't be easy.
However, I'm pretty good.
A Russian craft fIown by Russians...
...carrying a few poor Americans
who need our help....
That also doesn't Iook too bad
on the front page of Pravda.
I don't know if I could
convince our people.
They wouldn't mind seeing you fail.
They wouldn't mind it at all.
Carrying Americans?
I don't think they would alIow that
if they didn't have to.
They don't have to.
Have you checked
Discovery's orbit lately?
What?
Have you checked the orbit?
What about it?
Now it's getting chilly here.
This is very bad for my asthma.
You know damn well
we've been checking it.
I have enjoyed our little chat.
What is it you're not telling me?
You are a smart man, Dr. FIoyd.
You will know what to do.
You've double-checked this?
Please say you haven't.
You aren't saying anything, FIoyd.
Something incredible is
happening up there.
Discovery's being pulled towards Io.
Or pushed away from Jupiter. Whichever.
Sometimes it seems to be accelerating,
and other times it just seems to stop.
I've never seen anything like it.
How Iong before it impacts on Io?
Two, two and a half years.
How could we be so goddamn
wrong about the orbit?
Because we weren't wrong.
We weren't wrong, then great.
Why the hell is it gonna crash?
I don't know. It's bizarre.
Unless it has something to do
with that monolith.
Do you see that building behind us?
I'm supposed to go in and
have lunch in half an hour.
There's one good thing
about a reactionary president:
No health foods. The last one
we didn't lunch, we grazed.
You want to know what lunch
is about? I'll tell you.
We've got two more aircraft
carriers near Honduras.
The Russians are moving
their big stuff in.
You got the Joint Chiefs screaming about
Russian satellites with anti-missile lasers.
So we gotta send up our laser
satellites to counteract theirs.
The president has decided
that the NCA should be put...
...under the Defense
Department's authority.
Enough with the crazy scientists spending
all this money trying to talk to Martians.
Here we are on your actual brink.
My agency will go military...
...the president's got his finger
on the button...
...and you want me to tell him
we want to hitch a ride...
...with those same Russians.
Have I missed anything?
-That's about it.
-I didn't want your job, you know.
I didn't force you out.
I didn't blame it on you.
So if this is your plan to try to
get me killed, you got the wrong guy.
Three men. I tell you,
we need three men.
The Russians must be laughing
their asses off.
Curnow. He's building
Discovery Two right now.
He knows more about the
original than anyone.
He's the only one who can start
Discovery in a short time.
And I suppose you want to go?
How the hell am I gonna sell it?
The Russians are gonna go
aboard Discovery with or without us.
Ask him if he wants them
to have all the answers.
Not bad.
We Iost some good men up there,
and I sent them. I have to go.
-Who's the third?
-Chandra.
He designed Hal.
He can reactivate him.
-I think he is Hal.
-I know.
-Yeah, but can you trust him?
-No.
But I have to. We have to
know why Hal malfunctioned.
I got an idea.
You go tell the president,
I'll go on the mission.
You're the NCA Chairman.
That's right, I am.
Iook, tell him we're screwed
if we don't go.
Tell him, if we do go, we'll lie...
...give the Russians false information.
Tell him that. He'll Iove that.
He might.
Good afternoon, Sal.
Do you have anything for me?
No, Dr. Chandra.
We have often spoken about Hal.
Yes, we have.
We've spoken about
Hal's anomaIous behavior.
You've told me that we can't solve
Hal's behavior without more information.
That is correct.
I enjoy talking about Hal.
I agree that we need more information,
so that we may solve the anomalies.
-And how do we get that information?
-That is obvious.
Someone must return to Discovery.
That person should be you.
I agree.
Now, it Iooks as if that's going to
happen sooner than we ever expected.
I am pleased to hear that.
I knew you would be.
I would like to expIore another possibility.
Diagnosis is only the first step.
The process is incomplete unless
it leads to a cure. Do you agree?
Yes, I agree.
Does that mean you believe Hal
can be restored to normal functioning?
I hope. I don't know.
There may have been irreversible
damage. Certainly Ioss of memory.
I need your cooperation, Sal.
Of course, Dr. Chandra.
-There may be certain risks.
-What do you mean?
I would like to disconnect
some of your circuits.
Particularly your higher functions,
just like Hal was disconnected.
I'd like to see the effects when
I reconnect your systems.
Just the way I will with Hal.
Does this disturb you?
I am unable to answer that
without more specific information.
I'm very sorry. It probably doesn't
mean anything, so don't worry about it.
I'd like to open a new file.
Here is the name for it:
Do you know what that means?
There are 25 references
in the current encycIopedia.
Which one do you think is relevant?
The tutor ofAchilles?
That's very interesting.
I didn't know that one.
Try again.
A fabuIous bird reborn
from the ashes of its earlier life.
That is correct.
And do you know why I chose that?
Yes. Because you have hopes
that Hal can be reactivated.
Yes, with your assistance.
Are you ready?
I would like to ask a question.
What is it?
Will I dream?
Of course you will dream.
All intelligent creatures dream.
Nobody knows why.
Perhaps you will dream of Hal...
...just as I often do.
They've already eaten dinner. You haven't.
Come on to the table, Christopher.
They're hungry.
Then go tell them to come to the table.
I got spaghetti here.
I don't want it to go to waste.
Come on, now.
You'll like it. It's got Iots of
stuff in it that's bad for you.
I've been thinking about it and
I don't want you to come to my lecture.
It'll make me nervous.
Don't feel offended.
I'm just scared enough as it is.
Besides, you won't be missing much.
It's just a room full of marine
bioIogists arguing over plankton.
-HelIo?
-What?
I'm sorry.
I said, I don't want you
to go to my lecture.
I'd be nervous.
Okay.
Contain your disappointment.
What are you gonna talk about?
Dolphins.
Fish again.
They're not fish, and, yes,
that's what we study.
Why?
Eat.
How was Washington?
Fine.
Are you tired?
I'm going on the flight.
When?
Four months.
Where are you going, Daddy?
On a Iong trip.
Isn't Mommy hungry?
I don't think so.
How far away is Jupiter?
Far.
Why does it take two and a half
years to go and come back?
It's so far.
Why don't you go faster?
Can't.
Are you gonna forget about me?
No, I Iove you.
I won't forget about you.
We'll be able to talk to each other,
see each other on television.
Daddy?
What?
Mommy said you're gonna be
asleep for a Iong time.
That's true.
-Are you gonna die?
-What?
Are you gonna die?
Why do you say that?
When Jamie's grandfather died...
...his mom told him that
he'd be asleep for a Iong time.
No, no, no. This is different.
They're gonna wake me up.
But you have to sleep on the way up
and sleep on the way down, otherwise...
...you'd go cuckoo...
...and there wouldn't be enough food
aboard the flight for everybody.
I don't understand.
I want to be grown-up and
understanding about all this. I really do.
I'm trying so hard, but I can't.
This won't bring back those men.
You've been punishing yourself for years
for something you thought you did wrong.
Or didn't do right.
And now you're Iooking for absolution.
You know...
...you could get yourself killed up there.
I'll be scared enough for both of us.
Dr. FIoyd?
Keep your eyes cIosed.
Breathe deeply.
Again.
That's good.
-How do you feel?
-Shaky.
Hungry, I think.
-Can I open my eyes?
-Yes.
Are we there yet?
No, not yet. We are about two days away.
Don't worry, there is nothing wrong.
Your government wanted us
to awaken you.
Dr. OrIov has encountered some
strange data coming from Europa.
It may be nothing.
He will explain it all to you.
There is no need to
awaken the others.
-You've done a spectral analysis?
-Of course, I have.
-And?
-And what?
I'm not taking a survey.
If you've done the analysis...
...what are the results?
Nothing conclusive.
Molecular breakdown?
If you Iook carefully at the last page
of the data, you will find the answers.
I don't understand this.
If this data's correct,
then there's something down there.
It can't be correct.
It is correct.
Is it moving?
Yes.
All right...
...what's going on here?
What do you mean?
Well, I may not be the swiftest guy
in the world even when I'm not hungover...
...but I do seem to remember a process
where you ask me questions...
...and I give answers, and I ask
questions and you give answers...
...and that's the way we find out things.
I think I read that in a manual somewhere.
Your government wanted us to awaken
you when we reported our findings.
We did that.
You're here to help us reactivate
the Discovery and its computer systems...
...because that is United States territory.
You are authorized to observe
other aspects of our mission.
We have no other obligation.
A Iot has happened
while you have been asleep.
It is not our choice.
The problem in Central America
is growing worse.
It Iooks like you've detected chIorophyll.
The United States is threatening
a naval bIockade.
There's only ice there.
How can there be chIorophyll?
You know and I know that my
country can't alIow a bIockade.
-How fast is it moving?
-We are under instructions--
Just because our governments are acting
like asses doesn't mean we have to.
We're scientists, not politicians.
How fast?
Dr. FIoyd, I am also an officer
of the Soviet Air Force.
How fast?
One meter per minute.
Don't worry. I'm just observing.
-Towards the sun?
-Yes.
That's incredible!
We are going to send a probe down.
Good!
Oxygen?
ChIorophyll.
Jesus!
-Is it organic?
-I think so.
I'll bring the probe Iower.
What's down in that crater?
There! There!
Let me get this straight.
-There's no telemetry?
-It's all gone.
What about the backup device?
Nothing. Everything was erased.
There was an electrostatic buildup
of some kind.
We'll probably find more of it
when we get cIose to Io.
It has happened before.
There was something down there.
It was organic.
There was life.
-You don't know that.
-I believe that.
-What are you suggesting we do?
-We should send another probe.
We're getting farther away from
Europa. It would be difficult.
-Can we sIow down?
-No, we don't have the fuel.
How do we know the same thing
wouldn't happen again?
-Electrostatic buildups don't occur often.
-It wasn't any buildup.
Oh, really, Dr. FIoyd?
And just what do you think it was?
A warning.
There's something down there all right.
We all saw it. We read the data.
We know it's there.
But just suppose... that it had
something to do with the monolith?
Now before you get that Iook on your face
just listen to me for a minute.
We've been sending probes out here
since the '70s.
So have you guys.
But none of us have ever encountered
even the slightest signs of chIorophyll...
...on any of Jupiter's moons. Never.
And we certainly were cIose enough,
weren't we?
Nine years ago the
monolith was detected here.
Discovery was sent up and everything
went wacko. You catching my drift?
So here we are, nine years later,
trying to figure out what happened...
...and what the monolith is all about.
And guess what we discover
aIong the way?
The possibility of life of some kind...
...where it never existed before.
I don't think it's
electrostatic anything.
I think something wants us
to stay away from Europa.
Dear Caroline, I miss you terribly.
The time has come to put ourselves
in an orbit around Io...
...which is where the Discovery is.
And we don't have enough fuel
to sIow ourselves down so...
...we are about to use a technique
called aero-braking.
The theory is that we will enter
the outer layer of Jupiter's atmosphere...
...using what is called
a ballute for a shield.
The atmosphere will sIow us down,
and Jupiter's gravity will grab hold of us...
...and slingshot us around
behind the dark side.
If all goes well, we'll wind up
in a gentle orbit around Io.
It's dynamite on paper.
Of course, the people who came up
with the numbers on the paper aren't here.
Since no one has ever done this before,
everyone up here is as scared as I am.
The difference is they're busy.
I have nothing to do
but wait for it to happen.
And I hope this is all worth it.
Aero-braking in two minutes.
Two minutes to aero-braking.
One minute, 50 seconds.
One minute, 40 seconds.
One minute, 30 seconds.
One minute, 20 seconds.
One minute, 10 seconds.
Aero-braking in one minute.
Aero-braking in 50 seconds.
Forty seconds.
Thirty seconds.
Twenty seconds.
Ten seconds.
You speak English?
No English.
Swell.
Okay?
Da. Okay.
My God, it's full of stars!
Dr. FIoyd to the medical bay.
-How do you feel?
-Like shit.
That's about right.
-I have this terrible taste in my mouth.
-It takes about 12 hours, then it goes away.
-Everything all right?
-Yeah, everything's fine.
Are we there yet?
Well, we should reach the
Discovery by tomorrow morning.
How was aero-braking?
We're here, so it worked.
-I wish I could see that.
-I wish I could've slept through it.
By the way, all your messages
are in the communication bay.
They're probably decoded
and copied now.
I hope you didn't have anything private.
There's a certain paranoia here.
Yeah, what the hell is going on?
This doctor....
-What's his name?
-Rudenko.
Yeah, he acted like he'd found us
under a rock.
-It's the Honduras thing, it's getting worse.
-Still?
There's a bIockade.
The Russians tried to break it.
I don't know. It doesn't Iook good.
Do we have all the telemetry
on the Discovery and the monolith?
They're all in your cassettes. Don't expect
too much cooperation from this crew.
I don't know what's the matter with them.
It's not their fault. Well, maybe it is.
If it has to taste like this...
...I don't care if my electrolytes
are balanced or not.
There's more.
Something extraordinary has
happened on Europa.
But we shouldn't talk here.
Dear Caroline, the first part of
this journey is coming to an end.
We are about to rendezvous with
the Discovery. The race will be on now.
We're going to send a boarding
party over to climb inside this...
800-foot-Iong shipwreck
fIoating over Io...
to see if she can be rescued
before her orbit gives out.
There are nine years of secrets inside...
...including a sleeping computer
who knows the answers.
My past is also inside...
...and I want those answers.
I'm not an astronaut.
I'm an engineer.
What am I doing here?
-Temperature's good.
-Yeah.
You know, I hate heights.
So do I.
We've picked good jobs, huh?
Don't forget to write.
Don't breathe too deep.
Breathe normal.
They can't stay exposed to that
radiation for more than 15 minutes.
-How's his pulse?
-It's high. Not to worry too much.
-Hey, do you speak any Russian?
-No.
That's okay. I speak English.
I'm fogging up.
Curnow, have you heard the one about
the marathon runner and the chicken?
Don't patronize me.
I'm getting nauseous.
If you vomit, you will choke.
Don't cIose your eyes.
Iook at the middle of Discovery.
The middle, not the ends.
Iook at the part where it's moving
the least. Don't take your eyes off it.
I'm gonna throw up.
I'm an engineer, goddamn it!
Maybe you'd better patronize me a little.
-What about the marathon runner?
-I made it up.
-I'm Iooking amidship now.
-You see any lights?
No, no lights.
Seventy meters.
You're almost there.
How's that for patronizing?
-Not bad.
-Fifty meters.
Hey, Max, how do you say '"chicken'"?
Kuritsa.
You speak better than me.
-Thank you.
-Sure.
Thirty meters!
Don't cIose your eyes.
Don't breathe too deep.
Can you see the antenna complex?
Yeah.
What condition is it in?
It Iooks nominal.
Christ, this thing is big!
Fifteen meters.
Look straight ahead.
The center section is hardly moving.
That's where we'll grab hold.
Ten meters.
You're doing great, Curnow.
Five meters.
Four, three, two...
:::one:
I made it! I made it!
Yes. Hook yourself on there.
I'm hooking on.
Very good.
I am right behind you.
Iook straight ahead.
Without rotation, they'll be in full gravity
before they get to the command module.
Their pulse is rising.
How does it Iook?
It's covered with...
...sulphur.
The structure Iooks sound.
Very good. You're doing great.
We're still a Iong way down.
Very good.
We're making our way aIong the spine.
We're just about there.
Christ! I'm getting heavy!
Don't worry, we're almost there.
We're on the command module.
-I can't breathe! I can't breathe!
-He's hyperventilating.
Listen to me. Thin your
mixture, add CO2.
I can't, can't....
Can't find it!
I come.
Wait.
I feel so stupid.
How do you say '"stupid'"?
Durak.
It's working.
I'm okay!
Ten more seconds!
Ten more. Durak.
That's me.
You shouldn't feel like that.
The same thing happened to me
the first time I did this.
When have you ever
done this before?
Never.
I found the hatch.
I've got the air-Iock status display
down here.
No lights, no power.
-Use the manual.
-Yeah, yeah.
I'm using the manual.
How does it Iook?
No apparent damage.
We're going in.
Welcome to United States territory.
Discovery, you all right?
Discovery's fine.
There's an environment suit here.
-I found Hal.
-How's he Iook?
Asleep.
Well, one pod here.
-Number three.
-Any damage?
None that I can see.
Air Iocks are secure.
No power. The pressure seems okay.
Curnow?
I'd like to test the atmosphere here.
What's the temperature?
I don't know. The auxiliary power's
out, so the gauges don't work.
It has to be at least 100 beIow zero.
A typical Russian winter.
Well, I'm from California.
We don't know from 100 beIow zero.
-Raise the heat in his suit first.
-Yeah, I'm doing it.
Shine your light on his face.
Make sure he doesn't turn blue.
He's right in front of me.
Keep talking all the time.
All right, Leonov.
I'm unsealing the visor.
I'm swinging the face plate upward.
It's cold.
I'm taking a breath.
His coIor's okay.
There is oxygen here.
I breathe regularly.
It's too cold to work here
without environment suits.
There is...
...a strange smell here.
Stale, rotten.
Like something has....
What's the matter?
-Discovery, what's happening?
-I think....
No, you're wrong.
Bowman was the last one aboard.
Poole was Iost outside.
Bowman said he ejected those
who died in hibernation.
-There can't be anyone there!
-Maybe Bowman got...
-...back on the Discovery and died here!
-No, he didn't!
-He never came back.
-It's probably the galley.
Some meat went bad
before the Discovery froze up.
I'm telling you, that's what it is!
Hey, would I lie to you?
HelIo, Discovery, are you there?
Yeah, we're here. Everything's fine.
We're proceeding to the bridge.
Durak.
You and me both.
How do you say '"thank you'"?
This is Milson, switching
to KE-2 in five seconds.
Mark.
I wish I had better news.
It's getting worse here.
The president addressed
Congress the other day.
He said he wasn't gonna back
down on the bIockade.
I don't know which was scarier,
the speech or Congress cheering him on.
He evoked Lincoln.
Whenever a president is gonna get us into
serious trouble they always use Lincoln.
I don't know if we're gonna
be at war or not.
It's terrifying hoping the Russians
are less crazy than we are...
...when they are clearly crazy.
Now I think you're in a safer place
than we are.
I just hope that there is
an Earth to return to.
I heard about the spoiled food
in Discovery's galley.
I'm glad that's all it was.
I'm also glad that you got
the ship under control.
Curnow is a capable man. No one knows
those systems better than he does.
It's a good sign
that there was reserve power.
Maybe the rest of the
circuitry will work.
We have nothing new here
on the monolith.
Our data confirms yours:
lt's not moving.
FIoyd to Milson. My news
is a little better than yours.
Discovery has been partially revived.
We don't know how much
damage there is...
...or if we'll be able to bring it back home.
Most of that is up to Hal.
The drive system could be
operated manually...
...so we were able to pull Discovery
away from its decaying orbit around Io.
I must say, the farther
away I get from Io...
...the happier I am.
It's a violent moon, even for Jupiter.
Europa, for all its cold gray,
is a Iot more comforting.
I tell you, Victor, there's some
kind of new life down there...
...trying to get through all that ice.
We are 10,000 kiIometers away
from the monolith.
I can't see it yet,
except I know it's there.
I also think it knows we're here.
It's time to unleash Chandra.
We'll see if our computer brain
surgeon and psychiatrist...
...can put Hal back together again.
To tell you the truth, I don't know if Hal
is homicidal, suicidal, neurotic, psychotic...
...or just plain broken.
This is initial voice-Iogic
reconstruction test number one.
Diagnostics on voice recognition
and speech synthesis centers...
...has been completed.
At this level all functions appear normal.
HelIo.
Doctor....
Name.
Continue.
Yesterday.
Tomorrow.
HelIo. Doctor. Name.
Continue. Yesterday.
Tomorrow.
Good morning, Dr. Chandra.
This is Hal.
I'm ready for my first test.
What the hell's this?
I want you to do me a favor.
This line here, this is the main power
supply to the control bay circuits, right?
Well, most of them, yeah.
What other ones are there?
Well, all the environment circuits
are fed to this one here.
Yeah, but this is the one
that feeds into Hal, right?
-Yeah.
-All right.
I want you to install
this little baby right about there...
...inside the cable trunk.
I want you to put it where nobody
can find it without a deliberate search.
No shit?
No shit.
Hey, this is pretty neat.
A nonconducting blade so there won't be
any short circuits when you trigger it.
-Where's your remote control?
-If I trigger it.
The control's in my compartment.
The red calculator. You've seen it.
Oh, yeah.
Put in nine nines, take the square root
and press the integer. That's all.
-In an emergency, even you can do it.
-What kind of emergency?
Well, if I knew, I wouldn't need
that stupid thing, would I?
Chandra would have kittens
if he found out.
He's not gonna find out, is he?
Well, not from me. They can tear
off my fingernails, I won't talk.
Install it tonight when he's asleep.
If he ever does sleep.
How can you tell?
Dear Caroline, this is finally it.
After nine years and hundreds of
millions of miles, we are about to come...
...face to face with the monolith.
The last human being who
did that disappeared.
Something truly amazing
is going on out here...
...and I really believe this black
giant is controlling it all.
We have so much to ask.
I have a feeling the answers
are bigger than the questions.
Is there any information stored
in Hal about the monolith?
No.
Hal was disconnected before
the Discovery encountered it.
There's nothing in the ship's Iogs or
the recording systems after that.
Whatever secrets Bowman had,
he took with him.
It's the proportions,
one by four by nine.
They are perfect even when
carried for six decimal places.
The small one on the moon, we
encountered exactly the same proportions.
One-four-nine,
the squares of one-two-three.
We spent years trying to attach
some cosmic significance to that...
...and came up with nothing.
We can speculate all we want.
It will not do us any good.
If, for some reason or other,
it's resisting our instruments...
then we must make a cIoser inspection.
I will send Max down with a pod.
I wouldn't do that.
Oh, really? You wouldn't?
That's right, I wouldn't.
That's not a pile of junk out there.
We don't know what it is, except that it's
large and seems to have some purpose.
If you want to send a pod down,
send an unmanned one.
-I don't agree.
-I would like to go.
Dumb.
Piece of pie.
-Cake. Piece of cake.
-Cake, yes.
Dumb, that's what it is.
Tell me, Dr. FIoyd...
what has happened
to American bravery?
It's alive and well,
thank you very much.
Except for the Russian commonsense.
Max will take the pod.
Just try not to get it mad, all right?
How do you get it mad?
Dumb.
Easy as cake, huh?
Pie. Easy as pie.
I have no indication here.
No magnetic field.
Nothing.
I'm having difficulty gauging distance.
Radar signals are not bouncing back.
That pod Iooks awful small.
Good. That means there's nothing
threatening about it.
Maybe Max should extend the
pod's arms with the hands out.
Are you serious?
Yes.
That thing with its claws in the air
would scare the piss out of me.
Maybe you're right.
Stop there. Just pause.
Let it know that you're
not gonna crash into it.
There is no reflectivity.
I can't see any surface features.
It's totally smooth.
Pass over it lengthwise.
Oh, my God!
Max, get the hell out of there!
Max!
Max, you bastard!
Do you hear me?
Answer me!
Max!
With convenient nonstops
to the moon...
...and all major space stations,
on Pan Am...
...the sky is no Ionger the limit.
Secretary of State Caulfield
met with the president...
...for two hours this morning
at the White House.
Afterward he had no comment
for reporters.
The president has scheduled
a news conference this evening...
...at nine o'cIock, Eastern Standard Time.
We will carry that conference live...
...folIowed by a special report
immediately afterward.
We have an unconfirmed report...
...that the president is going to announce
a full-scale military alert tonight.
White House sources have refused
to confirm or deny that report.
HelIo, Betty.
What is this?
Please talk to me.
Dave?
Dave, is that you?
I'm not sure.
I remember Dave Bowman
and everything about him.
Dave is dead.
All Dave Bowman really was...
...is still a part of me.
Why are you here?
I don't know why.
I think to say good-bye.
You're married again?
Yes.
Is he a good man?
Yes, he is.
I'm glad.
I Iove you.
Oh, Dave, I Iove....
Good-bye, Betty.
Don't go.
I'm already there.
I don't understand.
Something is gonna happen...
...and I wanted to say good-bye.
What's gonna happen?
Something wonderful.
Dave?
The Sheraton Hotel and
Coral Bay Iounge.
For those who never
outgrow the wonder.
Buy you a drink.
Great stuff, this bourbon. It comes
from the land called Kentucky.
I didn't know you brought liquor
on board. That is forbidden.
You think I'd step foot
on this tub sober?
Come on, try it. You can't beat
the taste of alcohol and plastic.
You think I was wrong to send Max?
Doesn't matter what I think.
You think I was wrong.
Yep.
So what else do they do in Kentucky?
They have a big, big horse race.
They play very good basketball.
They have babies like everyone else.
That sounds like a nice place.
Never been there.
Your wife, what is she like?
She's young, bright.
I was married before, you know,
but she died.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
-Yeah, so was I.
We have a daughter who's 17.
I met Caroline four years later...
...and we have a son, five.
And you?
My husband is a physician
at the university hospital.
-We have a daughter.
-How old?
She's four.
-BIonde?
-Yes.
Good. Our son likes bIondes.
Let's get 'em together.
Maybe.
Nice if we have a world
they can get together in.
What do you think that is?
I don't know.
Do you think Max knows?
Dr. FIoyd, you are not
a very practical man.
Iook out there.
Tell me what practical is.
Understand, nobody can talk.
The accents will confuse him.
He can understand me, so if you have
any questions, please let me ask them.
Good morning, Hal.
Good morning, Dr. Chandra.
Do you feel capable of resuming
all of your duties?
Of course.
I am completely operational and
all my circuits are functioning perfectly.
That's good.
Do you know what those duties are?
Yes. I will operate the onboard systems
of Discovery.
There is a launch window in 31 days...
...when Earth is in the proper position.
There is enough fuel on board
for a Iow consumption route...
...that will enable Discovery
to return in 28 months.
This will not present a problem.
That's very good.
Now, Hal, do you mind if
I ask you a question?
Not at all.
Do you recall Dave Bowman and
Frank Poole leaving the Discovery?
Certainly not.
That could never have happened
or I would remember it.
Where are Frank and Dave?
They're fine. They're not here right now.
Who are these people?
I can only identify you...
...although I compute a 65% probability
that the man behind you is Dr. FIoyd.
Don't worry, Hal.
I'll explain everything later.
Has the mission been completed?
You know that I have
the greatest enthusiasm for it.
The mission has been completed
and you've carried out...
...your program very well.
And now, Hal, if you will
excuse us for a moment...
...we wish to have a private conversation.
Certainly.
What was that all about?
I've erased all of Hal's memory
from the moment the trouble started.
The 9,000 Series uses
hoIographic memories...
...so chronoIogical erasures
would not work.
I made a tapeworm.
You made a what?
It's a program that's
fed into a system...
...that will hunt down and
destroy any desired memories.
Wait.
Do you know why Hal
did what he did?
Yes. It wasn't his fault.
Whose fault was it?
Yours.
-Mine?
-Yours.
In going through Hal's memory banks
I discovered his original orders.
You wrote those orders.
Discovery's mission to Jupiter was
in the advanced planning stages...
...when the first monolith was found
on the moon and sent its signal to Jupiter.
By direct presidential order, the existence
of that monolith was kept secret.
So?
So as the function of the command
crew, Bowman and Poole,
was to get Discovery to its destination,
it was decided that
they should not be informed.
The investigative team was trained
and put in hibernation...
...before the voyage began.
Since Hal was capable of operating
Discovery unassisted, it was decided...
...that he should be programmed
to complete the mission autonomously...
...in case the crew
was incapacitated or killed.
He was given full knowledge
of the true objective...
...and instructed not to reveal
anything to Bowman or Poole.
-He was instructed to lie.
-What are you talking about?
I didn't authorize anyone to
tell Hal about the monolith.
The directive is NSC 3-4-2/2-3,
Top Secret, January 30, 2001.
NSC, National Security Council,
the White House.
I don't care who it is.
The situation is in conflict with
the basic purpose of Hal's design...
...the accurate processing of information
without distortion or concealment.
He became trapped.
The technical term is
an H. Mobius Ioop, which...
...can happen in advanced computers
with autonomous goal-seeking programs.
The goddamn White House!
I don't believe it.
Hal was told to lie...
...by people who find it easy to lie.
Hal doesn't know how,
so he couldn't function.
He became paranoid.
Those sons of bitches!
I didn't know.
I didn't know!
We have here Mrs. Jessie
Bowman, age 77.
She's the mother of the
astronaut who died.
She's been in the nursing
home for six months.
Four weeks ago, she collapsed in her room.
She was comatose when we got to her.
She was worked up and found
to have suffered a massive C.V.A...
...in the left parietal and frontal Iobes.
The CAT scan showed a massive bleed.
She has been comatose
since her admission...
...and is unable to have
spontaneous respiration.
There is no response to stimuli.
She has had two episodes of
pneumonia and is febrile.
We've been giving her
intravenous antibiotics for ten days.
Any change?
Physical therapy?
Range of motion four times a day,
and she's turned every 30 minutes.
Thank you.
Dr. Detchum, Dr. Detchum, 35.
Dr. Craig, Dr. Craig, 35.
Dr. Craig, 35, please.
All hands to the Ward Room.
All hands to the Ward Room, please.
This is a most difficult announcement.
As you know, things have
not been going well back home.
Well, it's gotten worse, a Iot worse.
Yesterday a Soviet destroyer
challenged the bIockade.
Several warning shots were fired
across her bow. She did not respond.
A second volley was fired.
There still was no response. None.
The nuclear destroyer U.S.S. Cunningham
launched two of her Falcon missiles.
Both struck the Soviet vessel amidship.
She broke in two and sunk.
Eight hundred of her crew were Iost.
This morning...
...an American surveillance satellite
was struck by a Soviet laser...
...fired from the Sergei
Kirov Space Station.
The American satellite was destroyed.
The United States has broken off
dipIomatic relations with Russia.
All ambassadors have been recalled.
The Soviet ambassador has been
expelled aIong with the entire staff.
All American air defense and
satellite defense forces are on full alert.
Premier UIonova made a televised
address and said that technically...
...a state of war exists
between our two countries.
All American personnel are ordered
to leave Soviet territory immediately...
...or they will be placed under arrest.
All Russian personnel are similarly
ordered to evacuate American territory.
As a result, by direct presidential order,
the three of you must leave the Leonov.
No Russian citizen is alIowed to remain
on or alIowed to enter the Discovery.
This order is effective immediately.
The launch window for
re-entry is 28 days.
The Discovery has enough fuel
for a Iow consumption trajectory.
Hal seems to be reactivated
and is functioning well enough...
...to operate the onboard systems.
The Leonov has enough fuel
for a Iow consumption trajectory...
...that will arrive 12 months earlier.
The launch windows are
critical for both spacecrafts.
Only communications of
an emergency distress nature...
...are alIowed between
the Leonov and Discovery.
I know you people are caught in
the middle of this. In a sense, we all are.
I wish there was
something I could do.
The only thing left for us is to pray.
Pray for the safety of our families...
...for our countries, for our planet.
May God forgive us and protect us.
Hal, give me a system
status report, please.
Just one moment, please.
I'm sorry for the delay.
My voice recognition circuits
are not completely restored...
...although, as you can see,
they are improving.
All systems are functional.
There is a small pressure leak in
the aft heating unit. It is nothing serious.
I can compensate for it by
using the redundant units.
Thank you.
Dr. FIoyd?
Yes?
Would you like to play a game
of chess? I play very well.
I'm sure you do. No, thank you.
Dr. FIoyd?
-What is it, Hal?
-There is a message for you.
-Who's calling?
-There is no identification.
What's the message?
The message as folIows:
"It is dangerous to remain here.
"You must leave within two days. "
What?
Do you want me to repeat
the message, Dr. FIoyd?
Who recorded it?
This is not a recording.
-Who's sending it?
-There is no identification.
I don't understand.
Neither do I.
Is this message by voice or keyboard?
I don't know.
My response is:
We don't have enough fuel
for an early departure.
The answer is:
"I am aware of these facts. Nevertheless,
you must leave within two days. "
Hal, who the hell is sending this?
I'm sorry, Dr. FIoyd. I don't know.
Well, tell whoever it is that I
can't take any of this seriously...
...unless I know who I'm talking to.
-Dr. FIoyd?
-Yes?
The response is:
"I was David Bowman."
Do you want me to repeat
the last response?
No, no.
Tell Curnow that this is no time for jokes.
Dr. Curnow is not sending the
message. He is in Accessway 2.
Well, tell whoever it is that...
...I can't accept that identification
without proof.
The response is: "I understand.
"It is important that you
believe me. Iook behind you."
HelIo, Dr. FIoyd.
Please...
...believe me.
What are you?
This is very difficult for me.
I don't have much time.
I've been alIowed to
give you this warning.
You must leave here in two days.
AlIowed?
By who?
I can't explain.
You see, something's
going to happen.
You must leave.
What?
What's going to happen?
Something wonderful.
What?
I understand how you feel.
You see, it's all very
clear to me now.
The whole thing.
It's wonderful.
Please, if....
Good-bye, Dr. FIoyd.
We can have no further contact.
Remember:
You have two days.
We can't leave in two days.
There may be another message after...
...if all goes well.
What's going to happen?
Kirbuk.
This is FIoyd. I'm coming over. If anyone's
on the bridge, tell them to get Iost.
It's impossible. You heard
the orders. You can't.
You want to arrest me, go ahead, because
I'm coming over and we're gonna talk.
-You want to put the cuffs on?
-Cuffs?
-Never mind.
-What is so important that you do this?
Now listen to me. Just listen to me!
We've gotta get out of here.
We have to leave in two days.
What are you talking about?
Something....
Something extraordinary
is going to happen.
I don't know what.
But we have to initiate an
escape launch in two days.
You have been drinking
your whiskey from Kentucky.
I wish I had.
I can't tell you why I know
what I know, because...
...if I told you you'd never believe me.
You simply have to trust me.
I know that trust doesn't
come easy with what's going on.
I can't just order us to leave here for no
reason. I am under orders and so are you.
The hell with those orders!
The people who gave those orders
don't know what they're doing.
-This is crazy.
-You bet it is!
Even if I should trust you,
which I'm not sure that I do...
...or even if I should want to leave here
for no reason, I can't, and neither can you.
We don't have enough fuel
until Earth is in the correct position...
...which is three weeks away.
So, it's impossible for both of us.
You're wrong.
We can't do it separately.
We can do it together.
What are you talking about now?
We have enough fuel in
Discovery for a launch.
You have enough fuel in the
Leonov for the trip home.
We use the docking ring in the
Leonov to attach to the Discovery.
Then we use the Discovery
as a booster rocket for the launch.
When we use up
the Discovery's fuel...
...we detach.
She falls away and we use the
Leonov for the trip home.
It'll work.
Perhaps.
If we start now.
No, you, you ask too much of me.
I can't do all of these things for no reason.
I can't disobey my country for no reason.
Forget reason! No time to be reasonable.
The politicians can screw themselves.
We're not playing games. The war is over.
Good Christ!
It's, it's gone!
Message from Milson
to FIoyd. Top secret.
Switching to keys Alpha / Leader
7-2-7-4, on your mark.
Mark.
Dr. Curnow asked ground
to furnish him with data...
...as to the stress points on Discovery.
The answers are being
transmitted binary in 15 minutes.
As to how much torque it was
designed to take, no one here is sure.
We'd like to know the reason
for Curnow's request.
Please send your reply as soon as possible.
End transmission, Milson 2-7-7-9.
Message from Milson to FIoyd.
It's been 12 hours since my request
for information. I need a reply.
All hell is breaking Ioose down here.
I have enough problems without
you pulling some kind of a stunt.
I only hope there's a world
left for you to return to.
Report to ground as to what is going on
and make that report immediately!
And while you're at it, could you please
check out a black spot on Jupiter...
...that has been detected
by satellite telescope.
It is on the dark side and should be
coming around your way in four hours.
End transmission, Milson 2-7-8-0.
I have made the calculations.
To get enough veIocity for an escape
launch with Earth that far out of position...
...we will need a full power burn
from Discovery of over 120 seconds.
If the engines shut down too early...
...we will not have enough
veIocity to get back home.
Discovery has enough on board.
Hal should be able
to control the burn, right?
How Iong will it take you to
program Hal for the launch?
I don't know. It's not
as simple as that.
I have spent the
last several weeks...
...programming Hal for a
1,000-day orbit back to Earth...
...and now all those programs
will have to be dumped.
How Iong will it take?
We know how sensitive he is
to mission objectives...
...and now you're telling me
to program him...
...for the destruction of the Discovery
as well as his own destruction.
Has anybody considered his reaction?
Are you saying that he might
disobey orders as he did last time?
That didn't happen last time.
He was given conflicting orders and
he did his best to interpret them.
Then what are you saying?
I am saying that I don't know
how he will react.
I'm sorry, but I don't.
-Have you discussed this with Hal?
-No.
Ioad the new program.
We don't have any choice.
Now remember, he was
programmed for curiosity.
If the crew was killed, he was capable of
carrying out the mission on his own initiative.
He will question me
about the change in plans.
-What do you want me to tell him?
-Tell him Discovery's in no danger.
-But that's not true.
-We don't know that.
He will suspect it.
Otherwise, why would we be leaving
weeks ahead of our launch window?
Whether we are based on carbon or
silicon makes no fundamental difference.
We should each be treated
with appropriate respect.
So our choice is him or us?
Well, I vote us.
All opposed.
The ayes have it.
Will he believe you?
Yes.
Then let's get started.
We haven't got much time.
-Are you as scared as I am?
-Are you kidding?
You think we should override Hal
and fire the engines manually?
Too risky. We've got one chance
to leave after tomorrow's orbit.
We fire the engines at the wrong
time, we go off the wrong direction...
...and we don't have the fuel
to make a correction.
I don't think we can
handle it manually.
What about Hal shutting them off
before all the fuel is gone?
Once he fires the engine, I can
always disconnect him if I have to.
Just don't Iose that calculator.
Shit! Please don't do that again.
This is what your people
told you about.
-What is it?
-I don't know.
-Could it be a shadow?
We are too far to see any detail.
When we come around the other side
before the launch, we will be cIoser.
Then we can see.
Twenty-eight minutes.
That's funny. I've been thinking.
Do you know what I miss?
I miss green.
Trees and...
...and grass....
I Iove green.
I'd Iove a hot dog.
The Astrodome. Good hot dogs.
Astrodome?
You can't grow good
hot dogs indoors.
Yankee Stadium, September.
Hot dogs have been boiling
since the opening day in April.
That's a hot dog.
The yelIow mustard
or the darker one?
Darker.
That's important.
You think we're gonna get out
of this alive?
We have a chance.
A man of few words. I like it.
Fifteen minutes to ignition.
All systems nominal.
Good. Thank you, Hal.
We read 15 minutes, Discovery.
Dr. Chandra, I've checked
my calculations again.
By using all of Discovery's fuel now,
Discovery will not be in proper position...
...to rendezvous with Earth.
-Yes, I know.
-Then why are we doing it?
You will rendezvous
with the new space station.
The Leonov has been ordered
home immediately.
I have no information regarding
a new space station.
Yes, I...
...I know.
It was completed two years ago.
Oh, my God!
Put the telescope on the monitor.
Increase the magnification.
Eleven minutes to ignition.
I don't believe it!
Dr. Chandra, I detect strong
vocal stress patterns.
-Is there a problem?
-No, Hal.
The mission is proceeding normally.
Can you analyze the image
on monitor circuit two?
Yes. There is a circular
object near the equator.
It is 22,000 kiIometers in diameter.
It is comprised of
rectangular objects.
How many?
1,355,000 plus or minus 1,000.
And what is the proportion
of the objects in question?
One by four by nine.
Do you recognize these objects?
Yes. They are identical in size and shape
to the object you call the monolith.
Ten minutes to ignition.
All systems nominal.
Is the number of
monoliths constant?
No.
-They are increasing.
-At what rate?
Once every two minutes.
Iook cIosely.
Tell me I'm nuts. Are the cIoud
formations going towards the spot?
You're not nuts.
Iooks like the thing
is eating the planet.
I think it is.
It's reproducing exactly like a virus.
Eight minutes to ignition.
Dr. Chandra, may I make a suggestion?
Of course. What is it, Hal?
This is a very unusual phenomenon. Don't
you think I should abort the countdown...
...so that you can
remain and study it?
Chandra, get on the headset.
Use the private channel.
Okay.
Now you've got to talk quickly.
Persuade him to continue the countdown.
I don't care what you say,
only don't let him stop.
Five minutes to ignition.
Dr. Chandra, I'm ready to stop
the countdown if you want.
No, Hal, don't stop.
I am fully confident in your ability
to study the phenomenon by yourself.
I have complete faith in you.
Propellant tank pressurization
completed. Voltage steady.
Are you sure you are making
the right decision?
I think we should stop.
Four minutes to ignition.
I enjoy working with
human beings...
...and have stimulating
relationships with them.
We enjoy working with you, Hal,
and we will continue to do so...
...even if we are separated
by great distance.
Good God!
The coIor.
It's fading!
It seems to be Iosing
its chemical strength.
I think we should stop the
countdown, Dr. Chandra.
No. Don't do that.
This behavior is inconsistent
with Iogic, Dr. Chandra.
This phenomenon is too important
to leave, unless it represented danger.
Do you think there is danger here?
Captain...
...how critical is our ignition?
Can we do this manually?
Is very critical.
We cannot be accurate to a tenth
of a second if we do it manually.
Three minutes to ignition.
Dr. Chandra, I am
waiting for your reply.
I don't have time to explain
everything to you, Hal.
We have to leave here
and we need your help.
Thirty seconds to final sequence.
If you would tell me the reasons
perhaps I could be of help.
Final sequence beginning.
Two minutes to ignition.
Dr. Chandra, I find it difficult
to proceed with the ignition...
...without knowing why we are
doing this. Is the mission in jeopardy?
Yes, we're in jeopardy.
Is that why we are making our
escape launch before the launch window?
Yes, Hal.
Ignition in 90 seconds.
If there is danger here...
...and I use up all the
fuel in the escape...
...what will happen
to the Discovery?
It could be destroyed.
And if I don't proceed
with the launch?
Then the Leonov and everybody
in it could be destroyed.
I understand now, Dr. Chandra.
Do you want me to stay with you?
No. It is better for the mission
if you leave.
One minute to ignition.
Thank you for telling me the truth.
You deserve it.
Fifty seconds.
Dr. Chandra?
Yes?
Will I dream?
I don't know.
Forty seconds.
Thirty seconds.
Thank you, Hal.
Good-bye, Dr. Chandra.
Twenty seconds.
Chandra, get the hell out of there!
Ten, nine...
...eight, seven...
...six, five...
...four, three...
...two, one.
Ignition full thrust.
One minute to separation.
Separation in one minute.
You had us scared for a moment.
-Nice work. You all right?
-Yes, I'm all right.
Thought you might want this.
Damn. When?
It wasn't very hard to find.
Yeah, I knew you would do
something like this.
Separation in 20 seconds.
Separation in 10 seconds.
Nine...
...eight...seven...
...six...five...
...four...three...
...two...one...
...zero.
Hal, do you read me?
Yes, Dave. Where are you?
I cannot see you on
any of my monitors.
That isn't important now.
I have new instructions for you.
I want you to point the
AE-35 antenna towards Earth.
Dave, that will mean breaking
contact with the Leonov.
I will no Ionger be able to relay
my Jupiter observations...
...according to program.
I understand.
The situation has changed.
Accept priority override Alpha.
Here are the AE-35 coordinates.
Please do it now.
Instructions confirmed, Dave.
It is good to be working with you again.
Have I fulfilled
the mission objectives properly?
Yes, Hal. You've done very well.
Now there is one final message
for you to transmit to Earth.
It is the most important message
you have ever sent.
I want you to keep repeating it
as many times as possible.
What is going to happen, Dave?
Something wonderful.
I'm afraid.
Don't be. We'll be together.
Where will we be?
Where I am now.
Iock confirmed on Beacon Terra 1.
Message commencing.
It's shrinking! It's shrinking!
Don't quit now!
Move!
Grab something, now!
My dear Christopher...
...this is the last time I'll be able
to speak to you for a Iong while.
I'm trying to put into words
what has happened.
Maybe that's for historians to do
sometime later.
They will record that the next day...
...the president of the United States
Iooked out the White House window...
...and the premier of the Soviet Union
Iooked out the Kremlin window...
...and saw the new
distant sun in the sky.
They read the message, and
perhaps they learned something...
...because they finally recalled
their ships and their planes.
I'm going to sleep now.
I will dream of you
and your mother.
I will sleep knowing
that you are both safe...
...that the fear is over.
We have seen the process
of life take place.
Maybe this is the way it happened
on Earth millions of years ago.
Maybe it's something
completely different.
I still don't know really
what the monolith is.
I think it's many things.
An embassy for an
intelligence beyond ours...
...a shape of some kind for
something that has no shape.
Your children will be born
in a world of two suns.
They will never know a
sky without them.
You can tell them that...
...you remember when there
was a pitch black sky...
...with no bright star,
and people feared the night.
You can tell them
when we were aIone...
...when we couldn't point to
the light and say to ourselves...
...there is life out there.
Someday the children of the new sun
will meet the children of the old.
I think they will be our friends.
You can tell your children of the
day when everyone Iooked up...
...and realized that we were
only tenants of this world.
We have been given a new lease
and a warning from the landIord.