Old Marley was as dead as a doornail.
This must be distinctly understood...
...or nothing wonderful can come
of this story I am going to relate.
On Christmas night all Christians sing
To hear the news the angels bring
Thank you, sir.
Holly! Get your Christmas holly!
Seven years ago today.
What's that you say?
Mr. Marley died.
Seven years ago this very day.
Would it be too much to ask...
...that you return to the work
for which I pay you so handsomely?
Mr. Cratchit!
The fire's gone cold, Mr. Scrooge.
Come over here, Mr. Cratchit.
- What is this?
- A shirt.
- And this?
- A waistcoat.
- A coat.
These are garments.
Garments were invented
as protection against the cold.
Once purchased,
they may be used indefinitely...
...for the purpose
for which they are intended.
Coal burns.
Coal is momentary, and coal is costly.
There will be no more coal
burnt in this office today.
- Is that quite clear, Mr. Cratchit?
- Yes, sir.
Get back to work
before I'm forced to conclude...
...that your services
are no longer required.
Yes, sir.
- Merry Christmas, Bob Cratchit.
- The same to you, Mr. Fred.
Merry Christmas, Uncle.
I said, merry Christmas, Uncle.
Humbug.
Christmas, a humbug, Uncle?
- Surely you don't mean that.
- I do.
What's Christmas...
...but a time for buying things...
...for which you have no need,
no money?
Time for finding yourself
a year older, not an hour richer.
If I could work my will...
...every idiot who has
"Merry Christmas" on his lips...
...should be boiled
in his own pudding...
...and buried with a stake of hollies
through his heart.
Come now, Uncle.
You keep Christmas in your way,
and let me keep it in mine.
You don't keep it.
Let me leave it alone then!
Much good it may do you.
Much good it has done you.
There are many things
in which I might have derived good...
...from which I have not profited.
Christmas, among the rest.
But I've always thought
of Christmastime as a good time...
...a kindlier, forgiving,
charitable time...
...when men and women
see their one consent...
...to open their shut-up hearts
freely to their fellow creatures.
Though it has never put a scrap
of gold or silver into my pocket...
...I do believe
that it has done me good.
And I say, God bless it.
Not a sound from you.
And you'll keep your Christmas
by losing your situation.
You're a powerful speaker.
I wonder you don't go into Parliament.
Please don't be angry, Uncle.
Come. Dine with us tomorrow.
Dine? I'd see myself in hell first.
It would be a great joy to me.
And to my wife.
Yes, your wife.
I'm told she brought little
to the marriage. A poor girl.
I love her.
And she loves me.
Love.
Good afternoon, Nephew.
I want nothing from you.
I ask nothing of you.
- Why can't we be friends?
- You are wasting my time.
I'm sorry to find you so resolute.
We've never had a quarrel,
so far as I know.
And so I shall keep my good humor
and wish you a merry Christmas.
- Goodbye.
- And a happy New Year.
- How's that fine family of yours?
- Well. All very well.
- You'll give them my best wishes?
- Yes, I shall.
- Goodbye, Cratchit.
- Goodbye, sir.
And a merry Christmas.
Idiot.
And he's made me late to Bushnel.
I'm off to the Exchange.
- Don't lock up a moment early.
- No, sir.
You'll want all day tomorrow,
I suppose?
- If it's quite convenient, sir.
- It is not convenient.
And it's not fair.
If I were to hold back half a crown
from your pay for it...
...you'd think yourself ill-used.
But you don't think me ill-used...
...when I pay a day's wages
for no work.
Christmas comes once a year.
Poor excuse for picking a man's pocket
every 25th of December.
But I suppose you must have it.
- Be here earlier the next morning.
- Yes, sir, I shall.
- Make sure.
- Yes, sir.
- And a merry Christmas to you.
- Humbug!
Merry Christmas, Mr. Scrooge.
Don't beg on this corner, boy.
I'm not begging, sir.
I'm Tim. Tim Cratchit.
I'm waiting for my father.
Tim Cratchit, huh? Well then,
you'll have a long wait, won't you?
- Thank you, sir.
- Humbug.
Our Savior Christ and His Lady
On Christmas day
On Christmas day in the morning
Clear the road. Out of the way.
Let me through.
Merry Christmas, sir.
The 18th of January.
The open market. Open market?
Buying here. Buying.
- We were afraid you weren't coming.
- It's almost closing, sir.
- I'm here.
- I said you'd be here.
- I knew you'd change your mind.
- You're right. I've changed my mind.
- Then you'll take our bid?
- The price has gone up.
Gone up? That's not possible.
You want my corn,
you must meet my quote.
Plus five percent for the delay.
You'll be left with a warehouse
stuffed with corn.
- That's my affair.
- If we pay your price...
...our bread will be dearer.
The poor will suffer.
Buy the corn someplace else.
Scrooge, a moment.
We'll take your corn at the price
you quoted yesterday.
Too late. Tomorrow it'll cost
you another five percent.
It's not fair!
No. But it's business.
I'll give you a moment
to make up your minds.
All right, Scrooge. Done and done.
Very good, gentlemen.
Now make sure that the draw
for this transaction...
...is deposited with my clerk.
I don't ship until I have the cash
in hand. Good day.
- Mr. Scrooge, I presume?
- Indeed you do, sir.
- You don't know us.
- Nor do I wish to.
My name is Poole,
and this is Mr. Hacking.
- Excellent. Now allow me to pass.
- Let me explain.
At this festive season of the year,
it seems desirable...
...that those of us with means
should make some provision...
...for the poor and destitute
who suffer greatly at this time.
Are you seeking money from me?
Thousands are in want
of common necessaries...
...and in want of common comforts.
- Are there no prisons?
- Plenty of prisons.
- Are the workhouses in operation?
I wish I could say no.
The treadmill, the poorhouses...
...still in full vigor?
- All very busy, sir.
I was afraid from what you said...
...that something had stopped them
in full force.
A few of us are endeavoring
to raise a fund...
...to buy the poor some meat, drink,
food and warmth.
- What can we put you down for, sir?
- Nothing.
- You wish to be anonymous?
- I wish to be left alone.
Since you asked me what I wish,
that is my answer.
I don't make merry myself
at Christmas...
...and I can't afford
to make idle people merry.
My taxes help to support
the public institutions.
And they cost enough.
Those who are badly off must go there.
Many can't go there.
And many would rather die.
Well, if they would rather die,
perhaps they had better do so...
...and decrease
the surplus population.
You don't mean that?
- With all my heart.
Now if you will
go about your business...
...and allow me to go about mine.
Good day.
Father!
Tim.
You must be frozen.
I'm all right now.
Can we go home by Corn Hill and watch
the children play in the snow?
Of course we can.
Tim, I'm to have
the whole day off tomorrow.
We'll be together,
the whole family for the entire day!
Hurrah for Christmas,
the best day of the year!
- Look.
- They're having such fun, Father.
Go on, catch it.
You'll be there one day, playing
with the other children.
I'm sure I will.
I feel I'm getting stronger every day.
We must go home now.
Your mother will be waiting.
Yes. It's time to go home.
Scrooge.
Ebenezer Scrooge.
Who's calling me?
Someone call my name?
Scrooge.
Marley?
Humbug.
It's humbug! I won't believe it!
What do you want with me?
Much.
- Who are you?
- Ask me who I was.
You are particular for a ghost.
Who are you then?
In life, I was your partner,
Jacob Marley.
- Well, can you sit down?
- I can.
Well, do it then.
You don't believe in me.
I don't.
What evidence would you have
of my reality...
...beyond that of your own senses?
- I don't know.
Why do you doubt your senses?
Because a little thing affects them.
A slight disorder of the stomach.
You might be a bit of bad beef
or a blot of mustard...
...or a fragment
of an underdone potato.
There's more of gravy than a grave
about you, whatever you are. Humbug!
Mercy.
Dreadful apparition.
Why do you trouble me?
Man of the worldly mind,
do you believe in me or not?!
I do! I must!
But why do spirits walk the earth?
Why do you come to me?
It is required of every man...
...that the spirit within him
should walk abroad...
...among his fellow men
and travel far and wide.
And if that spirit
goes not forth in life...
...it is condemned
to do so after death.
It is doomed to wander
through the world...
...and witness what it cannot share.
What might have shared.
And turn to happiness.
You're chained. Tell me why?
I wear the chain I forged in life.
I made it link by link
and yard by yard.
Is its pattern strange to you...
...or would you know
the weight and length...
...of the strong coil
you bear yourself?
It was as full, as heavy...
...and as long as this
seven Christmas Eves ago.
You have labored on it since.
It is a ponderous chain!
I see no chain.
Mine were invisible...
...until the day of my death...
...as yours shall be.
Jacob.
Tell me more. Speak comfort to me.
I have none to give.
My spirit...
...never walked
beyond our countinghouse.
In life, my spirit never roved
beyond the narrow limits...
...of our money-changing hole.
No doubt of that.
You were a good man of business.
Business?!
Mankind was my business.
The common welfare was my business.
Charity, mercy, forbearance
and benevolence were all my business.
The dealings of my trade
were but a drop of water...
...in the comprehensive ocean
of my business!
I'm sorry for you, Jacob.
Is there anything I can do for you?
For me?
Nay. It is too late.
But I have come...
...for your sake, Ebenezer.
Have you?
Well, you always were a good friend.
As part of my penance...
...I have been sent to warn you.
- And so you have.
And to offer you a hope and chance
of escaping my fate...
...you will be haunted
by three spirits.
Three spirits? Is that the chance
and hope you mention?
It is.
In that case, I think I'd rather not.
Expect the first tonight...
...when the bell tolls one.
Couldn't they all come
at the same time and have it over?
Expect the second
on the stroke of two.
The third, more mercurial...
...shall appear in his own good time.
Look to me no more.
Look that you may remember...
...what has passed between us.
Humbug.
Something I ate.
One.
What was it Marley said?
Nothing.
Just a dream.
Are you the spirit whose coming
was foretold to me?
I am.
Who and what are you?
I am the Ghost of Christmas Past.
- Long past?
- No. Your past.
Perhaps you would do me the favor...
...of placing upon your head that cap
that you hold in your hand.
I bring the light of truth.
Would you use this cap to put it out?
I beg your pardon.
I had no intention of offending.
What business brings you here?
- It is for your welfare that I appear.
- I can think of no greater welfare...
...than a night
of uninterrupted sleep.
Be careful, Ebenezer Scrooge.
I speak of your reclamation.
Well, if it's reclamation, then...
...let's get on with it.
Come.
We shall be invisible...
...and silent as the grave.
You will now see a child, a youth.
You will see yourself, Ebenezer.
The air is so clean.
How different from the city.
Do you know where you are?
Of course, I...
I was bred here.
I was a boy in this place.
That's Daniel Costas.
And Robert Estes.
Hello, Daniel.
The big one there, that's David Tyler.
David, look here! It's Ebenezer!
I told you, Ebenezer.
They can't hear you.
How happy they all seem.
That's right. They do.
Yes, well, it's time to move on.
Come along, Ebenezer.
You know the way.
I could walk it blindfolded.
Your school.
I remember.
And it's Christmas Day.
There's a boy in there, neglected.
The boy is deserted
by his friends and his family.
His mother is dead.
His father holds him a grudge.
Why does his father
hold him a grudge?
She died in childbirth.
His birth.
Weep for the boy,
if the tears will come.
He has his friends, even on this day.
All his beloved books.
His Ali Baba.
Dear old honest Ali Baba.
The Sultan's groom,
turned upside down for Genie.
But not a real child to talk to.
Not a living person.
Robinson Crusoe, not real?
And Friday? And the parrot...
...with green body and yellow tail?
Not real?
He made do, this boy.
Let us see another Christmas Day...
...when you were a youth.
Fan.
- Fan!
- Dear, dear brother!
I've come to bring you home,
dear brother.
To bring you home.
Home.
Home, little Fan?
Yes.
Home for good and all.
Father's much kinder
than he used to be.
He spoke to me so gently one night...
...I was not afraid to ask once more
if you might come home.
And he said yes, you should.
And sent me in a coach to bring you.
You're quite a woman, little Fan.
And you...
...are to be a man now.
And never come back here.
Come. We mustn't keep Father waiting.
Father!
There, boy, down. Stand still now.
Let me look at you.
They haven't been overfeeding you,
that's certain.
I've grown. I think.
Yes, most boys do.
- You know you won't move back here.
- Yes, sir.
It's time you made your way.
I've arranged an apprenticeship.
You'll move into Mr. Fezziwig's
in three days.
Three days, Father?
I'd hoped we'd have him home
for longer.
Longer?
Three days is quite long enough
for both of us.
Don't you think, Ebenezer?
Yes, sir.
Quite long enough.
- Finished back there?
All safe and secure, sir.
Into the carriage, Fan.
Be on our way.
Into the carriage, boy.
Giddyap!
Fan pleaded for more time,
but my father was a very...
...stern man.
- And Fan...
- She died a young woman.
She had such a generous nature.
Yes, too young.
- Old enough to bear a child.
- One son.
- Fred, your nephew.
- Fred Holywell, yes.
Who bears a strong resemblance
to your sister.
Does he? I never noticed.
You never noticed?
I think you've gone through life
with your eyes closed.
Open them. Open them wide.
You know this man.
It's old Fezziwig.
Oh, yes, my dear.
Would you ask Mr. Peuring to refer
that matter to Mr. Scrooge?
Thank you, my dear.
And you know this place.
Know it? Was I not apprenticed here?
Yoo-hoo!
Pay attention, everybody!
Dick? Ebenezer? Pens down.
No more work tonight, boys.
It is Christmas Eve.
So close those ledgers down.
Clear away in here, everybody.
We need the room.
Here we go, lad.
You'll enjoy yourself tonight,
Ebenezer. That is an order.
- Yes, sir. I'll try.
- Put your heart in it.
You put enough of yourself into your
work, and I have nothing but praise...
...but you're young.
There's more to life than
books of cloth and musty old ledgers.
It's Mrs. Fezziwig and the
three daughters and their suitors.
And a happy Christmas to you all!
And Belle.
I had forgotten...
...how beautiful she was.
Hello, Belle.
Hello.
- Would you like to dance?
- Yes.
How long since you've danced,
Ebenezer?
A waste of time, dancing.
You didn't think so then.
There was a reason then.
You've changed since you've come
to Fezziwig's. You were so gloomy.
I think I should warn you, Miss Belle.
I am of a serious bent of mind.
I consider seriousness
an admirable trait of character.
But it can be overdone.
I shall take heed of your advice
and go through life with a grin.
Come, you two! They're striking up
Sir Roger de Coverly.
Time enough to sample the punch
when you're old and fat like me.
I best partner my wife before that
young scamp goes dancing off with her.
What a difference it makes, Ebenezer,
to travel the rough road of life...
...with the right female
to help bear the burden.
What a lucky man I am!
Shall we join the others?
My pleasure, Miss Belle.
Old Fezziwig.
A silly man.
Silly? Why silly?
What did he do to deserve the praises
of those apprentices?
Spent a few pounds?
Dance like a monkey?
Beamed a great smile?
Well, the happiness he gives... Gave...
Was quite as great as though
it had cost 1000 pounds.
Just small things.
- Belle.
- Are you in love, Ebenezer?
- The thought had occurred to me.
- She's too good for you.
One day, when I've made my fortune...
...then I'll deserve her.
It was a night never to be forgotten.
Never.
But you did forget. Often.
Huh?
Look. Another Christmas Eve...
...delayed by the pressure
of business.
- Do you remember?
- No.
Hello, Belle.
Now do you remember?
I'm sorry I'm late.
I thought you might not come.
I know how busy you are.
Well...
...the time of year,
and the nature of my business.
It's important now that I use my time
and opportunities wisely.
Another idol has displaced me.
- What idol has displaced you?
- A golden one.
All your hopes have merged
into a master passion: profit.
The thought of money engrosses you.
Perhaps I've become wiser.
But I've not changed towards you.
Our contract is an old one.
It was made when we were young
and our prospects limited.
How often I've thought of those times.
If there had been
no understanding between us...
...would you seek me out
and try to win me now?
A dowerless girl with nothing but
myself to bring to a marriage?
You have no answer?
- You think I would not?
- Oh, what a safe and terrible answer.
So characteristic of the careful man.
Ebenezer, I release you.
You are a free man.
I let you go with a full heart.
May you be happy
in the life you have chosen.
I almost went after her.
"Almost" carries no weight.
Especially in matters of the heart.
And you did have a heart, didn't you?
Why didn't you follow her?
Upon his death, my father...
...left me a small inheritance.
Belle wished to be married,
insisting we'd get by on very little.
But I wanted something more
for both of us. So I...
...lent out that money.
Laid the foundations for financial
success, which I have achieved.
- Congratulations.
- And I'll thank you not to sneer.
- Show me no more. Conduct me home.
- You have explained what you gained.
Now I will show you
what you have lost.
Belle.
Yes, Belle.
And those are her children!
Oh, darling, he's wonderful!
Isn't he?
Oh, Lord, what a brood!
Hello, hello. Hello, my dear.
Hello, Papa. Where's my present?
Where's my present?
You will have to wait until tonight.
All of you.
Presents on Christmas Eve, as usual.
Fancy.
They might've been mine.
The same thought occurred to me.
I saw an old friend of yours
in the city this afternoon.
- Who was it?
- Guess.
I can't.
I don't know.
- Ebenezer Scrooge?
- Mr. Scrooge it was.
I passed his office window
and it was not shuttered.
He had a single candle
lit upon his desk.
His partner, Jacob Marley,
lies on the point of death.
And there he sat.
Ebenezer Scrooge, alone.
Quite alone in the world,
I do believe.
Poor Ebenezer.
Poor, wretched man.
Spare me your pity!
I have no need of it!
They can't hear you.
And as for you, I've had enough
of your pictures from the past!
Leave me!
Haunt me no longer!
Truth lives!
A nightmare.
A horrible nightmare.
God...
...let me sleep.
Let me sleep in peace.
Peace.
Two.
Well, Jacob Marley...
...where is this spirit
of which you spoke so glibly?
You did say at the stroke of two,
didn't you, Jacob?
Mistaken in death...
...as you were in life, old partner.
Ebenezer Scrooge!
Come in!
I intend to.
Come in and know me better, man!
You've never seen
the likes of me before?
That's quite true. I have not.
You never walked forth...
...with any of the
younger members of my family?
Not that I remember.
Nor any of my elder brothers
born these later years?
No, I'm afraid not. No.
Do you have many brothers, spirit?
Over 1800!
Tremendous family to provide for.
Take hold of my robe, Ebenezer Scrooge.
What day is it now?
Don't you know?
Christmas morning.
There's a lot of buying, isn't there?
Oh, Ebenezer, is that all you can see?
Follow me, and I'll show you
to what good use...
...these wares can be put.
Does some peculiar power
emanate from your torch?
Oh, yes...
...there is.
Do you know this house?
No, I can't say I do.
It is the house of Bob Cratchit.
Is it? He does very well
on 15 bob a week.
Shall we go in?
- I wouldn't want to disturb them.
- As with Christmas Past...
...we shall be invisible and unheard.
- I wonder what's keeping your father?
- Probably talking to the parson.
Father always likes to compliment him
on his sermons.
I hope the pudding's a success.
No one makes a better pudding
than you, Mother.
Peter?
- Save some for the family.
- Just testing the cooking.
I'm sure they'll manage very well
without your help.
- Hello, Mother!
- Smell the goose cooking, Martha!
- It makes my mouth water!
- Mine too!
- I can't wait!
You'll just have to. Run along
and help Martha butter the bread.
Here they are!
- Merry Christmas, everyone!
- You're late, Bob Cratchit.
Oh, and you're quite like an icicle,
Tim. You've been dawdling.
Father had a long talk
with the minister.
Thought as much.
Tim, listen to the pudding
hissing on the fire!
It's like a giant snake
inside the copper!
Go along with your brother and sister.
Off you go then.
Come on.
- How did he behave in church?
- As good as gold.
Better.
Mama's worried how it will turn out.
- Look how they support him.
- What did you say?
Nothing. It's...
...nothing.
Somehow he gets thoughtful
sitting by himself so much.
He thinks the strangest things.
He said he hoped the people in church
saw him because he was a cripple...
...and that it might be pleasant for
them to remember on Christmas Day...
...who it was
that made lame beggars walk...
...and blind men see.
It seems to me that Tim
is getting stronger every day.
That his limbs are growing. That he's
in better spirits, it seems to me.
Yes, Bob. I'm sure you're right.
He is getting stronger.
Well, we're all here.
That's the important thing.
- Belinda, help me with the goose.
Yes, Mother.
Peter, I have some good news for you.
I met by chance, this morning
at church, a fine gentleman.
Fred Holywell by name.
He's a nephew of our own Mr. Scrooge.
He remembered I have a son
coming of working age...
...and told me he had a position at
three shillings and six pence weekly.
Three shillings and six pence
every week?
So if you are agreeable...
...you may start work on Monday next.
Now I can help you and Mother.
More important...
...you shall be embarking
on a fine career.
To start a boy
at three and six pence a week.
Typical of my nephew. No wonder he's
never been able to put by a penny.
Perhaps he's "put by" more than money.
Fred?
He's doing this to spite me, you know?
Employing the son of my employee
at an exorbitant wage.
Come and get it!
Quiet, quiet, quiet, children. Quiet.
- A wonderful goose!
- It's enough for an army!
- Mother, you've outdone yourself!
- It's all right then?
Hurry, Father, cut the goose!
I can't wait!
Haven't we forgotten something?
Lord, we thank you for the bounty
you have placed before us.
We thank you for this day
of love and joy...
...for allowing us to be together, to
share with each other and with you...
...the fullness of our hearts
on this special day.
- Amen.
Amen.
- What?
You say something?
No, no.
I thought I heard you...
No, I said nothing.
Oh.
- Potato.
- Peter.
Alice.
- Belinda.
Potato, Alice?
It's a very small goose.
It's all Bob Cratchit can afford.
Me.
- Are we all served?
- Yes.
Then let's begin.
And a merry Christmas to us all.
A merry Christmas to us all.
And God bless us, everyone.
Tell me, spirit.
Will he live?
I see a vacant place at this table.
I see a crutch without an owner,
carefully preserved.
If these shadows...
...remain unaltered by the future,
the child will die.
No.
Say he will be spared.
If these shadows remain
unaltered by the future...
...none other of my species
will find him here.
But if he is to die,
then let him die...
...and decrease
the surplus population.
You use my own words against me.
Yes. So perhaps in the future
you will hold your tongue...
...until you have discovered
what the surplus population is...
...and where it is.
It may be
that in the sight of heaven...
...you are more worthless
and less fit to live...
...than millions
like this poor man's child.
A triumph, my dear. Another triumph!
I told you so, Mother.
It's a success.
What a relief for Mrs. Cratchit.
Now their feast is over.
Not quite.
Just one more ceremonious moment.
Look.
Now I would like to propose a toast
to Mr. Ebenezer Scrooge...
...the founder of our feast.
Mr. Scrooge.
The "founder of our feast" indeed.
I wish I had him here.
I'd give him a piece of my mind
and hope he had a good appetite for it.
My dear, the children.
It's Christmas Day.
It should be Christmas Day when one
drinks to the health of such...
...a stingy, odious, mean...
...hard, unfeeling man
as Mr. Ebenezer Scrooge.
My dear, have some charity.
Well, well.
I'll drink his health for your
sake, and the day's sake...
...but not for his.
Long life, Mr. Ebenezer Scrooge.
A merry Christmas
and a happy New Year.
I have no doubt his Christmas will be
very merry, and he'll be very happy.
Mr. Scrooge.
He's made a point, Bob Cratchit has.
Without me, there would be no feast.
No goose at all.
My head for business
has furnished him employment.
Is that all you've learned by
observing this family on Christmas Day?
Well, no. Not all.
But one must speak up for one's self,
for one's life.
Here we come a wassailing
Among the leaves so green
Here we come a wandering
So fair to be seen
Love and joy come to you
And a merry Christmas too
And God bless you and send you
A happy New Year
We have some time left.
Take my robe.
Love and joy come to you
And a merry Christmas too
And God bless you and send you
A happy New Year
- Where are we now?
- Just a street.
Any street.
This house. We're going here.
- I think it might amuse you.
- I am in no mood to be amused.
Is my playing so amusing?
- I'm sorry, my love.
I was thinking of his face yesterday.
Humbug, he said. Humbug.
He said Christmas was a humbug.
He believed it too.
I'd like to meet your uncle. The way
you portray him tickles my heart.
He is comical.
- But not pleasant.
- His offenses are their own punishment.
Brother-in-law,
it's said he's very rich.
That's true.
But his wealth is of no use to him.
He does no good and
doesn't even make himself comfortable.
I don't squander it,
if that's what you mean.
You mustn't argue with those we visit.
It's useless and tactless.
- Tact is a quality I despise.
- I can see.
- I have no patience with him.
- I feel sorry for him.
Sor...? Sorry for me?
Who suffers from his ill whims?
Himself. Always.
He takes it in his heart to dislike us
and not come and dine with us.
And loses a very good dinner.
The reason I talk about him so...
...is that my mother,
God rest her saintly soul...
...was very fond of him.
She loved him.
It's true.
Fan loved me and I her.
Dear Fan.
I wish she were alive today.
Fred looks very like her.
Yes.
I've been reminded of that
just recently.
The consequences
of his taking a dislike to us...
...and not making merry with us is
that he loses some pleasant moments...
...which could do him no harm.
I'll give him the chance every year
whether he likes it or not.
And every year he'll say, "Christmas!
Bah, humbug!"
Come, we must see to our guests.
Nougats?
So much noise.
- I can't hear myself think.
- They seem to be happy.
I suppose free food and drink is an
occasion for pleasure to most people.
Happy in each other's company, I mean.
Everyone, hush. We shall have
a word game. What shall it be?
Simile.
Does everyone know the rules?
You each have five seconds to answer.
I'll ask the question.
- Mr. Topper, you'll keep count.
- I shall do my best.
You have five seconds. If you fail
to give an acceptable answer...
...then you must
stand behind your chair.
- Last one seated wins the prize.
- Fred, don't go on. Just begin.
I'm sorry, my love. Yes, I shall.
And now...
Proud as...?
Proud as a peacock.
Peter? Dry as...?
- As a bone.
- Good.
- Plump as...?
- My wife!
Sorry, my dear. Just a little joke.
Plump as...
- One, two...
- Two seconds!
A partridge.
Quick as...?
- Wind?
- No!
One, two...
...three, four...
...five!
- A wink, you idiot.
- Ebenezer, shh.
- You said they couldn't see or hear us.
- That's quite true.
Oh, yes. Sorry.
Even I forget regulations sometimes.
After all, I do not come back often.
I'm trying to listen to the game.
Modest as...?
- A maiden.
- No.
- I'm sure it's a well-known simile.
- I was thinking of modest as a violet.
Fred.
However, I will accept your answer.
Janet?
Attend. Tight as...?
Tight as...
A drum. Anyone knows that.
Tight as...?
Not very bright, my nephew's wife.
Tight as your Uncle Scrooge's
purse strings!
That's quite wrong.
And your time is up.
You've lost and must stand
behind your chair.
Tight as a drum
is what I was thinking of.
Good for you, Fred.
Boy's got a head on his shoulders.
As for the laughter at my expense...
...I'll overlook it
in view of the general gaiety.
It's time to leave
this pleasant scene.
We have one more visit to make
before my time is done.
Take hold of my robe.
Sly as...?
A fox!
- Red as...?
- Red as a rose.
- Silent as...?
The night.
- No!
- A mouse!
- Not at all.
- I know. The grave.
Where are we now?
I'm sure I don't know this place.
The name would mean nothing to you.
It's a place...
...like many in this world.
- Do we have enough wood for the night?
- It'll last.
At least there's one thing
still free in this country.
Mary, a piece of that cooked.
- They're too hot.
- It'll be cold soon enough.
- Where did you get these, Father?
- I didn't steal them.
She didn't say you did.
- She should have some respect.
- Don't berate the girl.
They fell from a cart into the road.
Your father's not a thief, girl.
Not yet.
Why are these people out here?
Men and women in rags.
Children eating scraps!
There are institutions.
Have you visited any of them,
these institutions you speak of?
No! I'm taxed for them.
Isn't that enough?
Is it?
- Ben, come back to the fire.
- Look at these hands.
They're hard hands.
They've done hard work.
I want to work.
I want to have bread for my children.
It's not right that there's no work.
We're together.
That's the important thing.
I love you, Meg. I love the children.
Tomorrow take the children
to the parish poor house.
No. No.
I'd rather we all drowned in the river
than go there and be separated forever.
- Until I get work!
- No.
Ben, we're a family.
We stay together.
Come.
Come back to the fire. Come.
Why do you show me this?
What has it to do with me?
Are they not of the human race?
Look here...
...beneath my robe!
Look upon these!
What are they?
They are your children.
They are the children of all
who walk the earth unseen.
Their names are ignorance...
...and want.
Beware of them.
For upon their brow
is written the word...
..."doom. "
They spell the downfall of you...
...and all who deny their existence.
Have they no refuge? No resource?
Are there no workhouses?
Are there no prisons?
Cover them.
I do not wish to see them.
I thought as much.
They're hidden.
But they live.
Oh, they live.
Well...
...time has come for me to leave you,
Ebenezer Scrooge.
Leave me? Leave me here?
Oh, yes.
Well, you cannot.
Take me back to my bed.
It's too late.
It's cold. The place is strange.
Don't leave me.
Spirit?
Come back.
I wish to talk!
Perhaps...
...I have made a mistake
here and there.
Talked too quickly about matters
which I gave no great thought.
Very well, we'll have a give and take.
Come to some meeting of the minds.
I'm a reasonable man.
Spirit!
Have pity on me.
Don't leave me.
What have I done?
To be abandoned like this?
What?
Are you the spirit which Jacob Marley
foretold would visit me?
I'm in the presence of the Ghost
of Christmas Yet to Come?
You'll show me the shadows
of the things that haven't happened...
...but will happen in the time
before us. Is that so?
I fear you.
More than any specter I've seen.
I'm prepared to bear your company.
Will you not speak to me?
Very well, lead on.
The night is waning fast.
Time is precious to me.
I know this place very well. The
Exchange is like a second home to me.
I don't know much about it.
I only know he's dead.
When did he die?
Last night.
What about his money?
Left it to his company, perhaps?
Who else did he have?
It'll likely be a small funeral
if we volunteered and form a party.
I'll go if lunch is provided.
But I insist on being fed
for the time I'll waste.
Have these men
no respect for the dead?
I should go, I suppose.
After all, we did considerable
business together.
Well, I must go and find
the price of corn. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
Why was I privy to their conversation?
What purpose could it have for me?
Merciful heavens, what is this?
Spirit.
This is a fearful place.
I wish to leave.
No, I will not.
This you can't make me do.
I say, I understand.
That is sufficient.
There must be someone who feels
some emotion for this man's death.
I demand to see that person!
This is a foul part of town.
You've made a mistake.
Taken a wrong turn.
In there?
I have no business
to transact in there.
Open it up, Mrs. Dilber.
Am I to pay you for goods
I haven't seen?
You'll not ask me how I came by these?
Every person has a right
to take care of himself.
That's my motto.
- Well, he was dead.
- Yes.
And who's the worst
for the loss of a few things?
- Not a dead man, I suppose.
- No, indeed.
If he wanted to keep them after
he was dead, the wicked old screw...
...why wasn't he more natural
in his lifetime?
He'd have had someone to look after
him when he was struck with death...
...instead of lying there
gasping out his last.
Alone.
By himself.
Those are my things.
She's stolen my things.
I'll have her before a magistrate.
What do you call these?
Bed curtains.
You took them down?
Rings and all, with him lying there?
Why not?
- And don't get wax on his blankets.
- His blankets?
I hope he didn't die
of anything catching.
I wasn't so fond of him
as I'd loiter about if he did.
What's your offer then?
Those are not my things.
Yes, they are similar...
...but the person she speaks of
could not be me.
A similarity perhaps, but...
One pound five and three. Not a penny
more if I was to be boiled for it.
You're hardened, Joe.
And no mistake.
I'm always kind to the ladies.
That's the way I ruin myself.
Spirit, what perversity is this?
I ask to see some emotion
for this man's death...
...and you show me only
greed and avarice!
Let me see some tenderness!
Some depth of feeling!
There must be some confusion.
Your fellow spirit
brought me here earlier.
Very well.
You're devilishly hard
to have a conversation with.
"Suffer the little children to come
unto me, and forbid them not.
For such is the Kingdom of God.
Verily I say unto you...
...whosoever shall not receive the
Kingdom of God as a little child...
...he shall not enter therein. "
This color hurts my eyes.
It's better now.
This work makes my eyes red.
I wouldn't show red eyes
to your father when he comes home.
Not for the world.
It must be nearly his time.
Past it rather.
I think he walks slower than he
used to these last few evenings.
Yet I've seen him walk home with...
...with Tiny Tim on his shoulders
very fast.
And so have I.
But he was very light to carry.
And your father loved him so that...
...it was no trouble.
No trouble.
There is your father now.
Hello, Father.
Hello, my dear.
- Hello, my dear ones.
- Hello, Father.
You're late. We were worried.
- I'm glad you're home, Father.
- I am too.
You've become quite a little armful.
The reason that I'm late is because
I walked by there today.
Today?
I couldn't keep away.
It's so quiet and green.
You shall see it on Sunday.
We shall all go on Sunday.
I promised him that every Sunday
I would walk...
My little child.
My little, little child.
Father, please don't grieve so.
I'm sorry.
I have all of you.
A blessing to be thankful for.
Do you know who I saw
in the street today?
Mr. Scrooge's nephew, Fred.
And he greeted me
in his usual cheerful way.
And he saw that I was a little sad.
He asked me what was distressing me.
And when I told him...
...he said that he was
heartily sorry for it, and...
Robert.
Timmy's part of all of us.
But for his sake,
we must go on living.
So long as we love one another,
he will always be alive.
Yes, of course, my dear.
But however and whenever...
...we're parted from one another...
...I'm sure that none of us will
forget poor Tiny Tim.
No, never. Never.
And when we recollect how patient
he was, and how mild...
...although he was
but a little child...
...I'm sure that we will not easily
quarrel among ourselves.
I am a happy man.
I am a truly happy man.
I asked for tenderness
and depth of feeling.
And you've shown me that.
Nothing more I need to see.
Take me home.
What is this?
I thought we agreed that you'd
transport me home?
Specter.
Something informs me that the moment
of our parting is at hand.
I know it, but I know not how.
Tell me.
What man was that
who we saw lying dead?
No.
Before I draw near to that stone,
answer me this:
Are the things you have shown me the
shadows of the things that will be?
Or are they the shadows
of the things that may be only?
Men's courses will foreshadow
certain ends. I accept that.
But if those courses
be departed from...
...the ends must change.
Tell me that is so
by what you show me.
Dear me, I am not the man I was.
I will not be the man I was
before this visitation.
Why show me this if I'm past all hope?
Good spirit.
Your nature intercedes for me
and pities me.
Say that I may change these things
by an altered life.
I'll honor Christmas in my heart
and keep it all the year.
I'll live in the past,
present and future.
The spirits of all
shall strive within me!
I will not shut out
the lessons that they teach!
Tell me.
Tell me that I may sponge away
the writing on this stone!
Spare me!
Spare me! Spare me!
My own room.
I'm alive.
Thank you, spirits.
I will keep my promise.
I will live in the past,
present and future.
The spirits of all three
will strive within me.
Heaven and Christmastime
will be praised for this.
I say this on my knees, Jacob Marley.
On my knees.
9:00.
And daylight.
But what day?
Hello! You there, boy!
Me, sir?
Yes, you, my good fellow.
What day is today?
Today? It's Christmas Day, of course!
Christmas Day?
I haven't missed it.
The spirits did it all in one night.
Well, they can do anything they like.
- Hello, my fine fellow!
- Hello!
You know the poulterers in the next
street but on the corner?
I should hope I did!
Intelligent boy. Remarkable boy.
Have they sold the prize turkey
that was hanging there?
What? The one as big as me?
Delightful boy.
A pleasure talking to him.
Yes! The one as big as you!
It's hanging there now.
Well, go and buy it!
And bring them around so that
I may tell them where to deliver it.
Come back with the man
and I'll give you a shilling.
Come back in less than five minutes,
I'll give you half a crown!
I must dress. So much to do.
I don't want to lose any time.
I'm as light as a feather!
I'm as happy as an angel.
I'm as May as a school boy!
I'm as giddy as a drunken man.
Merry Christmas to everybody.
And a happy New Year to the world!
If this be a prank,
I'll box your ears.
He was in that window. I swear it.
Ah, there you are.
This boy says you wish to
purchase this turkey.
Yes, quite right.
Your half-crown
for a service well rendered.
- Thank you, sir!
- Splendid boy.
Now, here's an address
and the price of the turkey.
Take this fine bird
to Bob Cratchit in Camden.
The directions are written down.
- Leave immediately.
- Yes, sir.
And you'll say only
that it comes from a friend.
And it must be there in time for
Christmas dinner.
It will be, sir.
Here's something for your trouble.
- Thank you, sir.
- Here, all for you.
- Thank you.
- Merry Christmas.
Wonderful day.
So grant us all a change of heart
Good morning. Merry Christmas to you.
Like angels. Yes, exactly.
You sing excellently. Here.
- Thank you, sir.
- It is I who thank you...
...for that glorious music
on this glorious Christmas Day.
Good morning.
Oh, gentlemen.
Merry Christmas to you.
Mr. Scrooge.
I feel my name is not pleasant to you.
I beg your pardons, and please accept
my pledge to the needy for...
Lord, bless me!
My dear, Mr. Scrooge!
Are you quite serious?
And not a farthing less.
A great many back payments
are included, I assure you.
What can I say to such generosity?
Don't say anything.
But, dear sir!
- Will you come and see me?
- We will!
- I am very much obliged.
- Thank you 50 times!
- Thank you, sir. Thank you.
- Yes?
- Bob Cratchit?
- Yes.
- This is for you.
There must be some mistake.
- You are Bob Cratchit?
- Yes.
There ain't no mistake.
I didn't order this.
This here prize turkey was
bought and paid for by a gentleman...
...to be delivered to you
in time for Christmas dinner.
What's the gentleman's name?
Anonymous.
He wishes to remain anonymous.
Anonymous you said?
That's what he said.
An anonymous gentleman.
- Who could have sent it?
- No idea.
- Is it a mistake?
- I thought so too.
It's got our name on it.
- What shall we do?
- I say we cook it and eat it...
...and have the best Christmas
feast we've ever had.
And I say, Mrs. Cratchit,
what a splendid idea.
And God bless us all, everyone.
And God bless us all, everyone!
- Merry Christmas, sir.
- Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas.
Oh, Fred! It's much too expensive.
But do you like it?
Oh, I love it!
It's the most beautiful thing
I've ever seen.
It belongs upon your wrist,
my darling. Merry Christmas.
Oh, Fred! I do love you.
- And not just for this.
- I know.
I know.
- Who can that be?
- No one's expected this early.
My God!
It's Uncle Ebenezer.
Your uncle?
What would he want?
Open the door, Mary.
I'm sure I don't know.
Fred.
Uncle Ebenezer.
May I come in?
Yes, come in.
- Please.
- Thank you.
Do come in.
Good afternoon, madame.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas to you.
Uncle Ebenezer,
this is my wife, Janet.
Janet, this is Uncle Ebenezer.
It's a pleasure.
More like a surprise,
wouldn't you say?
Well, that too.
Well, that is quite true.
Quite honestly, it is a surprise.
When we spoke yesterday,
you made it quite clear...
...that you wouldn't accept
my invitation.
I made other things clear too,
didn't I, Fred?
That Christmas was a humbug,
a waste of time and money.
A false and commercial festival...
...devoutly to be ignored.
Yes, basically that was it.
I've come for three reasons.
First, to beg your pardon.
For what I said about Christmas.
That was a humbug, Fred.
- Was it?
- I didn't know it then, but I do now.
Secondly, I've come to meet your wife.
- Well, here she is.
- Yes.
And a very beautiful woman
she is too.
Thank you.
I, uh...
I was in love once.
Would you believe that?
Yes.
But I possessed neither the courage
nor the optimism...
...perhaps the depth of feeling
that you two have.
Thirdly, if the invitation
to dine is still in force...
...I accept.
Of course it's still in force.
Hurrah!
I was sure that one day...
You were sure?
Well, apparently you were right.
Yes, I should like to dine with you.
You'll be more than welcome.
You like games, don't you?
Yes, as a matter of fact I do.
Do you ever play Similes?
It's one of our favorites.
- Perhaps we could play today.
- Quite possibly.
I'm very good at it.
And should the phrase
"tight as... " be thrown out...
...the answer is, a drum.
Why, yes. So it is.
Good.
Forgive me for saying this, but I see
the shadow of my sister in your face.
I loved your mother, Fred.
For a time there,
I forgot just how much I loved her.
Perhaps I chose to forget.
Well, now.
I should like to sample
some of that famous punch.
Of course. You've made us both
very happy, Uncle Ebenezer.
Have I?
Yes.
God forgive me
for the time I've wasted.
9:00. Late again, eh, Cratchit.
We'll see about this.
Mr. Cratchit!
Yes, sir.
You know what time it is?
What time is it?
Eighteen past the hour, sir.
Eighteen and a half past the hour.
What do you mean coming here
at this time of day?
I'm sorry, sir. I am behind my time.
Yes, I think you are.
Step this way, if you will, please?
It's only once a year, sir.
It shall not be repeated.
I was making rather merry yesterday.
Well I'll tell you, my friend,
I won't stand for this any longer.
Therefore...
Therefore, I am going to...
...double your salary!
Double my salary, sir?
Yes, Bob!
A merry Christmas to you!
I'll double your salary and assist
your family in any way I can.
And Tim? Tim will walk again.
And grow stronger and stronger.
Upon my life, he will.
We'll discuss the particulars
this afternoon over a Christmas bowl.
What is the matter with you?
Nothing, sir.
Well, it's just that...
Nothing.
- Thank you, sir.
- You're welcome, my good fellow.
Make up the fire
before we freeze to death.
Buy some more coal...
...before you dot another "I"!
Yes, sir.
Ebenezer Scrooge
was better than his word.
He became as good a friend,
as good a master...
...as good a man
as the old city knew.
And to Tiny Tim, who did not die,
he was a second father.
It was said of Ebenezer Scrooge
that he kept Christmas well.
If any man alive
possessed the knowledge...
...may that be truly said of us,
and all of us.
And so as Tiny Tim observed:
"God bless us, everyone!"
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group