Señor.
- Have you seen this woman?
- No, señor.
Gracias.
No.
No?
Señor. Señor.
Gracias.
Ten, 42, 36, hut, hut, hut!
Way to go, Brogan!
The old man
can still catch, huh?
Take care of that shoulder.
Good job.
Nice snatch, for an old man,
but watch this one.
Brogan!
I didn't like what I saw on Sunday.
What? I caught
the winning touchdown.
You missed that track-back block
on Cooper's run.
You were worried
about your shoulder.
What's that gotta do with the operation.
There's no permanent damage.
I don't want any weaknesses
that can be read by the other team.
You took yourself off
the injured reserve.
You said you were healthy.
The shoulder is solid.
Why don't you
prove that to me.
I intend to.
I mean right now.
Mrs. Wyler's paying you
a lot of money
to play football, not talk about it.
Why don't you go over to the sled
and impress me.
The sled is bullshit.
I got two rookies who need
playing time, Brogan.
Either go to the sled
or sit on the bench.
No, Stassen. I'll go over there
and prove it to you.
Sam! Go with him.
Yeah, come on, Sam.
No matter how long you play,
they want you to prove it one more time.
North field scrimmage.
That guy's been on my ass
since he got here.
Here we go.
All right, hand down.
Look at me. Ready.
Hit it!
Sam, get on it.
All right, hand down.
Look at me.
Hit it!
Argh! Fuck!
Sully! I'd like you to meet our
county supervisor, Ed Phillips.
He's Mrs. Wyler's guest today.
- Hi, Ed.
- I'm a big fan.
Not only of the Outlaws,
but of the kind of football you played.
Football's changed since
I was a player.
Right, right.
I guess that run
of injuries
kind of hurt you guys
last season.
Yeah. We had a lousy bench
last year.
We had to play a lot of injured ball players
that shouldn't have been playing.
That's part of the job.
You telling us
you never played injured?
Yeah, well, I was dumb.
I don't like my boys
getting hurt permanently.
- That's why they call him "Mother".
- Hit it!
I don't know about
being a supervisor.
I sure as hell don't know
about being a lawyer.
But if I was a lawyer I wouldn't know
shit about football, would I?
Excuse me.
Let's get out of here.
- Hit it!
- Ugh!
You don't have to do this, Brogan.
The fucker's not beating me.
Hand down again. Look at me!
- Hit it!
- Ugh!
I'm the trainer here,
and I say he's had enough.
Hey, come on, Brogan.
What are you trying to prove?
You're a veteran!
What a dumb fucking thing
to have me do!
Wait for me in my office, Brogan.
Steve Kirsch's office.
This is Terry Brogan.
I need to speak to Steve.
Yeah, the Outlaws
just put me on waivers.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
I'm a big fan of yours, Terry.
Hold, please.
It's Terry Brogan. He's been cut.
- Tell him to call Schumacher.
- He needs to talk to you.
I don't handle players anymore.
- Steve.
- Get rid of him.
Hello again. Mr. Kirsch can't talk right now,
but he suggests you call Hal Schumacher.
I don't want Hal Schumacher,
I wanna speak to Steve.
When's he available?
I really don't know.
Thank you. Thanks a lot.
- They hurt my shoulder, then cut me.
- Shit!
That's it in a word.
They promised me
they'd keep you.
This is behind my back, kid.
Yeah, I figured.
At first I thought
they'd pay me off.
But fuck,
I want to play football.
Not this year.
Not with that shoulder.
Let me ask you something.
What makes you think
they'll pay you off?
I was injured.
You played two games great.
If you were injured, you didn't look it.
What was I supposed to do, huh?
I could smell what they were thinking.
I give them any trouble, they cut me.
They cut you anyway.
They're rebuilding.
More profit, less talent.
You cost too much,
my friend.
They're not screwing me around.
I'm gonna see my lawyer.
I'll miss the pressure, Hank.
Give me a call.
Caxton, Benjamin,
Parker and Stein.
Yes, he is. Hold on a moment.
Hello. May I help you?
- Yeah. I'm here to see Steve Kirsch.
- I'll ring his office.
Please have a seat.
Hello.
Hi.
I'm here to see Steve Kirsch.
I know.
I'm the one you've been talking to all day.
The one who's a big fan.
- Oh, right. What's your name?
- Edie.
Edie, I guess he's not ever
going to talk to me?
Oh, you're down
in my book to call.
- Where's his office?
- He's not here.
I know you gotta keep
your job, Edie.
You have a nice face. I...
I'm telling you the truth.
It wouldn't be out of line
for you to lie, would it?
No.
Where is he?
- Terry. It's good to see you.
- I've been cut from the Outlaws.
Yeah, I know, I heard.
The firm represents Mrs. Wyler.
Since I joined the firm,
I can't represent players.
Mrs. Wyler owns the Outlaws.
She's our biggest client.
It's a conflict of interest.
Wait a minute. Listen, Steve.
When you came hustling me in school,
I put my career in your hands.
Remember those times, please.
You're right, I'm sorry.
Sit down.
Now,
I've been playing injured.
They know that and they don't wanna admit it
because they don't want to pay me off.
Yup. I think that's what their
position's gonna be.
Their position's fucked.
I'll go to the Players' Association.
They'll back me.
You could do that, but listen.
What happens if the Outlaws prove
that you're perfectly fine?
They've got film on you
at practice, preseason games.
They're gonna fight for
a long, long time.
Steve, look.
I'm having money problems, man.
I'm broke.
Terry. Did you spend
every single cent you ever made?
Let me think for just a second here.
I should get you a low-interest loan
to tide you over in the meantime.
- Excuse me...
- Could you just wait for a second, please?
And then I'll talk to these guys,
see if I can soften their position
and get you something
so it's not such a big hassle for you.
Yeah?
Excuse me, Mr. Kirsch.
The reception?
Mr. Caxton's waiting.
Oh, right, I forgot. I gotta go.
Look, I gotta know something
about this soon, Steve.
I'll get on it first thing.
Hey, you're one of
my first players, huh?
Mike Hogan and his wife, Susan.
Ben Cassidy.
Thank you for coming.
Here's Hal Schumacher's number.
Call him. He's a nice man.
Do they always get bombed
at the end of the day?
It's business down there.
It's an intimate fundraiser.
What do you mean?
Mr. Caxton has assessed
every lawyer in the firm
$1500 to contribute to the
reelection of Councilman Weinberg.
Mrs. Wyler is Caxton's
biggest client, isn't she?
Yes. In fact, he's doing
business for her right now.
Yeah? For the Outlaws?
No. Mrs. Wyler's real business
is real estate.
Caxton wants a zoning variance
on Mrs. Wyler's canyon
so she can build houses there.
His guest of honor tonight
could vote against it.
Trust me, he won't now.
I hate things like before,
when I couldn't be straight with you.
I'm running out
of conversation.
I'm sorry. Look, I gotta go.
I'd like to have a drink
with you.
The Ginger Man, after work?
Okay, sure.
The Ginger Man.
Touchdown.
What are you doing here?
You been cut.
- They can get you for trespassing.
- I'd outrun them.
Why are you here, Tommy?
Jake wants to see you.
How is Jake?
He got stabbed last week.
What a shame.
He survived, Brogan.
Why does he want me?
- He might have a job for you.
- Heh, heh.
You tell him "No, thanks".
He'll be at the beach tomorrow.
There's a volleyball game.
Yeah? Is he playing?
I told you, he got stabbed, man.
Well, he lived, right?
You got problems now, Terry.
You want trouble too?
Come to the beach tomorrow.
You're not dumb.
Besides,
what the hell else
you got to do?
Sam!
Sam! Come here!
Hey, you look good as a cripple.
Is that why I had to come here, after two years,
to give you my opinion on that?
- Good to see you. How you doing?
- Lousy.
How's your life?
The club? The Palace is doing great.
The other business is even better.
My action's about half a million dollars a week.
You know the grand prize today for the two
guys who win this thing? Thirty grand.
It's not bad, is it?
A few hours running on the beach.
Don't tell me you're taking
action on this game?
You think these are beach rats
running around here? Huh?
These guys
are world-class players.
You didn't know that?
Sam! Sam, come here!
People love to bet on sports.
You know that. I just help them out.
Yeah, right.
South Bay guys love this fucking game,
and they got money to burn.
I'll take their action.
Hey, who's the fuzzy face?
Do you want a cookie?
There's one! Whoa!
You fuzzy face, come on!
What kind of dog is gonna
hang out with you, Jake?
He doesn't belong to me.
He belongs to the lady
who cut me.
You're into
violent women now, hm?
Look, I was a bit of an asshole.
I got crazy and popped her a few times.
She came after me with a knife.
Just missed my balls.
And was she going for them?
Don't they all?
- You got a new Porsche, huh?
- Yeah.
What the fuck,
you're rich, right?
Let's talk it over at the Palace.
What do you say?
We'll get there like the old days.
You up to it?
No.
Come on, Sam. Come on!
Come on, get in the car.
I'll just meet you there.
You getting afraid of me
in your old age?
Yeah, right.
Come on.
Be a good release. You don't need
to release a little tension?
Do I have to tie one leg
behind my back?
Take the old route.
Sunset.
Let's see if you still got balls!
- How'd you like that?
- All good!
Where were you?
That was smart. Ha, ha.
See you!
Shit.
You're still number two!
Dream on, Terry!
Jake!
Son of a bitch!
Shit.
What a fucking idiot!
Scared the shit out of you, huh?
No!
I'm an asshole for racing with you!
I'm pulling out!
Come on, don't pussy out
on me now!
The fun's over, Jake!
Not yet!
- Hey. Sam, be quiet!
- Get over here.
What kept you?
I was getting worried.
I was afraid you flew out of your
car got stuck in all that garbage.
Can't have a fair race
with a goddamn maniac.
Here, maybe this
will fix you up.
Come here.
Have a taste of this.
How about a Guinness?
Wanna tell me what
I'm doing here?
You're out of a job, right?
I've got some
job possibilities for you.
For one, you can work
right back here.
Celebrity bartender.
Making drinks and telling your football
stories to drunks every night.
How does that sound?
You take the job.
You're a lot funnier than I am.
How about security guard?
I mean,
you know how to get hit.
The point is, for a guy
in your situation, Terry,
the options stink.
Or you can find her for me.
Who's this, the knife lady?
She's very important to me, Terry.
I think about her
the whole fucking time.
Hey, that's a new reality for you.
She stole 50 grand from me.
I would've given her the money.
I want her back.
And I want you to find her.
You're crazy. Why would you
trust me with her anyway?
Jessie hates football players.
You think that's funny?
She's also Mrs. Wyler's daughter.
Did you ever meet her?
Jake.
I've heard about her.
She's supposed to be pretty wild.
Her father was this English guy
Mrs. Wyler use to be married to.
One of those London stage actors who comes
over here, can't make it in American films.
Anyway, after he died,
Mr. Wyler adopted her.
An owner's daughter,
living with a bookie.
That's something, isn't it?
She hates her mother. The woman treated
her like a possession all her life.
You know what it feels like to be one of
Mrs. Wyler's possessions, don't you?
I'll give you $10,000 right now.
Pay your expenses.
And if you find her,
I'll give you 20,000 more.
You're crazy.
I'm a football player.
Without a team.
Hey, that new Porsche
of yours, is it paid for?
What are you gonna do, man?
Sell insurance? I mean, that's it.
You don't have the personality
to work for one of the networks.
Look, Terry.
I don't want you to bring
her back, man.
Just find her. Tell me where she is.
What does that take?
Time and money.
You got the time right now.
I got the money.
Oh, great.
You know, I've never used
what I got on you.
Could be otherwise.
I wouldn't want that. Would you?
It's simple.
Either you want to play
football again or you don't.
You never change, do you?
Not a bit.
Try Mrs. Wyler. She's probably
got an idea where Jessie is.
Right.
If this is about you being cut,
I don't involve myself with
the day-to-day business of the team.
That's not why I came here,
Mrs. Wyler.
Oh?
Then suppose you tell me exactly
what you want with me, Mr. Brogan.
I'm looking for your daughter.
We were very close,
and she disappeared all of a sudden.
- Give me a break.
- What do you mean?
He sent you.
Who?
Jake...
Wise.
She was only with him to spite me.
I don't know what she did
to get away from him.
What matters is,
she got the hell away from him.
Why don't you drink to that?
Grace?
Hi.
Well, Ed seems to have solved
the Soames problem.
The head of the planning commission
is coming to your party Saturday.
We're finally softening up
these environmentalists.
How wonderful.
You seem to have won
the opposition over on your own.
A good project sells itself.
MOBSO's got lots of other
mountains to save.
- You know Terry Brogan.
- How are you?
Okay.
- And Supervisor Phillips.
- I'm a big fan.
Thanks.
Ed, I wonder if you'd mind going ahead
to the table. We'll be right along.
Oh, yes.
Yes, of course.
- Be with you in a minute.
- See you then.
Well, Ben,
it seems Mr. Brogan
has a new job.
Working for Jake Wise.
Looking for Jessica.
Oh.
You and Wise good friends?
I go to his club for the music.
So do a lot of the team.
Uh-huh.
Why don't you let us
steal you away from him.
I won't let Jessica live like this.
I'll double whatever he's paying you.
I'm not some gun for hire.
He can't top what we can offer,
can he, Ben?
He can't give you your job back
with the Outlaws.
Well, we could consider something.
You know, it isn't easy for
Jessica to hide from me.
She's been drawing from her trust.
It's going to a little bank in Mexico.
To an island.
Cozumel.
You could keep a watch on her.
Make sure he gets nowhere
near her again. Hmm?
You know, uh...
I think I used Jake Wise
as an excuse to come here.
I guess I did come here
to get my job back.
I didn't deserve what I got.
I played some damn good ball for you.
I got a lot of good years left.
Of course I want to be back on the
team, but because I'm worth it.
Not because I spied on some
25-year-old who ran away from home.
I'm not going to spy for you
or Jake Wise.
Ben, this young man
is trespassing here.
Throw him out.
I don't believe you're wanted here.
And you can forget about Kirsch.
He's on my team.
You want the Outlaws
to pay you off? Sue us.
Walk him to his car.
I can kick myself out, thanks.
Ten years' work, Grace.
And we're this close.
I think just a few members of the
team would have been enough.
Having the Outlaws out here,
full force, is kind of crowding it.
I have to get some use out of them.
I don't like football.
Ben!
We got troubles.
Soames is here.
He's brought a lot of those
'Save the Mountain' people with him.
It doesn't look good.
Goddamn environmentalist
bastards.
I think you'd better handle this.
Come on, Ed.
I can't believe
he's doing this to us, Ben.
- Good afternoon, Mrs. Wyler.
- Hello.
I'm Bob Soames.
I'm on the County Planning Commission.
- But then you know that.
- Of course I do.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
It's been a long time coming.
I've brought a few of my friends.
I hope you don't mind.
Not at all.
Bob, are your friends
from the Sierra Club?
Yes, as a matter of fact.
Quite a few of them.
I hope they're welcome here.
I've supported them for years.
Not only financially, of course,
but also in my heart.
Please join us for refreshments.
- Oh, no, no. I really don't think so.
- Oh, come on.
Please.
All right.
Thank you.
I'm sorry, Ben.
He promised me.
Soames thinks he's a smart-ass.
I'm not laughing.
Cute little stores
on the bottom.
"Zoning variances don't count."
I say, "Come on..."
What's it been,
three weeks?
Could you excuse me
for just a second?
What are you doing here?
Free eats, right?
Right. It's Mrs. Wyler's party.
You don't wanna be here.
That was total bullshit
in your office, wasn't it?
You don't care about me.
You work for Caxton.
You wanted to play
pro football, right?
Every year, there's a 25 percent chance
you'd lose your job because of injury.
You players never grasp,
it is not a very secure job.
A lot of us made you rich,
didn't we?
That's right, Brogan. I got rich.
I'm getting still richer all the time.
That's good, Steve.
- Come on, come on.
- God.
You can afford it
when I kick your teeth in!
Do it, see what happens!
You're a has-been!
Cool it, man.
Come on, goddamn it!
That's intelligent.
- Will you cool it?
- You know Caxton's here.
Hey, come on.
Relax.
You're finished in football!
- Get him out!
- I'm out of here!
- You're not playing this right.
- I could give a fuck.
Mr. Wyler never mixed his
other businesses with the team.
We played football.
We didn't sell real estate.
You're saying I'm lucky
to be off the team?
It's a new goddamn ball game.
That's all I'm telling you.
It's all bullshit!
I don't belong here either.
It's a goddamn circus!
- I'm hearing weird things about you.
- Heh, heh. Like what?
Like you might be going
to work for Jake Wise.
He offered me a job.
But you turned him down.
You're a smart kid. Wait.
You're worried about money,
but don't screw around with Wise.
I'll make a call.
I'm gonna get you a coaching job.
Just for the year.
I'm not ready to do what you do.
I'm a player!
There's nothing here
for me now but shit!
They won't pay me my money.
My shoulder's screwed up.
Know what
I'm telling myself to do?
Take Wise's money.
Take a damn vacation!
I'll find his rich girl for him
and lay in the sun.
Have a good season, Hank.
- Terry!
- I'm on my own.
Keep away from Wise, damn it!
Thank you.
Jessie?
I'm sorry.
No.
Jessie?
You're Jessie Wyler, aren't you?
I'm Terry Brogan.
I played ball for the Outlaws.
The Outlaws don't interest me.
I'm not playing this season.
Gracias.
Say, there's not much going on here.
Where can I go to have a good time?
Get off the island.
The ferry leaves every morning.
- Can I buy you a drink or something?
- Nope.
How about a taco, huh?
I guess you can have anybody
do that for you in L.A., huh?
- What's that?
- Have some football player
buy you a couple tacos
and a beer.
There are a lot better things to do.
Even in L.A.
What is it you don't like exactly?
Football players,
tacos or beer?
I like tacos and I like beer.
Hey!
I should take the ferry, huh?
I figure if I keep talking,
you won't disappear.
Bye.
You sure about that?
Hey!
Yeah?
Hey, Jake. How's it going?
No, nothing yet.
No.
Hey, I didn't expect to have signs
telling me where she is, you know?
I don't know.
Maybe I'll be outside having a drink,
I'll look over and, out of nowhere,
she'll be buying some fruit or something.
I'll call you in a few days.
All right. See you. Bye.
Hey, pretty slick, Roberto.
Okay, señor. Cerveza, no glass.
Gracias. I've been hanging
out here a lot, huh?
Sí.
Some hangout.
Damn it!
- Where's that boat going?
- Tulum.
- When's the next ferry?
- Six hours.
Shit!
Should I be afraid of you?
I don't know.
It's beautiful, huh?
If this were L.A., my stepfather
would've bought it.
Torn it up and built condominiums.
Here, the land intimidates them.
They leave it in peace, thank God.
Some spot.
It's nothing like the great
Maya cities of the Yucatán.
Chichén Itzá.
Should have hidden there.
Is that what you're doing? Hiding?
Yep.
From you, right?
What do you mean?
Jake sent you.
Maybe your mother did.
Hey, I wouldn't know which one
had more to threaten you with.
You wanna know the truth?
I came for the hell of it.
I wanted to get out of L.A. An island
in the Caribbean didn't sound too bad.
Only trouble is,
now I'm here I find myself
in the middle of something
I have absolutely no feeling for.
Well, you're not doing this for free.
You're getting paid well, aren't you?
Which one are you
working for?
Which one knows you found me?
Nobody knows anything, okay?
Oh, sure!
I figure, fuck them. You know?
Fuck you too, lady.
I loved your drawing.
Yeah?
I wanna talk to you.
Talk.
Why should I believe
you won't tell Jake where I am?
Hey, look, there are probably people who care
what you believe. I don't see them in the room.
I have a broken shoulder,
both my knees are shot,
there are guys
crippling themselves now
so you can act like a 13-year-old
runaway from some mansion in Bel Air.
I could really give a shit
what you believe.
- How's Sam?
- Who?
My dog.
I don't know.
Looks like he's being fed.
I think you were right.
I shouldn't be afraid of you.
When you leaving?
I think 4:00.
I wish it were sooner.
Never found where I live, did you?
I don't think anybody could.
It's the prettiest place on the island.
Don't leave without saying goodbye.
You take the highway out of town
to kilometer 19.
When you see
the three Tecate cans,
it's the first dirt road on the right.
Don't leave without
saying goodbye.
You don't have to worry about
the neighbors.
They were building homes here
when a storm hit.
They all fell down except this one.
- Waited for you, huh?
- Yeah.
Like a drink?
All right.
That'd be great.
Tequila okay?
That's great, yeah.
It's Maya.
Third century, I think.
- No ice.
- That's all right.
You don't have
any electricity here, huh?
No.
Propane.
So how'd you end up
with Jake?
The Palace, I guess.
I wanted to be a rock 'n' roll singer.
Jake convinced me that rich girls
don't have the soul for it.
Sounds like Jake. Always convincing
somebody of something.
It seems I have the soul to
live with him, be his girlfriend.
Well, he never had anybody
like you before, I can tell you that.
You're a whole different class
for him.
Not really.
My family didn't get to own most
of Bel Air by being honest.
Jake always thought
I was his luck.
I helped him outthink people
like my family.
I know why he wanted you.
But why were you with him?
I liked that my being with him
made a lot of people crazy.
Like your mom?
It even frightened her.
And that was really something
to finally pull off.
If only my brother had done that
and not by killing himself.
Your brother killed himself?
I guess.
He got into drugs
for the same reason I did.
To get away from our terrible life.
Did his dying make you stop?
No.
Jake did.
Jake did?
After I was with him awhile, it became
very important to him that I stop.
Wouldn't leave me alone.
Kept after me until I quit.
The truth is I wanted to quit.
When I did,
I didn't need Jake anymore.
Bet that kind of threw him, huh?
He said the only way I could
get away from him was to kill him.
Well, you almost did.
Not really.
I'm gonna stay away from Jake.
And my mother.
Good.
I ought to get going.
Why?
What'd you come here for?
You know, this is the best
I've felt in years.
I think you're incredible.
You do?
Yes, I do.
There's a great canyon down there.
Let's go back down there.
Don't you ever have
to breathe?
Come on, it's good therapy
for my shoulder.
This is a dream, you know that?
It's true! I've completely
forgotten about football.
- You liar!
- Hey!
That's the first thing
you've said I don't believe.
Hey, come here! It's true!
Then come in here
and prove it!
I'm not coming in there!
Whoo!
Come on, guapo.
It's good therapy for your shoulder.
Ay, caramba!
You know, I thought Jake would
send someone awful.
- How do you know I'm not awful?
- Maybe I'm no different than Jake.
We haven't left each other's side
for the last two weeks.
I figure I know who you are,
Terry Brogan.
- Jess.
- Hmm?
You know...
when I got my pro contract,
it was the first real money
I ever had.
It wasn't much because my lawyer
took a big hunk out of it.
But still,
I bought everything in sight.
And the girl that I was
living with at the time,
she moved out on me when I was on the road.
Took all my furniture with her.
It seems funny now,
but at the time it flipped me out.
I was under a lot of pressure,
trying to make the starting lineup.
I started acting crazy,
hanging out with Jake.
We got along great.
He was as crazy as I was.
And after a couple of years,
I got my ass into debt.
I mean, really badly.
And I made a deal with him
to shave points.
You know, you don't have to
tell me this, okay?
I'm supposed to stop now,
or something?
You said you know me.
Well, you don't. I want you to.
It was a game during the playoffs.
We were expected to win
by a four-point spread.
I was supposed to see
we didn't win by so fucking much.
I kept putting off doing anything about
it because I was feeling so good.
You know,
blow the other team out.
In the fourth quarter, they scored
14 points. Everything was great.
The point spread was four.
We were ahead by three.
I didn't have to do anything.
Then the quarterback,
he threw this pass.
Put it right into my hands.
It was just so perfect I just
had to catch it, you know.
All I had to do was just
drop the fucker.
But my reflexes took over.
So their guy tackled me
on the five...
and I fumbled. I, uh...
I just made my hands
let go of the ball.
It scared the shit out of me.
I thought everybody
in the stadium, all 55,000,
knew I was a son of a bitch.
So you won by three instead
of four points.
Jess, if another player
would have done that,
you'd have to pull me off of him quick,
or he'd be dead.
It's still torturing you, isn't it?
See, I do know who you are.
Do you know what I wish?
I wish I'd seen you play football.
I bet you were wonderful.
God.
I can see how Jake would
go crazy without you.
God, Jess.
All from Jake.
They stopped coming in
four days ago.
We should leave here, you know.
Oh, Terry, I don't want to leave.
It's so perfect here.
Yeah, I know.
We have no choice, though.
Well, I don't have
much money left.
Can't draw from my trust
for another three months.
Jake's money's all gone?
What do you mean, Jake's money?
He said you took, uh,
50 grand from him.
Steal from him,
when I want him off me?
I'd be out of my mind.
I didn't take a cent
of his goddamn money.
Well, I've got the money
he gave me so...
Hey, I'll go to the hotel
in the morning and get my bags.
We'll cover our tracks, huh?
But you have to go to
Chichén Itzá alone, okay?
I gotta get Jake off our trail.
Okay.
God, where have you been, Terry?
I've had 10 days
in this horrible place.
I found a guy to
get us a house in Oaxaca.
- Anywhere but here.
- I hope he's for real.
It'll cost all I've got.
- You don't know what it's like here.
- Where are we going?
- Come on, people can see us.
- If they can, who cares?
Jess, come on.
Will you cool it?
Come on,
you know we had to separate.
Jake thinks I'm all over
the place looking for you.
I've been to Mexico City,
Cuernavaca, Taxco.
Jessie. Hey.
I wired Jake.
He thinks you're in Campeche.
I wonder, when was the last time
someone used this court?
Fourteen or 15 centuries ago,
maybe.
The games they had here must've
been incredible. Look at this.
They even wore facemasks,
had shoulder pads.
Games were a little more serious
than the ones you play, Terry.
They'd play for days. The team that
lost got their heads chopped off.
And the guys who bet
on the game,
wagered themselves,
even their children.
And if they lost, they were slaves.
You're going crazy here,
aren't you?
I think I'd be crazy if I weren't.
We're getting out.
To go where?
Another place
we don't belong?
We could do better.
With what?
Jess.
I don't have the money Jake and
your mother have, but so what?
I'm taking care of you, aren't I?
Jess.
There's money
in Mexico City.
- What do you mean? Whose money?
- Mine.
Yours?
Jake's.
- Why didn't you tell me this before?
- I couldn't trust you for sure.
Since when
couldn't you trust me?
- In the beginning.
- What beginning?
We've been in this 10 minutes
after we saw each other.
Hey, tell me. When did you
start trusting me?
Terry, it was a risk
to trust you, all right?
That's funny.
I never thought of it that way.
I took the risk by letting
you come with me.
You let me come with you?
Yeah. It would've been different
if I were alone.
What, do you think I'm caging you in
or something?
Well, it's true, isn't it?
I'm standing in your way of freedom?
I'm keeping you from your money in Mexico City?
You're twisting what I say.
Hey, Jesus, I love you.
You've become everything I'm about!
Don't you understand?
Can't anyone love me
without it being
life or death to them?
Most people are afraid they're
never going to be loved like that.
Terry, wait!
I've lied and used people all my life because
I thought that's what everybody did.
Everyone except my brother,
and look where it got him.
It's just so hard for me
to trust anyone.
I'm not anyone.
I know.
I know you're not, and I'm trying.
I want to trust you.
God, I love you.
I love you.
Come on.
The park's closing.
Let's go to the sweathouse.
Okay.
Terry.
There's somebody in here.
- Where?
- There's somebody there.
Sully.
- What the fuck...-?
- Sorry I walked in on you like that.
Walked in on me?
What the hell
are you doing here?
What am I doing here?
What are we doing here?
You're in a lot of trouble.
I came to talk some sense
into you, I guess.
You came here to talk to me?
Terry,
if a tired old guy like me
can find you...
I don't understand.
What are you talking about?
Who is he, Terry?
It's Hank Sully.
He's with the Outlaws.
Jake sent him.
That's crazy.
I know his name!
He called Jake at the house.
Talk to me, Sul.
Why did you leave the team
in the middle of the season?
Come on, talk!
What do you want from me?
That jackass Caxton and her
old lady screwing up the team.
You know, if Mr. Wyler were alive,
I'd be head coach.
I think about that a lot, Terry.
So I just figured, fuck it!
I'd do something for me
for a change.
I was close to you guys. I knew
who was in debt, and how deep.
So when Jake wanted,
I could always finger
who was ready to break.
You're going home from here
with nothing. You know that.
Wise will send someone
a lot tougher than me, Terry.
Hank, come on.
Man, this is crazy.
- How much trouble are you in?
- Enough.
- I'm sorry.
- Come on, Terry.
Hold it!
Hank. Come on, man.
You said you were old and tired,
you're not out of your mind too,
are you?
Hank, come on.
This is Terry, man.
You're talking to him like he's a friend.
You don't know him.
Just let me take her back with me.
Who's gonna hurt her? Wise?
He worships her.
Back off, Sully.
Goddamn you, Terry!
She's worthless!
Come on, Terry.
You're no good at this.
It was easy to find you.
Mexico City, Cuernavaca.
I was breathing down your neck
and you didn't know it.
Come on, Terry.
I'm taking her back!
Son of a bitch!
Jessie!
Damn it, Sully!
Go on and get it, Terry!
Stop it!
Get off him!
Hank!
You jackass!
Terry! Goddamn it.
Stop!
- Come on, Terry.
- Okay, stop.
- Stop!
- Shut the fuck up!
Back off, Sully.
Get away, please!
- Get away!
- See what you've done?
Give me that fucking gun.
He grabbed the gun, Terry.
I couldn't help it.
Come on, let's get out of here.
- He's not dead!
- He will be, Terry.
There's no one to help him.
She's right.
Maybe I'll stop bleeding.
What do you think?
Sure. Sure.
You're full of shit, Brogan.
- We gotta do something...
- Do what?
Take him to a Mexican jail, with a body and a gun?
Are you crazy?
It's not our fault.
We can explain it.
We can't, Terry! Let's just get out!
Let's go! Let's run!
This isn't something
we can run from anymore!
Oh, God! You're so innocent!
You just don't understand! Do you?
Come on, Sul,
hang in there.
Bury me here, Brogan.
Forget that shit, will you?
What are we doing
down here?
Hank.
Jess?
Jessie!
Jess!
Oh, God. Jess, no!
Give it to me.
All right, I'm not spiking.
- I got it. I got it.
- Get it.
Nice. You playing with
your high heels on?
- Impressive.
- Terry.
Now see, if I like a guy and it looks
like I'll never see him again,
I don't worry.
You know why?
Because I always get lucky.
Thanks, honey.
You're working up a sweat.
That's good.
I love sports, Terry.
You know that.
Okay.
An Outlaws game is starting.
Come on up.
Tommy, head into town.
Call me after the games, okay?
So did you notice?
I'm walking without a limp.
You got your life together, Jake.
I'm impressed.
You know, Ter,
there's never just one game.
There's always a whole
mess of them.
Like life.
You get hit hard by one,
you get blessed
by a couple of others.
You still like football, don't you?
I love the game, myself.
Business and pleasure.
You got a new conditioning coach.
Did you know that?
Sully's gone.
When the hell
are you going to tell me?
What happened to you down there?
I decided it was a shit job.
So you just walked away from it?
You still looking for her?
- Didn't you find her yet?
- It's none of your business, Terry.
You didn't finish the job, so I don't
owe you the rest of the money. Okay?
I figure you just came over
today to say we're still friends.
- Am I right? Tell me I'm right.
- No.
No. I just wanted to tell you
to your face to eat it.
That's nice.
You mentioned having something on me?
You hang me, you hang yourself.
Go to hell.
It's not that easy, Terry.
There's other people involved.
It's just not you and me.
If you want to play football again,
there's something you gotta do.
Another job.
It's gonna help both of us.
You didn't hear what I said, did you?
It's finished with us.
Don't you feel you owe me
just a little something?
Hello, Terry.
She look great, or what?
Christ, would you look
at that defense, huh?
It's like the whole team's
gone out of shape without Sully.
Sully is missed.
I can tell you that.
Don't leave.
Stay and watch the game, man.
If you want,
you can even place a bet.
Some other time.
Oh, hey. There's a party
at the Palace tomorrow night.
You'll hear some good music.
And I'll tell you all about that job.
This is something
you've got to do for yourself.
Because your career's
all you got now, my friend.
So I'll expect you, right?
Hey, get out of there!
Get out!
Get out of there!
Have you been all right?
Wait till I get my wind back, will you?
Get your dog out of here.
Come on, Sam.
I think about you.
I think about you too, lady.
- Let's leave it at that, huh?
- You've gotta understand who I am.
Someone's always been there
to take care of things.
You couldn't handle what happened to Sully.
I had to come back.
It was either Jake or my mother.
And I couldn't go to her.
Terry, he knows about Sully.
What's he know?
What did you tell him?
Terry, he could hurt us.
You mean he could hurt me.
Just do what he wants
and finish it with him.
Are you scared for me, Jess? Huh?
Yes.
You know, I've been down there
looking for you.
I came back hoping somebody might know something.
I was worried about you.
You came back to this fuck.
I love you.
Oh, yeah, I noticed.
Todd, how you doing?
Let's go upstairs
and talk some football.
- You're here to watch the show.
- Catch me when I'm in the mood.
Tommy.
Hang out at the bar.
You want to talk,
maybe Tommy will listen.
Look, Jake, he never writes anything down.
I don't even know if he can write.
- Hey.
- I don't trust...
Watch your mouth when you fucking
talk about Tommy. Do you hear me?
Now if not, okay, go play your money
someplace else. Hi. How are you? Go on.
Go on.
I'll be in the bar.
He'll be at the bar.
Hi. How are you?
Nice to see you.
Glad you showed up.
That's nice.
Came to get your stink
off me.
Listen, pal, I'm not the one
who blew this friendship, okay?
- Where's Jessie?
- She stayed at home. She's upset.
I don't know what it could be.
What you think?
- I think you've got a lot of friends.
- Go mingle with them. Okay?
Tommy,
show Terry to his table.
Talk to you later.
I want something in return.
I want a complete catalog
on Bob Marley.
Everything, all the records.
And I want live concerts.
Everything.
- Listen, if I ask him to...
- Hi.
You heard about this band?
No.
It's supposed to be great,
I can't wait.
What are you doing here?
If you have something to say to me,
say it and get out.
This guy looks familiar. Why?
Listen, smart ass,
just get out of here.
Okay.
Uh, Tommy?
Hey, Tommy.
Go ahead.
Hey, Tommy!
- This guy a friend of yours?
- Go ahead.
This guy the show, or what?
Sit down!
You're such a prick.
Thank you!
Well, the good news is that some
of my best friends are here tonight.
The bad news is,
the rest of you are here.
It's a good thing I'm in the music
business instead of in comedy.
Okay, a great act tonight,
straight from my hometown.
Where's my hometown?
Nueva York, New York City.
The Big Apple. Yeah!
Rotten to the core, as tonight's
group will aptly demonstrate.
They think of themselves
as tropical gangsters,
but we like to call them
Kid Creole and the Coconuts.
Planning Commissioner Soames.
Dealing with politicians now.
I'm a top sports accountant.
Bob Soames has been a client
for a long time.
I only deal with uptown people.
Like this guy I'm sitting with?
Kirsch? As a matter of fact,
this job I have for you,
it's got to do with Kirsch.
You're really coming up in the world.
Lawyers, politicians.
I've done business
with Kirsch for a long time.
Yeah. Sully too.
Sully kept me up on injuries
that might affect upcoming games.
Kirsch let me know
what players wouldn't have
their contracts renewed.
I had it great.
It's a shitty business, Jake.
Well, it's a shitty world, Terry.
You see, Kirsch and Sully
fixed a game behind my back.
Kirsch placed what I thought
was an off-the-wall bet.
But when he won big,
I paid the cocksucker.
I guess he figured when I lost Jessie,
I was ripe for being screwed.
Must be an epidemic.
- How'd you find out?
- Your friend.
Sully.
Kirsch, the greedy son of a bitch,
cheated Sully on his cut.
So he came up here, figured there would
be some money telling me about it.
Poor fucking Sully.
I'd like to kick the shit
out of Kirsch.
The asshole's got files on me.
And I'm the dumb fuck
who's supposed to get them for you?
He's got records of the games.
Of the business I did
with the players.
Know who that includes?
You got no smart-mouth remark
for that one?
Here. These will get you into
Kirsch's building and the office.
Sunday night. Late.
It's a little dirty,
but not so dirty
you won't sleep nights.
Why me? Why not Tommy?
I want Tommy clean.
You? I was ready to be
your friend for life.
You owe me.
This is what I want from you.
It's in our mutual interest.
As far as I'm concerned,
it finishes all the shit
between us.
I'm missing the show.
What the hell made you think
you could handle Jessie?
I bet you brought her flowers.
You don't have to do that
when you're living in the jungle.
You just take her outside, show her
what tree you're gonna do it under.
Hell, we hit lots of trees.
Shit! Now you follow me into the fucking toilet.
Give me a break, please.
- What is this?
- It's a warning. Be careful.
Okay, Terry. I'm going to be
very careful, all right?
Just fuck right off.
You think we're sitting at
the same table by accident? Hm?
I figure the bet was you'd
make a scene. We'd be noticed.
Really? Hm.
I'm looking out for myself.
I've done what I can for you.
Okay, fuck off.
I keep thinking of what I did
to make me deserve you.
Go to hell.
Oh, I have.
You know that, lady!
What's it like with Jake? Huh?
When you two are doing it?
Is he good?
Shut up, Terry!
Does he have a bigger cock
than I do? Huh?
Shut up!
Do you know what
he wants me to do for him?
You and I have seen worse.
Jake's a gambler. He thinks I took
his luck when I took you.
I hit him too hard.
Then get out
of it now.
But what about all the things
you and I shared, Jess? Hm?
What about Sully?
Hm?
You remember him?
That guy we killed down there
in the jungle.
He's got me one way
or the other, doesn't he?
Huh? Doesn't he?
Yeah, go ahead,
you rip the shirt off. Come on.
Rip the shirt off.
Rip the fucking shirt off!
What am I gonna do, Jess?
Oh, Terry! I'm sorry.
- I'm so sorry.
- I love you.
Hold me.
What are we gonna do?
Is this Sam?
Is this Sam? I bet it is Sam, is it?
There's Sam.
Sam's crazy about me.
That's a fact.
You know, dogs kill
for people they love.
Maybe Sam knows
I'd kill for you.
- What do you mean?
- See that?
Now you're looking at me.
Why do I have to frighten you
to get you to look at me?
I give you everything you want.
Your mother and Caxton can't stomp on me.
You're not even afraid of them anymore.
Jake.
You know, when you came
at me with a knife,
all I could think of
was that you'd hurt yourself.
I'm not spitting in your face.
I just want you to let me go.
When we were first together,
it was so great.
I finally impressed those fucks
in Beverly Hills. Remember?
You know what was even better?
You were smart.
You really helped me.
But I don't care about
any of that now.
I need you.
It's just not okay
to be alone anymore.
No, Jake.
No.
You ruined my life.
Goddamn it, I'm not gonna lose you.
He's got files on the business I did
with the players.
You do want to play ball again,
don't you, Terry?
Sunday night.
Late.
It's a little dirty, but not so dirty
you won't sleep nights.
Steve?
This is the rest
of what Jake owes you...
Jesus Christ! What?
I hid the body.
They'll find it sooner or later.
He killed him?
- He had him killed?
- Shh. Edie.
Oh, my God.
Not that it's any great loss, but...
Look, Jake Wise planted
something up in his office
to frame me.
I didn't find it in time.
Oh, they're all bastards.
- All of them.
- Look, Edie, I need your help.
You worked with Kirsch
for a long time.
You could knock the hell
out of them.
What do you mean?
I don't know what Jake planted.
But Kirsch kept a tiny treasure chest
that could blow everybody up.
I shouldn't be this drunk.
Listen, if the booze helps...
I can't believe this is my life. Ugh.
Where was this box?
Terry...
I'd be too scared to do it.
You worked for Kirsch. You knew most
of what he knew. They know that.
Edie, they'll kill you too.
Edie, help me.
- But it means...
- What?
Going back there.
To Kirsch's office.
There shouldn't be a dog in here.
Who the hell are you?
I worked for Kirsch.
You must be the one
who unemployed me.
Sit.
- Are the others here?
- Mm-hm.
They're all over the building.
Looking for the body.
Some mess.
We're gonna find him.
Jake wants certain things
out of the office right away.
Why?
I guess he's a little jumpy.
Things seem to be
disappearing tonight, don't they?
Your dog bothers me.
It's supposed to bother people.
Put him in there, please.
No.
You're making this take
much more time than it has to.
Mister...
Mr. Wise is waiting for me.
Listen,
you're not a security guard.
But I belong here.
Now put the goddamn dog in there!
Come on.
Stay.
Yeah?
Hello, Mr. Wise.
No, we haven't found Kirsch's body.
Don't worry about it.
Don't get excited. We'll find it.
Gonna take it a floor at a time.
I'm sure of it.
No, we're in the office
looking for those papers you wanted.
The ones you asked that girl to get.
Hey, come back here!
- Get back!
- You crazy bitch!
Who are you? Goddamn it!
Who the hell are you?
You little punk! You're dead!
Argh!
Run, Edie!
Come on!
Edie!
- Did you get the papers?
- Yes, I got them!
Hey!
- Here, I'll park it for you.
- I live here.
Jessica.
Hello, Mother.
You're looking well.
I need to see Ben.
I've missed you.
Please get Ben, Mother. Please.
He's much too busy celebrating.
Bob Soames changed his vote
on Wyler Canyon.
Why do you want Ben?
I just wanna talk to him
about something.
- You can talk to him tomorrow.
- No, I need to speak to him now!
- Right now!
- Keep your voice down.
I'll embarrass you, Mother.
I'll just walk right in there
and I'll be my sweet self.
Hello, Jessie.
Hello, Ben.
I have to talk to you, alone.
- Excuse us.
- Sure.
Let's go in there.
- Jake's had Kirsch killed.
- What?
He's made it look like Terry did it.
He was trying to get Terry for what he
did with me, but it's more than that.
He's been fixing games
and betting against his own bank.
Kirsch was making the bets
for him.
Something's going down
at Kirsch's office.
- Brogan wouldn't have gone back.
- Why would he?
He'd be crazy to.
Would you get over there and find
out what's going on? Come on.
You've gotten out of hand, Jake.
Come on, Tommy.
What've you done to me?
He's here to help me, not hurt you.
The things you don't know.
This man that you, your mother
and everybody thinks so much of,
he's my bank.
I work for him.
Ben?
Yeah.
Ben. You told him everything,
didn't you?
Didn't you?
Oh, God.
You're still trying to kill me.
This time I might just be dead.
Jake.
I love you, Jessie.
Why did that have to be
a bad thing?
I tell you,
I didn't mean anything bad.
Your office is still busy.
Yeah?
That you, Brogan?
Here.
Hello, Brogan.
Who's this?
Hey, Señor Caxton!
Couldn't catch the game tonight.
We won. Listen, Brogan,
I'm getting into this
because of my goddaughter, Jessica.
I'll tell you, there's somebody else
you gotta help tonight, Caxton.
Yourself.
I've just been in Kirsch's safe.
You know what he had in there?
The goods on you,
Supervisor Phillips,
a whole lot of people.
I know all about Soames.
You know, the commissioner
who wanted to
protect the environment
but liked to bet on football too.
Guess he found out the two
don't mix, didn't he, Caxton?
I think we should meet.
I got no problem with that.
As a matter of fact, I know a great place.
Wyler Canyon, in an hour.
The spot where you're gonna break
ground in a couple of weeks.
I know the place.
That idiot football player
you were going to get
has got me by the balls.
Come on.
Jessie.
You too, Wise.
Your friend Brogan is
a threat to me, Jessie.
I don't know what he wants,
but it's got to be settled. Tonight.
I can't believe this is you, Ben.
I think my mother would snap
if she knew.
I get things done in this town.
And the people I work for,
like your mother,
have no interest in how that happens.
Just that I do it.
She wants Wyler Canyon
developed, but she can't
get through to everybody
with campaign contributions.
So I have to go into business
with some very strange people.
Like that asshole next to you.
I don't have to take
this from you, Caxton.
He's as dirty as I am, Jessie.
He owns 75 percent of the book
and 75 percent of the club.
I take all the heat while
he sits on his ass.
Shut him up, Tommy!
He got you into this. Now convince me
you're not an asshole.
Come on, Tommy.
They'll never let you sit on top.
When you had Kirsch killed,
you buried yourself.
You think they'll ever
do business with you?
Wise up!
I'm telling you no one in Beverly Hills is
ever gonna do business with a black man.
Shut up, Jake.
You're a dead man.
Not yet, Caxton.
Brogan won't beat anybody.
I'll take care of him.
You still need me.
Put that gun away.
Take it, Jake.
My best friend?
Brogan!
- Watch it, they've got a gun!
- Shut up, Jessie!
That's okay, Jessie!
Things have a way of getting
messed up when you're in them.
I don't expect the best.
What the hell are
you doing, Brogan?
This mountain's pretty important
to you, isn't it, Caxton?
With what I got from Kirsch's safe,
I can knock all your plans to hell!
Mrs. Wyler wouldn't like that,
would she?
What do you want?
- Don't shoot!
- Terry!
You're trying to kill me!
What do you think I want?
I wanna stay alive!
What do you want?
I didn't want you, Caxton!
I want Jake's shit out of my life!
Now I want yours out too!
That's all you want?
Why don't I believe you?
Because you're a corrupt old man.
Your coverage stinks, Tommy.
What's your deal, Brogan?
I found out tonight Jake jumps for you.
Slap him down.
It's that fucking simple, Caxton.
I'll keep Kirsch's stuff
until I'm satisfied.
That can be arranged.
Are you crazy?
Don't let this punk beat you.
It can still work. Sully the trainer,
Kirsch the lawyer, and Brogan the player,
all cheating each other on the fix!
- Knock it off, Jake!
Drop the gun.
Drop the fucking gun.
Take the gun away from her head.
You're not gonna hurt her.
You wanna gamble with me, Terry?
Go ahead.
Take the gun away.
You were my friend. You know me.
Take your shot.
Don't do it, Terry.
He won't hurt me.
I'm not gonna take that chance.
Thattaboy.
Don't think about it, Tommy.
I'll blow you away. Step back.
Step fucking back.
Who's gonna be a dead man, Caxton?
Not me.
It's gotta be Terry.
What makes somebody
your friend, Jake?
How much shit
they're willing to do for you?
Jake. Jake, don't do it.
Don't... Jake, I love him!
Right in my face.
Right in my fucking face.
I'll blow him the fuck...
Jessie.
Keep away from her, Brogan.
You can't help her with this.
But you can, Caxton.
I think so.
But it means doing things my way.
I want that stuff from Kirsch.
And Jessie's going back
where she belongs.
You'll leave him alone, Ben.
I'll do what you want,
but you'll leave him alone.
What I'm most happy about is
the opportunity to share this land.
It's beauty and the beauty
around it
won't be sitting up here
alone anymore, just going to waste.
I'm sharing what I believe is the best
location on the West Side.
Close to Century City
and the ocean.
We won't crowd the hillsides.
Each owner will feel that
the canyon belongs to him.
A sanctuary from the crowding
and crime of the city below us.
Specifically, I'd like to acknowledge
three public officials
without whose generous support
we wouldn't be here:
Supervisor Ed Phillips,
Councilman Leonard Weinberg...
Stay here.
Just remember your promise, Ben.
And the head of the commission,
Bob Soames.
Thank you, gentlemen.
Now for the big moment.
This was the only way you could
get a look at her, eh?
Nothing stops progress,
does it?
We had to put it off for six months
until things died down in the press.
Moving 5 million yards of earth
out of here.
Enough to fill dump trucks
from here to Nova Scotia.
This town does
belong to people like you, doesn't it?
You and her mother control
what she says, what she does.
There's nothing in the news that
isn't exactly the way you wanted it.
Jake Wise did things even
he'd freak out about.
There's a lot of sympathy for her.
Well, there should be.
It didn't seem to hurt you, Brogan.
I heard you got some tryouts
with good teams.
I'm playing with the Dolphins
next season.
That's one you couldn't put
a stop to, could you?
I'll be ready.
Couple of good years
and I'll quit on my own terms.
So you're going to leave L.A. Good.
Look, when you need me in court,
I'll be there for her.
But forget anything else.
Remember, Brogan,
you're out of her life.
I figure that's up to her.
You're not gonna control us forever.
Believe me.