I love you.
You're so beautiful.
- I want you.
Renee.
Want me to get her?
- It's okay. I'll get her.
Renee.
Hi.
Did we wake you up?
Come here. Look at you.
Daddy wants to give you a kiss.
- 20.
21.
22.
Oh, Renee, help me. 23.
24.
Either you're getting bigger
or I'm losing it.
I won't be too late.
Yeah? You bet.
Hey, Johnny,
Gino's waiting for you.
- Dumas, what's happening?
- Lippy give me
10 bottles of 357.
- We aim to please
and so does Louise.
- Louise?
- See you later Dumas, man.
- See you Friday.
Lippy.
Lippy! Lippy.
- Hello.
- Lippy.
Lippy!
Why aren't you
minding the store?
You're supposed to be
running the night shift!
What are you doing?
- It's cool, baby!
I got some of my finest
employees covering.
I just sold 10 bottles
to that dumb ass honkie.
T-I-N. 10.
- I'm not impressed, honey.
I'm running a volume business,
not a nickel dime side show.
Oh, kiss me, honey.
Damn, look at you,
you're a human mess.
- Alphabet Johnny, so clean now.
You got it all.
What you gonna do,
you gonna pick on this
poor defenseless black-
- Why don't you can the
act, all right, Lip?
All right? Stop being
your own best customer.
- Yeah?
I'll tell you what, man.
- What?
- I only peddle this shit
so I don't gotta pay for it.
- All right? Oh,
my God, can I cry?
Just a few. Let me
squirt a few. All right?
- Give me a fucking cigarette.
Give me a fucking cigarette.
- You want a cigarette?
- Give me a fucking cigarette.
Come on man, don't fuck about.
- In the back. In the back.
Man, what do you
think you're doing?
- In the back, in the back.
Come on, in the
back, in the back.
- Put this window down.
-Come on, I got a
pack in the back.
- Something smells in here.
- What do you want? You
want me to light it for you?
- I can light it myself.
You paint these with tranny
helper, or something, man?
- Come on, I have,
I have a big heart.
- I got a big heart, you got
something else that's big.
- What are you doing?
What are you doing?
Come on, I have
to save these for
charity cases like yourself.
Come on, hold it.
Ah, forget about it.
- I can light my own.
I can handle it, man.
- Lippy.
Lippy.
What happened to you, huh?
You used to be pretty
once I remember.
- Look, man...
- I was in love with you.
- I'm gonna tell you something.
We're making more money
than we can count, man.
What do you want from me?
- Hey, goombah, huh!
- Yeah, my butt!
- You and me got this
street by the balls,
we're practically
legends, immortal!
Huh?
- Well, why you on my ass?
- Because I want your
ass watching the store.
You know how much those
dudes could be skimming?
- You ought to know. What?
What did you say?
- What's the matter, man?
What's the matter, brother?
You got a salami up
your eye-tie ass?
- I got Gino up my ass.
Oh, is that right?
What does Don Corleone want now?
- This building.
- Count me out,
John, like you say.
I'm just a no...
No good fucked up junkie, man.
I hate fire!
Don't go away mad!
- Sophia, you're
too much, honey.
- Hi, Ma.
What're you doing?
- Get away, you're
gonna burn yourself.
- Who is that man?
Give me a hug or what?
- Get away.
What is this?
- How you doing, huh?
What, what? You know I'm lazy.
- Well, I don't like the beard.
Hi, princess.
- How you doing, Johnny?
Whoo!
- So, what's on TV tonight, huh?
Hmm?
Who's that?
- A friend.
- Ooh, that's Julio Iglesias.
He's handsome, ain't he?
Whoo!
- Really, what?
- He treat you good, Mama?
- Yeah.
Better than your
father ever did.
- You let him rest in
peace, all right, Ma?
This guy hit you?
- No.
- This guy hits you,
you tell me-
- Hit?
- And I'll take care of it.
- No!
He just drinks all her
beer and passes out.
- What is... What? What?
- Mama.
- What?
- You don't have to
slave for nobody.
- Yeah.
- You don't have to
show us what a saint
you are all the time.
- Yeah, we already know.
- What is that? What is that?
You want me to wash
it? Want me to-
- Come on, Ma, just take it.
- I'll wash it.
Get it off, I don't
want that dirty money.
I do honest work.
Will you listen to her?
You gotta do something with
her. You gotta talk to her.
I think she'll listen to you.
Be careful of the iron.
- It's gonna be all right.
It's gonna be all right. Yeah.
- Yeah, it's gonna be terrific.
Every night I think they're
gonna wake me up, ring my bell,
tell me you're dead
in an alley somewhere.
- Oh, Mama.
It's never gonna happen.
Never.
- Yeah.
- We always go through the
same thing, am I right? Huh?
- Yeah.
- I got it under
control. No problem.
- It's got you under control.
- No, it doesn't!
I'm gonna talk to her.
I didn't
do nothing, Johnny.
- 15 years old and
already she's a tramp!
- I'm an escort, Ma. Oh.
- You're an escort.
What is that?
Is that the uptown
name for a whore, huh?
When you sell your ass for
Alphabet City, you're a whore.
Okay?
- Oh, Johnny.
Johnny, I don't sell my ass.
They pay me for the
privilege of my company.
I don't even have
to come across.
It's a goddamn joke,
I'm telling you, Johnny.
- It's not a joke.
You know that.
- Yeah?
- It's no joke.
- Well listen to
this, big brother.
A limo. Uh-huh.
A limo is coming to
take me to Park Avenue.
Some big doctor or a lawyer.
Johnny, look at me.
I ain't gonna end up like Mama,
having those old bums lying
around me in my old age.
- You shut up your mouth!
You don't ever talk about Mama
like that. You understand?
- Johnny, Johnny, I didn't
mean nothing against Mama.
It's just that I don't
like all those dead beats
trying to catch me in
my underwear, you know?
- What? What?
What are you, Miss Bashful,
now all of a sudden, huh?
- Maybe.
- Look at yourself,
Sophia, look at yourself.
- What's wrong, huh?
- You're giving them
plenty of chances, babe.
Hmm?
Now, let me tell you
something. Let me tell you.
When you get sick,
and you can't work, what do
you think is gonna happen, huh?
- Sick?
- You know what? You ask those
other chicks what happens.
Ask them.
- Johnny. Johnny.
I ain't like those wasted
broads that work for Gino.
I go uptown, strictly uptown.
- How do you think those
wasted broads started out?
Huh?
They was just like you, Sophia.
They was thinking they're
special. They're special.
They're gonna live some good
life, humping the uptown trade.
But you know something?
They're all down here now.
All of them.
Working for a goddamn pimp
and none of them
was ever special.
Is that what you want?
Oh, baby, you're
gonna have the best.
I guarantee it.
But you ain't gonna get it
the way you're going about it.
Now, listen to me.
You and Mama gotta get out
of the building tonight.
They're gonna torch it.
- Who's gonna
torch the building?
- It don't matter who.
You don't wanna know.
It's economics, you know, the...
The real estate, property
values, etcetera.
Somebody wants to
make a killing.
And they don't care
if they have to Kill
a few people to do it.
You and Mama just gotta get out.
- Why can't you stop 'em, huh?
- I can't stop them.
- Wait, wait, Johnny.
I thought you were
their golden boy.
Big man on his way up.
Big man on the streets.
Alphabet Johnny.
Why can't you stop them, huh?
-'Cause I'm the man
with the matches.
- You?
You're gonna do it?
And you can't say no, huh?
- Sophia.
Suppose I say no?
- Yeah?
- It's still gonna go.
All I can do is get you
and Mama out of here.
- What the fuck you
want from me, huh?
I got a date.
This is your problem,
big brother, you hear me?
It's yours.
Maria? Maria!
Maria, come into the house now.
Don't talk back to me.
- Bye, Ma.
Bye, Johnny.
- I'm not going anywhere.
- Mama.
What do you mean you're
not going anywhere?
You don't go, you die.
- I'd rather die.
- For Christ's sake, Mama.
I mean, what... I buy you
any kind of place you want.
Anything. Huh?
We can all get away
from this goddamn hell.
Ma. Ma.
Do it for me. All right?
Do it for me. Okay?
Come on, why you
wanna stay here?
- 'Cause it's my life and
I don't want to hand it out
to a bunch of cheap hoods.
You scared?
Tough guy.
Not me!
I don't scare so easy.
They want me out of here,
they can carry me out.
You like that?
Maybe you don't understand that.
Maybe it's time you did.
- Johnny?
- Sophia. Get out of the car.
- Johnny, what the fuck
are you doing here?
Get out of here!
Get out of here, Johnny!
I swear to God...
- Get out of the car.
- Hey, what the hell do
you think you're doing?
You stupid
fuck, what are you doing?
No, Johnny!
Oh, my God. Johnny,
he has a gun.
- Hey, hey. You wanna live?
Huh?
Get in your car and take off.
- You are crazy!
No!
You made me lose my job, Johnny.
I hate you!
Will you get away from
me? You're hurting me!
Good boy, Johnny.
Johnny, what
are you doing out here?
- Stop it, Johnny,
please, stop it.
Johnny, I'm really
getting angry!
Johnny!
Shut your mouth,
or I'll come downstairs
and shut it for you.
- Well, fuck you, dildo brain!
Why are you doing
this to me, huh?
No, why you doing this to me?
You make me lose my job,
you make me look like shit
in front of my friends.
- Shh. Shh.
- Why you doing this
to me, Johnny, huh?
- I ain't trying to
screw you up, Kid.
Believe me.
Please.
Someday...
But now, tonight...
Tonight, you gotta
get Mama out of here.
Okay?
She won't listen to me,
she only listens to you.
All right?
- You're gonna do it?
- No.
No.
They're gonna do it anyway.
Do you understand?
Now, listen to me.
I want you to take this.
All right?
You guys get whatever you need.
You get Mama and get a cab.
Go... Go uptown, some place nice.
A Holiday Inn, whatever,
and you stay there
until you hear from me.
Okay?
- What about you, Johnny?
They're gonna come
after you now.
- You don't worry about me, kid?
Okay?
All right?
You're such a good kid.
I gotta go.
All right?
- Yeah.
- A cab, okay?
- Okay.
- Johnny.
Hey, macho man.
- Look, you stay
away from my sister.
- Que pasa, man?
I been looking heavy for you.
- Guess I found you first.
- Oh, man, what
is this shit, huh?
Yeah. Yeah.
So, how's business, huh?
You getting that good dough?
Those hot ladies?
Those tight little boys?
- What the fuck do you want?
- Yo, man, I want it all.
I want me a fucking Mercedes-Benz,
man, you understand?
A Rolls with a turbo
diesel on that shit.
And I want me a gun, too.
You got a gun.
- Areal gun, man.
I'm talking one of those
imported .45s, man.
You know, the kind that
that foreign faggot makes.
Gold plated.
You know what else I want, man?
I want the territory, man.
I want Alphabet City!
But first I gotta
talk some business
with you, man, you know.
- What the fuck
do you wanna talk?
- Well, I was thinking, uh...
Sophia.
I said she could be looking
real fresh, man, you know.
And, uh, I want her
for my stable, man.
Yo, man.
Slow down, man!
Slow, man!
My God!
Damn.
- You better do
some talking to Oz
about a fucking brain, Juani,
'cause you ain't smart
enough to run this city.
You talk too much,
you scare too fucking easy.
You're nobody.
Nobody. Small time.
You couldn't run
fucking Disneyland.
Now, get out of my car.
- Oh, yeah?
- Get out.
- Yeah, well, what
about Sophia, huh?
What about Sophia?
- What about Sophia?
What about her?
Come on, Juani.
Just ask me again.
You know I could blow your
fucking brains out
all over the fucking street.
But I don't wanna... I
don't wanna mess up my car.
You get out of my sight!
And don't let me see you
on my fucking streets!
- Yeah, I was just fucking
with you, man, you know.
Hey, well fuck you, man!
Who is it?
- Chunga.
- Hey, Johnny.
- Ramon.
- Hola.
Rock steady.
Johnny.
Thy kingdom
is heaven.
Keep to the right.
The right, god damn it.
Move, move, walk, walk.
Against the wall,
against the wall!
Fucking idiots!
And no talking!
You talk, you walk!
Where you going?
- Uh, inside.
- What for?
Junk. D.
- Universal.
Let me see the tracks.
Now, get your ass up there.
Move, bastard, move.
Oh, man, I'm
gonna be sick, man.
Where do you
think you're going?
- You talk, you walk!
- He got my money, man.
- Chunga.
Go get your stuff.
- Get your money ready.
Pay and get out!
I don't want to hear
a sound, not a sound!
- Yo, what is it, man?
- What is the total?
- 11 grams.
- 20 thou, man. 20 thou.
- Not bad.
- That's two bundles, all right?
It's the
fuzz! Everybody out!
Nobody move!
Evening, Ociffer.
- Get all of it!
Come on!
- Come on.
A good
night's work, right?
- Everything is a big
fucking show to you.
Big show.
One day no show.
It's gonna be you
and me brother.
- What you talking about, man?
Don't matter how
close they get, man.
We're too fast,
too slick.
Shit.
Sounds like you're losing
your nerve, or something.
- I ain't losing my nerve,
but you're so high all the time,
you couldn't be scared if
your life depended on it.
- Hey, babe.
I can dig it, man. It's cool.
I assume it's gonna
start getting you, man.
But that don't leave you
to tell me my business.
- Your business, Mr. Fucking
Bright Boy, is my business.
You understand?
You don't take care of
you, they get to me.
You hurt my arm.
Like dominoes.
Look at you. Lippy!
Look at yourself.
You think I can be
dependent on you anymore?
Huh?
No way, man.
It's gone.
You don't got it.
You couldn't tell one of those
cops from a fucking doorman.
- Have I ever let you down?
Tell me the truth, have
I ever fucked you up?
- No, you never fucked...
- Huh?
- You never fucked me up, no!
- Fuck then.
Lippy,
you gotta kick.
You gotta kick for you.
You understand? Hear me.
Now, I know you're your own man.
But I ain't gonna stand by
and watch you kill yourself.
Lippy.
Listen to me.
We've been real lucky.
But times change.
Times change.
This whole fucking
scene's catching up on me.
It ain't that I can't
hack it anymore.
I don't wanna hack it anymore.
- No way out for us, man.
No way.
Only way out for me is in a box.
You find a way out of here.
You find a way out, ain't
nothing I wouldn't do to help you.
You know that, man.
Just don't tell me about...
Don't tell...
Don't tell me
nothing about junk.
That's my business!
- I got a feeling about tonight.
I got a feeling.
Get the fuck out.
Eddie, got him outside?
You got him?
- Gino.
- Hey, Johnny boy.
What's the matter?
You got a problem?
- No problem.
- The building, Johnny
boy, the building.
What happened, you lose
your matches, or what?
- There was trouble. Trouble
at the store, another bust.
You know, I haven't...
- Yeah, yeah,
yeah. I know, John.
How much, John?
- Uh, $15,000.
- 1572
Come on, John, don't give me
that shit. That's too low.
- There was a bust. I gotta
take care of my people.
- Hey, hey, fuck the bust, huh?
Listen to me, Johnny.
Don't go talking to
me about your people.
Maybe you forgot
who your people are.
And that building's
priority number one tonight.
Numero uno, capisce?
- Yeah, okay.
- They got all this faith
in you, you know why?
I'll tell you why, John.
Because of me.
So, don't go fucking up.
Okay.
- All right, now listen.
I'm waiting,
but not too much longer,
so get your shit together.
I'll talk to you.
- Fuck you!
Get Ready to Break,
Ready to Break
- Yipee, Johnny.
I know what you want.
- Benny.
Benny!
- Payday! Fine!
Sayonara.
- Benny!
Too low.
- Oh. I got.
I got it right here for you.
- Good boy.
Come on.
- Oh, bambino, how you doing?
Have a drink. What drink?
I said to give him a drink.
- No, no, it's all right, honey.
- Don't give him a drink.
- Look, Tony...
- Wanna feed your face?
- No, no, no. It's all
right, it's all right.
- You wanna do her?
- No, no. Look, Tony,
I'm late, all right?
- For what?
Smokey the Bear over here.
So, where's the fire?
A drink, please.
- Tony, I just wanna
make my collection
and get out of here, all right?
- Ooh! Relax!
What do you wanna do, give
me a heart attack over here?
Come on. It'll be
a little while.
How long
is a little while?
- I don't know, a
while, that's all.
- Look, Tony, I ain't got
time to hang out, all right?
I'm running late. Real late.
- Maron.
Come on, you gonna
give me agita.
Bulls made a stop here
about an hour ago,
so, we have a cash-flow
problem tonight.
Unexpected problems of a
legitimate business operation.
- How long?
- Hmm?
Tony, how long
till I can collect?
- Oh, shit,
about an hour or
two, that's all.
Listen,
go down to Vinnie's Clam Bar,
get some shrimp balls, and
have 'em put it on my check...
- I ain't fucking hungry, Tony.
- All right.
Why don't you go and take
a long hike for yourself?
Get a couple of sticks
and rub 'em together
like a good scout, huh?
- How come you know so much?
- Come on, give me a break.
Huh? La famiglia.
La famiglia.
We all gotta stick up
for our own, don't we?
You wanna get your
pipe cleaned, or what?
- One hour, Tony. One.
- One hour.
- Well, excuse us, tough guy.
- Who do you think you are?
- Gino.
- Why you stalling, Johnny?
- Stalling?
- Look.
The only smoke I see up here
is coming from my cigar.
- There's heat. Cops
all over the place.
- No more than usual, John.
What are you doing
at the club, anyway?
- Business.
- You're making your collections
real fast tonight, Johnny.
You going somewhere?
- Just taking care of business.
- You fucking punk. I've been
saving your ass all along.
Now, you got sticky fingers,
you know that? But no more.
I want you to get
your ass up here.
'Cause you and me are gonna
have a little sit down.
We got things to talk about.
Now, you remember when
I gave you that rock.
I told ya,
we was married now.
And there's no divorce
in our family, Johnny.
There's only one
way out of this.
Hear what I'm saying, John?
Remember one thing, Johnny.
Nobody's fucking indispersable.
You know what I mean?
- Hello?
Johnny.
I'm tired.
Um, can you pick up
some disposable diapers?
Thanks. Bye.
- Why you working so late, huh?
Baby's asleep.
The phone's quiet.
Suddenly, I found
myself all alone again.
What's the matter?
- Nothing. Nothing.
- Hey! You'll wake the baby.
- Angela.
Um...
We got to get out
of here for a while.
- What do you mean?
Who? You?
- Yeah.
Me.
And you.
And Renee. All of us.
- When?
- Tonight.
It's just for a little while.
- Tonight, huh?
You're crazy.
I'm not going anywhere tonight,
except back to bed.
Hopefully, with you.
- Angel.
I'm in trouble.
- What kind of trouble?
God damn it, talk to
me! What's going on?
- My boss...
I have...
I have to...
Gino
wants me to burn
down a building.
Mama's building.
- Oh.
Oh.
Great.
Daddy's a fire bug now!
You once promised me
you wanted to change.
Build a family, accept
some responsibility.
Johnny, when are you
finally gonna change?
- Tonight.
Tonight.
Angela.
It's just for a couple of days.
A couple of days, I can
straighten everything out.
Look, I've told you before,
I don't want any more
of this life of yours.
It stinks.
You come into my apartment,
our home,
dragging all kinds of shit
out of the gutters with you.
And you expect me to drop
everything like that?
Angie, you've got to trust me.
You know I wouldn't let anything
happen to you and the baby.
I love you too much.
And you love me too.
- Yeah?
Johnny, we're not
going with you.
I don't think you really know
what you're asking of me.
Yeah, I do.
I didn't plan it
this way, Angela.
- I know.
I guess I...
I guess I wanted you
to be someone else.
- Oh, yeah?
Who'd you want me to be?
The president?
I'm gonna be president.
President Johnny.
Want to live in the White House?
Want to do it on
the great lawn, huh?
I ain't never been anybody else.
Never.
I've always been
straight with you.
No lies, no
bullshit. No secrets.
Just me, Johnny.
Now you don't want me.
Maybe this is it.
Maybe this is the last chance
I get to be somebody else.
- Johnny, I love you.
But we're not going.
- I'll be back.
What's going on?
- Some junkie.
She OD'd in the bathroom.
- Tony still here?
- Yeah.
But he's busy.
Shit!
Look what you made me do.
- Yes.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, sure.
It'll be done.
Mm-hmm.
Some business just came up.
Uh-huh. You got it.
I'll get back to you
later, all right?
Okay. Bye.
- Tony, I'll just take my money,
then you can get
back to your, er...
- Listen, kid, you
should learn to knock.
- Tony, I ain't waiting no more.
Uh... Karen.
Karen, do me a favor.
Um...
Do me a favor, please.
- Mm-hmm.
- Pick up the shit.
And meet me in the bar in a
couple of minutes, all right?
I just have some
personal business
with this gentleman, okay?
Okay. Okay?
- Present for Karen?
- Tony, the money, all right?
- Lock the door,
will ya, Johnny boy?
- Come on, Tony, don't break
my balls, all right? Hurry up.
- Relax, relax. I'm counting it.
Motherfucker!
Shut up!
Ciao, Tony, you slithering fuck!
I was fucking set up, and
I saw it coming all night.
I When you're out of sight
There we go.
Get out. Out. Get out!
Out, come on.
Come on, out. Get away.
Get yourself some cheese.
Knock yourself out.
- Shit!
Oh, shit!
Motherfucker!
John...
- I'm gonna Kill you.
- Johnny, man.
Your mother and sister got out.
- You fucking rat!
You son of a bitch!
- Motherfucker!
- What the fuck are you doing?
Lippy...
- Gino put the word out,
man, the word is you're dead.
- Lippy,
I'm going away, for good.
- Good idea.
- For good.
I need a car, a truck,
anything that moves fast. Okay?
- You got it, brother.
- Bring it to my house, please.
Wait a second, wait a minute.
You never invited
me over for dinner.
18 Great Jones Street.
Hurry up, please.
- Go careful, brother, you
ain't so popular no more.
- Hey, brother,
I ain't dead yet.
Oh, shit.
Gino.
- Freeze!
- Goddamn!
Jesus Christ, Johnny, what
the fuck are you doing?
Damn!
Hey, sweetheart.
You could've hurt us.
- I thought they were here.
- Who?
Gino?
- Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Are you okay? God!
You look like hell.
What happened to you?
Oh, God! Johnny.
Let's get you washed up, okay?
Honey.
What's this?
- It's our future.
Go ahead, open it.
- Is this why we have
to get out of here?
Is this what they want?
- No.
They want me.
- Johnny, I'm scared.
For God's sake, let's
get out of here, now.
- Not yet.
My friend Lippy is
bringing a car, okay.
- You've got a car.
- No, no more.
We'll take a fucking
taxi, anything. Angela...
- Johnny, the baby.
- Go get her.
Angela, go get her.
Angie, we're going
out the back way.
- Why?
- Go! Back way.
Come on.
Hold on, hold on.
Go! Come on!
- Sal, you stay down
here with the elevators.
I'll take the stairs.
- Okay, chief.
- You got a key to this thing?
- Oh, God!
- Do ya?
- Yeah.
Get it, come on.
Here, I'll get it.
- Small key, Johnny, small key.
Come on, sweetie.
Johnny, what're we gonna do?
Hug the baby.
Fuck!
- Johnny!
Oh, God!
Johnny, Johnny,
we got to keep moving,
we got to keep moving.
- Where?
Oh, my God, Johnny!
Come on,
come on, go ahead!
Kill me, you fuck!
No more fun, capisce?
Come on!
Come on, you fuck!
What are you gonna do?
Oh, my God!
Chief!
Hey, come on, man.
- Get down, get down.
It's okay.
It's okay, it's over.
It's over.
It's over, okay?
- Let's get out of here.
Let's go.
I got her.
Gino.
- You going somewhere, John?
You know, I always
liked you, kid.
You come from the
streets, like me.
I tried to get you out of that
sewer, and you've ruined it.
Just you.
But you didn't do the
right thing, John.
- Hey, Gino, not my family.
Not them. Me.
Nobody walks away.
Nobody.
Not even you, John.
Lippy!
Lippy, you okay?
One hell of a ride.
- I love you, brother. Come on.
Gino, baby, you
got my mailing address?
Send me a postcard
from hell, man.
Al in a day's work.
Hey, Johnny.
What's up, man?
Let's go, Angie.
Peace, brother.
I When you're out of sight