Hi, Angel.
Hi.
- Rise is freaky.
- Jennifer!
Come here.
- Molly!
3:30.
Don't yell at me!
- I just...
- Now that's trash.
Well,
that's not my fault!
You're not the one studying.
Jennifer, come here!
Hey Sally, do you
wanna have lunch together?
Oh, so
I'm stuck with you,
there he goes!
- What's doing?
- Sh, don't say anything.
Your homework assignment
tonight, ah, ah, ah, please,
is to read and digest
the first act of "King Lear".
Mr. Shakespeare thanks
you and I thank you.
Um, Molly.
Yeah.
Hi, um, I was wondering, well,
I, I, I thought that maybe um,
oh, my name's Wayne.
I know.
Oh, you know.
Oh, well, I, I, I
thought maybe, um,
maybe you'd like to go
to a movie or something.
Thanks for asking, Wayne,
but my mom thinks I'm
too young to date.
Oh, okay, I understand.
Um, thanks anyway,
uh, maybe next time.
Maybe.
♪ You've got something sweet
♪ You've got what I need
- Would you like a picture?
Well, let me borrow your back.
Turn right around here.
Thank you very much.
Here we go, from the
original Kit Carson.
There you are, lady,
thank you so much.
Thank you.
♪ We can take it
♪ Whoa, whoa, yeah
♪ We can make it
♪ Can't you see
♪ You've got something that's
A little rock, a little
cradle, you like that?
This next trick I can
even do, here we go!
Walk the dog, it's what
you been waiting for.
♪ Come to you lady
Jesus Christ can save you,
save you here and now!
What you need in your life.
When was the last time
you got down on your knees
and thanked him?
♪ You and me
♪ We can make it can't you see
♪ You and me look
fancy tonight
♪ I'll make you feel so right
♪ We'll make you feel so right
Oh sweet tits!
Honey, can we talk?
I mean, come on up here and
play my mouth organ for me.
I don't like to play by myself.
Well what the hell's
the matter with you?
Ain't my dollars good
enough for ya, huh?
Well I'll tell you something,
if you just take a pimp
you can just take a piss on
one of those Hollywood stars.
I wouldn't diddle you
with your daddy's dick!
How much you want to spend?
About 20 bucks?
You have a good night.
Hey all's I wanted to
do was borrow it, not buy it.
Genuine peacemaker.
It's a gift from Tom Mix.
These are really nifty, Kit.
Great balance.
It's lucky for you you got
those fake bullets of yours
in there, or I'd
have to haul you in.
I know what I'm doing, deputy.
My pappy didn't raise
no turnip farmer.
Take care, cowboy.
- Goodnight boys.
- Good to see ya.
Goodnight.
Hey Dick, who's Tom Mix?
Well, sweet thing.
What's your name?
Angel.
Well, Angel.
I thought you and me could
have us a little party, huh?
I bet you would.
Look mister, I'm underage.
Or are you one of those perverts
that gets off on little girls?
We're a little
touchy, aren't we?
Look, why don't you just
drop me off on that corner?
I see a friend over there.
Look, I didn't do anything.
Thanks for the ride, officer.
What makes you think
I'm a cop, honey?
If you're not a cop, then
what are you doing with this?
Here, call the station.
Angel!
What, goddamn freaks!
Happening to this neighborhood?
I hate those, sweetheart,
don't let fatso go yet.
Why don't you go home now and
spank your monkey, numbnuts?
Sweetheart, I thought
they busted you.
I had porky made out the
minute I got in the car.
Good.
Didn't I
have the best teacher?
You better believe it!
Come on, let's get
another ice cream cone.
Ah keep going, here we go.
Wait.
This is your correct
address, both of you?
- Yeah.
- That's right.
Okay I'll give you
a break this time,
but don't let me catch you
working the boulevard again.
Thanks.
Hey.
Aha, lieutenant!
What do you say, Collins?
Looking good!
Hey it's good to
have you back, man.
See they're keeping
you busy, huh?
Yeah, you'd think with
a psycho on the loose
these girls would
stay off the streets.
Collins, nothing
stops the action.
If a tidal wave hit this street,
the hookers would bob up
like a bunch of corks.
You got that
right, lieutenant.
Guess you're investigating
the hooker murders, huh?
The way he chopped
up those girls?
This guy is one
sick son of a bitch.
What I can't understand is,
what makes that sleazebag tick?
Well?
Figure he was dumped by his
old man when he was a kid,
his mother probably
sexually abused him.
We know he's a necro, probably
bisexual, possibly impotent.
My guess is he
wants to get busted.
Whatever the case, pal,
he's out there somewhere
cruising this fuckin' boulevard.
Ooh, salt and pepper.
You operated that kid yet?
No, but I've seen
her around a lot.
She keeps her nose pretty clean.
You really know this area
pretty well, don't ya Collins?
Yeah, well I've worked
around here a lot of years.
How'd you like to get outta
those rags and help out?
Who me?
I thought you'd never ask!
Good.
Try to get rid of that.
I'll be back for it later.
Two blind lesbians
lost in a fish market.
That is crazy, get it?
Hey Crystal, you
know those stars
on the Hollywood Walk of Fame?
My dad installed a lot of 'em.
Sure he did.
No really, really.
He was a terrazzo stone artist.
When I was about
five, he took me
to the dedication ceremonies
and he propped me
up on his shoulders
so I could see all
the movie stars.
That was the best
time of my life.
Hey, you kids should've seen
Hollywood Boulevard
25 years ago.
Then it was a boulevard
something to see.
Now it's a toilet!
An ulcer, that bum is
gonna give me an ulcer!
How's your mama, Angel?
Oh she's much better
and she loved your soup.
So does that bum,
son of a bitch.
I don't know about you ladies,
but it's lean out there tonight.
It's the murders, Mae.
Even the johns are scared.
Why should the
johns be scared?
It's the hookers gettin' killed.
Ever see a man try to run away
with his pants wrapped
around his ankles?
I don't know about you girls,
I wanna get the hell
outta this town.
Go somewhere where
there's clean air,
where I can breathe.
I dunno, maybe Tahiti.
Tahiti, why Tahiti?
Because the men use
their dicks for oars.
Ooh.
Goddamn it, Mae.
Fay and Sherry aren't even
cold in their graves yet,
and you can't stop
with the jokes.
You ever hear anybody
whistle in the graveyard?
Don't tell me no money.
You call that more, man?
You sit out before,
and don't come back!
At least the hookers,
they got money, they pay!
- My dear.
- What?
Relax!
Puff on this, huh?
I never saw it to fail.
Give a man something to
suck on, and he's happy.
Come, off we go.
Come on, let's
go back to work.
Okay, let's go by
the theater this time.
Okay.
Give me some.
Here.
You know what it says here?
It's ridiculous.
- Hey.
- What?
I'm gonna go see Yoyo.
Okay, 'cause he's so cute.
Yeah I know.
I'll see ya.
I'll see ya tomorrow.
I have to study after this.
- Okay, bye-bye.
- Bye.
Mae West liked it.
I used to do it for her all
the time in her bedroom.
You like that?
Wait, wait, there's more.
Next show in a half an hour.
Thanks folks, your donations
will go to a worthy cause.
My survival!
Good show, Yoyo.
Thanks, Kit.
Goodnight.
You have a nice
evening, Crystal.
Thanks, Kit.
Goodnight.
Oh, hi Crystal.
Hi.
Boy you look great.
Thank you.
I was with Kit and we,
you look great.
You really look good, I mean it.
I mean I guess
I look great huh?
So how's,
so how's business?
It's kinda like you, Yoyo.
Up and down.
Oh.
Get it?
Yeah.
Oh wait, let me show
you this new trick.
Okay.
Let me show you this.
Hold out your hand.
Like this?
Oh, that's beautiful!
It's yours.
- Thanks, Yoyo.
- You're welcome.
Maybe I'll see ya after work?
You can bet your top on it.
Bye.
Ooh, just what I like.
Nice and strong.
Come on.
We're gonna have us
a real nice time.
I bet you can't guess
what I do in the daytime.
I go to school.
I'm studying to
be an accountant.
I got straight As
on my report card.
Oh, this is the place.
It's right over here,
it's number four.
Hey you know, I'm
into astrology.
I bet I could do your sign.
He's out like a light.
Hey you think
we should untie him?
That was the
easiest hundred I ever made.
Whoops, I forgot
my panties, girl.
Don't bother, the old
buzzard probably ate 'em.
Hey, you know I thought
he was dead at first?
We woke up lucky.
Shh.
Now this here is
called a tombstone twirl.
Yes sir, learned that
trick from Tom Mix.
Used to double 'em in
all of his pictures.
Matter of fact, I worked with
most of the old western stars.
Let's see there was Ken Maynard,
there was Buck Jones,
there was William...
Okay, I gotta a .45 finger
in your back, partner.
One false move,
and you're a goner.
Why you slippery
little sidewinder,
you went and snuck
up on me again.
I should've known
it was you two.
Here you go, sonny.
Hang that on the
wall and tell 'em
you got it from Kit
Carson in person.
Now.
- Damn pygmies.
What are you
doing out so late?
It's past midnight and it's
time for you to be home in bed.
Well, I was heading
that way now, partner.
You ladies mind
if I escort you?
Thank you.
Say, Angel.
- What?
Did I ever tell you
about the time your pappy and me
got thrown out of
the Brown Derby?
Yeah, but tell me again.
I like that one.
Or was it Musso and Frank's?
I'll tell you, when you've
been around as long as I have,
the old memory begins to dim
like a campfire at sunrise.
I'll tell you, we tipped
a few, your pappy and me.
I bet.
I miss him.
So do I.
Goodnight, Kit.
Goodnight, Angel.
- Come on, Mae.
- Come on.
Oh Angel.
Get yourself a good
night's sleep, you hear?
I will.
- Night ladies.
- Goodnight.
How about a little
drink, my dear?
Say a glass of 100
proof milk, huh?
Hey!
Girls!
Come here!
Bring out the spray, my dear.
I hear a cockroach.
Shall we investigate?
Oh, she's painting
by numbers again.
I wanna show you my
latest masterpiece.
I call it fruit with gun.
I call it shit.
What do you know
about it, fagele?
You don't even wear
the right clothes.
The hell are
you talking about?
This dress cost
me over 600 bucks.
Hey Solly, where'd
you get the cannon?
What are you crazy?
This is no toy, dear!
And for your information,
I bought it today.
Why, bear season
isn't even open yet.
This psycho killer shows,
I'm gonna blow his
fuckin' head off.
Hey, you wanna play a game?
Why not?
I'll break out the board.
Oh hey, I gotta go study.
It's getting late, Mae.
Goodnight.
Goodnight honey.
- Goodnight Solly.
- Goodnight darling.
Sweet dreams.
- Thanks.
Have you noticed our
little Molly is growing up?
I've noticed that
you've noticed.
Now you keep your hands off her.
Listen, why don't you take
that thing out of your pants
before you blow your balls off?
All eight of them.
Who is it?
Solly!
Just wait a second, Solly.
I'll be right there.
Morning, darling.
Good morning, come on in.
It's rent time.
Oh gee, I almost forgot.
I was just serving
breakfast to my mom.
I'll have her write you a check.
I'll be right back.
Here you go, Solly.
Oh, thank you darling.
My mom says to say hello.
And how is your mother?
She's improving.
- Receipt.
- Oh great.
I gotta go dump the garbage.
Have a good day.
- Later darling.
- Bye.
Northup, Northup, rah rah rah!
Five, six, seven, eight!
V-V-V-I-C!
T-T-O-R-Y!
Victory, victory
for Northup High!
Hey, look who's coming.
You're always bragging
about all your scoring.
Here's one you
haven't even touched.
Oh ye of little faith.
Center the fuckin' ball, man.
All right, Rick, on three.
Set, two, three!
Touchdown.
Come on baby, no applause?
Look, I hear you're really smart,
and I was wondering if you
could help me with my homework.
Then I'll give you something
you can really applaud.
Gee Rick, I'd really
like to help you.
But I have better things to do.
Woo, Romeo!
Romeo Ricky!
Miss Allen?
Molly, is that you?
Yeah.
Oh I'll be right with you.
Just get this apron off before
I get covered with paint.
You are looking terrific!
How's it going?
- Good, good.
- Good.
You wanted to see me?
Yes, why don't you
have a seat right there?
Is there
something wrong, Miss Allen?
No, not a thing!
I just thought it'd be
nice to have a little chat.
What do you say?
- Okay.
- Great.
Well, you know Molly,
I'm just a little
curious about something.
I see here that
you're not taking part
in any of the social
activities at school,
and I was just wondering,
are you having difficulty
making friends?
No, not at all Miss Allen.
Well Molly, your parents are
paying a great deal of money
to see that you have
the very best education.
Well I don't understand.
I'm on top of the honors list.
There's more to life
than getting straight As.
That means excelling
outside of the classroom
as well as inside,
you understand?
Yes.
It's my mother.
She's had a stroke,
and she's paralyzed.
Oh, Molly, I didn't know.
I'm so sorry.
So you see, I don't have time
for school stuff
or clubs and stuff.
I have to go home right after
school and take care of her.
I understand.
Will you do me a favor?
If you ever have need to talk,
or I can help in any way,
would you call me
at that number?
Okay.
Promise?
Promise.
Okay.
Thank you Miss
Allen, I appreciate it.
Okay.
1247, 1247 meeting
the officer at 77 station.
1247, 1247 meet
933 clear.
I was supposed
to meet her today,
and when she didn't come by I...
How long did you know her?
Not very long,
she was new in town.
How can anybody do
a thing like this?
Can you prove where you
were yesterday evening?
Yes sir.
Okay.
What's that you've
got there, son?
Who is it?
It's me.
Hi Mae.
What's wrong?
Oh, baby.
It's Crystal.
What's wrong with Crystal?
Did you take a look in there?
It looked like a slaughterhouse!
There's blood everywhere!
There was blood on the
walls, on the ceiling,
the rug was sticky with it.
It looked like
Custer's last stand
without the fuckin' Indians!
Folks, would you
settle down please?
Hey, hold it!
What's the problem?
Three of our friends are dead!
That's the problem, now what
are you gonna do about it?
We're gonna do
the best we can.
That's not good
enough, obviously.
You catch this son
of a bitch, lieutenant!
Excuse me, ladies, and
we'll hang the bastard!
We're bringing in more men
and putting out extra patrols.
The rest is up to you.
I mean you ladies of the night.
Be careful on the
street, watch yourself.
Work in pairs if you can,
and for Christ's sakes,
stick to regulars.
Are you nuts?
What do you know
about our business?
No matter how insignificant
or trivial it appears,
it could be important.
Please phone.
Take it.
Thank you
fearless fa's dick.
I had a john that
has a travel agency.
He told me that if we go
to Tahiti in December,
you get 20% off.
Tahiti in December?
Bitchin!
You know what else is
that if we go as family?
Yeah.
Which is sisters, right?
We get 50% off.
Oh wow.
Hey look, I got some
brochures, check it out.
It is so pretty,
I gotta tell ya.
Look in these
brochures are great.
When you said Tahiti I went...
I think I see our down
payment, I'll see you later.
What are you waiting for, honey?
Why didn't you take
your clothes off?
All right, you clean off the
tables, you set up the chairs,
and then you get
your ass out of here.
Yes sir, I'll do it right now.
Ah, uh-huh.
Thank you, thank you.
Excuse me, miss.
You were recommended to me.
Wanna take a little break?
Would you be interested?
- Why not?
A girlfriend and I
share this room, here.
Come on Lana, time's up.
What's the matter, can't
you talk with your mouth full?
Let us in, we'll have a
little menage a twat, huh?
I think we'd better do this
another time, definitely.
Hey hold it!
You're not going anywhere, cunt.
Let go of my arm!
Okay.
Maybe this'll put a little
smile on your face, hm?
You better be 14, baby,
or I'm gonna throw you
back in for being too old.
Now use your goddamn key.
Why don't you go
get cleaned up first?
All right, baby.
But you pour yourself
into that bed,
'cause I'll be right out.
What's wrong?
Help me.
Look at it, Angel.
There must be something
else you remember.
Would you leave me alone?
I told you all I know.
It was dark, I
couldn't see that well.
What about his voice,
his speech pattern,
something he said?
He was across the street.
Is there
anything else you can tell us?
Yeah, he killed Lana,
I can tell you that.
Get this xeroxed,
put out an APB.
You got a pimp?
You think I'm stupid?
Stupid?
Why would I think that?
Hell, you've got
everything going for you.
You're young,
attractive, healthy,
and you're swimming
around in a toilet bowl.
It's my life!
The hell it is.
You think you're out
there by yourself?
I'm on that street
too, goddamnit
and every time I see a kid
like you turning a trick,
I wanna blow up the
whole goddamn strip.
Leave me alone,
you're not my father!
You have no right to judge me.
You don't even know
anything about me!
How old are you?
15, 16?
You know what happens
to used up whores?
They don't go to
Leisure World, baby.
They end up on
hard shit or booze,
and spend half their
time in the slammer
and that's just
where you're headed.
You're living in a
dream world, baby.
What you need is a good,
swift kick in the butt.
You think I'm proud
of what I'm doing?
I hate it, bunch
of fat old slobs
drooling and
slobbering all over me?
Sometimes I get so
disgusted with myself
I just think I wanna throw up!
Then why do you do it?
I have my reasons, and
believe me I have no intention
of doing this the
rest of my life!
What do you think
this is, a game?
You think you get
away Scott free?
Everything in life has
a price on it, Angel.
Whatever you do,
you pay the price.
Somewhere down the line,
you're gonna have to pay.
Then I'll pay!
Then there
was the Durango Kid.
His real name was Charles Derek.
Remember Sunset Carson?
♪ I'm gonna let it shine
♪ Let it shine, let it shine
♪ Let it shine
♪ This little light of mine
Toughest star I
ever worked with
was Franklin Fineham
in Rough Gulch.
Then there was that time
I broke a leg in a movie stage.
The Duke himself signed my cast.
He was a tough one,
did his own stunts.
Well folks, I could
go on all night,
but it's getting late.
I think I saw that
on television last week.
That was a good movie, too.
The Indians came around,
and they had a stagecoach...
Lana's dead, Mae.
I know, baby, I know.
Come on, come on, let's go home.
Come on, baby.
You too, Kit.
♪ A band of angels
♪ Coming for to carry me home
And I'm telling you, I ain't
going to no retirement home.
Oh I love it.
Will you please put that
cap pistol away, Mr. Cornwall?
Carson!
The name is Carson, Kit Carson!
Hey hey, what's going on here?
Old baldy here is the
executor to Kit's estate.
He wants to put sweet little
old Kit here in one of those
creepy retirement homes.
That'd mean I'd never be able
to walk the boulevard
again, Angel.
You can't force him
to do that, can ya?
You're damn right he can't.
No, I don't think so.
You better let him go, Kit.
Thank you.
If you can't force him,
let's just leave him be.
Young lady, I have been
a lawyer for 25 years.
Listen, schmucko.
You heard what the
young lady said.
Now get your ass
outta here, okay?
Hey cheapo, I get
five bucks for that.
Come sit, sweetie.
Well, when I get ready
to be put out to pasture,
I know exactly where I'm going.
Arizona, well hell all of
my friends are out there.
I'll get to see Tom Mix again.
Kit, Tom Mix is dead.
Oh that's right, I
plum forgot about that.
Well hell, then I'll
see Hoot Gibson.
I think Hoot
Gibson's dead too.
Damn it.
There ain't hardly any
of us left anymore.
Look, I'm really
glad I found you two,
because I was just on
my way to the morgue.
For Lana!
Do you have any idea what
they do to unclaimed bodies?
No, I don't reckon I do.
Oh, well I don't either,
but whatever it is
it can't be good.
Well we'd better
get over there,
before she ends up in a
tomb for the unknown hooker.
You had no business
being at the morgue.
What the hell did you
expect to accomplish?
We've got a right
to claim the body.
We're the only family she have.
I can appreciate that, Angel,
but I don't make the rules.
You mean to say there
ain't no exceptions?
Look, there's nothing I can
do about it, it's the law.
Then the law sucks.
You people have
got Lana in an icebox
while you sit on your...
She needs to be buried,
but you don't give a damn.
You've got no feelings inside!
It's because you're
nothing but a damn cop!
Come on Mae, Kit,
let's get outta here.
Remind me never
to get murdered.
Ooh, strong aren't you?
I bet you're wild
in the sack, huh?
Rick, I'm gonna be
late for gym class.
Oh come on, you don't know
what you're missing, Molly.
I mean why do you think
they call me Razzle Dazzle?
Oh, my hand!
You bitch!
We are gonna have
so much fun you guys.
We're gonna have the
best game in the world.
Okay, we've got
the victory song,
we've got the
Northup rah rah rah.
We'll do the fight song,
and it will just be so much fun,
so you guys really liven up
and have a great time with it.
Stephanie, hurry up!
Hi Molly.
Hi there.
Wait up!
Diane!
Diane?
Hey scumbag, get your
dirty boots off the seat.
This ain't your fucking office.
Get the fuck outta here.
What he hell...
♪ You've got something sweet
♪ You've got what I need
♪ Come to me
Yes, inside, yes.
Damn right I saw him.
He's got a spur on his boot.
He's sitting right over here.
Shit, well goddamn it
the sleaze bag was here
not more than 10 minutes ago.
There he is!
- You, hold it right there.
Freeze!
Gentlemen, turn
to your left please.
Would you face front?
Angel?
I don't know, I'm not sure.
He could be the second
one from the left.
Could be is not enough, Angel.
I gotta have more than that.
I only took one look at him,
and it was dark, I'm sorry.
I just got...
I can't swear by it.
Thanks
for your help, gentlemen.
You can take the men back.
Lieutenant, the
rookie with the coffee.
His weapon's in his holster.
Will the officer
holding the refreshments
please exit the
room immediately?
On the double.
I repeat...
- That's him, that's him!
The guy at the booth!
Sir, do you see
anything over there?
Check the alley
on the other side.
Get the chopper and
cordon the area.
Right.
He went over the
wall, lieutenant.
We found the girl
unconscious between the cars.
She's alive.
- Collins, we need you.
- Right there.
Shit!
All
units, shots fired.
Hostile situation,
officer detail.
Don't worry about
it, we'll get him.
Come on.
Shit.
Really blew that.
Have to pack it in.
Second time I had a scene
like that in 15 years.
What happened the first time?
Come on, I'll take you in.
Thanks a lot,
Lieutenant Andrews.
I know, I won't leave town
without notifying you.
Isn't that the way it goes?
Very good.
I want to meet your mother.
What, what no!
Wait a minute, there's a
law against illegal entry!
Hey, this is really great!
Why don't you go out
and catch that killer?
You're not gonna
find him in here.
I'm curious about
something, Angel.
Or is it Molly?
That's your name, isn't it?
Molly Stewart?
Tell me something, Molly.
Why does 15 year old
straight A honor student
who doesn't drink,
doesn't take drugs,
never been arrested, and
lives at home with her parents
work as a street prostitute, hm?
You've been to my
school, haven't you?
Yeah,
it's a good school.
They think a lot of you.
Yeah well I don't like people
butting into my business.
You work the street,
you're fair game kiddo.
Where's your mother?
I want to speak to her.
She doesn't want
to speak with you!
She doesn't like cops either!
In there huh?
Mrs. Stewart, my
name is Andrews.
I'm with the police.
I'd like to speak with you.
Mrs. Stewart?
Get away from there,
you son of a bitch!
Haven't you ever heard
of the Fourth Amendment?
You mean the
right of the people
to be secure in
their persons against
unreasonable search and
seizure shall not be violated?
Yes, I've heard of it.
Pardon me.
Pretty, nice.
I like the color.
Your dad?
How long has he been gone?
Nine years.
Where's your mom, Angel?
Molly.
Please try to forgive me.
I found somebody.
He's taking me to New York.
Don't think I'll be back.
Take care of yourself,
I'm sorry, Mom.
Knowing her she probably
got dumped in Cleveland.
It happened about
three years ago.
One day I came home from
school, and she was gone.
Just that note and a hundred dollar bill.
You've been on the
streets since you were 12?
It was easy.
I just put on some sexy
clothes and high heels
and went out and made a living.
Jesus Christ.
You still don't
understand, do ya Andrews?
I was alone, I'm a minor!
They'd throw my
ass in some court,
and then it'd be foster
homes from then on.
I am not gonna be put
in some foster home,
or some institution, or
somebody else's home.
I am gonna stay right here
until my father
comes back for me.
Until your father comes back?
Yes damn it, until
my father comes back.
What
makes you think
he's coming back
after nine years?
My father will.
I know he will.
So what are you gonna
do now, lieutenant?
I know what I should do.
I should turn you over to
the juvenile authorities,
let them take care of ya.
So why don't you?
I don't know.
Stay home, keep the door locked.
For Christ's sake, stay away
from the goddamn street.
I've already made
up my mind, Mae.
I'm against it.
Dead set against it.
Somebody could get
hurt, honey, you.
You weren't there,
you didn't see
the way that guy looked at me.
I'm not letting
that freak get to me
like he did Crystal and Lana.
I don't know about
you, but I'm hungry.
Hungry?
How could you eat
at a time like this?
Watch.
Whatever you got in that
box would make me throw up.
Oh.
Welcome to my home, ma'am.
Wow!
This is really cool.
It's great!
This is where you live?
- Yep.
What's this?
Best of luck, Kit.
Keep them shooting
irons of yourn hot,
especially the
one in your pants.
Regards, Tom Mix.
Tom Mix, you really
did know him!
Well you don't
think I'd josh you
about a thing like that, do ya?
Well, I'm gonna give you a
shooting iron lesson, little lady,
and I want you to
listen real good,
'cause there ain't
nothing to it.
First of all, you
don't aim at all.
You pretend the
barrel is your finger,
and you point it
and you shoot it
just like you did
when you was a kid.
Well that was the pretend part.
Now this here is the real part.
I thought those were toys!
What in tarnation would
I be doing with toys?
These have got the firing pins
in them, and real bullets.
Now, these here are the bullets
I use out on the street,
and they're fake.
Oh.
Now, let me see that
peashooter of yours.
Good god almighty.
Lookin' good!
Woohoo,
look at those legs!
All aboard beaver junction!
I don't fuckin' believe it.
Do you know who that was?
That was Molly Stewart!
She's a hooker.
No shit!
Let's pick her up.
Hey mama, I got
what you're looking for.
♪ Don't you agree
♪ Sweet
- Come on Molly.
- Come on, hurry up!
- Let's go Rick!
- Come on!
- Go go, go go!
- Wahoo!
Look Rick, you've
had your fun.
Now please let me go.
Oh you know, you're really
one hell of an actress.
You had us all fooled.
So sweet, so innocent.
Oh come on, Molly, show
us your whisker biscuit.
Listen you guys, if you
know what's good for you,
you'll let me go right now.
Oh no, no, no!
We're gonna teach you a
new meaning of gang bang.
Please, wait, wait you
don't have to force me.
I'll do anything you want!
Look, I just don't
wanna get pregnant.
Tough shit, bitch.
'Cause we don't use rubbers.
Please, I've got some
right here in my purse.
Hey Rick, maybe we should.
No telling what we might
catch from this slut.
Okay.
I always keep them with me.
Ah!
Go ahead, make your move,
but I'll blow his
fucking brains out.
Rick, don't anybody move!
Rick.
Okay you bastards,
now get out of the car.
Get out of the goddamn car!
Let's get out, Rick.
She's bluffing.
Oh yeah?
Don't shoot, don't shoot!
Please please don't shoot me!
- Hey!
- Don't shoot, don't shoot!
Hey.
Look me up again, Rick.
When you're toilet trained.
Sarah listen, did
you hear about Molly Stewart?
No, what?
Rick Sawyer
said she made it
with all three of them.
Oh god, that's gross!
Wait listen,
that's not all.
He said, and I swear
to god, she's a whore!
Oh no!
Yeah, and she's
hooking on Hollywood Boulevard.
Oh shit.
Oh gee, I really liked her.
Yeah.
Miss Allen, I'm telling
you what I saw is the truth!
This is ridiculous.
I know this girl very, very well
and what you're saying
is absolutely impossible!
Miss Allen, the
girl is a prostitute
on Hollywood Boulevard.
This is ridiculous.
Molly, Molly.
What is it Wayne?
I just wanted to ask you out.
I told you, my mother
won't let me out.
No, no, no, look.
I've been saving this, it's $23.
It's all I've got.
Will it be enough?
Molly?
I used to love
going to school.
You know I used to pretend
that I was just
like everybody else.
Now they all know the truth.
You know, I've had sex
with hundreds of men,
but I've never had anybody
that loved me, or held me.
I mean not anybody that
I wanted to be with.
I've never even had a boyfriend.
You know, I wake
up every morning
and I think this is the
last day I have to do this.
Today my dad's gonna come home.
You still believe that?
Nah.
Not anymore.
You know Angel, sometimes
a guy meets a woman
and he sees a new
life for himself,
so he splits, cuts his
ties with whatever he had.
Time goes by and comes a point when
where he can't come
back, no matter what.
It's not 'cause he
doesn't love you.
Then all I've done has
been a waste, hasn't it?
Nothing's a waste, kid.
Nothing.
I feel so ashamed.
Easy, kid.
Easy.
What have you
done to your hair?
Looks like an orangutan has been
sitting on your face all night.
Good, good, good.
Whee, oh.
Mhmm.
Grab it.
A queen, how sweet.
Listen, kumquat.
I don't mind the smoke, but
your breath is behind it.
Don't you ever inhale that?
God.
What was that?
What?
This, you took
this little thing
and moved it from here to here.
Now that's not nice.
It's called cheating, okay?
How fuckin' dare you?
How fuckin' dare you, ya cunt?
I don't have to cheat to
beat the likes of you!
You're not
playing with blind Amy,
I saw you move the goddamn peg.
You're hallucinating!
I'm gonna bite your
goddamn falsies off,
now play this game here.
You're stalling!
You owe me $147, see that?
I owe you shit.
Screw you, Lulu Bell!
When I was a kid,
my father warned me.
He said Rachel, don't ever
play cards with a Jewish dyke.
They cheat!
Eat my puff, will ya?
Puff?
Hello.
One moment.
Look, unless you have
an instant replay
and you can prove on that
last move that I cheated,
you will continue
this goddamn game!
I don't need a camera, I
have eyes, you cheat, cheat!
Hello?
Hold onto your jack jack!
Now listen, freeze
everything there.
I know where every peg is!
I'll be right back.
What do you want?
You have a Margaret
Stewart here?
I'd like to see her,
if you don't mind.
Molly Stewart is her daughter.
I'm her counselor at
school, Patricia Allen.
Yeah well now that
woman's an invalid.
She don't see nobody.
Yes, I understand but would
you ring her for me please?
I'd like to find
that out for myself.
Ring her?
What do you think
this is, a Biltmore?
You gotta wait 'til Molly
gets home from school.
I don't gotta do anything.
Now I would really like
to speak to Mrs. Stewart.
What room is she in please?
Look, Miss Hoighty toighty.
The woman cannot
answer the goddamn door
'cause she can't get
out of her goddamn bed.
Is that goddamn
clear enough for ya?
Well, if you give me the key
then we won't have to
inconvenience the woman now,
will we?
You don't seem to
understand, lady.
I can't just give someone the
key to someone's apartment.
Listen, fuckface.
I used to work for the
city health department
and you got so many
violations in this flea trap
that one phone call downtown
will put your ass
in court so fast
that you won't have
time to wipe it,
let alone pull your pants
up, do you get my drift?
Now you give me the goddamn key.
Thank you, very much.
Teh, the fuckin'
mouth on that broad.
Oh.
Hi, honey.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
I didn't mean to disturb you.
I was looking for Mrs. Stewart.
I'll just check on...
Oh no, no, no, no.
I am Mrs. Stewart,
please come in.
This is the right
apartment, lovely.
Now, I know what
you're thinking.
All this talk about me
being an invalid, you know?
Well, sometimes I am an
invalid and sometimes I'm not.
It just comes and goes,
and now it's all gone
so won't you join
me in sitting down
and a little
conversation please?
Thank you.
Yes, the girls and I,
I give a course on needlepoint
and sometimes they
get a little messy.
I must talk to the girls.
Now, what shall we talk about?
Look I don't know
whose mother you are,
but you are definitely
not Molly's.
I'm not?
No.
You're right.
But I love her.
More than her mother ever did.
What the hell?
Shit.
We gotta get her
off the streets.
We've gotta find her a home.
And soon.
Now Mae, you know how
much I care for Molly
and I will do anything
I can to help.
You keep me posted, all right?
Okay.
Hey, let me help you out.
Oh, by the way,
what's your real name?
Marvin.
Marvin Walker.
Oh, well it has been a
pleasure meeting you, Marvin.
Thank you.
I meant to ask you,
that dress, Saks?
I. Magnin's.
Oh, stunning.
Thank you.
I got it on sale.
Who dyed your hair, dickface?
Hey, hey now wait a minute now.
You got me all wrong.
I'm not a, I'm not
a girl, I'm a guy.
See this?
Look at all this
hair like this, huh?
Look, look.
Phony tits.
You like impressions?
I do a great Eddie Cantor,
how do you like this?
♪ You knew Susie
like I know Susie
Huh, ah before your
time of course.
Rock music, that's
your bag isn't it?
Listen to this, ah!
Oh!
My hair, my hair!
My luck I gotta get a
bald head in fighting.
About your breath,
ew that stinks.
Fuck with me!
Bitch!
Please!
Oh my god.
Mae?
Darling.
Oh no.
Just my luck.
Last thing I'm gonna see in
this world is your ugly face.
Christ.
Oh what are you doing?
Dying, goddamnit, I'm dying.
Geez.
You can't die, you owe
me $147 you fuckin' faggot.
Solly?
What darling?
I don't want Angel to
see me like this, okay?
Promise?
Yes I promise,
you gorgeous broad.
Thanks, baby.
Oh Jesus.
Mae.
Darling?
Mae?
Sweetheart?
Don't go, darling, sweetie.
You gorgeous broad.
You don't wanna go in there.
You don't wanna go in there!
In the bedroom, officer.
Believe me, you don't
wanna see it, honey?
Just stay here.
You stay right here.
Answer is 257.
Angel!
Angel, Angel!
Officer?
Officer!
Need a full team
here right away.
Officer, she's got my gun!
Kit, Angel, you seen her?
Oh no I haven't.
She's on the street
and she's got a gun.
Good lord, allmight.
All right you take that
side, I'll go this way.
All right.
Hey!
Angel look out!
Angel, hey, Angel!
Out of my trunk, asshole!
Get outta the way!
Hold it!
Oh shit!
Kit, you okay?
Help Angel.
Angel get back,
leave him to me!
Listen to me, kid.
Angel.
It hurts.
♪ You've got something sweet
♪ You've got what I need
♪ Come to me
♪ Can't you see
♪ You'll agree
♪ We can make it you and me
♪ We can make it
yes you'll see
♪ You've got something nice
♪ And you'll do something
right right right right
♪ Come to me
♪ Can't you see
♪ Don't you agree
♪ We can make it you and me
♪ We can make it
yes you'll see
♪ You make me feel so right
♪ I'll make you feel so right
♪ You'll make it feel so right
♪ Tonight
♪ You've got something sweet
♪ And you've got what
I need need need need
♪ Come to me
♪ Can't you see
♪ Don't you agree
♪ We can make it you and me
♪ We can make it
yes you'll see
♪ Sweet