Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Beat, Beat, Beat Street
You got to believe in something
You got to believe in someone
You got to have that special something
makes you want to meet the morning sun
'Cause there's people laughing
and people crying
There's people giving up
and people trying
There's people living
and people dying
Nobody seems to know the reason why
It's like a heartbeat
Beat Street
I'm talkin' about Beat Street
No one said it'd be easy
And people never treat you like they should
You got to get out and go for yourself
But you knew that you always would
It's like a heartbeat
Beat Street
Kenny, let me go with you.
All right.
Fresh.
Ramo, when will you teach me that style?
Practice up on it.
I like you, man.
- I'm going with you.
- Check it out.
Cotton-Field Chants and Hollers. Very fresh.
- Why can't I go with you, Kenny?
- Do your homework.
Man, you're crazy.
If I take you, I got to bring you back,
and maybe I don't want to come right back.
Maybe I'll meet a female. Come on, let's go.
About time.
Meet a female.
That's bullshit...
'cause you ain't going nowhere
till you bring your records home.
Yo, Mom.
- Where are you going?
- Off to work, Mrs. Kirkland.
It's party night.
- Which is it?
- It's both.
Well, you boys be careful.
- See you later, Momski.
- Kenny, don't get in too late.
Lee, where do you think you're going?
You get in there and do your homework.
- Y'all haven't seen the last of me yet.
- Lee!
Check it out. Fresh. I could use this sound.
It's cold, man. Let's get.
Luis!
Hi.
How about checking out that train
we bombed yesterday?
Jackpot! Come on, fellas!
Slow down.
Merry Christmas, New York.
- Check it out, man.
- "Island paradise."
That's fresh, man.
Get good pictures, I need them for my kid.
- You got it in focus?
- I know what I'm doing.
Ramon, my man, that is bad.
Right! That's the word! Man, that's def!
- That's it, kid.
- Fresh, Ramon!
- King of the line.
- All right.
You see that? That is your baddest burner.
That is my favorite.
It's all right.
- Heads up!
- Yo, Chollie.
What's up, Tony? What's going on?
- Yo, Tony!
- Kenny.
- Make it snappy, we're running behind.
- Right, let's go.
- Yeah.
- Come on.
- Let's go, Double K.
- Yo, Kong. How's it going?
King Kong. Angie.
It's about time.
Sorry, we had business to take care of.
But we're here now, all right?
Everything under control, baby?
Yo, Pop, how you doing?
All right, go!
Testing, one, two, three.
It's working
Party people, if you're ready to rock
Let me hear you scream
If you really, really came to party
Then let me hear everybody
Say, "We came to party!"
We came to party!
Everybody put your hands together like this
Come on, clap
Let me hear you clap, everybody clap
Now here's a funky beat
Now here's a scratch beat
Put it all together and make it complete
Break, break, break
Play that beat
Why don't you play it for me?
Play it, kick it, play that beat
Play it, kick it
Yo, bust it, bust it.
Why don't you break, man?
Why don't you break for us?
Come on, now!
Come on, baby, get down!
Beat this
All right!
Kenny, there goes Sha-Rock,
Lisa Lee and Debbie D.
Go get their record.
Well, here are three ladies
from our neighborhood
Guaranteed to rock the beat
and rock the beat good
So come on,
Debbie D, Sha-Rock and Lisa Lee
Step up to the front
so all your friends can see
We're all backing you up 100 percent
We know you practiced all week
Now this is it
If you're in favor of what I've said
Everybody say, "Go ahead!"
Go ahead!
Us girls
can boogie, too
We can dance, we can shake it
'Cause us girls
can boogie, too
So come on, girls, let's go break it
Let's go break it
Us girls are the best of friends
If one ain't got no money,
the other one lends
When we go out, we know we look real hot
What the boys want, you know we got
The fly girl Debbie D
Needs someone who can hold my policy
So fellas, move on close
Take me on a cruise and watch me float
Wine and dine my mind, show me I'm fresh
and I'll always let you know Debbie D is best
Sha-Rock's the woman
with the magical touch
I'm like burning fire,
you know I'm just too much
Treat you like a king
In the heat of the night
Romance to the moon if your timing is right
Get your back wet, all soaked in sweat
He says I'm the kind of girl
that he can never forget
Sophisticated is the lady Lisa Lee
To be the man in my life,
you got to be my only
I'll always hold ya secure
In my arms real tight
Squeeze you real good
till you feel just right
Have a heart of gold
I want to share with you
Give you the type of loving
you never been through
And if you dig where we're comin' from
say, "Yeah!"
Yeah!
And if you want to rock this party tonight
say, "Yeah!"
Yeah!
Us, us, us
'Cause us girls
can boogie, too
We can dance, we can shake it
'Cause us girls
can boogie, too
So come on, girls, let's go break it
Us girls can boogie, too
We can dance, we can shake it
'Cause us girls
can boogie, too
So come on, girls, let's go break it
Chollie.
Do you hear that?
Yeah, man.
It's weird.
What the hell is that?
It's weird, man.
It's spooky.
It's coming from in there.
Tito?
- Tito who?
- Tito Reyes.
What the hell are you doing down here?
I'm looking for him, all right?
He's about this high, plays congas.
I was in the army with him.
- You're looking for him in the basement?
- Este esta loco. Let's get out of here.
No, wait.
This is the address, right?
- Sure. Malo's big brother.
- Yeah, but they dipped out a long time ago.
- After the fire.
- What fire? Tito was in a fire?
Tito wasn't in a fire. The building was.
Landlord torched this building
about five times.
Damn.
I've thought about him for almost a year.
Man, he could play them conga drums, too.
We were supposed to get up a band.
It's been my dream to play in a band
in New York.
This ain't New York, this is the Bronx.
Come on, K, let's get back to business.
- Could you give me something to eat?
- You got any cash?
Come on.
What's up?
You're biters. All your homeboys are biters.
- You're all wack. What's up with that?
- What are you talking about?
I never stole moves from you.
Your moves ain't worth it to be bit.
What's up with that, punk?
Punk? Who you calling punk?
That's biting.
Later. Roxy?
- Don't flake.
- Be there.
- Damn Spit! Writes his name on everything.
- Ramo, what you doing?
Lousy bastard, Spit!
That was Luis' best burner.
It's only been running three days.
- Ramo, later for that.
- Come on.
Get on the train.
Good morning.
Ramo's making us
the baddest sweatshirts. Word.
You know the kind that turn inside out?
One side's gonna say "Beat Street"
and our name.
The other side will have curvy lines.
And when I do my backspin...
it'll be the baddest, man. Incredible.
Kenny, why don't you just move that cereal
and lay your whole body across the table?
I thought we'd stopped
dancing on the sidewalk for pennies.
But, Mom. We made $46 last time.
The money is not the issue, Lee.
Sit up, Kenny.
What time did you get in last night?
About midnight.
I'm glad you're still telling me the truth.
Now eat.
What's the big deal about eating oatmeal...
when all I feel is tired for real?
Is my rap too slick, my tongue too quick
my gallant talent like a magic trick?
Eat your eggs before I break your legs.
Now you know where your
gallant talent came from.
Open the door, Lee.
Open the door.
Who goes there?
Chollie, brother.
Who goes there, little brother?
You know I don't want you out so late.
When you do it, Lee does it, too.
Then I've got the both of you
to worry about.
I've already lost one son out there.
There he is, Double K. How you doing?
- How are you, Mrs. Kirkland?
- Good morning, Chollie.
You want this toast, man?
Tomorrow, we're loose.
And I got a rocket in my pocket.
Comps to the Roxy.
I'm talking major leagues.
How did you do that?
Just a little business.
If you're going to be a superstar
you have to check out the style.
I've got my own style.
Yeah, but you just need some
of them professional touches.
Chollie, superstar is not a profession.
You can keep your dreams, gentlemen.
But get something to fall back on.
We got to get going.
Yo, Kenny. Yo, Chollie.
What's happening, Lee?
Yo, Chollie. Watch this.
You better practice up.
When we get to the Roxy tonight,
Beat Street breakers are gonna kick ass.
I don't know, little brother.
The Bronx Rockers are tough.
Yo, Ramon, let's go, my man.
Goddamn.
What are you doing? Stop!
Please, don't do this to me. Stop.
Man, I would not put up with that shit.
What are you, crazy?
- You're beautiful.
- Yeah, I'm beautiful.
Fuck him!
He's just helping you stir the paint, brother.
"When are you going to stop
writing on the walls and make some money?
"When are you going to stop tagging
the subway cars?
"When are you going
to make your son legitimate?"
Legitimate, shit.
Just tell him about all the money
you're going to make with me and Kenny.
You know we're gonna have album covers,
posters, T-shirts, buttons...
- Chollie, you're always talking that shit.
- You're damn right.
Talk about something else.
Yeah, let's talk about
bombing subway cars, Ramon.
That's real fresh, brother, real smart.
Why don't we talk about what
a big goddamn deal you're gonna be?
That's all you ever think about anymore.
King of the Hustlers.
And you think like some little kid.
Man, you're so phony.
What are you doing?
Live from the Bronx, it's the 6:00 news
Tapin' two little homeboys singin' the blues
One talkin' paint, the other one money
And they're so full of shit
that it ain't even funny
Take it away, Walter.
Let's kick his ass.
You gonna kick what?
This could be the night
Gonna find the special one
to make you feel all right
This could be the night
We'll be living in a dream
until the morning light
I'm talking to you, ladies
Listen to me carefully
I know you're gonna find what you want
If you're waiting patiently
Don't make your move too fast
If you want this night to last forever
Love is waiting for you
This could be the night
Gonna find the special one
to make you feel all right
This could be the night
We'll be living in a dream
until the morning light
Do you feel the magic
Everywhere tonight?
If you are gonna give all your love
Make sure that the feeling's right
This could be the night
Don't you make your move too fast
Tonight's gonna be for you and me
Hold it. He with you?
Yeah. He's my bodyguard.
Hi.
What you doing, man?
How come you don't frisk them?
Tracy!
Robert!
I'll see you all later.
I got a battle to attend to.
Yo, Double K, chill out.
All right! Get down!
So come on, everybody, everybody come on
Let's all get together and rock along
Twist and scream and shout
Now do what you came here to
In order to get frantic, you got to get loose
Say, say what, everybody say
It's a frantic
Situation
Worldwide
It's a musical drive
Emancipation
It's a proclamation
All across the nation
It's a heavy situation
Frantic, frantic, frantic
Now Shango and Soul Sonic
Two groups of heavy knowledge
are trying to educate you
So you won't become a frantic fool
Vibration of the music,
On the dance floor, fantasy illusion
A breakin' beat, electric boogaloo
Street dancing's now a cultural school
Now sing, now sing
Yo, Jazzy! Jazzy J!
What's happening? What's up, man?
What's up, Double K?
What's going on, man? All right.
Come here. Come on up.
Come on up and check this out.
Bronx Rockers.
Gino.
Come on.
There's Beat Street. Let's serve them.
The Bronx Rockers are here, man.
It's Beat Street, man.
They're gonna battle, man.
Do it!
Break dancing's where it's at
Say what?
Hit me
We all take
Energy
San Francisco
And Zimbabwe
Break dancing's where it's at
Say, where it's at
Break, break
Come on, Crazy baby.
Crazy, my man! Do it!
Break, break, break, break, break
Let's go, Kuriaki!
Come on, Beat Street!
Little brother was hot.
The Roxy's having auditions
next Tuesday, my man.
- We're gonna get you in here, mark my word.
- Baby, let's dance.
All right, let's dance.
Hi, I'm Tracy Carlson from City College.
What's your name?
Hello, my name's Lee.
- You're a wonderful breaker.
- Thank you.
I like you a lot.
Can you give me your phone number?
Damn!
- Why'd Spit do it, man?
- 'Cause he can't do no better.
Like, he used to do these tags
that were just stupid.
They were so lame, everybody thought
they were already messed up.
So now, he's gonna go over
everybody else's stuff.
Man, somebody needs to break his hands.
Does anybody know who this guy is?
Nobody knows.
Check it out.
It's so white.
It's so clean!
Ramo, we gotta.
All you ever talk about is white trains.
We gotta go.
If I get in that show of theirs,
ain't gonna be nothing like it.
Just let us do all the talking about business.
But I don't need help.
I can do my own talking.
We're all going in with you, Lee.
She didn't invite nobody but me.
Little brother, this is the big time.
If you want to be part of their show,
your manager has to protect your interests.
What if they want to take you on the road?
How about some extra money
if they put you on TV?
You think about that?
Check that out.
Hold it.
Tracy, hold it.
Tracy, the tempo on this section
is a little slow...
Yo, Tracy!
Lee! Come on up.
Bring your friends!
That's the guy that I met. The dancer.
He's a fabulous dancer.
Thank you so much. Thank you, too, Tracy.
It's a wonderful idea.
We're going to have a discussion now,
but you're all welcome to stay.
And Tracy knows where to reach you
with tickets for our performance.
I want to check something out.
My brother ain't here
to be in your show, is he?
I'm afraid this performance
is limited to our students.
- How come no one told him that?
- I thought they had.
I made it perfectly clear to Lee.
That's cool. Ain't no big deal.
I've never been on TV before,
so if you just flip on that tape...
I don't think so. Maybe tomorrow,
if you come back, we can...
- But I don't understand.
- We're too busy now.
Wait a minute. He can't see the tape?
After you all check him out
like he's some freak?
- Wait a minute...
- You wait a minute, mister.
Lady, you're showing people
how you down with breakin'...
and that's bullshit,
because you ain't down with nothing.
And you looked so proud.
"I found that little nigger myself.
Do I get an A, teacher?"
You're like all the biters.
You just take a bite and leave the rest.
- Our tape!
- Let him have it.
Linda.
Little runt.
Carmen!
Ramon!
Where have you been all week?
I missed you.
I had some stuff to take care of.
Yeah, I know.
I've been wanting to talk to you.
- Where's Julian?
- He's in the kitchen.
- I brought a gift for him.
- You did?
Hello, Mrs. Cavarro.
Here's your daddy.
That's a joke.
How can you even look him in the face?
Ramon.
It's so beautiful.
A little T-shirt doesn't make up for anything.
When will you take
some responsibility, Ramon?
- I'll put it on him right now.
- Is everybody deaf?
- Mommy, please don't start.
- I have to know why...
I'm sorry.
You can see how bad it is here.
Take us somewhere.
I got no place to take you.
Please, Ramon.
We'll be together.
- Where?
- Anywhere.
Two more.
Now single count.
Reach left and right,
and left, and right. Come on.
Hold on now. Just four more.
- Yes?
- Is this Lee Kirkland's house?
I'm Lee's mother. What you want him for?
I'd like to talk to him.
Maybe you want to talk to his brother.
I'd like to talk to him, too.
- Come on in.
- Thank you.
This young lady's looking for Lee.
For what?
Could you turn that down a little?
Lee's out right now.
If you want,
I can tell him what you came for.
Exactly what did I come for?
To get your tape back.
Who do you think you are?
You wreck my class with bullshit about me...
taking a bite out of your brother
and leaving the rest.
Let me tell you something.
I'm not a taker, and I'm not a user.
I told Lee exactly what was involved.
He's out right now.
I don't know what to tell you.
You just tell him I came by.
I know where Lee's at.
Where?
It's kind of dangerous.
I mean, you might not be up to it.
- Let me be the judge of that.
- Yes, ma'am.
Can I ask what you were doing?
Mixing, just trying some new stuff.
Like what?
It's kind of hard to explain.
Do you want to hear something?
Yeah.
See, I tape anything I think sounds good.
You know, add it with a lot of other stuff.
Water coming off a pipe...
making that tick-tock sound.
Add a little reverb.
Or this...
That's my piece.
- You mean you wrote that?
- Why, is that strange?
No.
That is some heavy shit.
You know, it's not so different
from what you're doing here.
How do you mean?
When I wrote this,
I tried to combine different styles...
- but it's really hard.
- Tell me about it.
I can't get the sounds in my head on tape.
I haven't got the right equipment.
You should come to school.
We have great equipment.
- I'd introduce you to the studio guy.
- You'd really do that?
Yeah.
You still feel like being dangerous?
Come on.
You sure now?
Let's go.
Where are we going?
Down there? I'm not going down there.
You're crazy.
It's not too far. This time of night,
locals run every 16 minutes.
- There's lights all the way.
- I'm not going down there.
I'm not gonna let you get hurt.
I promise.
There's no electricity this side of the tracks.
Stay right with me.
When the spur comes in up ahead,
just watch where I'm walking.
Right over here.
Train!
A white one.
Train's coming.
Come on.
- Yo, Ramo.
- Yo, check this out.
All right. Get back up, guys.
I saw a cop on that last train.
Hurry!
- Hi, Lee.
- Hi. How you doing?
I dig it. This is really fresh, Ramo.
Where'd you learn to do this?
- English class.
- No, I'm serious.
No kidding.
I used to trace these old DC comics,
'cause it was so boring.
That's where I figured out
all the streaks and blurs and shit.
Not too high on that cloud, all right?
You're gonna go over that Phase 2.
Come on, I ain't stupid.
What's Phase 2?
Phase 2 is the guy who practically
invented the idea of burners.
Before that,
everything was just these little tags.
A tag is your name.
And this...
That's a burner.
Pack it up!
Want to get something to eat?
No. We got some plans.
How about you?
Do you have brothers and sisters,
besides Lee?
I had an older brother.
What happened?
He was in this big gang in the Bronx.
He was into some bad shit.
When the cops came down on them...
a lot of guys got wasted,
and Franklin was one of them.
I was 12 years old, and I was mad.
I wanted to go to war.
But my friends told me that that was stupid.
Anyway, gangs died out back then.
Are you cold?
No.
Do you have a boyfriend?
Not really.
What are you doing here?
You have a home?
Damn, you smell good. I'd say you got up.
Be cool, Kenny. Let me hear the details.
Kenny, was she good?
- What?
- Man!
Little brother might have to learn
that information someday.
Turn me loose right now,
or you'd better never let go.
See that, Lee? Man gets a little nooky,
he cops an attitude.
He already has an attitude.
Damn it! You're gonna give me rabies.
You keep your voice down.
What are you doing here, man?
Opportunity is beating on our door, man.
DJ at the Burning Spear
got his fingers smashed by his little brother.
Slammed 'em in a window.
We'll be in Kool Herc's office
before Kool Herc.
- Kenny, tell me how she feels.
- Shut your dumb mouth.
Sounds to me like Double K is in love.
Better get some sleep, brother.
We got work to do.
It's a shame about
Super Ease's hands and all...
but you're gonna love Double K.
He is the baddest,
the freshest young DJ in the Bronx.
He better be.
Funk
Ain't it funky now?
- You think you got it together?
- Yeah, man, it's chill.
All right, you people get ready to cheer
For the Christmas show
at the Burning Spear
All you hip-hops are in for a treat
'cause Santa Claus is on Beat Street
Open up your door
I'm Santa Claus, and guess what, y'all?
I got something to show
I came to bring some Christmas spirit
I got a big bag, now guess what's in it
Something for the rich
and something for the poor
So Merry Christmas and ho, ho, ho!
"Ho, ho, ho, Merry Christmas", my foot
I'm gonna tell you what Santa really put
Under my so-called tree
But in reality looked like nothing
but a decorated pole to me
Man, you talk about a tree,
it makes me wonder
'Cause I never had a tree
to put anything under
If I ever did luck up and get a tree
There was never anything under it for me
Man, y'all should be glad that I didn't quit
'Cause I'm gettin' too old
for this Santa Claus shit
Y'all think I'm gettin' presents
made for free?
I got to pay them elves, nobody payin' me
You big fat whale, you might as well quit
'cause I can name 100 presents I didn't get
And if I did get a present
it'd be a hand-me-down
I got this for Christmas
Now how'd that sound?
It sounds good to me
'cause I'm about to freeze
Want to see something?
Look at the bottom of these
Me and my brothers can't go out
at the same time
A coat that's theirs
is a coat that's mine
I know one thing, y'all better get off my neck
And wait till you get your welfare check
Go on down to the office
and stand on the line
Better hurry up, see, I got mine
Jingle jangle
Jingle for the poor
And once you get your welfare check
Y'all can kiss my mistletoe
That's why the presents
keep getting mixed up
'Cause year after year, you keep fucking up
And now I know why,
'cause you're always drunk
- Instead of G.I. Joe, you send me this junk
- That ain't a G.I. Joe, that's a G.I. Jerk
With a kung fu grip that don't even work
So all I did was just put him away
'cause my G.I. Joe looked G.I. Gay
That's why you don't get presents
'cause you're ingrates
If G.I. Joe's gay
what difference does it make?
He's just a doll,
ain't too much he can do
If you ask me, boy,
I ain't too sure about you
Listen, bloat-o, with your big fat suit
Next time say no, don't send no substitute
Because I asked you for a beat box
and you know what I got?
Douggie Fresh
You know, that kid from down the block?
For a facsimile, we must admit
Douggie Fresh is good
and made a perfect fit
He's the only reason
why we weren't totally mad
Without Douggie,
our Christmas would have been really sad
Go sing Silent Night and Jingle Bells
And all those Christmas rhymes
'Cause nobody gives a shit
About a reindeer and hard times
You just jingle and jangle
And hang out with the poor
And when you get your welfare check
You can buy reindeer by the score
Well, let's get Douggie Fresh
And Magnificent Force
And head on out the door
And leave these party people singing
Jingle jangle for the poor
Sing jingle jangle
Jingle jangle with the poor
Jingle jangle, jingle with the poor
Jingle jangle
Jingle jangle with the poor
What are you doing next weekend?
- I'm free.
- No, you're not.
Let's dance.
Tell your mother
Pedro wants me to work late tonight.
Carmen needs to stay with us.
- We have no bed for her. You know that.
- She can stay with me.
You are not married to her.
If I marry her, she can stay with me?
She can stay in the place
that you make for her...
if you was a man.
I am a man.
A man?
A man takes care of his own.
A man has a job.
He's not a criminal who goes around
scrawling on the subways.
How come a man's what you say?
I'm a graffiti writer.
I'm an artist. I don't just throw up little tags
all over the place.
I make them trains beautiful.
How come you won't even
come see what I do?
Nothing's gonna come easy
In your life, not in your life
Nothing's gonna come easy in your life
In your life
I don't know why you can't see
All the things in your life you could be
You could live out your fantasies in your life
Make sure I speak to her manager.
It is possible
That a man can fly, make a fool of science
Gravity defied
If you're searching for paradise
Searching for something
that'll make you feel all right
Take a look deep down inside yourself
Just move your feet
and let the music do the rest
While the music's hot it just won't stop
Everybody dance to the radio rock
Music's hot, it just won't stop
Everybody's dancing,
they'll baptize the beat
Baptize the beat, baptize the beat
Next.
Damn.
That's right, that's deep
Everybody jumps to the vicious beat
Vicious beat, beat, vicious beat, beat
I'm Brenda Starr, and I rap to the beat
I go to the Roxy just to move my feet
You see, I break and boogie,
I rap to the beat
I'm rappin' to the rhythm of the vicious beat
Vicious beat, vicious beat
vicious beat, vicious beat
Hey, you
Yeah, I'm talkin' to you
I'm here to tell you, to tell you the scoop
I play no games, I'm right to the point
Make sure her manager
gets in touch with me.
- Hold up a minute, K.
- What are you talking about?
I want you to wait outside for me, all right?
I know what I'm doing.
What are you doing?
I am just about to take
the biggest chance of your life.
Great. Next.
Come on. Trust me.
I was born and raised
in the South Bronx streets
I'm so proud to say that my life's complete
My father's strong, and I am told
The family name I must uphold
Strong, bold, and demanding
That makes the girl outstanding
Often imitated
But never duplicated
I always stated Wanda Dee is one of a kind
And elegant is here,
she's gonna rock your mind
You know you won't resist
When I give you this
You know that we just met
Tonight I know you'll get wet
You showed up just in time
Nice.
I'm gonna make you sweat and whine
You are the one I want
I hold the tongue of fun
You know it's hip-hop rock
That's why you won't stop
So shake down, break down
- Shake down, break down
- Here's some guitar
Thank you. That's it.
You've got some pretty good talent
for your show.
You think they're talented?
- No, most of them are pretty lame, right?
- Who the hell are you calling lame?
You calling Tina B lame?
No.
My point is, I got a man
that's got something special.
Auditions are over.
He's Kool Herc's main man
down at the Burning Spear.
Kool Herc?
Okay, bring him in. I'll give him a listen.
- You want to see him?
- I just said I did, Jim.
Then be at the Burning Spear,
Saturday night.
Yo, Kenny!
- Let's go.
- What happened?
It's in the pocket, brother.
Okay.
What do you think?
- The place don't look so bad after all.
- Looking good.
Landlord's gonna raise your rent.
You can really fix up
one of these old places.
Yeah.
Yo, Double K, what's happening?
How's it going, Kenny?
Trace cut you loose tonight or what?
She's rehearsing her show.
Girl's too busy for me.
You really think Monte will show up
Saturday night?
I told you, it's in the pocket.
I really charmed that sucker.
You know, I was thinking...
that empty apartment upstairs...
maybe I'll start hanging out around here.
Fix it up for me and Carmen and the baby.
Really, Ramo? That'd be great.
We could be neighbors.
What're you gonna do about money, man?
- Get a job.
- Say what? You?
Yeah. What the hell.
Give me some tape.
Watch it.
Surprise! Merry Christmas.
Welcome home.
God.
Let's throw on some music here.
Get this party going.
You know what I mean?
See? We put the crib right by the heat.
Keep him nice and warm.
Water's running.
Yeah, and the bed works, too.
We checked it out personally.
Oh, God.
I just don't know
how I'm gonna thank you all.
- How you feeling?
- Great, man.
Thanks a lot, you guys are the greatest.
Us Puerto Ricans
got to stick together, right?
He's crazy.
Yo, Kenny, it's Monte.
He's coming?
- You listen pretty good.
- Herc, I'm not stealing your headliner.
Just giving him a little downtown exposure.
You got everything to gain.
- I'm looking out for the boy's interest.
- I can look out for Double K's interests.
Do me a favor.
New Year's Eve,
do exactly what you did tonight.
Don't worry about it.
Double K won't change a note.
So when do we see the contract?
He your manager?
Yeah, well, don't let that stop you.
Yo, chill out, man. I hear something.
Battle cry
Let's do the right thing.
Let's serve these dudes, man.
Fight this dancer
Super solid
The battle cry
No way.
You see
Is it time for what's in store
The crews are headed for a dancing war
Who rocks, who rocks,
who rocks, who rocks?
Battle cry
Street drums
Speed drums
Who rocks, who rocks,
who rocks, who rocks?
Battle cry
It's the police!
Come on, man. Let's get out of here!
Get off me, man!
Stay still.
Amazing, isn't it?
Then do the same thing to add other sounds
to other keyboard registers.
Look.
Add a little scratch.
And the computer prints out the score.
Isn't that incredible?
Yeah. That's good, man.
Here, play with it a while.
In a couple of hours, he'll probably
have it doing tricks nobody else thought of.
Kenny, while you're working,
I have some work to complete with Tracy.
- It's the piano part.
- The intro.
Yes.
- I can't believe the performance is tomorrow.
- You'd better believe it.
Need some help?
The keyboard went dead.
You wiped out the disk.
Here, I'll reprogram it for you.
- I got to get going.
- Going?
I thought you wanted to use the studio...
to try out some sounds
for your New Year's Eve show at the Roxy.
I don't need new sounds, man.
What I got's plenty.
It was plenty good enough
to get me the gig.
Excuse me, Robert.
Kenny, what's the matter?
Nothing's the matter.
I'm fine, you're fine.
We should just leave it that way.
What do you mean by that?
I've got things to do, my own things.
You got your own things to do
with your own friends.
Robert?
You think that was so new and great,
what he was doing? That was nothing.
- We were just trying to help you.
- I don't need help.
- Other people respect what I do.
- And I don't?
You don't even know why I'm with you.
I got it figured out.
You are the missionary, and I'm the native.
Man, look at these toy cops.
They don't know the difference
between dancing and fighting.
Word. It's true, man.
If we were fighting,
these people would've run the other way.
If you know what's good for you,
you'll shut up!
Mom!
Mom, these fools busted us for dancing.
Could you believe this?
I believe you better shut your mouth
before I decide to leave you here.
Take my advice.
You better nip that little attitude in the bud.
That's heading for nowhere but trouble.
You're kind of young
to be giving advice, aren't you?
If my son says he was dancing,
that's what he was doing.
If you're gonna arrest people for dancing,
maybe you're the one who needs advice...
'cause there are lots of worse things
these kids could be doing.
- That I know.
- Word.
I don't know. Maybe I made a bad mistake.
I mean, she's got this big performance
of her composition tonight...
so she's thinking about that.
Man, women are always trying
to change you.
Is Carmen trying to change you?
Hell, no. Who told you that?
You got that dumb job.
That's a big change, isn't it?
That was just something I had to do.
It'll be better once I start working day shifts.
Night shifts interfere with my real work.
Is that all you want to do?
Go bombing trains at night
and pushing a broom all day?
Why are you getting on my case?
I'm not getting on you, man.
You see them?
Their tags are little black letters
on little white cards of paper.
My tag's running...
in Brooklyn, the Bronx, Queens, right now.
In every borough, on every line.
It's eight feet high, and it's beautiful.
- But what about tomorrow?
- Tomorrow's a long way off, man.
When I'm writing trains...
or when you're mixing sounds,
making people dance, that's everything.
We're alive.
The white one.
- Somebody made it an A train.
- So, what does that mean?
That means tonight, after work, it's mine.
There it is.
Take this off, will you?
- Do that fill-in in red, okay?
- Okay.
Come on.
Let's go do the other side.
You've got to be kidding. Ramo!
Do you hear something?
Spit!
Kenny.
Sorry I missed your concert.
That wasn't important.
I know what you mean.
That New Year's Eve gig at the Roxy...
I don't think that's so important.
But you're gonna do it, aren't you?
I don't know.
I have an idea for something I could do.
- But I'm not sure how.
- Can I help?
Please?
Grand Master Melle and the Furious Five...
Twenty-five breakers,
the City College dancers...
and a Bronx gospel choir?
Do you realize
what you're asking these people to do?
- They'll do it.
Yeah, so they'll do it...
but there's no way in hell anybody's
gonna let you turn New Year's Eve at Roxy...
into some kind of a funeral.
It won't be a funeral. It'll be a celebration.
Kenny, are you crazy?
This is the opportunity of your life.
It's my life.
Okay, brother.
Then let's do it right.
Beat Street, breakdown
Beat Street, the king of the beat
You see 'em rockin' that beat
from across the street
Beat street is a lesson, too
Because you can't let the streets beat you
Well, a picture can express
a thousand words
To describe all the beauty of life you give
And if the world was yours to do over
I know you'd paint a better place to live
Where the colors would swirl
and the boys and girls
Can grow in peace and harmony
And where murals stand on walls so grand
As far as the eyes are able to see
I never knew art till I saw your face
And there'll never be one to take your place
'Cause every time
you touch a spray-paint can
Michelangelo's soul controls your hands
Then serenades of blue and red
And the beauty of the rainbow
fills your head
Crescendo colors play in tune
Man, why did you have to die so soon?
Sayin' one, two, three, four
Just let me know what you came here for
And just clap your hands, everybody
And let me know that I'm not alone
And if you knew my man when he was alive
Scream it out and say, "Ramon!"
Ramon!
I'm talking 'bout
ashes to ashes and dust to dust
Where the good die young as all they must
'Cause as life must live, death must die
And the tears shall fall from the living eye
Tell me, who's gonna dream
the impossible dream
Of the beautiful cities
and the island streams
When your works of art brought into being
All that the ghetto stopped you from seeing
Still-life, urban masterpiece
Your trademark was written
on trains and walls
A million-dollar gift only God would leave
And yet you got killed for nothing at all
So after this, there'll be no more hard times
No more bad times, and no more pain
No more chump change, none of that bull
Just movies, museums, and the hall of fame
So all you hip-hops, get on up
And let's take it to the top where we belong
'Cause the age
of the Beat Street wave is here
Everybody, let's sing along,
now come on, say, "Ho!"
Say, "Ho!"
And to let me know
I'm rockin' the microphone
Everybody say, "Ramon!"
Ramon!
A newspaper burns in the sand
And the headlines say, "Man destroys man"
Extra, extra, read all the bad news
On the war of peace
that everybody would lose
The rise and fall, the last great empire
The sound of the whole world caught on fire
The ruthless struggle, the desperate gamble
The game that left the whole world
in shambles
The cheats, the lies, the alibis
And the foolish attempt to conquer the skies
Lost in space, and what is it worth?
The President just forgot about Earth
Spendin' multi-billions
and maybe even trillions
The cost of weapons ran in the zillions
There's gold in the street
Diamonds under feet
And there's children in Africa don't even eat
Flies on their faces, they're living like mice
The houses even make the ghetto look nice
The water tastes funny,
it's forever too sunny
And they work all month
and don't make no money
A fight for power, a nuclear shower
People shout out in the darkest hour
At sights unseen and voices unheard
And finally the bomb gets the last word
Christians killed Muslims,
and Germans killed Jews
And everybody's bodies
are used and abused
Minds are poisoned and souls are polluted
Superiority complex is deep-rooted
Leeches and lices, and people got prices
Egomaniacs control the self-righteous
Nothing is sacred, and nothing is pure
So the revelation of death is our cure
Dachau, Auschwitz, Hiroshima
Vietnam, Leningrad, Iwo Jima
Okinawa, Korea, the Philippines
Devastation, death,
catch the killing machine
The people's in terror,
the leaders made an error
And now they can't even look in the mirror
'Cause we got to suffer
while things get rougher
And that's why we got to get tougher
So learn from the past
and work for the future
And don't be a slave to no computer
'Cause the children of man inherit the land
And the future of the world is in your hands
So just throw your hands in the air
And wave them like you just don't care
And if you believe that you're the future
Scream it out and say, "Yeah!"
Yeah!
Everybody, do you believe?
Do you believe?
Let me hear you say, "Yeah!"
Believe it
They buried us
So we became a flower, believe it
Believe it
They gave us nothing
So we took power, believe it
Believe it
They tried to break us
And now we're the breakers, believe it
Believe it
We come from the ashes
The movers and shakers
Believe it
Now we're going on
We're the hip-hop
We're gonna take you to the top
Now we're going on
We can't stop, believe it
Strut, strut
Break it down, break it down
We are the harvest of a bitter seed
Some of us fall
Some of us bleed
But we are the future
And we will succeed
Believe it
We are the miracle
We are the strong
We are the right that came from wrong
We made hope into our song
Believe it
I'm a Christian, a Muslim, a Hindu, a Jew
I believe in me, I believe in you
Yes, I believe it, I do believe it
Yes, I believe it
Do you
believe it?
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org