Oh, my God!
If you'd like to make a call, please--
Hurry, hurry!
He's right behind you!
Look out! Oh, my God!
Stop!
Hey, you guys, stop!
-Stop! Stop!
-What do you want?
What are you doing?
There's a woman being killed up here.
Come on.
L.A. City Emergency. This is 91 1.
What are you reporting?
This is L.A. City Emergency, 91 1.
I'm sorry, I can't hear you.
Please tell me the nature
of your emergency.
I can't hear you. Can you speak up?
No, don't.
Please don't.
Get him off of me. He's killing me!
Stop!
l'm Detective McLean.
l'm in charge of this investigation.
l see you're an actor.
Ever been in anything?
Emerald Point and a Hart to Hart
that was pretty good.
Very interesting.
You make a living?
Good-looking boy.
Talented.
Scully, l got a real problem with you.
What do you mean?
l mean, you're my only witness
to this murder.
And you're a peeper.
ln my book that's a pervert
and a sex offender.
-What do you mean, ''a sex offender''?
-Save it.
l ask the questions.
What about this lndian? He snatched
her pocketbook, you got it back for her?
That's right.
Was anything missing?
Well, l saw him take a credit card.
Not a credit card. A card key, Scully.
He used it to get into her house.
Did Gloria know it was missing?
l don't know.
She didn't say anything to me.
You talked to her?
Come on, Scully,
you must have said something.
-lt was just small talk, you know.
-No, l don't know.
Did you come on to her?
Trying to do a number on her head?
Trying to freak her out
with all you know about her life.
Then why were you following
Gloria Revelle?
Because l got concerned
when l saw that guy following her.
-You kept on her after he disappeared.
-l know, l know, because....
l guess, l wanted to....
You wanted to what?
Nothing.
What's this?
Pants. Some underpants.
Yours?
Where'd you get them?
-She dropped them in the trash.
-Who?
Gloria.
And you just picked them up.
Why?
Come on, Scully, tell the truth.
You fucked her and kept them
for a souvenir.
No, you didn't fuck her? Or no,
you didn't keep them as a souvenir?
-You're just a harmless panty sniffer?
-You got a dirty mind.
That's a laugh.
You peep on her, follow her,
fuck her, keep her panties...
-...then watch her being slaughtered.
-You're twisting everything around!
l tried to save her!
Some save, Scully.
Some save.
Remind me to never put my life
in your hands.
Tell me about Alexander Revelle.
What?
Alexander Revelle.
You know, Gloria's husband.
Friend of yours?
No, l never met him.
-You sure?
-Yeah, l'm sure.
Was he around when Gloria got nailed?
You think he had something
to do with it?
Gloria Revelle was a rich lady.
Very rich.
When rich wives get dead...
...l usually go after the husband.
The only problem is, you saw a thief.
An lndian killed Gloria Revelle.
l'm not gonna hold you, Scully.
You got witnesses
to back up your story.
But l want you to think real hard
about this.
As far as l'm concerned, you're
the reason she got murdered.
lf you hadn't been so busy
getting off by peeping on her...
...if you'd called the police about
your blood brother, the lndian...
...Gloria Revelle would still be alive.
So, Linda...
...you have your own
production company now.
-Yes. Linda Shaw Enterprises.
-Linda Shaw Enterprises.
What are some of those ''enterprises''?
We have a film, Deep Ghost.
Ah, The Mating Game....
The Mating Game?
-One Night at a Time.
-One Night at a Time. Yes.
I believe you have a film
opening this Friday...
...at the Pussy Flick Theatre.
-What's the title?
-Bold Obsession.
Bold Obsession.
Tell us, Linda,
what is your ''bold obsession''?
That script was written for me,
because I'm a bit of a exbasitionist.
You are an ''exbasitionist''?
You mean an ''exhibitionist''?
Exhibitionist. Yeah.
I get so ex cited when I know
they're all watching me.
Well, of course they're watching you.
-Oh, yeah, so hot....
-Hot? It does?
-What happens when you get hot?
-It makes me want to come.
While you're coming,
why don't we watch this clip?
-Five minutes, Miss Body.
-I'm ready.
We've got five minutes.
Danny, where the hell are you?
We need you on the set.
Come on, let's go.
Holly Does Hollywood.
The X Cinema!
L.A. 's classiest X-rated movie house.
See the film everyone's talking about.
Holly Does Hollywood.
And does it well.
Screw Magazine says.
''Holly Body keeps this business where
it belongs. In the gutter. ''
In the words of Eros magazine.
''The Gone With the Wind
of adult films. ''
Holly Does Hollywood
is a hedonist's heaven.
Hustler magazine gives its
highest rating.
Ten nominations, including
best picture.
Critics Adult Film Association.
Starring Holly Body.
Holly Does Hollywood.
Now playing at the X Cinema.
And for home viewers, you can pick
it up now at Tower Records video sale.
Excuse me. Do you have
Holly Does Hollywood?
Yeah, we do. lt's in our
adult section. Follow me.
-On VHS?
-VHS. Whatever you want.
Half-inch, three-quarter, Beta.
-ls this what you're talking about?
-That's it.
Hello. Adult Blue Films.
Hello, are you the company that
distributes Holly Does Hollywood?
l'm not just some fucking stunt cock.
l'm an actor!
You just have to wait.
I've been waiting
for more than an hour.
Do you know how many pictures
I've made with Holly?
I'm sure you've made a lot.
l don't have to take this shit.
l have a reputation.
Look, if you want to audition,
sit down. Oh, I'm sorry.
That's okay.
-Can I help you?
-How late are the auditions going?
-Probably past 6.
-Thank you.
You're welcome. Bye.
Mr. Corso, Jake Scully.
Pleasure to meet you.
Stand over there.
You ready?
Go ahead.
l like to watch.
Makes you hot, doesn't it?
Makes me hot too. Real hot.
Come over here,
l'll show you how hot.
All right.
Take off your clothes.
l want to take some pictures.
What is it that we're watching?
l don't know.
What are you,
some kind of method actor?
Give it to me one time now
Relax, don't do it
When you wanna go to it
When you wanna come
Relax, don't do it
When you wanna suck it to it
When you wanna come
Relax, don't do it
When you wanna go to it
When you wanna come
Relax, don't do it
When you wanna suck it to it
When you wanna come
l like to watch.
Makes you hot, doesn't it?
Makes me hot too.
Why don't you come over here,
and l'll show you how hot.
Where's the come shot?
l thought we were doing
Body Talk, not Last Tango.
You were great out there.
Come on, l'll buy you a drink.
A drink? l don't even know you.
Hey, l'm talking business.
Come on.
You know the mirror out there?
That was my idea.
So you're a genius.
But l can make a better film
than Corso with my eyes closed.
Films cost money, you know.
l got money.
Then what are you doing in hard-core?
l wanted to meet you.
Why?
Because l think you're sensational.
You're the best in the business.
l'll pay you top dollar.
l'll give you points.
Whatever it takes.
Really?
l want you in my picture.
-You're really serious?
-Of course l am.
Okay, good.
There are some things l like
to get straight up front...
...so there are no misunderstandings.
l don't blame you.
l do not do animal acts.
l don't do S & M or any variations
of that particular bent.
No watersports, either.
l will not shave my pussy,
no fist-fucking...
...and absolutely
no coming in my face.
l get $2,000 a day,
and l don't work without a contract.
Fine. l mean, that's no problem.
l think we got a deal.
You ever do any special work?
What kind are you looking for?
A woman alone.
Getting herself off.
lt's gotta be really hot.
ls that all?
l have a routine that is
a sure 1 0 on the peter-metre.
l know. l've seen it.
A few times.
l'm known far and wide
for that little bit of business.
l want you to know
l saw Holly Does Hollywood...
...and your acting was top-drawer.
My acting?
You're fantastic.
Really sensational.
And l'll tell you something else.
-You've got a terrific--
-Body.
Smile.
Smile?
Jake?
Jake Scully! Look at you.
-Kimberly, how are you?
-l'm fine. Just lovely.
Aren't you going to
introduce me to your friend?
-Holly Body.
-Kimberly Hess.
So, Jake, you working?
Here and there.
We gotta run.
Great to see you.
Jake and l worked together
a few times in the past.
l thought l knew everybody
in this business.
Really?
l don't see how someone
could know everyone.
Well, it's a funny business.
l wanted to ask you...
...have you heard of any roles
that might be right for...?
l have. l have a tip for you.
Simon La Farge is just casting
his picture. You know him, right?
Where you from, outer space?
Just tell him that you ran into me.
Here's his number.
You might want to firm up a little bit
before you go and see him.
One more thing.
Do you mind working with ladies?
Well, no. l mean,
acting is acting, right?
That's right.
l think that's really admirable.
l mean, me myself,
l can't get into it. But....
Good luck and say hello
to Simon for me.
-Good seeing you.
-Sure. Thanks.
By the way...
...what's the film about?
That's good.
We need more comedians
in our business. Good luck.
Very nice.
What can l get you?
Jack Daniel's?
How about Jake Scully...
...straight up?
Very funny.
Listen, Holly....
l don't want to talk
anymore business.
Yeah, well, listen....
Lie down.
We had one of these in Star Whores.
There's something l gotta tell you.
You're married.
l'm not a producer.
You're not a producer.
Just a second.
l'm not interested
in making a film with you.
-What are you interested in then?
-You.
l saw you in the house
those other nights.
What house?
You know, that little show
you put on...
...with the masturbation routine and
the diamonds. l watched you from here.
You were the girl
in the window, right?
That wasn't Gloria, that was you.
What's it to you?
Just tell me if l'm right.
That was you in the Revelle house.
Right?
l'm not saying it was me,
and l'm not saying it wasn't me.
l'm saying, why are you
interested in knowing?
l think that...
...one of my crazy friends
played a practical joke on me.
You know how it is with the idle rich.
Tell me, okay? Tell me...
...were you the girl in the house?
-Yeah, it was me.
-l knew it. How did this get set up?
Tell me, just to satisfy my curiosity,
because one of my....
One of my crazy friends set this up,
and l don't know who.
-Who hired you?
-You were the one l was playing to?
And there's no part for me?
-l'm sorry.
-So this whole thing was a joke.
lt was a practical joke on me.
Did Sam Bouchard set this thing up?
Did he hire you to do your routine?
He didn't tell me his name.
Well, whoever you talked to,
what did he say?
This guy called me up and said
he'd seen my self-help routine...
...in Holly Does Hollywood...
...and he wanted to hire me
to do it in private.
He said he had this friend
who got off on peeping.
-He didn't tell you who he was?
-No, he didn't tell me his name.
He just sent a messenger
over with money...
...and with a card key...
...and a wig.
Please don't leave, okay?
Stay here for a second.
Can you hold on?
-Jake, it's Sam. How's it going?
-How are you doing? Can you hold on?
Listen to this guy's voice...
...and tell me if he's the one
that hired you.
Please?
Sorry, you got me in the shower.
How you doing?
I'm afraid I've got
some bad news for you, pal.
What's that?
Seattle Rep and I had some differences.
I'm heading back to L.A.
I guess you'll have to
find another place to crash.
That's him.
You got company?
l do. lt's kind of
a bad time to talk.
You want to call me back
in about 1 5 minutes?
That was the guy who hired you?
-Are you sure?
-l'm sure that was him.
-Listen.
-You're really sick!
-Listen to me.
-lf this is your idea of fun--
l am not a film producer
and l am not a rich kid.
No, you're a jerk.
Please just listen
to me for a second.
You were hired to come in
and do two nights' work.
You were hired to do your routine
and leave. ls that true?
-Do you know why?
-You just told me why.
You just told me some guy
was playing a joke on you.
He wasn't playing a joke on you.
Do you now want
to tell me what it was?
The truth, Holly.
The truth is a woman was murdered.
lt's not funny! A woman was murdered.
We were set up by a murderer!
He wanted to be sure l witnessed
the murder. That's why he hired you.
He arranged it
so that l'd be watching.
He wanted me to think Gloria Revelle
was the one who was getting off.
Meanwhile, he thought
l'd watch and keep watching.
Are you listening to me?
l don't understand what you've said--
Listen, the man who hired you
is a murderer!
Here, come here.
Please come here.
Do you remember
where you did your routine?
See that house down there?
That's where you were, right?
-Now do you understand?
-Yes, l understand.
l understand you're sick.
And you're a liar.
You need help.
And l don't like being yelled at.
l should've known when
you said l had a nice smile.
No real producer would say that!
Now get out of my way.
-What?
-Come with me to the police.
To the police? Are you crazy?
Listen, you weirdo.
l'm leaving and don't follow me.
l have friends who'll break your legs!
Let go of me! Christ!
Weirdo! l should know better.
lt's Hollywood!
Could l have the Hollywood police?
Fucking freaky actors!
That's what there is here.
Masochistic directors.
l should've known when he didn't
know what a come shot was.
Detective McLean, please.
Excuse me. Stop, please?
Thank you very much, lady!
l was set up.
Hollywood's busiest sex offender.
Listen to me for a minute.
l got something important to tell you.
l know who killed Gloria Revelle.
ls this a confession?
Just pay attention, all right?
A few days ago, l was
looking for an apartment.
Do you know any sublets
available right away?
No. l'll check around.
Then I noticed this guy.
Sam Bouchard. He was looking for
somebody who needed a place to stay.
I thought it was a coincidence
we kept running into each other.
Hi, again.
Anyway, now I realize...
...he was throwing out a net,
sizing me up for a part he was casting.
l want you to cry out for help!
l can't.
And I fit the bill perfectly.
Lovesick sucker, out on his ass.
Shit, what a fool l am.
You know what the part was?
l'm listening.
The part of the witness.
He said there was a neighbour that
did a number on herself every night.
He knew I'd look.
Nice, huh?
He knew I'd keep looking.
It wasn't Gloria, it was Holly.
That's why I never saw her face.
You sound like one of those
conspiracy nuts, plots all around you.
Please just listen to me for a second.
Sam Bouchard is Alexander Revelle.
He hired the Indian
to follow Gloria...
...snatch her purse and
steal the key to her house...
...and then sneak inside.
When she got home, the Indian opened
the blinds so I'd see him kill her.
Alexander Revelle set me up
in this house to witness the murder.
And he hired a porno actress
to be the bait.
Can l have a ride, please?
Thanks a lot, you jerks! God!
Oh, my God!
l've been trying to build a case
against the husband all along.
The reason it hasn't panned out
is because of your testimony...
...that Gloria was killed by an lndian.
That's it, don't you see?
That's what he wanted.
lt looks like a burglary but
it's a murder with me as the witness.
l'm Sam's--
l mean, Alexander Revelle's alibi.
Listen. Stop, all right?
Stop right there!
There has been an accident up there.
-People are probably hurt.
-Slow down, lady.
-And nobody's bothered to stop.
-Get in.
lt sounds crazy to me.
l know.
But it's the truth.
Maybe you'd better come down here.
Pull it up. Pull your car
right up here, nice and slow.
All right, stay in your car, please.
We'll have it cleaned up in a minute.
Nothing to look at.
Get back in your car, please.
There's a woman being killed
in that Ford Bronco.
He hit her on the head with something.
We gotta help her!
Get back in your car.
He hit her in the back--
l don't have time to run you in.
Please, he's getting away.
Call somebody on the radio.
Don't you understand?
l saw him killing her.
-You fucking idiot!
-That's it. You're coming with me.
Call Detective McLean.
He knows all about this.
Come here, you son of a bitch!
Holly, are you okay?
Look what you did.
You ruined my surprise ending!
l gave you your part.
The witness.
You were perfect.
You played it to a tee.
But that was it. End of part.
Wrap Jake Scully.
You had to play the hero...
...improvise all this crap
about finding a body double...
...unmasking the lndian.
But you didn't think it through,
did you, Jake?
Sometimes heroes come to tragic ends.
What's the matter, Jake?
A little short of breath?
What a terrible way to die.
Especially when
you're so claustrophobic.
Wait a minute.
l'm gonna give you another take, Jake.
The only problem is
you've got to act.
Come on, Jake.
Action.
And action.
Jake, action.
Cut! Get him out.
Move the camera.
Joe, give me a hand.
Just take it easy.
Something's going on.
Take it easy.
We're getting you out.
We got you.
Don't worry about it.
-That's all right.
-We're here.
Give him some air.
Talk to me, talk to me.
Walk it off.
Just go for a walk.
Just relax, just breathe in.
Give him some air.
All right, that's good.
What's the matter, babe?
You had us scared.
What's the problem?
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Get away from me.
Just relax.
We're trying to help you.
l know.
l can help myself.
Listen, Scully,
why don't you cool off?
Go on home and we'll shoot this
another time, all right?
Don't lie to me. lf l don't get
this shot, you're going to fire me.
Don't be ridiculous.
Why would l do a thing like that?
Save the speech. l know about your
personal commitment to the actors.
So l'm a little claustrophobic.
You'll work around it, right?
Yeah, that's right.
l don't think l like your attitude.
lf l get this shot,
you'll like it a lot better, right?
Let's do it!
And Jake, you'd better
get it right this time.
You're one pain in the ass
l don't need.
Roll sound. Quiet.
And action!
You bastard!
Don't be so melodramatic.
Kill! Kill!
What are you doing?
-What am l doing? l'm saving you.
-From who?
Listen.
The lndian was Sam Bouchard.
Am l missing something?
ls somebody here l don't see?
Yes, the dog knocked him in.
Come here, Holly.
Look, he must have knocked him in.
l thought it belonged to Gloria but
it must have belonged to the husband.
That's why he never barked
at the lndian in the house.
You're right.
We should go to the police.
Really? You believe me?
l believe you're a number one sicko
and should be put away for life.
l know all about you guys.
l've seen about you on television.
You're one of those necrophiliacs.
A corpse fucker!
l am not.
l turn you on all right.
The problem is l'm still moving.
Unconscious is good,
but dead is better.
Holly, are you all right?
Take my hand.
Do not touch me!
l'm not dead yet.
This all seems crazy,
but you've gotta believe me.
l'm trying to help you.
Are you gonna stay in there
for the rest of your life?
Freeze. Don't move your hand.
How's it look, Doug?
Good. Hold that move.
All right, let's 86 the bat.
lt's a wrap on the bat.
Get the bat out.
l gotta hold the hand really still.
Help him out.
Turn the water off.
Can l slip out?
Wait till we get the bar in there.
Between the bottom two fingers.
Good. Okay, sweetheart,
you can slide out.
Don't move the hand.
Freeze the hand.
Makeup.
Touchup for Jake.
Don't move the hand.
Keep the hand very still.
Don't move the bar!
-l'm sorry.
-That's okay.
You look great.
-Did l flash the teeth enough?
-Best teeth flashing l've seen.
Beautiful, babe.
l'm glad l fired that other asshole.
This part was made for you.
You look sensational.
The bar's falling.
l can't believe l'm holding it.
You getting tired?
Just a little longer.
Bring in the body double.
The hair looks good.
ls that as hot as that water gets?
Okay, slide in, sweetheart.
Don't move the bar.
lt's important.
l'm Mindy. Pleased to meet you.
Be very, very careful, okay?
My breasts are very tender.
l got my period.
All right, we good here?
Now just bring your body up like this.
l can't move my hand.
Keep your hand exactly still.
Let's take the bar out.
Drop the camera.
Get the camera down.
Bring your body to my hand.
Quiet, please!
l'm trying to think.
You're gonna get a lot of dates
when this comes out.
Action.
Action with the hand.
Great action.
Great action, yeah.
ls that too hard?
Subtitles by
GELULA & CO., lNC.