Stay by your phone.
Dr. Nancy Love will be up on
KCMY Talk Radio...
with The Love Line.
I recommend that you examine...
the deeper feelings
you have for your wife, Tom.
I don't know, Dr. Love.
She gets pretty wild sometimes.
These wild things she does,
they'll never change.
They may take different forms...
but that woman is who she is
for life.
There's really no mystery to
sex, but there may be to her...
so I really urge you to make
an effort...
and try to be more accepting of
who she is.
- Thank you, Dr. Love.
- Well, thank you for calling.
We have time
for one more caller.
This is The Love Line.
I'm Dr. Nancy Love,
and you're on The Love Line.
- Your name, please.
- Jane.
What would you
like to talk about?
Is Love really your last name?
That's what you want to discuss?
I just think it's great that
nobody knows...
what you look like
and you can...
walk around with a last name
like that.
That's my life, Jane,
and we're talking about yours.
My life's pretty good,
thank you.
I'm stable. I know what I want.
Just...
just have this one teensy
problem.
A love problem.
That's right. A love problem.
And you're deciding whether
or not to make a change.
It's occurred to me.
How long have you been
in this relationship?
Three and a half years.
- How old are you?
- 32.
- And him?
- 45.
- And he's married.
- That's right.
He's married.
Classic stuff, huh?
Well, with the dilemma
you're in, Jane...
we could discuss sexual
attitudes, early childhood...
but the truth is
when you make changes...
you sometimes
have to endure pain.
Is that what you do
with your pain?
We're talking about you.
Have you ever considered
therapy?
You're my therapy.
You're a doctor.
I talk anonymously on the radio.
That's very different
from what you might need.
You're a legitimate doctor,
aren't you... Doctor?
That's what it says on
my credentials.
People invent things
all the time.
Then that would be my problem.
Come on... Dr. Love.
Don't you sometimes get the urge
to go into a bar...
and meet someone and talk about
your life?
Stand by for the news.
We're running out of time.
I'm sorry,
but it's time for the news.
We'll be right back.
Please hold on.
Thank you, Mr. Chomsky.
Where's she off to this evening?
How about dinner?
I can't, Ralph.
Nancy, you've been here
for six months...
and I don't know whether
you're living with someone...
or married or what.
All I know is you won't go out
to dinner with me.
I'm working, always working.
How about tomorrow night?
Well, is he crazy or what?
We don't use terms like that.
He's just confused
about his personality.
Just got into a little trouble.
Women trouble, right?
Mickey tells lies. That's
basically all that's wrong.
- Hell, everybody lies.
- Precisely.
But you said
he sometimes gets violent.
Frankly, we are understaffed,
and we need the space.
You'll have to take him home.
We're going to need
some more copies.
I made a mistake on this one.
It'll take just a minute to fix.
Hey, Louis.
Here you go. Enjoy.
Thanks.
What can I do for you?
Smirnoff. Shooter, please.
And a Guinness.
With two inches of head.
Sounds good.
You, yes, you.
Listen to this
and tell me what you think.
"I like the way
you wear your hair and smell.
"When you're asleep,
I see all your beauty.
"But we just can't seem to work
this sex thing out."
Well?
Why do you want to know
what I think?
Who else?
You don't want to know
what I think.
I just escaped
from a mental home.
So that makes you an expert.
Tell me.
I think it sucks. You stole it.
I did not! I didn't steal it.
It's what I feel.
I got notebooks
full of what I feel.
Then I think it's great.
You do?
Absolutely.
Now you're lying.
I never lie.
I taught poetry at Yale.
Bullshit.
"No matter who I'm with,
they want to know...
"if I'm still sleeping with you.
"I say that you sleep
while I die a little...
"but I'm not afraid of death.
"At least you get laid
in your coffin."
You weren't even listening.
You want to get laid.
It was just a poem.
Just a thought.
Around 6:30, someone's coming by
to see me...
about moving into my house.
If you're looking for
a roommate...
what's wrong with me?
Female roommate.
- What'll you have?
- Excuse me. I'm looking for Eve.
You found her.
I'm Ann.
You want something to drink
while we talk?
Scotch, please. Straight.
Why don't we sit over there?
Thank you.
Got it?
It seems like
a pleasant place to work.
I own it.
That's wonderful.
So what about you?
What do you do?
I only work half days, sort of
telephone answering service.
Servicing is very big
these days.
I suppose so.
God, you love to stare at women.
- Old habit.
- Ever been married?
- Sure.
- What happened?
Which time?
So you'll come by
around noon tomorrow?
If that's all right with you.
No problem.
Most of my men are early risers.
Eve, I don't want
to interrupt anything.
You're not interrupting
anything.
Finished that one? History.
Hey, Ace. Smirnoff. Straight.
I'm drunk. How about you?
Never.
Something to do with my blood.
Smirnoff. Neat.
You new in town or what?
No, I'm the same.
Town's different.
Right.
Got any money?
- I can get it.
- I got plenty of money.
So where are you from?
Las Vegas.
Nobody's from Las Vegas.
I am.
So where you headed?
- Las Vegas.
- You're crazy!
That's what they say.
When I go away,
I'm headed for Europe.
I'm learning how
to speak French.
Parlez-vous Français?
I spent six years in Europe.
Yeah? Where?
Berlin. Rome. Moscow.
You been to Russia?
- Twice.
- What for?
I'm not supposed to tell you.
God, you been a lot of places
and done a lot of things.
Just like a dream.
I guess I'm nervous because...
I've always lived alone.
Always?
Never even with a man?
I don't have much success
with men.
I have too much.
The key's under the mat.
I have to be going. I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Looking for a good time?
No, I'm not.
How you doing, soldier?
Need another round?
I haven't been a soldier
in a while.
Class dismissed?
I used to come in here a lot.
I know this area pretty well.
I flew jets down south.
I knew Eve.
You mean the original owner?
She died.
Do you know that?
I never knew her.
I just moved out and...
I was walking down the street
one night.
I saw my name on a neon sign...
with a lounge bar for sale
underneath it.
I decided I had to take
advantage and go into business.
Figured it had to be better
than marriage.
You were getting married?
No way.
I'm never getting married.
You moving?
Photographic equipment.
Really?
I do portraits.
I've won awards.
I see. And you came in here
to find new faces?
I came here to find Eve.
Good night, Eve.
Good night, ladies.
That how you saw the sign
that first night?
Didn't you know?
All us working girls are pals.
You work long hours.
I can say the same about you.
You think I'm working on you.
Part-time work.
You smile for a lot of the guys.
I like men. I always have.
I was just thinking what it
would be like to kiss you.
And?
I wanted to marry you.
I've ruined too many marriages
to have one of my own.
You smile for
a lot of the guys...
because you have
a beautiful smile.
I can see some guy falling
for your smile alone.
She used to smile
for everyone, too.
How well did you know her?
I knew her.
Did you know she shot herself?
Committed suicide over some guy.
Maybe that's what we have
in common besides our name.
Men problems.
You said this was
a rough neighborhood at night.
You said you wanted someone
to walk you to your car.
I did.
I came this far because we had
an understanding, didn't we?
- An understanding.
- You said you wanted protection.
I'm just trying to be correct
about all this.
You're right,
and you're correct.
I scare you.
I just think
I can make it alone now.
What if I wanted to see
more of you privately?
You'd have to really want that.
Good night.
Hi, Ann. Come on in.
- Good morning.
- What time is it?
- Do you want some coffee?
- Please.
Great. Cream and sugar or black?
Actually, I'm not going to have
coffee.
I have to go
to the phone company.
Did you want to take
a grand tour?
- Maybe later.
- Is that all you brought?
Yeah. A mover's coming with
the rest.
It's not much, though.
Here's the key, and...
Let's see, I usually leave
for work around 4:00.
I get off at 5:00.
That's great. We should get
along just fine.
Let me think.
The refrigerator
always needs help, and...
Hot water's always hot.
- I shouldn't be long.
- Neither should he.
Eve, come here.
This is Ernest Greene.
- Am I bothering you?
- Nancy?
Am I?
I've always said you could call
on this line day or night...
if there's a problem.
Now, what is the problem?
I just want to talk with you.
I've moved again.
I see. Would you like
to come in to discuss it?
No. Over the phone.
You know I'll only do it
over the phone.
Please.
If you can't accept that...
I'll find someone who will.
I'm with another patient now.
I can call you
after the session...
No. It's all right. It'll be OK.
I'm sorry I got upset. Sorry.
Jerk.
No. Don't try to fight.
Don't tell me that.
I know it's not true.
You're lying. You're lying.
You're always lying.
Yes, sir?
What time's the next bus
leave for Las Vegas?
- Hi, Babs.
- Hi, Lou.
2:38.
How much?
$93.48.
That's tax included, one way.
Can I go on credit?
We'll take a credit card,
if that's what you mean.
All my credit cards and
my money's in Las Vegas.
Sorry, sir.
Bum a smoke?
Don't have any matches.
Got a match?
Having trouble with that Spatzel
out there?
Yeah, friggin' monster.
I've been working on that clutch
assembly two whole days.
They ain't even made in America.
This ain't working either.
They're gonna can my ass
if I don't fix it today.
I can fix it.
Trick is, you got to rotate
the flywheel just right.
I worked at the plant
in Stuttgart.
I'll fix that thing
in half an hour.
There's 20 bucks in it for you.
Let's go.
Can I give you the rest later
on that ticket to Las Vegas?
I'm really sorry, sir.
I still can't do it.
Of course you can't.
Got some place
I can change my clothes?
There's a rest room in the back.
I'd better be going.
I got a lot of errands to run.
Thank you.
Listen, if my phone rings,
don't worry about it.
I don't mind answering.
That's right.
It's your profession.
What a night I had.
I'm sorry I came by so early.
You were on time. I was off.
I can't imagine you off, Eve.
See you.
Is Eve there?
- No, she isn't.
- Who is this?
Would you like
to leave a message?
There is a message,
but first tell me who this is.
I'm Ann. Eve's new roommate.
Roommate?
Can you tell Eve
that Zack called?
That's all, Zack?
That isn't all. Tell her
that Pearl knows everything.
Will Eve know what that means?
I wish she didn't, but she will.
Maybe you should
tell her yourself, Zack.
Somehow things work out
differently that way.
What do you mean
"things work out differently"?
How old are you, Zack?
J'ai I'age du temps.
He's right there,
you know what I mean?
He looks at you, he listens...
He's a good lover.
Being a good lover's
a distant third...
in that race as far
as I'm concerned.
Do you have other lovers, Diane?
That's the reason I called.
There's this guy at work.
He got a crush on me.
Last night, I made love with him
for the first time.
Why did you do that?
Because something happened,
and it was late and...
I wanted a man to hold me.
He's not for me, though.
Sometimes I wonder
if there is anyone for me.
I met this other guy yesterday.
I swear to God, I almost
fell for him in a minute.
Then he came on in a crazy way,
and I got confused.
Nancy, stand by
for a station break.
Bullshit.
- You think I'm pretty loose.
- No, I don't think that.
I don't judge any of my callers,
Diane...
but we have to break
for a commercial.
I think that when
you speak to Dr. Love...
you should phrase the call
in something like...
you can't separate
pain from pleasure.
Then she'll be able to get right
to your problem.
So... what gives, babe?
I'm getting more attention
from the saxophone player.
You were in a panic last night.
I thanked you for last night.
Jesus Christ. You call me
at 4:00 in the morning.
Last night you couldn't
live without me...
and today
we're fucking strangers?
It'll never happen again.
God damn it, I want it to.
We are not talking about
this anymore, is that clear?
Good.
Yes? What, honey?
Tell me, Eve...
why do you suppose
men are drawn to you?
Because I don't ask
dumb questions.
Two inches of head, right?
Right. And a Smirnoff shooter.
You like her, don't you?
Could be.
How come?
Her name reminds me of someone.
Just her name?
Different face, different
personality, same name.
What happened to the other one?
We were supposed to get married.
Married again?
She would have been the first.
I asked her twice.
So what happened?
I was in the Air Force...
jet pilot.
Met her in a bar.
Walked her to her car,
kissed her...
asked her to marry me.
She met another guy
a week before the wedding.
So what did you do?
What did I do?
I became a mechanic...
a spy, gambler, madman.
Don't forget photog...
Photographer.
I'll be right back.
Don't go away, OK?
Wouldn't think of it.
Get home safely last night?
Yeah. Fine.
Everything worked out fine.
Well?
Well, what?
When can I see you again?
You said I had to really
want that, and I really do.
It's meant to be, right?
I could give you
her phone number and address.
- My old man sees her sometimes.
- Your father?
He's old enough to be my father,
but he's my husband.
We're separated. He doesn't
go over there all the time...
just when he thinks
I'm not looking.
So I come in here
to try and catch him.
She doesn't know who I am.
You really a gambler?
Sometimes.
There's a big game
a few blocks from my house.
Real serious stuff.
I could drop you there
on my way home.
Let's go.
Night, Eve.
Can I ask you something?
You just did.
What I mean is...
what did you do about the man
who stole your woman?
I killed him.
Liar.
How did you kill him?
Shot him with his own gun.
Self-defense.
That's why my wife divorced me.
My second wife.
And then you went to Russia
to forget.
No. That was before.
That's why my wife divorced me.
My first wife.
She heard I was brainwashed.
Wow! Did it hurt?
- What?
- The divorce.
- They always hurt.
- That's what I've heard.
See the buzzer by the door?
Push it and tell them Whitey
said it was all right.
Right. Thanks.
Are you really a photographer?
Six covers of Newsweek,
three of Esquire.
Wow. That's what I need...
a good job.
You know what my favorite job
would be of all time?
To be the radio talk lady...
Dr. Nancy Love.
Ever listen to her?
I don't listen to radio talk.
You should,
because she's real smart.
Just think, having a job where
you talk on the phone all day...
and get paid for it.
Women trust her.
Men fantasize about her.
What a life.
I hear she's tall and blonde.
Would you like
to take my picture?
I could marry you.
God, you're crazy...
but the key's
still under the mat.
This is Eve's phone number
and address.
I forgot to give it to you.
What a guy.
Why did you come here, Zack?
I had to see you.
I called your house.
I spoke to your new
roommate... Ann.
What?
She's a very perceptive woman.
Clarified a few things for me.
She did what?
Don't worry. They're all good.
But we must talk.
I want to see you. Tonight.
We've been through this
too many times before.
Listen, Eve...
Ann told me something
that really helped...
but we must talk.
Come back around 2:00.
We'll talk.
Max?
Daddy's here.
I'm feeling lucky tonight.
Good. The moon is in Pluto.
My throat is so sore.
It is to you, Zack.
Five.
Bump five.
My judgment goes kaput, ja?
Well, this is the last card,
gentlemen.
Got any more smokes?
Zigarette, bitte.
Ten.
Bump ten.
Raise you twenty.
Bump 20.
That hole must be magic.
Cost you twenty more
to find out.
Who'd you say told you about
this place, mister?
I didn't.
Didn't think you did.
Thirty...
six.
Max?
No, not with the moon in Pluto.
Call it a day.
I got things to do now.
Did I tell you
I don't like your face, mister?
Did you get that impression?
I hadn't noticed.
Attention
qu'est-ce que tu dis, eh?
Les murs ont des oreilles.
I don't want to see you
around, mister.
Madame X.
Zigarette, mein freund?
Next time, Fritz.
Ciao.
Auf wiedersehen.
Another game, gentlemen?
Nancy, this is Ernest Greene.
You never called back.
I'm having dinner with someone.
You had me worried.
I'm fine. I'm working.
There's a sound in your voice,
Nancy.
I'm fine.
You don't sound fine.
Are you on any medication?
I'm beginning to understand
myself better now...
entering a more knowing phase.
And I know that I remain
my own worst enemy.
But I also know
that I am my own savior...
because freedom
means responsibility.
You're not making any sense.
And believe me,
I also know how easily...
desire can be converted to deed.
Even when I close my eyes...
I have to be careful
of what I dream and how.
All right, Nancy.
It's happening again.
I want to see you first thing
in the morning.
I don't care
what your schedule is.
I have to go. I wouldn't want
to be rude to my guest.
Thanks for your concern.
I'll call tomorrow.
Nancy, listen to me.
Don't hang up...
All I was asking was for
some time to think about it.
You're married, but not to me.
You don't want to get married.
That's not the point.
Stop it.
What are you doing here?
This is my friend Mickey.
He's a photographer,
and I met him at Eve's.
Don't fight.
Please don't fight, Zack.
Stop it, you guys!
Don't! Don't fight!
- Flowers!
- Your favorites.
Please, be careful.
He said he'd killed a man.
You're wearing our wedding ring.
The money.
I'm gonna get it
one way or another.
Don't you know about fucking
somebody else's wife, pervert.
And then photographing
what you did.
Don't shoot, Zack.
You want to put
that gun away, friend.
You can do it with the ladies
on Adams Street...
but not with my wife.
Leave him alone, Zack.
He didn't know we were married.
I want my money.
You're not going to shoot me.
We both know
you can't do it here.
You're a dead man, pervert.
I love my flowers,
and I love you.
Tu m'as manqué, ma petite.
C'était triste sans toi.
Will you come home around 3:00,
like last night?
Like last night, and the next...
and hopefully
the one after that.
- Were you ever married?
- Nope, and I don't plan to be.
May I ask why?
Sure, you can,
and I'll tell you why, Ann.
Because I wouldn't want
my marriage to fail.
One way or another they all do.
Maybe not with the right man.
All my men are the right man.
You talked to one yesterday.
What's your opinion?
You're angry, and I'm sorry.
No, I'm not.
I should probably thank you.
It was the sweetest
Zack's been to me in months.
I'll try to be more quiet
when I come in tonight.
No problem.
I'd just gone to bed myself.
I was at a dinner party.
Yeah? Did you get lucky?
Lucky? I think so. Very lucky.
This is Mickey.
Does it bother you
that I called?
Would it bother you
if I came over?
I need a place to lie down
for a while.
Look, I'm just tired,
that's all.
You don't even have
to talk to me.
Great. I'll be there
in half an hour.
Is Eve around?
That's blood.
You know when she'll be back?
3:00 in the morning.
How did you know I was hungry?
It was in your eyes.
It's also in my stomach.
Less than in your eyes.
What's your name?
What's yours?
I remember seeing you
at Eve's place.
Were you there?
What's your name?
Ann.
Mickey.
Have you known Eve long?
I just moved in here.
It's nice.
Eve's very nice,
don't you think?
Yes. I like her.
I do, too.
There's a strength about her.
Very solid.
I'm impressed. I truly am.
I think she's a blink away
from going off.
I've seen it before.
No, not at all.
I'm a good judge of people.
She's one of
the more stable ones.
I remember you now.
What do you do, Ann?
I operate
a telephone answering service.
You like to talk on the phone.
It's comfortable for me.
I learn a lot on the phone.
Not having to deal with the
complexities of people's faces.
Getting straight answers
if I ask straight questions.
I mean, when I ask questions,
that is.
Someone told me last night...
they thought the best job
of all time...
would be to talk on the phone
all day long... radio talk.
What did you say?
They had to be
some radio doctor...
named Norma Love or
Nancy Love or something.
Yeah, Nancy Love.
You don't know
who Nancy Love is?
Truthfully?
Always.
She's quite popular, you know.
That's why I asked you.
- Smart?
- Her?
Extremely smart.
She helps a great deal
of people.
Good.
But there's a price involved.
She can help others,
but not herself.
She gives advice to
the lovelorn every day...
but she's never been in love
herself.
Or so I've heard.
Rough.
Some people worship her.
Can you imagine how hard
that must be to live with?
Knowing that anything
you ever say to anyone...
will count heavily,
be acted upon...
whether you're right or wrong.
There's tremendous
responsibility in that.
She'd have to live
a life of secrecy...
to avoid that kind of pressure.
Even then,
she'd have to be careful...
of listening to herself,
you know?
And she must wonder about
her own life experiences.
She must have difficulty
touching life...
because she gives so much of
herself to others.
She spends so much of her time
absorbing others.
People really listen
to that shit?
Yes, they do. Believe me.
I've heard her show before.
I can tell.
Very complex person.
I would imagine very few people
understand her.
She must do
some eccentric things...
that have become quite natural
to her, you know?
Half in, half out of reality.
Yeah. Very complex.
Men fantasize about her,
women trust her.
You're right.
I think that's true.
How long have you known Eve?
You already asked me that.
Then you said she was solid,
and I said she was scared.
Then you talked
about Norma Love.
Nancy Love. Scared of what?
What else? Herself.
Yeah. Interesting.
You must be close.
I met her the day
you were there.
And she gave you
her phone number and address?
She didn't give them to me.
I kissed her, too.
I wanted to kiss her more.
She wouldn't let you?
We ran out of time, that's all.
So you've come here
for more time.
I came here to get some rest,
get cleaned up, food.
I see, but kissing
would come later.
It's up to you.
I beg your pardon.
No, you don't.
What are you doing?
The same thing you are.
No, you're mistaken.
I need a woman right now.
- I can tell.
- Can you use a man?
No, I don't. I can't.
It's been...
Yeah. I thought so.
Which room's yours?
This is silly. Really silly.
I know it's the wine.
It's blood, not wine.
Marry me.
I'm serious.
We don't know each other.
What did we just do,
become strangers?
We can take the bus to Vegas.
I can get money there.
I have to go to work.
Let someone else answer
the phone. Marry me.
You may never get
as good an offer.
I've been engaged three times.
Married two of those...
colonel's daughter and
a teacher's assistant.
I loved them both.
I'd still be married...
if something hadn't
happened each time.
So what happened?
What didn't? A little foreign
intrigue with one...
domestic crime with the other.
They were both forced
to divorce me. I understood.
Got nothing to do
with you and me.
You came over here
expecting Eve.
I might have married her,
but she wasn't home.
You're impossible.
- You mean crazy?
- I didn't say that.
I hear it enough.
You think I'm crazy?
I can give you a few pointers.
I have to go to work.
Forget work.
I can get money in Vegas.
You'll never have to work again.
Marry me, damn it.
You can't go around asking
everyone you kiss to marry you.
Why not?
I only kiss women I'd marry.
And once I'm married to them,
I never cheat.
That's the way it is with me.
My wives own me.
It's everybody else
that breaks you up...
governments, cops, hospitals.
It's crazy.
I know it's the wine...
and you know, I'm leaving.
And I think
you should leave, too.
So you're not coming to Vegas
with me?
Pick up some dough,
get married, start something.
You're not serious, Mickey.
Even if you were, I can't.
I am serious. I told you.
So give me one good reason.
And don't say because
we don't know each other.
I'm not...
You see,
other people's problems...
Your best reason.
I've never loved anyone.
I don't think I can.
I think you just don't know
enough about it.
I could teach you that, too.
How to be crazy,
how to be in love.
Please go now.
Dr. Love doesn't believe...
that sex is the most important
thing in a relationship, Stella.
Have you figured out why your
husband sees other women...
if he says he loves you?
People have
to cultivate each other.
He loves sex,
and he loves to mess around.
- He does?
- Yeah, he does.
You knew that about him
when you married him.
That's why I married him.
Sex is all we had in common.
He's twice my age,
and it was great...
but then we started talking,
and it stopped working.
I love him. I really do,
even though he roughs me up.
At least he cares enough
to do it.
Dr. Love, I need your help.
I'm trying to help you, Rita.
Do you know what it is when you
feel something for somebody...
and you don't know what it is...
because if you knew
what it was...
you wouldn't feel it anymore?
It sort of happens,
and then it goes away.
Maybe it's just not one man.
Maybe it's a feeling
you have for all men.
Sex, like everything else,
is largely a mystery.
There's no such thing
as normal sex.
Normal sex
is a matter of statistics.
What may be normal
for the vast majority...
is no criterion of behavior
for the exceptional person.
But I am exceptional.
Throughout history, individuals
of the first rank...
would never have produced had
they not been immersed in sex...
and spontaneous sexual behavior.
I mean that uncontrollable
impulse...
that shakes you
to your very foundation...
that makes your nerve ends
tickle and your head spin...
and that makes
you feel like jelly.
You may think it's wine, Rita,
but it's not, it's blood...
and there's nothing wrong
with that feeling.
We all need to get it.
We all need it.
There's nothing wrong with it!
But I know about all that.
Nancy, stand by
for a station break.
I'm sorry, Rita, we're going
for a station identification.
She's just sensational. God!
Don't go away. We'll be back...
with more of Dr. Nancy Love
and The Love Line...
right here on KCMY Talk Radio.
Bradshaw, cue the I.D.
- Feel OK?
- What?
I said, are you feeling
all right?
I got to make a phone call.
I know Dr. Love is very
concerned...
about emotional fulfillment...
but she's also been
concerned these days...
with the necessity
for sexual fulfillment.
Yet you're still drawn to her?
She'll be on with you
in about 20 minutes...
after the next call.
- I don't know.
- It's a long call, yeah.
I just met him.
We've only talked a few times...
but I'm attracted to him.
I think about him.
Does it bother you that you
could be attracted...
to someone you hardly know?
It bothers me more that I might
not be able to see him again.
Maybe what concerns me
is that I'm not sure...
I'm able to give myself
to anyone.
Then along comes this guy
who could be the right type...
and I play hard to get.
I don't know.
Maybe I should've given in
to a few things.
You mean sexual things?
There she goes again.
Sex? Are you kidding?
I wrote the book on sex.
I'm a prisoner of it.
Hell, I'm a victim of it.
I know all about that feeling...
you get in your belly
when a man says he wants you.
Even if I know he's lying,
I still get that feeling.
I'm conditioned now.
I understand, Karen.
Do you? Then what do I do,
if you understand?
What in the hell
should I be doing?
I'm not sure that I know what
you're after.
I mean, I'm not sure that...
you can do things like that
on the spur of the moment.
You mean fall for some guy
or resist him?
Giving in. No, giving in,
either to him or to yourself.
And yet, there's something
so thrilling about giving in.
Don't you think, Karen?
I thought that was what was
wrong with me.
I trusted the moment too much.
That's why I never got married.
I know that much about myself.
There'd always be another moment
with another man.
This man we're talking about...
Where is he now?
Can you talk to him now?
No. I may never see him again.
Can't you reach him?
Didn't he call you?
No, he didn't call me.
He doesn't have my number.
I thought he called.
Now you said he asked you
to marry him.
No. He was only joking.
Look, what I'm trying to tell
you is that I don't think...
I can make marriage
last with anyone.
If you can't see him,
what will you do?
Won't kill me.
Maybe it wasn't even him.
Maybe it was just the thrill
of it, like you said.
Yes. The thrill.
He sure seemed OK, though.
Honest, somehow.
Somehow it made sense
in a funny way.
We didn't even talk that much.
Like he said,
sex doesn't make you strangers.
We didn't have sex.
I thought you said
you made love with him.
No. He kissed me. Once.
It was very first kiss-like,
you know what I mean?
It's a wonderful feeling.
I just love that feeling.
Karen, what would you think
of a man...
who'd kiss only women
he'd marry?
I never met a man like that,
although you know what?
There is a little bit of that
in this guy.
Don't you think
she's going overboard?
Come on, just answer your calls.
I know what that woman needs...
and I'd like to give it to her.
We have to break for the news.
I've enjoyed talking with you.
I hope we can do that again.
I mean that.
You never know, Dr. Love.
And I hope you find that man
again.
You're listening to KCMY...
the home of Dr. Nancy Love
and The Love Line...
here on 97 Talk Radio.
That's quite a show, Nancy.
Very provocative.
Sun went down
about four hours ago.
Jesus Christ. Who gave you that?
You know this guy.
He comes in here a lot.
What's his name?
What difference does it make
what his name is?
Look, what are you getting
so upset with me about?
You know him, and he's mine.
He can get dangerous...
but it's nothing like me
if you don't stop seeing him.
Why don't you tell him that?
Because I'm telling you,
Eve, woman to woman.
Leave him alone.
Hey, how's it going?
You know anything about
Spatzel master cylinders?
There's 20 bucks in it for you.
I need 93.48, including tax.
What are you trying to do,
put the squeeze on me?
Look, I could afford maybe 50?
Yeah, OK. 50.
Did you really work over there
in that factory in Germany?
- Jawohl.
- How'd you manage that?
I was doing intelligence work
for the Air Force...
following a connection
out of East Berlin.
Ultimately,
it took me to Moscow...
where I was arrested
by the KGB...
and the CIA had to trade for me.
Sorry I asked. Good night, Babs.
Good night, Lou.
I'll walk you to your car.
I'm tired, Bill.
I said walk.
Thanks. See you tomorrow.
I'm not gonna always be here,
you know that?
Nobody's always here.
Your choice.
Nope. I think it's beyond me.
It wasn't beyond you to get your
ass off the street corner...
into a place of your own,
was it?
How dare you talk to me
like that?
I want you.
Trying to scare me?
What are you doing here?
I just didn't want
to go into the lounge.
But I had to see you.
Please, get out of my car.
I want to go home.
Home. Right.
Listen, about that...
Don't touch me!
Look, I've seen
some of your handiwork.
Now, there's a gun in this car,
OK?
A gun, huh?
Why did you do that to her?
I didn't do anything to her.
We did something together.
It happened. It's over.
I thought I was through
getting involved...
with men who are trouble.
Falling in love on a look.
I can't look at you.
You have perfection about you.
Oh, brother.
Perfection. Me.
Your eyes have music.
Your heart's the best part
of your body.
And when you move...
every man, woman, and child
is forced to watch.
You really can make it up.
I'll give you that much.
I'm an expert.
I make everything up.
I'm a pathological liar.
That's why they locked me up
in a mental home.
I make everything up...
except this.
Why am I so privileged?
Because your name reminds me of
a time when I was a lot happier.
And I came here looking for...
some of that time.
And there you were
under the blinking sign.
And now I get
this strange feeling...
that it's all part of some plan,
so why fight it?
I want you, Eve.
I want you to want me.
Sure, there might be
someone else...
that'd fit the bill
for either one of us...
but we're here now, they're not.
And there isn't as much time
as there used to be.
So I just want to go home
to Vegas...
pick up a few things for
the future... yours and mine.
I want to marry you, Eve.
I got this thing about marriage.
You really are out of your mind.
And you're not?
So tell me who isn't out of
their goddamn mind.
Most marriages don't last,
you know.
Probably because
they start out like this.
Is that a "yes"?
I'm not going to marry anybody.
OK?
God!
Zack! What the hell...
Stay out of this.
Every time I see you,
I feel bad.
You're messing up my life,
pervert.
I was thinking the same thing
about you.
Zack, what are you...
Jesus Christ!
This guy's fucking up
everything I got.
My money, you, my wife.
- Your wife?
- He's full of shit.
Listen to this.
First he sleeps with her.
I understand. I'm French.
But then he's taking nude
pictures of her when I walk in.
The guy's a pervert.
It's my duty as a citizen
to eliminate him.
He broke my nose!
Are you all right?
Fine. Thanks. I'm just thirsty.
I heard your car arrive.
I hope you don't mind.
I couldn't sleep.
I was hoping we could talk.
I don't much feel like talking.
I understand.
Maybe you'll listen.
Listening I can do, Ann.
You really don't know
that much about me, Eve.
For instance, my name isn't Ann.
And I have lived with people
before, but it was always...
like research.
Maybe I should listen to this
in the morning.
I've had a rough night.
It shouldn't wait until morning.
It concerns Mickey,
and I want to clear that up.
How do you know about Mickey?
He was over here today.
Looking for you.
What?
I'm a very complicated person...
not all of which
I can explain to you now.
Look, I don't want to hear about
any of this, Ann...
or whatever your name is.
I don't think I could take it.
Mickey said that you two
had just met each other.
I know that played an
important part in my behavior.
Look...
I don't even know this man.
From my point of view,
I'm sure it's just sexual.
I've been with men before...
but it was always some sort of
planned event.
No matter how attached
I'd become to a man's sex...
I was always more interested
in the person who owned it.
But...
this is new for me.
This is a major breakthrough.
From Mickey,
I learned that, perhaps...
when a man enters your life
through your sex...
it might just be as good a way
as any.
Isn't that marvelous? All along
I'm thinking it's the wine.
And, Eve, seeing how you
admit...
that you don't really know him
all that well...
I'm wondering
if we might share him.
Are you telling me that Mickey
found out where I lived...
and that he came here and that
you were home...
and that you fucked him?
He said you barely knew each
other.
Eve, you just said that
yourself.
And he was quite taken with me.
As a matter of fact...
as strange as it sounds,
he asked me to marry him.
Now, it was amusing,
but most interesting.
At least part of him
was serious.
I got excited. I admit it.
You would have done
the same, Eve.
And for a while,
I thought it was simply...
sensual pleasure, you see.
I even said that on the radi...
at work this afternoon.
But now it's evolving
even further.
It's all very exciting
because it'll have...
a tremendous impact
on a great number of people.
I don't want
to get into all this.
I'm sorry about it,
but knowing all the facts...
and under the circumstances...
I don't think that I did
something all that wrong.
After all, it's not as if you
owned the man.
No. I don't own him.
I don't own any man,
and I never have...
and no man owns me.
I used to think
I wanted to own this house.
Now I don't care.
Why don't you keep it?
You seem to be much more
comfortable here than I do.
Why don't you
just keep the house...
and all the men I've collected?
You're not listening, Eve!
I just want to help.
Ann? Is that you?
No. I mean, yes. It's me.
Who's this?
I miss you.
You're the first person in years
who's understood me.
You don't have to say anything.
Thanks, soldier.
How about you? Need anything?
You don't want to kiss me.
It won't cost you much
to find out.
I got ten bucks.
You got a car.
Forget it, soldier.
I don't do it in cars.
I'll give you the ten to take me
to the end of Garden Street.
That's blood again
on your shirt.
Where is she?
I need to see Eve.
I told her about us.
What did she say?
It was very helpful.
She said she didn't own anybody.
You sorry I told her?
Well, you can't lie.
You sorry it's me?
She has my suitcase in her car.
Right. I remember that suitcase.
You!
Please stop it, both of you.
Mickey, I know the man.
Put the gun down.
I'm telling you I know him.
I'm going to kill
the son of a bitch. Get up!
Don't you fucking move.
You don't think I'd do it,
do you?
I've done it before,
right in this town.
It was just like this...
him or me.
Go ahead, pervert. Shoot me.
He doesn't mean it.
Zack's a very caring person.
The guy's a goddamn menace.
He's not going to shoot me.
Are you, Zack?
You I want to talk to.
It's him I want to kill.
Please come back later.
I want to talk to you...
and I have to talk to him.
I'd rather hear the gun go off
than listen to this shit.
Hey, handsome.
- Need some company, maybe?
- Oh, God.
Guess not.
Get away from me.
I'll kill myself.
I swear to God I will.
No, you won't.
You don't have anything
to say about it.
I'm doing this for me.
Ever wonder what it is with you
and women named Eve?
I am never going to forgive
my father for calling me that.
If I knew who he was.
Don't! One more step,
and you'll get splattered.
That's right.
Now get away from me.
Get away.
I've always found
the naughty part of town.
Futile fucking hopes.
Vengeful dreams.
How do you like that?
Professor Poet.
You don't mean it, Eve.
How do you know what I mean?
Who do you think you are
lying to me all the time?
You are no better than I am.
You and me are just the same.
Then maybe I should join you.
What are you doing?
You're not alone in the dark.
Fuck hope and dreams.
Mickey, don't do that.
Come on back.
Please, Mickey?
Mine wasn't loaded.
Neither was mine.
Imagine whatever you say to
anyone...
will count heavily,
be acted upon...
whether you're right or wrong.
That's a tremendous
responsibility.
I never thought of that.
So I'm learning, Betty,
like you and so many others.
I'm devoting my life to learn
about men and women.
But you have to help me,
Dr. Love.
I've no one else
I can discuss this with.
I'll do whatever you tell me.
But that's my point, Betty.
You can't just listen to me.
Even I have to be careful of
listening to myself.
But, Dr. Love,
everybody listens to you.
Betty, I'm not God.
I mean, I share with you...
the sum of my experiences
and my knowledge...
but I'm just a clown.
You are so wonderful.
I think you're just fantastic.
Thank you so much
for being there for me.
I don't know what I'd do
without you.
I listen to you every day.
You're the greatest person.
What are you always worried
about money for?
- 'Cause I ain't got none.
- Nice show, don't you think?
See you later, Ralph.
How about dinner tonight?
Well, Nancy,
let me think about it.
Yes. Well, you think about it.
Tune in 2:00 to 5:00
for another session...
with Dr. Nancy Love on KCMY,
your station.
On vacation in Las Vegas?
Gambling?
You could call it that.
- I'm on my honeymoon.
- Oh, how lovely.
Had you been planning it
for long?
All my life.
Marriage is a very sacred thing.
So I've heard.
Marriage is a sacred thing.
Isn't it?
In a beautiful but sordid way.
I don't know why
I ask you anything.
You're a lunatic.
That's why you chose me.