'Ho, ho, ho!
'Hello, children!
'This is Father Christmas speaking.
'Welcome to my Christmas sweet factory,
'where my little helpers make
all those lovely tasty sweets
'that go into your Christmas stocking.
'Watch how it's done.
'First of all, they fill the special
sweet-making machine with sugar
'and then they add
all the other lovely mixtures
'that go to make up your favourite sweets.
'Here you can see
some of my little helpers...'
God rest ye merry, gentlemen
Let nothing you dismay
Remember Christ, our Saviour,
was born on Christmas Day
To save us all from Satan's power
when we were gone astray
O tidings of comfort and joy,
comfort and joy
O tidings of comfort and joy
In Bethlehem in Jewry
this blessed babe was born
And laid within a manger
upon this blessed morn
The which His Mother Mary
nothing did take in scorn
O tidings of comfort and joy,
comfort and Joy
O tidings of comfort and joy
From God our Heavenly Father
a blessed angel came
And unto certain shepherds
brought tidings of the same...
- Thank you. Bye.
- Bye-bye.
- You'll be the death of me, Maddy.
- Shut up and get the car.
You're going bald. It must be nerves.
Thank you.
Shit, these are all size large.
You've got to stop it, Maddy.
I can't stand the strain.
Stay home, then.
If you've got to steal things,
then at least be practical.
We needed onions.
We did not need more Christmas lights.
You buy the food, I'll get the goodies.
Please don't smoke in the car, Maddy.
Stop it. Stop it.
Now, Maddy, have you any idea
what a burning cigarette
can do to velour upholstery?
I can live with the pollution,
but you're becoming a fire hazard too,
and that's a problem.
Now, look, don't get me wrong.
I'm not worried about the car.
I can live without it.
It's your own safety that concerns me.
The summer's gone...
And all the leaves are dying...
Hm. Very, very nice.
Thank you, Maddy. Mwah!
But why the four sets of Christmas lights?
I want to have lots of lights on the tree.
Uh-huh. Well, we can always use
the other two sets as spares.
No, they'll all go on the tree.
OK. OK.
OK.
Do you want to go out tonight?
No.
Do you want to eat?
Later.
Do you want to wrap
Auntie Betty's handbag?
No.
- No?
- No.
- No? No, no?
No, no, no? No?
Mm...
Mm-mm.
- What time is it, Alan?
- Christmas time, I think. Mm-hm.
Oh, God.
Just a wee something.
Cheers.
Maddy, I think it's time we took some
of the price tags off these things.
Why?
I think there were some tags
on the olives.
OK.
What are you doing?
Are you collecting them or what?
I am, yeah. You get a Ford Fiesta.
Are you sure you don't want to go out,
Maddy? It's only eight.
Er... no.
Maddy? What are you up to?
I'm leaving, Alan.
I'm taking some things,
my things, and I'm leaving.
I meant to tell you ages ago,
but the moment didn't arise.
I have to go.
I wanted to talk to you about it,
but it just didn't happen.
Maddy, please. Sit down.
We can talk about it now.
It's too late.
George is coming over soon.
He's, er... he's hired a truck.
I meant to tell you ages ago.
It's your sister set this up, didn't she?
It's your crazy sister!
No, it's me. I'm doing it.
I asked George to help me move out.
That... that's all.
To be honest,
this last room may take a while.
No, be all right.
Be finished quick, I would think.
Evening, Alan. All right?
- All right?
- Good evening.
Er... fellows,
if you could go through here...
- Aye, sure.
- There's a table and some chairs.
Well, you're quite serious
about this, then, Maddy?
Look, I'm really sorry about this, Alan.
I'm just helping out.
There'll be no hard feelings, eh?
I mean, it's just... you know, just women.
George, there's some more
chairs in the kitchen.
- Right, Maddy.
- Maddy, baby, please talk to me.
- Please stay and talk to me.
- Oh, don't let's drag it out, Alan.
Don't be cruel.
- Could you take that?
- Nice chair.
Aye, lovely. Sorry.
Maddy!
Please stop this, Alan.
You're not making it easy.
You don't make anything easy.
All right, just leave the book.
I'm reading it, eh?
- Just leave that book. I'm reading it.
- No, put it in the box. It's my book.
I'm halfway through it.
Could you just leave the damn book?
- You didn't buy it.
- Neither did you buy it.
- Well, it's mine.
- Oh, right.
Right. Well, that's my sweater, if it comes
down to it, so give me the sweater.
Oh, you're upset. Don't be childish.
If I'm a child, well, you're a thief!
I only wanted it as a keepsake.
But if you feel that strongly about it,
you can have it.
Have the book too, with my compliments.
I don't want to do this, you know.
I don't know why I'm doing this.
I don't want to do it.
Well, it's very good of you, Alan,
very good. No, no, no, down, down.
Now easy with the handle. Right.
So, you really, really
want to leave, then, eh?
You really want to go?
Now? Leave?
Yeah.
Huh!
It's a bit of a shock.
I know.
I wanted to get the lights
on the tree for you before I left.
Well, come upstairs and do that, then, eh?
No, you do it.
Don't leave it bare.
Can I drive you anywhere?
No, I'll go with George.
Be good.
It's six o'clock in the morning!
- Morning, Moira.
- Good morning, Dicky.
On 261 we're bringing you
the national news on the hour!
'This is the six o'clock news headlines
with Peter Porter reporting.
'More fighting has broken out
in Berunda, West Africa.
'Rival guerrilla groups are claiming victory
over President Mandi's Republican troops
'and Radio Berunda last night
announced a total curfew in the capital.'
In Washington, the Pentagon has confirmed
that the US fleet at present
exercising off the coast of Berunda
would continue its watching patrol.
In the Middle East, the hoped-for
settlement of fighting in Avonia
has hit new obstacles.
Delegates from both sides abandoned the
Christmas peace conference yesterday
and later fresh rocket attacks
took place at the capital's airport.
27 people died before UN troops
managed to stop the shelling.
And in the Far East,
40 civilian refugees died
in heavy bombing attacks
on the island of Samato
when the Christmas truce there
broke down yesterday.
Opponents of the dictatorship
government of President Barmai
claimed that the armed forces were
deliberately attacking civilian targets
as an act of provocation.
More foreign news.
Mamie, the giant panda,
recently arrived at the Moscow Zoo,
as a gift from
the People's Republic of China,
might just be pregnant.
Officials at the Moscow Zoo
said that tests today
should confirm the pregnancy.
All this week, Mamie has been off her food
and suffering from morning sickness.
Mamie needs peace and quiet now,
said the zoo official.
And lastly, the weather
for west central Scotland and the city.
This morning will be milder
than overnight,
still no sign of a white Christmas,
and some light rain might reach
the area by early evening.
The next news at seven,
and now stand by
for your daily dose of Dicky Bird.
National news on the hour!
Thanks for all that wonderful
six o'clock news, Peter.
You know, I keep telling him
that it would be cheaper
to telephone the early news
to those half a dozen poor souls
that have been listening
to yawn-a-minute Kelly all night,
- but he won't listen to me.
- Time to get up!
Hello, Dicky! Good morning!
Hello!
- Hello!
- Good morning! Tweet-tweet!
Anyway, the fun starts now
because Dicky Bird is here
to get you up, get you to work
or wherever it is you have to be by nine.
Don't you know what they say
about the early worm?
- The early worm!
- What do they say?
It always gets the bird
Yes, "The Dicky Bird Early Worm Show".
Hello there!
Oh. Hi, Steve.
- You OK, kid?
- Aye, I'm fine, I'm fine.
Keep your pecker up, eh?
He's done it again, folks.
Kelly's fallen asleep at the microphone.
I got here only just in time.
Anyway, here's a quick traffic roundup.
There's absolutely nothing in the streets
right now, not a car in sight,
so why don't you take advantage of that?
Get in your car
and get into work straightaway.
You'll be in three hours early,
and there'll be another traffic roundup
at the same time tomorrow.
And Nancy in the front office
has just come in to tell me that
the lookalikes competition has captured
her imagination again this week.
A man from Paisley has just phoned in
to say that his wife is the absolute
double of Richard Nixon.
Ha-ha-ha! We'll believe anything
that happens in Paisley,
but the rules are either a photograph
sent up here to the station
or why don't you just pop up
and let Nancy check you out in person?
And I can tell you that's a journey
very, very well worth making, eh?
Lookalike, lookalike, someday famous
I've just seen the very lovely Anne
coming in there
to give us the 8.30 travel roundup.
I wonder who Anne
thinks she looks like, eh?
I think there's a little touch
of the Ingrid Bergman in there, eh?
How are you, Annie? Are you all right?
'Thank you, yes, Dicky, I'm fine.'
OK, now, where should we avoid
traffic-wise today?
'Er... how about everywhere?'
Oh, dear, oh, dear, oh, dear!
I'll leave you to it, then.
'Thank you. Well, Dicky,
'Christmas traffic is expected to be
the main problem again today,
'with all city-centre car parks likely
to be filling up by mid-morning
'and a lot more vehicles prowling the
streets, looking for parking space, so...'
Would you get me a line, Nancy, please?
'If you can use public transport,
it will make sense for everybody.
'At the moment, however, traffic is
moving well on the Kingston Bridge
'despite the closure
of Bothwell Street exit
'and the tunnel northbound and
southbound is easing off now too.'
Hello, Colin? Yeah, Alan here, yeah.
I'm in deep trouble, friend.
Can you come over?
I'll see you at the house at about 11, OK?
And God bless.
'...for some snow on the A9
and M9 north of Perth.
'Nothing else at the moment
so back to you, Dicky.'
- Radio
- 261
You're on 261
Oh, boy.
- She really meant business, eh?
- Don't say that.
Well, what do you want me to say?
That she'll be back in a day or two,
with her tail between her legs
and the piano and the dining table?
She left the washing machine.
That could be a good sign, eh?
I don't see Maddy coming back
for a washing machine. Fur coat, maybe.
She, er... didn't leave
her fur coat, did she?
- Was everything hers?
- Mm-hm.
Except for the mortgage. That was mine.
Well, you know Maddy. She was
always acquiring things, you know.
She liked acquiring things.
What am I going to do?
Do you realise how lucky you are?
Don't you see
what an opportunity you have?
How many people our age
would give an arm and a leg
to be able to just break out
and start all over again?
It's a new life. That's what
you've been handed on a plate.
And look around you.
Everything here is you.
This little table is you.
The book there. I mean, it's you.
There's nothing but you here now.
What a chance!
Look, you've been submerged
in another person's personality,
become a sub-person, and now you're free.
Well, thanks a lot.
Why didn't you tell me all this before?
Because Maddy was
just utterly fantastic and special...
and you deserved as much of her
as you were going to get.
But now you've had it.
It's your turn now.
Anyway, there was always
something unreal about you two.
You were like kids, playing and fighting.
It was a bit of a caper, wasn't it?
No, no, don't say that.
No, I worshipped her.
That's not the nicest thing
you can do to somebody, is it?
- I hope you don't worship me.
- No. No, you're my friend.
- Did Maddy take the telephone?
- No, no, it's...
it's in there.
286, please.
It works. You're still in business.
Rhona? It's Colin.
Uh-huh.
Er... where does it come from?
Ah. What age?
What was it? An accident?
Erm... good.
Er... well, you fix up
the theatre for, er... two.
Uh-huh.
Get the pre-med finished
and I'll see you in, er... ten minutes, OK?
Um... I've got to go and introduce
somebody to a second-hand kidney.
What will you do?
I'll do some shopping, get some things
for the house, pots and pans and things.
Good lad.
Erm... want to eat with us tonight?
Er... yeah, maybe. I'll let you know.
OK.
Colin?
- Do you think she loved me?
- Sure she did.
She told me one night when she was drunk.
- She never told me.
- Well, she wouldn't.
Where was I at the time?
You were through in the kitchen
telling Fiona you loved her.
You were drunk too.
You know you can have
all three products the same colour?
- Aye, I know it. It doesn't matter.
- Sure? OK.
I kind of like to mix and match.
I just thought it might look nicer.
'No less than eight Christmas truces
are in jeopardy around the world today,
'and intense diplomatic activity continues
'in an effort to reduce global tension.
'In the Middle East, the American
Special Envoy had breakfast meetings
'with rival Palazi leaders in Avonia,
'whilst heavy fighting continued
on the outskirts of the city.
'He said later, "We will have
peace here at any price."
'Mamie the giant panda is said to be
comfortable and well at Moscow Zoo,
'shortly after her pregnancy
was confirmed.'
Frosty the snowman
was alive as he could be
And the children say
he could laugh and play...
'...population in the capital in acts
of looting and other violence.'
Ba-do-ba-do-ba
- Ba-ba-doba-do-ba
- Sit tight
We'll bring you the traffic situation
right now in your car
Right now in your car
'Hello, folks!
'Hello, folks!'
- Yes, please, sir?
- A 99, please.
- With or without?
- Hm?
- Raspberry.
- Oh, with, please.
Right.
There you are.
And a, er... a Highland Toffee, please.
- Thank you.
- There you are. Thank you.
Thank you.
Ah, you...
Come on!
Just beat it!
- Get to hell, the pair of you!
- Oh! Oh!
Hey! It's you, isn't it?
It's Dicky Bird! Dicky Bird's here!
- For God's sake, get in the car!
- Give us an autograph, Dicky.
- I'm sorry, I don't have a pen on me.
- Come on! Let's get out of here!
Give us a dedication at least, eh?
For my mother.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Sure, sure.
- Tomorrow morning.
- Right.
Have you any Mantovani or Dean Martin?
Oh, bound to, bound to, yeah.
What, "Memories Are Made Of This"?
Aye, lovely.
Yes, sir, can I help you?
- A refill for your 99?
- Are you OK?
What? Yes, everything's under control.
Don't worry about a thing, sir.
- Was there something you wanted?
- Are you hurt? Is that blood?
Eh? Oh, no, no, no.
It's just raspberry essence.
Don't worry about a thing.
Just some high-spirited youths, that's all.
Now, if there's nothing else you want,
I think we'd better be on our way.
'Hello, folks! Hello, folks! Hello, folks!
'Hello, folks! Hello, folks!
'Hello, folks!'
Oh...!
Maddy!
Oh, baby. Oh.
- Have you still got a bed?
- Mm-hm.
Oh, I've missed you, Maddy.
Oh...
Where did you get these pyjamas?
I was cold. I don't need them.
Can I stay the night?
You can stay forever. You know that.
OK.
I'll stay forever.
Mm.
Oh.
Oh, shit.
Shit!
Oh...
National news!
National news on the hour
'Another border clash took place
in the night in the Bulati mountains
'between troops of Bulati and Nigora.
'A Bulati Army statement claimed...'
- Keith?
- Yeah?
Fix me up a booth
for ten o'clock, will you?
I'd like to do some commercials
and some trailers for the weekend.
- You could edit them, OK?
- Sure thing, Alan.
- Oh, Keith?
- Yeah?
What would clean ice-cream stains
off velour upholstery?
Er... now, that sounds like
a hot-water-and-detergent job.
But you'd need to wet the whole seat
so it wouldn't leave a mark.
- It'll be a bit tricky.
- OK, thanks.
Thrifty Pops, the big, big bag of munchies
That last the whole day
Thrifty Pops, Thrifty Pops.
You just munch them all day.
They never stop.
Thrifty Pops, Thrifty Pops,
I want them now
Thrifty Pops, the big, big bag
of munchies that last all day!
Well, it was a bit dry, maybe.
All right, spin it again.
Thrifty Pops, the big, big bag of munchies
That last the whole day
Thrifty Pops! Thrifty Pops!
You just eat them all day.
They never stop.
- Thrifty Pops...
- No, no, no. You said "eat", Alan.
- It should be "munch".
- Oh, shit.
The big, big bag of munchies
that last the whole day
Thrifty Pops! Thrifty Pops!
You just munch them all day.
They never stop. Cut!
There's something wrong.
The rhythm's wrong. It's that "you".
We don't need this "you".
Who wrote this stuff?
Thrifty Pops, the big, big bag of munchies
That last the whole day
Thrifty Pops! Thrifty Pops!
Munch them all day. They never stop.
Thrifty Pops! Thrifty Pops...
Well...
I'm not so sure. I think the "you"
had something. It... it broke the beat.
The way it came in on the sub-beat
was quite special.
Give us it again.
The big, big bag of munchies
that last the whole day
Nancy, is Hilary in?
I'd like a word with him.
- I'll find out if he's free.
- Thrifty Pops, Thrifty Pops...
- Oh, shut it.
- Hello, Gloria?
Alan Bird would like to see Hilary,
if he's free.
- Two minutes' time?
- Lovely.
- Thanks, Gloria.
- Yeah.
How's the lookalikes competition
coming along?
Fine. Everyone still wants to look
like Princess You-Know-Who, though.
You know, I'm gonna get
my dentist to write in.
He's the absolute spitting image
of George C. Scott.
I hear the seven deadly sins and
the terrible twins came to call on you.
Dire Straits.
The bigger they are, babe,
the harder they fall on you.
- Turn your radio on
Hello?
- Now, stop your nonsense, Gloria.
- Now, that's not fair!
It's absolutely fair.
I'm allowed to do that.
Right, right, I want a turn next.
Oh, look, you...
Listen, don't put your finger there.
I can't get in
if you put your finger there.
Oh, you'll have to be quicker than that.
I was always doing it very quick.
You did that when I wasn't looking!
- Oh, look what you've done now!
- Oh, no!
Oh, get... get out of there!
- I think that'll be all, er... Gloria...
- What?
...er... for the moment.
- Ah, come in, Alan. Come away in.
- Hello, Hilary.
That, er... phone-in joke spot,
Monday, was ace, tiptop.
- I hope you're going to keep it in.
- Thanks.
Well, now, what can I do for you?
I'd just like to talk.
I think... I think things are changing.
I think I'm changing.
Maybe. I don't think this is a good time
to talk about money, Alan.
I mean, the Christmas bonus is
in the pipeline. Now, you know that.
Oh, it's not money, Hilary.
No, I don't mean money.
No, I mean formats. Programmes.
You know, all the things
that maybe I could handle.
What do you mean?
I'm not a kid.
I'm a serious person,
I've got serious friends,
and maybe I should be more serious,
sometimes, on the air.
- I don't... catch your drift.
- I'm not just a clown.
Maybe I could do other kinds of shows,
like a... like a documentary.
- A documentary?
- It's a real kind of a show.
It's got real things, people.
Out on the streets, real things.
You know, I could follow something up
and make a show in depth.
Aye, Rufus told me about Madeline leaving.
Who the hell told Rufus?
Anyway, it's got nothing to do
with Maddy. This is work.
I think I'm on to something.
I want to chase it up. Make a programme.
You know, there are things going on in
this town that would make your hair curl.
Have I ever told you about my Navy days?
We used to do ship-to-ship transfers.
You know, breeches buoy.
Just a little bucket seat
way out there in the ocean.
There was a point, you see, when you'd be
halfway between one ship and the other
and the swell sometimes
which put both ships out of sight,
oh, for... 15, 20 seconds...
and there you'd be,
hanging beneath a bit of rope...
and nothing all around you
but angry water.
Do you get my point?
No.
But surely, I mean, I...
if you're sat there, where you...
- Are you sure you don't get the point?
- Not exactly.
Well, it's... it's depression,
Alan, depression.
You're stuck between where you've been
and where you're going,
and you've lost sight of both.
The secret, Alan, is faith.
Next time you look up,
the way ahead will be clear.
Think about it.
Can I make a documentary anyway?
Alan, the resources of the station
are yours to make use of, you know that,
but I don't see any need to tamper with
"The Dicky Bird Early Worm Show",
do you?
Fair enough.
I can pick up a tape recorder
at the newsroom?
Of course you can.
Knock on the door any time, Alan.
Oh, and Alan,
don't fret about
these angry seas below you.
I'll be seeing you, Hilary.
Hi, Gloria. Listen, get onto
the legal department, would you?
I want the lowdown
on Alan Bird's contract.
Aye, find out if it's yearly
or six-monthly.
Oh, and, Gloria, find out
if there's a sanity clause.
No, a sanity clause.
Santa Claus!
Dicky Bird documentary,
"Bird's-eye View", take one.
Alan Bird documentary,
Here I am in the heart of the city...
talking about this place that...
We all think that we know our own place...
our own town, but do we?
How much do we know...
or care?
Things happen around us...
The other night, I saw two men demolish
an ice-cream van with iron bars.
Can you believe it?
Right here in this city.
There are things...
going on in this city
that would make you...
Maddy, please come home.
I want to see you today.
I want to see what you're wearing.
I want you to tell me a joke.
I want to make you something nice to eat.
Ice cream is not something that many
of us give a great deal of thought to.
But, um...
especially at this time of year, I mean.
Hello, Colin? Yeah, this is Alan.
Yeah, this is an SOS.
Can I come over?
'Hi, this is Dicky Bird
and I've got a real problem.
'I've just tasted an exciting
new minty snack called EasiChews,
'but I can't decide whether
it's a mint or a chew bar.
'It comes from the people
who make Minty Crunch,
'so you know that
it tastes good and minty,
'but it chews like a real chewy chew bar.
'It's a between-meal snack that comes
in four big chocolate-covered fingers.
'Try one, and then you decide.
Is it a mint or is it a chew?
'It's a problem.'
How was the operation yesterday?
- Eh?
- The operation.
Oh, yeah. That was fine. Um...
The bugger had eaten a sandwich
the night before and not told us.
I very nearly sewed his new kidney
onto a piece of tomato.
The one essential is a good empty gut.
But the kidney seems like a good match.
- What did you do last night?
- I bought some ice cream.
Oh.
Do you know anything about ice cream?
I mean professionally.
- Medically.
- Erm...
- Chemically.
- Not a lot, no.
- You should ask the experts.
- Aye.
Could you sew it for her, please?
Oh, I've left my needle and thread
at the hospital, sweetheart.
Oh, this is a real mess, Lilly.
I've told you about amputations.
Now, you just watch them closely
and only chop if you have to, OK?
I wish I could cry like that.
I've forgotten how to.
Have another couple of drinks
and it'll all come back.
- Oh, aye.
- Well, that's serious medical advice.
Sometimes there's
nothing like a good skinful.
Stay the night, Alan.
The girls can double up.
Do you want me to ask him?
Lilly says you can get her ready
for bed tonight, Uncle Dicky.
- Now, that's a great honour.
- Lilly.
Dicky in the bed,
girls in the bunk, all right?
- Yes.
- Night-night, ladies.
Kiss Daddy night-night.
- Big kiss. Mm-mm!
- Aw...!
Night-night, night-night, sweetheart.
Come on, baby. There.
Come on.
You're a lucky bugger.
How did you get it all together?
You're so productive.
Reproductive. There's a difference.
Now, don't forget. I was always
jealous of you at university.
Organising the hops, hm?
Mr Showbiz.
- Pulling girls.
- Failing exams.
Even that made me jealous.
I didn't have the guts to fail exams.
You're just trying to make me feel better.
Well, that's my job.
I only hung around with you
because you knew all the fast girls.
Yeah, but you married one of them.
You got one of them to keep.
I don't even have a home.
You drive around the city
and all you see are homes,
and I don't have one.
Oh, we've all got worries, you know.
I have this recurring nightmare about you
coming to date one of my daughters
in about ten years' time. It's awful.
Well, she will be old enough
to know her own mind, Colin.
Well, imagine, that little madam
wanting you to undress her tonight.
Six years old.
Night-night, Dicky.
Night-night, Lilly.
Er... will you be staying tomorrow night?
I don't think so.
Will you play me a record?
On the Saturday show. I promise.
Um... it's for Andrew,
but don't mention my name.
OK.
- Night-night.
- What happened to the car?
- Ice-cream cones.
Take me home. I'm freezing.
How did you find me?
Oh, I tried you at home
and the rest was easy.
You're a dream, aren't you?
No, I'm real.
Touch me.
Feel me.
Sniff me.
I smell nice, don't I?
Even my sweat smells nice.
Take me home.
Oh, you wee bugger, you're not a dream.
Maddy, I'm...
Hi, Dicky Bird here.
My parties are going with a zing
this Christmas, and you know why?
It's new Party Mix,
the drink mixer for every taste,
in tangy, tropical four-fruits
or smoothie-tomato flavour.
Yes, gin, vodka and Bacardi
taste new and exciting with Party Mix.
Come in and join the crowd with Party Mix.
'Hey, Dicky darling, over here!'
Excuse me, folks. See you later.
Help yourself to the Party Mix.
Party Mix, your new Party Mix
Sorry, Alan. We'd like to go again.
We'll have to do a live mix, OK?
Clive says could you make it
a bit more suggestive at the end,
like you know you're going
to have a good time.
A good time. Lovely, thanks.
Mm-hm.
...around me tight,
oh, Santa, hear my plea...
A message for you, Alan.
Santa, bring my baby back to me...
A Mr Bruno Cullinari says he'll see you
outside the car park at six o'clock.
- Mr who?
- Bruno Cullinari? He was a bit weird.
Mm-hm. OK, thanks.
Alan? Bob Hope and Fred Astaire.
The doubles competition.
- I'm Bob Hope.
- Right.
I was actually more like him
when I was younger.
I've got a photograph.
Does photographs count?
Er... I'm not sure about that.
No, the rules are a wee bit hazy
on that score.
Now, look, this was taken in 1958
and everybody says
I was Bob Hope's double.
Surely that must go for something.
Er... yeah, well, look, Bob,
we'll let you know on that. Thanks.
Er... Mr Bird? Fred Astaire.
- Yes?
- Thank you for coming, Mr Bird.
Come on out. You're OK.
It's a real treat to meet you, Mr Bird.
- That's my brother Paolo.
- How do you do?
That's Renato....
and I'm Bruno.
Come inside and meet Mr McCool.
Mr Bird, meet Mr McCool.
Mr Bird.
- I believe you know Mr Bunny.
- Oh, no, hardly at all.
No, I bought a 99 from him and, er...
we exchanged a few words.
Sit down, please, Mr Bird.
Mr Bird, ice cream
is an old established business.
Everybody knows
where he stands in the city.
We all work together.
It's a kind of family.
That sounds nice.
Of course, everything works on trust.
Kind of unwritten rules.
A certain amount of honour is involved.
But Mr Bunny doesn't play by the rules.
- The unwritten ones?
- Yes.
The unwritten ones.
It's a territorial thing, really.
Other people work in the east,
in the south,
but we do business here in the north,
where we belong.
But Mr Bunny,
he's all over the place, Mr Bird.
He is an interloper.
He's like a rogue elephant,
wild, no rules.
Well, as I say,
we only exchanged a few words.
In fact I'm not even sure
if it was Mr Bunny himself.
No, no, no, there is no Mr Bunny, Mr Bird.
I told you, he's wild. He's a rogue.
No family, no heart.
Just a bunch of desperadoes.
Well, what's it got to do with me?
You must talk to him,
let him see reason...
before things get bad.
But they're bad already.
I mean, my car, the seats are ruined!
Have you ever tried to get
ice cream off velour upholstery?
My father says that things can
only get worse if you don't help us.
People do desperate things
when their livelihood is threatened.
For reasons of honour
and for other reasons,
we can't talk directly to Mr Bunny.
Everybody puts their faith in you.
My father says that he speaks for
the whole of the ice-cream community,
and my father asks
if he can call you Dicky.
My father says that ice cream is his life
and, er... he's called you Dicky again.
Call me Alan.
Yeah, my friends call me Alan, er...
Well, er... I'll do what I can.
Thank you for helping us.
I knew you would.
You came along just when we needed you.
The best machines for the best ice cream.
Ah, grazie, Renato.
A small early token
of our appreciation, Alan.
Gold Medal de luxe vanilla.
Of course, you can have
any flavour you like it.
Oh, no, that's... that's fine.
Vanilla is fine, yes.
And this is what Mr Bunny and people
like him want to deprive the people of,
a first-class ice cream. Please.
- Oh, thank you.
- Pleasure.
- Oh, and I wonder...
- Yes?
Could you help me out with a pint of milk?
I think I missed the shops.
Of course, of course.
Si, si.
Er... that's Archie and Amos,
two of my best men.
This is Dicky Bird from the radio.
Er... I'm Amos. He's Archie.
Bruno.
Oh. Ha.
Here. Let me pay for this.
Well, if you insist. It's 20 pence.
That's exactly what we pay.
Aye, 20p. Well, there you are. Thank you.
- Ah, Bruno?
- Si?
My father apologises
for speaking in Italian,
but he says
it's the language of his heart.
Oh, sure.
Well, er... cheerio and, er...
thanks for the milk
and the ice cream and, er...
Good night, Mr Bird. Thank you very much.
- Good night.
- Good night, sir.
Good night.
- Good night. We'll keep in touch.
- Thank you.
Bye-bye.
Dicky? Dicky.
- Could I have your autograph?
- Oh, sure, sure, yes.
Have you got a... have you got a pen?
Right, lovely. What was your name again?
Er... could... could you make it to
"my dear friend Paolo"?
- To my dear friend Paolo, eh?
- Paolo.
That's a good Scottish name,
that, isn't it?
Dicky Bird.
"Tweet, twiddly, tweet."
- That's great.
- Lovely. OK?
- Right, thanks a lot.
- See you.
- Lovely car.
- Aye, thanks very much.
Me and Mrs Jones
We got a thing going on
We meet every day at the same cafe
6.30 and no-one knows she'll be there
Holding hands
Making all kinds of plans
While the jukebox plays our favourite song
Me and Mrs... Mrs Jones
Mrs Jones, Mrs Jones, Mrs Jones...
And I know that this will be very bad
news for Bob Hope of Anniesland,
but, come on, Bob, keep trying.
Maybe you could practise
looking like somebody else, eh?
Someday famous
Lookalike, lookalike, someday famous
And before I go today,
I just want to steal the airwaves
and just get a teensy bit serious.
I've got a message for someone
who might just be listening. Mr Bunny.
Or Miss Bunny.
I do want to talk to you again.
So, how about same time, same place?
Tonight. End of message.
And listen, everybody. One day soon,
I'm gonna tell you all about this.
Perhaps in a very special programme.
But until then I'm a man of mystery.
I'm afraid that tooth's very bad.
So, what we'll do, seeing it's you...
we'll put a dressing into it
and...
if there's no pain at all,
fix it on your next visit.
'Hello, folks!
'Hello, folks!'
This is the reserve vehicle.
The rest are back at the body shop.
This is me completely out of action.
No more front-line units.
- I just wanted to have a word with you.
- I know that.
I was coming to see you.
What did you think I was doing?
- I thought you were trying to get away.
- Oh, God Almighty.
This is my first night on the Loganvale
estate. I was cleaning up here!
Let's have a look. Your radiator's OK.
I'll get the lads at the body shop
to beat this out for you.
Oh, no, no, no. I'll get it fixed.
No point hanging about here, is there?
Come on, follow me back to HQ.
'Hello, folks!'
You seen some action tonight, Trevor.
Was it a ramming job?
No, it was Robin Hood here
coming to rescue me.
'Hello, folks!
- 'Hello, folks!'
- Oh, you're, er...
Aye.
'Hello, folks!'
Oh, it's just superficial damage.
I'll get Roddy to bash it out
and slap some paint on it.
Oh, no, please. I'll fix it tomorrow.
Suit yourself. It'll cost you a fortune
to get it fixed anywhere else.
- Really?
- We can field two units tomorrow night.
- I've fixed up the freezer on the Merc.
- Oh, good, good. Well done.
- Listen, is Charlotte in the...
- She's in the office.
Right.
'Hello, folks!'
So, is this really
the ultimate driving machine?
- Mm-hm.
- Good.
Hello, folks!
'Hello, folks!'
Take a seat.
Mr Bird here wants to talk to us.
- He's seen McCool.
- Oh, yeah?
McCool wants to get together,
reach an agreement.
He's very upset.
I think it's a serious offer.
Oh, McCool's serious, all right.
He's deadly serious.
Do you have any idea
what you're getting involved in here?
- Do you work for McCool?
- Oh, certainly not. I'm a journalist.
I'm trying to stop senseless violence.
McCool runs a big outfit.
He wants to talk.
He wants to annihilate us,
that's what he wants.
McCool has got a stranglehold on
every operator in the north of this city.
He controls every franchise.
Wafer supply, ice cream, soft drinks.
He's even got a 10% mark-up
on every gallon of raspberry essence.
Now, you do your shopping elsewhere
and you got the demolition treatment.
How long have you been locked up
in that radio station of yours, Mr Bird?
Do you have any idea
what's going on around here?
Well, I got the impression that he wants
to try and find a working relationship.
Oh, yeah, exactly. Us working for him.
And you want me to tell those people
that you want them to work for McCool,
after the threats, the violence,
the day-and-night work here?
You go and tell them!
Well, something's got to be done.
It seems so stupid. It's almost like a joke.
People getting so angry about ice cream.
It's a joke.
And what deadly serious occupation
are you involved in, Mr Dicky Bird?
What exactly is
your contribution to humanity?
I want to help. But what can I do?
I want to help all of you find a solution.
You tell McCool this. We'll take
his ice cream, but under our conditions.
Every Mr Bunny's his own boss,
and that's the way it stays.
Now, we're talking equal prices
with no mark-ups.
And an open market in wafers.
We buy where we want.
If he prices fairly,
then he gets the business.
Now, on territories, we are willing
to negotiate openly around the table.
We talk under those conditions.
Where do you get your supplies from
at the moment?
So, that's what McCool's after.
That's why he sent you.
- He must be worried, Charlotte.
- Nobody sent me.
OK, well, you go back
to where nobody sent you from
and you tell them what we said,
we talk in an open market.
- OK.
Now, you'd better go before
the boys get to work on your car.
You'll end up with a fridge in the back
and a set of chimes.
'Hello, folks!'
Charlotte? See Mr Bird off the premises.
Parlare italiano, er... non...
I speak English.
Oh, good.
Well, I'm on your side, Charlotte.
- You know that.
- Oh?
Well, I'm on... I'm on both your sides,
really, because what I think...
I think you should all be
on the same side.
'Cheerio, folks!'
I'd really like to see you again...
and get to know you better.
'Cheerio, folks!'
What's the matter? Don't people
date each other anymore?
- Well, gee, I don't know.
- 'Cheerio, folks!'
Mr Bird!
When you see McCool,
be sure and remind him.
Formerly Mr Softy. No more.
'Cheerio, folks!'
Here. Here's some ice cream for you.
Oh. Thank you.
'Cheerio, folks!'
Oh, in the name of...
Be finished in a minute, Dicky.
Munch them all day!
'Thrifty Pops! Thrifty Pops!
'You just munch them all day.
They never stop.'
Thrifty Pops! Thrifty Pops!
I want them now...
Oh, hello, Mr Bird. Please come in.
- Sit down.
- Thank you.
Sit down. Have a cup of coffee.
A wee cake
or some chocolate biscuit, Alan?
- Yes, please.
- Maria.
Maria, what have you got left?
Any Kunzle cake?
Yes, I have two Kunzle cakes
and, er... some apple pie.
Oh, good, good, good.
Mr Bird and I will have the Kunzle cakes.
Some biscuit for the boys.
Oh, a wee slice of apple pie too.
There's a good girl.
I wanted some Kunzle cake as well.
Well, that's a pity, Bruno,
because you'll just have to have
some apple pie or a Yo Yo, won't you?
So, Alan, what did Mr Bunny
have to say for himself?
A lot. He wants to talk.
- I think it could work out good.
- Hm.
Where did you meet? His place?
Mm-hm. We went there, yes.
Where? Where is it?
Now, listen. I'm not taking any sides.
You asked me to help you talk
to Mr Bunny. That's all.
Hey, Bruno, please. Here, have this.
- Thanks.
- Bruno.
Give Alan his Kunzle cake.
Well, they have simple demands.
They want to do business with you,
that's obvious.
Who? Who's they?
I spoke with Trevor.
That's no secret, is it?
Trevor? Trevor, Trevor, Trevor!
My father says,
"Of all the most loathsome names,
"you have to mention that one,
the most abhorred name of all,
"the name of a two-timing,
interloping, fish-and-chip seller.
- "A name without honour."
- Yes.
"The name of a son
whose father turns in his grave
"to see the disgrace
that he brings to his family."
I don't understand.
Trevor's a Marinetti.
They have fish-and-chip shops all over.
We were close to them at one time.
Then Trevor started to drift into ice cream,
and he shouldn't have,
because there was a...
there was a kind of a...
Unwritten law.
Yes, an unwritten law.
Oh, dear God! What's this?
I forgot I was at the dentist today.
What else happened at Mr Bunny, Alan?
Ah, well, nothing much.
He wants to talk, that's for sure,
and, um...
and they gave me some ice cream,
just like you did.
Ah, they gave you some ice cream?
Some ice cream.
Bruno...
Si. Bravo, Papa. Si, si.
My father says that one taste of that
ice cream can answer many questions.
My father has the taste buds of a master.
He knows every ice cream in the country.
Paolo! Silenzio!
You're not having my ice cream, Mr McCool.
If you want one, there's a Mr Bunny van
every night up in Rosshall Park.
Alan, Alan, please come back.
Have another cup of coffee.
- Come on, please.
- Can I have your autograph?
Aye, sure, sure. Is that to Maria?
Just let me know
when you really want to talk.
I'll be happy to fix it up for you.
Ciao!
Bruno, no!
Stupido!
'It was announced in Moscow today
'that Mamie the giant panda
died in the night.
'Earlier this week, zoo officials were
rejoicing at Mamie's confirmed pregnancy,
'but a spokesman said today that tests
had revealed a serious stomach illness
'bearing similar symptoms to pregnancy.
'Messages of condolence have
been arriving at the Moscow Zoo
'from all over the world.
'The spokesman also said
'that there would be early plans
to have Mamie stuffed
'and put on permanent display at the zoo
'as a lasting tribute to the generosity
of the People's Republic of China
'in gifting the animal
to the Russian people.'
And I'm saying this for any Mr Bunny who
may be listening. The message is urgent.
Mr McCool is on the trail.
Be prepared. Mr McCool is on to you.
So, please, same time, same place,
Mr Bunny, and I'll give you all the details
but in the meantime double the guards,
and send the women and children
to the hills.
'So, this is Dicky Worm,
your early bird, saying cheery-bye
'and don't forget, big prize day
tomorrow on the doubles match
'and the big prize this week
is a wee bitty special.
'It's one whole day's use
'of big station boss Hilary Sandeman's
American Express card,
'but knowing our Hilary,
'he'll make sure that it's Boxing Day
when all the shops are shut.
'But never mind.
Finally, once again, Mr Bunny.
'If any Mr Bunny is listening out there,
'then please get the word
back to big Mr Bunny.'
- Gloria? I want to see Alan Bird.
- 'The McCools are on the warpath. Bye!'
Well, I told you. I'm on to something.
It'll break soon. I'll make a programme.
- Alan, you have not been yourself lately.
- Well, that's just the point.
I wasn't myself before, when I was myself,
but now I am myself, or very nearly.
- I don't follow you.
- I told you.
I'm changing. I had to.
My life was the wrong flavour.
My whole life was the wrong ice cream.
It needed a new flavour.
Ice cream?
You see, I was raspberry when I
should have been vanilla. Do you get it?
Alan, does, er...
Does this Bunny talk to you a lot?
Oh, I talk to them all. I see them all.
I'm helping them. They need me.
- Them all?
- Yes.
I needed to care for something,
to get involved.
You can ask my friend Colin.
He's a surgeon.
Mm-hm.
I've got a friend too, Alan,
who's a kind of a doctor.
Would you like to have a talk with him?
What about?
I think you should see someone soon, Alan,
someone who could help you find yourself.
Oh, do you mean a head psychiatrist?
Oh, you think I'm nuts. I'm not nuts!
Alan, before you go back on the air again,
I have to insist.
- Mr Swan?
- Bird.
Make yourself at home.
I'll be with you in a jiffy.
I wouldn't lie there.
That's another 20 an hour.
Oh. Ha-ha.
It's mostly used for group therapy
nowadays, anyway.
So, I hear you have
a friend called Mr Bunny?
Er... not a friend, no.
Somebody I'm helping.
I'm helping all of them,
all the Mr Bunnys.
How long have you been associating
with these Mr Bunnys?
All week, since Maddy left.
- Maddy?
- Yeah, my girl. She left me.
Yeah, we'd been together for four years.
It was... it was a bit of a shock.
How did that happen?
A removal truck came one night
and she left.
It was very sudden, yes, quite a shock.
How was your relationship with Maddy?
Er... well, it was fine.
Well, I thought it was fine.
Yes, I thought we were a very good team.
Do you have a healthy sexual relationship?
Mm, very healthy, I thought.
Any abnormal sexual practices?
No.
- Nothing at all?
- No.
- Any sexual violence?
- No, certainly not.
Very well, we'll take your word for it.
So, tell me, how do you feel
about losing Maddy?
Heartbroken. It was a big shock.
And I've had these dreams,
these awful depressing dreams.
- Dreams?
- Yes, but now I see it's all for the best.
I've already explained this to Hilary.
I think...
I think that we've all got
to change at certain times.
But if your life is like...
like an apple cake,
when it should be like a Kunzle cake,
I think you're in trouble.
I think you've got
to find the right flavour.
Now, Maddy and I,
we were like a chocolate mousse.
We were really terrific chocolate mousse,
but you can't live on chocolate mousse.
No, you need other things.
So, I... I do miss her, though.
She was wonderful.
We were some chocolate mousse.
I wonder if you've ever done
any sailing, Mr Bird.
No.
I have a little illustration
that might be of some comfort.
It goes back to my days in the Navy.
They used to move us medicos
around a great deal, ship to ship,
and they had this contraption
called a breeches buoy...
Mm-hm.
...and sometimes you could find
yourself out there on the ocean...
Hanging on a piece of rope.
There's nothing else around you
but the angry waters
and you're stuck between here and there.
Oh, yes, I know, I know. You're right.
How did you know that? That's my story.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- It's my story.
It really happened to me.
Where did you hear it?
Oh, I don't remember.
Maybe I read it in a book.
No, you didn't.
I haven't written the book yet.
- I'm sorry.
- This is very upsetting.
It really happened, you know.
It really happened.
I've got to warn the bunnies tonight.
I think the McCools could be onto them.
Listen. What about Maddy?
It's only been four days now.
I think you should take a little bit longer
than that to get over her,
after all she meant to you.
I don't think you're being fair.
Don't worry. I'm still miserable.
I'll be miserable for ages, I know.
But I can see the way forward now,
the ship on the horizon.
- Hello, Miss Wilson.
- Hello, Doctor.
- How are you?
- Fine, Doctor. Just a bit stiff.
Well, I'll tell Sister you can have
a real bath today, then.
Oh, thank you.
I've brought someone to meet you.
It's Dicky Bird from the radio.
- Oh...!
- A friend of mine.
Very pleased to meet you, Dicky.
This is a real treat.
I listen to you every morning here.
I'm always awake first, and they don't
bring breakfast till half past seven.
Well, thank you very much.
I wish you did Saturday and Sunday too.
They've got
that other noisy clown on then.
- Oh, aye, Rufus.
- I don't like him.
I don't like him much either.
We'll have to go just now.
Bye, Doctor. Cheerio, Dicky.
You make an old lady smile every morning.
Cheery-bye.
- How long has she been in for?
- A couple of months.
Oh, Jesus.
No, she's OK. She's got you.
Well, anyway, you've obviously got
a great deal to do
and you shouldn't really be here
unless you're sick.
- You're not sick, are you?
- Oh, no.
Well, not really.
Ah, well, I'll be seeing you, Colin.
- Keep on taking the alcohol.
- Check.
'Hello, folks!'
Trevor. I'm glad you're here.
- Did you get my message?
- What was that?
McCool got ahold of your ice cream.
He reckons that he can track you down.
I don't think he'll get too far.
You see, it's his own recipe.
- 'Hello, folks!'
- McCool's my father.
I don't get it. What are you playing at?
You're all crackers.
Nothing like a family feud,
Dicky, is there?
Crazy people. You're all crazy people!
You brought them here. You bastard.
You're a dead man, Dicky Bird.
You are a dead man!
Come on!
Cheerio, folks!
Bastard! Bastard!
You bastard!
Gonna have you!
I'll have you, you bastard!
Andiamo!
They used me. They all used me.
They could've picked up the telephone
if they'd wanted to talk to each other.
And the girl, all along, it turns out
that she's McCool's daughter.
- Do you want some eggs, Alan?
- Eh? No, thanks, Colin. No, thanks.
All the best fights
happen inside families.
Yeah, that's what Trevor said,
shortly before he demolished my car.
I just don't see any hope for the world.
If people want to damage each other
over ice cream, we're doomed.
I don't know.
I think ice cream's quite important.
- Isn't it, girls?
- Yes.
Did you, er... pay the milk this morning?
- No, you paid him two weeks last week.
- I wasn't here last week, love.
Oh, Colin, you said you were going to.
I told you.
Look, I hadn't got any cash
to pay him this morning.
Are you remembering that Lilly's
got to be at her party at two o'clock?
- Can you take her?
- Well, if I'm back, love, OK?
- She's got two brothers, this girl?
- Yes, yeah.
Well, that explains her rebellion, anyway.
Well, that's what got McCool really angry,
his daughter mixed up
with a fish-and-chip family.
He's mortified.
- Ice cream and chips.
- Oh, aye.
Eh? Oh, no, no.
No, it couldn't work.
You said you'd get me
a request today, Dicky.
Oh, goodness, so I did, Lilly.
I'm sorry. Don't worry. I'll fix it.
I'll go into the station
right after I've had my breakfast,
and, Rufus, he'll let me on
for a minute or two.
You watch out for the ice-cream men, OK?
Aye, but I've got to
do something about them.
They're all so angry,
they can't think straight.
Let me into the studio,
Rufus, just for one minute,
to say hello to a kiddie and an old lady
that's in hospital, that's all.
I'm sorry, Alan.
I'd have to clear it with Hilary first.
I don't know what happened between
you two yesterday. I'd have to clear it.
You're a shit, Rufus.
I let you onto my show
on Mother's Day, do you remember?
Just because you hadn't
phoned her for three weeks.
Just give me the names
and I'll take care of it, OK?
OK. Right, thank you.
Well, this is to Andrew from Lilly,
but don't mention her name.
And to a Miss Wilson
in the Western Infirmary.
Just lots of love from me, OK? Thanks.
- Which ward?
- Oh, I don't know which ward.
I'll play them something nice, Alan.
No sweat, no sweat.
No heavy metal, please.
Well, after all that exercise,
let's all sit down and think
about a nice fattening pudding.
And here's Katie Pollock
with today's recipe.
It sounds delicious. Banana fritters.
'Hello, everyone.
'The Chinese are the acknowledged
masters in the art of fritter-making.
'Everything from the humble
apple and pineapple fritters
'to the rare and exotic
and difficult ice-cream fritter.
'But today we'll concentrate
on the easy-to-make banana fritter,
'a very delicious hot sweet
'that'll make a change
from leftover Christmas pudding.'
- She said ice-cream fritters.
- Sorry, Alan?
Katie Pollock.
She said ice-cream fritters.
Yeah, that's right, like baked Alaska.
- How do you make them?
- Ask Katie Pollock.
Er... but-but, I mean, well,
is she... is she a real person?
I don't know if she's a real person,
but she's Hilary Sandeman's wife.
'...baking the banana before frittering,
but I don't hold with that.
'I think it's worth the extra effort...'
Yeah, Hilary, much better.
Yeah, I feel fine.
Yeah, I think everything's
going to work out fine. Yeah.
Oh, yeah, yeah,
the angry scenes are subsiding. Yeah.
No, I really phoned
about something else, Hilary. Yes.
I wanted to speak to Heather.
Do you know, I never realised
that she was Katie Pollock?
Well, I wanted to ask her for a recipe.
Mm, just a recipe. Mm-hm.
Eh? No, no, I'm fine, honestly.
I'm fine, I'm cool. Everything's cool.
Yeah, good shape, good shape.
But I do need a recipe from Katie.
I mean Heather, and it's quite urgent.
Look, I swear to you, Hilary,
I'm on top of the world.
Yes, but, er...
it's a specific recipe. Ah...!
- Trevor wants to see you.
- Oh, no, pal. No, you've got it wrong.
No, I want to see Trevor.
Oh, and, er... just one other thing.
From now on, if anybody hits this car,
it'll be me and nobody else. Get in.
So, it's gone about
as far as it can go, eh?
Yeah.
What does honour demand now? Hara-kiri?
Listen, I just wanted to tell you, I don't
blame you for anything that's happened.
Thank you!
Now, you and I are going to see Mr McCool.
I've got something to say
to both of you. Fix it.
- How?
- Phone the bastard.
Or would you rather send a war party?
Er... what do I say?
Just tell him that I want to talk to him,
that's all. He'll turn up.
'Hello, folks!'
He's a weird old bugger,
picking a place like this.
What did he say on the telephone?
He said they do
a nice lemon-meringue pie here.
What's the joke?
Oh, dear.
- Hello, Trevor.
- Hello, Uncle Luigi.
- How's your mother?
- She's very well, thanks.
Good, good. Have a sweetie.
Can we get down to business,
Mr Bird, please?
- You're Trevor's uncle?
- That's right.
All the best families fight.
You know that, Mr Bird.
Yes, I've heard that one a lot this week.
Only, I'm not family,
and neither is my car,
and neither are any of all those
freedom-loving independent operators
that you care about so deeply, Trevor.
Now, I'm gonna give you a chance
to make it up,
to me, to all those people
that you've duped into believing in you,
and to yourselves.
You're going to work together on this,
a joint venture.
What is it?
Ice-cream fritters.
Alan, you must be mad. Matto!
You can't afford to laugh.
You're going to annihilate one another.
Now, this way, you pool your resources.
Your ice cream.
Your deep-fry shops. Your trucks.
You share a new product.
600 million Chinese can't be wrong.
600 million Chinese!
Here's the secret bit.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
And we create...
a commodity...
which we sell
at extreme profit to ourselves.
Perfect, eh?
Oh! Hot, and, er... and then it's cold.
It's... it's interesting.
It's very, very interesting.
It's bitter. It's sweet.
Syrup. It needs syrup.
But the syrup will be extra, on the side.
Five, even ten pence a portion.
I know, 30, 40 pence a fritter.
More maybe.
More, definitely more.
It's a luxury item. It needs a royal name.
- King Fritter.
- That's too obvious.
Right, we've got to precook, freeze-pack,
- and microwave at point of sale.
- Yeah.
Hot ice cream, year-round sales,
summer and winter - it's a miracle.
It's a miracle!
Hey, hey, hey... Slow down. You haven't
said if you liked it yet. Do you like it?
- It's a winner, Dicky.
- Well done, Dicky.
50-50 on the whole thing, Trevor.
Manufacture and sales.
Paolo and I can handle the syrups.
- Yeah.
- Maybe five or six flavours.
Flavours! Good boy, Bruno, good boy.
You've got the syrups.
Slow down, slow down, slow down.
Look, if you're talking business,
you ought to be talking to me.
Don't you worry, Dicky.
We need a big campaign behind this one.
We are revolutionising the market.
You can do the voiceovers.
No, no, you boys can run the show.
That's fine.
But, er... I'm in for, er... what?
Er... 30 per cent off the top, hm?
Yeah, you could call that a consideration
for having thought up the whole
damned idea in the first place.
And just in case you get any fancy ideas,
you won't find this in any cookery book.
This is the batter adhesive agent.
Without this, you get
a sticky, gooey mess.
The Chinese don't tell
everybody about this one.
So, why don't we just visit a lawyer
first thing Monday morning
and make this wonderful friendship legal?
Oh, er... and just one other further
item of mutual company expenditure.
My car gets a new roof. OK?
Yeah, sure, Dicky.
OK, Dicky. Va bene.
No, no, wait a minute. Wait a minute.
We need something short and sweet,
right? Bunnyfrits.
No, McCool Bunny Fritters.
Well, it's four o'clock on this lovely
peaceful Christmas afternoon,
and this is Dicky Bird here,
being a very happy Christmas worm.
You know, I got really sentimental
after the morning show today
and I thought about poor old
Steve Kelly having to come in here,
spend the afternoon away
from his lovely wife and happy kids,
so bachelor boy Dicky volunteered
and here I am.
You know, I must be crackers.
Matto. Crazy.
But to tell you the truth, we are having
a pretty good time in Metrosound today.
There's definitely a party atmosphere.
We've got the food, we've got
the goodies, and the odd drink or two,
so don't you feel too sorry for us.
And anyway, Hilary Sandeman has
promised all us Christmas workers
an extra four weeks' holiday
in the Caribbean
as a means of compensation,
so that can't be at all bad.
What an awfully nice boss Hilary is!
So, I hope that you'll stay with us
and let us join your party
or, if you haven't got a party of your own,
you come and join ours.
So, cheers, everybody, in this great, big,
weird and wonderful city of ours,
and, listen, folks, I'm not gonna tell you
what the time is today,
or tell you what the traffic is doing,
or tell you what's happening
with the weather.
Oh, no, we're gonna have
a day away from all that.
I'm just gonna sit back, play you some
very nice music, talk my head off,
and tell you some of the worst jokes
that you're ever likely to repeat.
So, in the meantime,
here's a little bit of music,
while I tuck into my Christmas pud.
Mm-mm.
Merry Christmas, everybody.
God bless us, everyone.
'Hello, folks, this is Dicky Bird
'and I'm here to tell you that winter
will never be the same again.
'From this Monday, exclusively from
all Mr McCool and Mr Bunny outlets,
'you'll be able to enjoy
the new taste sensation, Frostihots,
'a smooth and creamy ice cream
wrapped in delicious hot batter
'and smothered
in your favourite fruity syrup.
'Wow! And guess what? I invented it.
'Yes, I tell you that once
my Frostihots reach the Eskimos,
'they won't need igloos any more.
'But right now, Frostihots are for you.
'So, stop a Bunny or McCool van.
'Ice cream will never be the same again.'
'Sorry, Alan. We'd like to go again.'
'Oh, shit.'