Hi.
Julie Schofield.
Hello.
That thing does work properly,
does it?
Oh, it works just fine.
I want my words
preserved for posterity.
I won't miss a thing.
Drink?
Thanks very much.
No bourbon, I'm afraid. Scotch.
Scotch would be great.
Ice?
Mm-hm.
Yes, of course.
I'm afraid so.
I've always wanted fame.
I've always liked the idea
of my name going down in history.
Going down as a spy for Russia?
Fame or infamy -- what does it matter?
I shan't be forgotten.
If my mother could only see me now.
The last of the few.
It really was only a few?
Oh, there were plenty of people
waiting to see which way to jump.
Things only had to go a little
differently and...well, you know.
But, yes, in practice
we were just a few.
A happy few.
"A band of brothers."
Shakespeare. 'Henry V'.
Our most patriotic king.
How big a band were you,
this band of brothers?
Some things have to remain secret,
even now.
You sure?
Certain, no less.
Background, dear lady,
is all I can give you.
The whole delightful, utterly
despicable English background.
Well, I understand
the delightfulness, alright,
but not why you had to despise it.
How someone of your class
and, well, background...
Should want to kick it in the teeth?
Precisely.
You have no idea what life in England
in the 1930s was like.
Treason and loyalty,
they're all relative, you know.
Treason to what?
Loyalty to whom?
That's what matters.
.. I vow to thee,
my country
.. All earthly things above
.. Entire and whole and perfect
.. The service of my love
.. The love that asks no question
.. The love that stands the test
.. That lays upon the altar
.. The dearest and the best
.. The land that never falters
.. The love that pays the price
.. The love that makes undaunted
.. The final sacrifice
.. And there's another country
.. I've heard of long ago
.. Most dear to them that love her
.. Most great to them that know.....
.. We may not count her armies
.. We may not see her king
.. Her fortress
is a faithful heart.....
.. Her pride is suffering.....
.. And soul by soul and silently
.. Her shining bounds increase
.. And her ways
are ways of gentleness.....
Martineau! Robbins!
.. And all her paths are peace...
They shall grow not old
as we that are left grow old.
Age shall not weary them,
nor the years condemn.
At the going down of the sun,
and in the morning,
we will remember them.
We will remember them.
Want to come and have lunch?
My parents are down.
That's very nice of you. Thanks.
You were laughing.
I was not.
Giggling, then.
I didn't utter a sound.
You were giggling silently.
I couldn't concentrate at all.
Even a crusty old Tory like you,
Devenish,
must see it's absolutely ludicrous
for 400 boys to line up and blub
for people they never knew.
What do you mean, didn't know?
Who died in a businessman's war
because they were too stupid
to shoot their superior officers
and start a revolution
like the Russians.
They were the superior officers,
weren't they?
We could all see
who YOU were thinking about.
Wharton! Wharton!
A glass of sherry?
Yes, Barclay?
Take these round to all the Houses.
I want one on every noticeboard
before lunch.
Yes, Barclay.
What you forget
is all those people died for us.
They died for their class.
You are their class.
It's silly to pretend you're not.
You're always
trying to be different.
What's wrong with being different?
There you are.
I mean, you want to be elected
to be a God, don't you, Devenish?
Yes.
They're different.
That's not what I mean.
You wait.
My waistcoats are going to be
the most different you've ever seen.
Why an intelligent person like you
should want to be part
of a self-perpetuating oligarchy...
It's a pity you have to be a prefect
before you can be elected,
else I'd be wearing one now.
You'll make it. Menzies will see to
that. Will I? That's the question.
I expect so.
Would you like to do the honours?
Yes, of course.
Well, I must say I think
that's the best service yet.
Yes.
Boys! Have any of you seen Martineau?
Bennett, do pull yourself together.
It's not even
as though he was there.
Not yet.
Any moment now,
the great oak doors of Longford
will swing open
on their rusty hinges...
That door does need oiling.
..and the glorious vision
will step forth.
He'll stand a moment, winsomely
framed in the tumescent archway.
Doing what?
Sniffing the wind.
Like a dappled deer.
Oh, my God.
And then... then he'll shoot
a tender yet burning,
soft yet passionate glance
across the 300 yards of sacred turf,
hoping against hope
that I shall be there to receive it.
Hmm.
And I shall lay my heart at his feet.
Must have enormous feet
if they'll stretch from Longford's to here.
They are. Want a peek?
Thank you, no.
You seen Martineau?
No, I only have eyes for one person
in the entire world.
Any of you?
Probably with his parents.
I don't think that they came down.
Still, never mind. Thanks.
No, thank you
for the good-humoured restraint
with which you exercise your power.
It's not only not fair,
it's not even sensible.
Come on, Judd.
Our parents spend hundreds of pounds
sending us here to be educated
and we spend the entire time
playing games.
Quite right too.
Games are good for Bolsheviks.
Teach you a bit of team spirit.
You could be good at cricket
if you'd try.
I don't want to try. I want
to be left alone to do my work.
I hope you're not taking those
bio notes out of House, Bennett.
Then you hope in vain, Fowler.
Farcical's given me permission
to use them for nature study.
Who?
Farcical.
If you mean the Housemaster,
kindly use his proper name.
You didn't.
What?
Use his proper name.
His proper name is Mr Farquharson.
Are you trying to be clever?
I don't have to try. I am clever.
I've half a mind
to ask for permission to beat you.
You've half a mind,
we agree on that.
Quiet!
Get changed, everybody.
Anyone late for the House matches
will be up before Barclay
for six strokes.
Ooh!
What you have to grasp, Devenish,
is that Fowler is precisely what
this school was designed to produce.
Not empire builders. Dear me, no.
Building empires needs imagination.
Empire ruling.
Oh, do dry up.
Fowler will go straight from
the King's African Rifles
into the Colonial Service.
He'll end up with an OBE.
And syphilis.
Bennett, do you mind?
He'll catch it off a little native girl
who he'll visit after dark
in her steamy primeval hut.
When he gets back to his mildewed wife
in Bexhill-on-Sea,
he won't be able to look at her
so he'll turn her over...
For heaven's sake!
Serves her right for marrying
an imperialist and an exploiter.
There's nothing wrong
with the Colonial Service...
"It's a perfectly decent career."
Shut up!
There is nothing decent
about colonialism.
I don't see why
you have to be against everything.
I'm not. I'm FOR revolution.
Alright, everyone!
Umpires for Longfords
versus Chancellors?
Me, please. Me and Judd.
Alright.
I don't want to go and umpire.
Yes, you do. Come along.
Umpire!
Umpire, that was a wide.
No, it wasn't.
I couldn't possibly
have reached that.
Course you could. You just didn't try.
It was practically
outside the white line.
Are you arguing with the umpire?
Because arguing with the umpire
is not school practice.
It might be in your House
but it isn't in ours.
Since we beat you last week,
you can shut up.
Play!
Howzat?!
Out!
We should have rung
the muffled peal after the dedication.
I don't see why we didn't.
Because we're not good enough.
You don't have to be good
to run a muffled peal. It's muffled.
No-one can really tell.
I'll muffle you if you don't shut up.
Out! You lot -- go! Out, all of you.
Spungin, you get a master. Now!
Jesus, God! Did you see?
That was Martineau.
This place.
This place!
These things
should be left to the Gods.
He'd never have done it if he hadn't
been sent to see the headmaster.
He knew that meant expulsion.
Yes, but once a master caught him,
Delahay, it was out of our hands.
Especially as it was
with a man from another House.
The Gods could have dealt with it.
That's what we're here for.
Prefects handle House matters.
The Gods deal with everything else.
And masters
should mind their own business.
Even the mighty Gods
can't expel people, Delahay.
Who needs people expelled?
You wouldn't have let Martineau stay?
Of course.
But he wouldn't have sat down
for a week
after the Gods finished with him.
If we expel everyone who indulges...
There we are, aren't we?
The tone of this whole House
has gone to pieces
and you, Delahay,
are mainly responsible.
Fowler, please.
Yes. Shut up, Fowler.
But it's precisely attitudes like that...
Will you shut up?!
Now, we're all, I know, very
distressed about what's happened.
Personally... well, I've always tried
to make everyone feel
he can come to me at any time,
whatever the problem.
But he must have been desperate.
It probably
wouldn't have made any difference.
But if he'd talked to me, to you...
Anyone!
However, we have to try
and overcome our personal feelings.
And remember
our responsibility to the House.
We don't want people rushing off
confessing things,
which, quite frankly, they'd
do better to keep to themselves.
If people have things to confess,
they should confess them.
A thorough clear-out
is what this House needs.
I'd like there to BE a House
next term for me to be Head of.
I'm sure it's not nearly on that scale.
Anyway, wouldn't you like
to start with a clean House?
Quite frankly, I doubt if such a thing
as a clean House exists,
in this school or any other.
What about a special session
of House prayers?
Almighty
and most merciful Father.
"Almighty
and most merciful Father,
"we have erred and strayed
from thy ways like lost sheep.
"We have followed too much
"the devices and desires
of our own hearts."
If you ask me, it all comes of having
masters who aren't old boys.
I see.
Well, an old boy
would have more sense
than to go prowling around
gymnasium changing room.
Everybody knows what goes on there.
Look, you'd better watch yourself,
Bennett.
Discretion is going to be the
better part of valour around here.
Wouldn't you say?
May I go and talk to Judd, please?
If you think you can get a word in.
"Thou shalt not lie with mankind
as with womankind.
"It is abomination.
"Neither shalt thy lie with any beast
to defile thyself therewith.
"Neither shall any woman stand before
a beast to lie down there too.
"It is confusion. Defile not ye
yourselves in any of these things."
Alone at last!
Get off.
I'll get you one day.
No, you won't.
Yes, I will. Everyone gives in
in the end. It's Bennett's Law.
I won't give in.
Then you're not normal.
My God, that was quick. Who did it?
Matron.
Poor Martineau.
The reason everyone gives in
in the end
is they get lonely
doing it on their own.
They long for company.
Well, I don't.
Not your sort, anyway.
That's why my mother's marrying
this awful Colonel person.
Arthur.
It couldn't just possibly be
that she loves him?
Out of the question.
He's got one of those awful little
moustaches. He's ghastly.
Almost as much of a loather
as my father was.
You mean even you
would draw the line?
Don't be revolting.
He's a grown-up.
Of course. And it's all
just a passing phase.
Exactly.
Just like you being a communist.
Ha, ha.
Judd...
Hmm?
You and your usherette.
What about her?
Is is really so different?
From what?
Boys.
How would I know?
I've only ever had a girl.
What is it, Wharton?
I don't know what to do
about Spungin's water.
Leave him to pass it on his own.
Pour it out.
He makes a terrible fuss
if his water's cold.
He said he'd report me to Barclay.
Go and fill up the jug
with new hot water, bring it back,
cover it with a flannel
and leave it by Spungin's bed.
Thanks, Judd.
Hurry up, Wharton.
Yes, Delahay.
God, 'Das Kapital' looks difficult.
I haven't found anything
I couldn't understand eventually.
And if they taught us
any economics here
instead of Tudors
and bloody Stuarts...
Marx should be a set book
for the 6ths.
They shouldn't leave us to
fight our way through it on our own.
And under the blankets.
Barclay confiscated
another torch last night.
How many's that?
12.
12 torches taken away
to stop me getting the education
I'm supposed to be here for.
God, if our parents only knew
what actually went on here.
They do know.
The fathers, anyway.
Bennett, what the hell
are you doing? Go to bed.
.. My kingdom says
.. I'm yours forever
.. Dear Lord, thy creatures all
.. I swear.....
What's this?
I'm very sorry, Fowler,
I thought I...
Juniors aren't required to think,
Wharton.
They're required to obey orders
and I told you to make this shine.
Yes, Fowler.
Well...
..not bad except for that smear.
Get it off.
Yes, Fowler.
If you're going to be
in the south of France,
you might look around
for a little villa for August.
Might I?
Why not just extend the honeymoon?
I could pop down on the Blue Train
just as soon as school's over.
I see.
I only want to bring one friend.
It won't be at all expensive.
I don't think Arthur
would like Judd, darling.
I don't mean Judd, darling.
Anyway, Arthur thinks
everyone under the age of 18
is either a pinko or a pansy,
so it won't make much difference
who I bring, will it?
You know, I'm awfully worried.
You see, it is an established fact
that people who go around
suspecting vice in others
are highly suspect themselves.
But Arthur's the most normal man
I've ever known!
What better disguise?
Listen, there's still time to call it off.
Come on, let's stop the car.
You really shouldn't joke about it, Guy.
Not after that poor boy.
I suppose
he was dreadfully unpopular.
Martineau? No.
I should've thought a boy like that...
Better off dead, no doubt about it.
Well, I have known
one or two of, er... of those.
And they're never very happy,
you know.
Mummy!
Oh, they can be very amusing,
but, er... Oh, here we are!
If you ask me,
public schools go on too long.
Arthur means the fees.
It's not just the fees.
Look at Guy. He's not a boy anymore.
He's a young man.
Aren't you, old chap?
Rather.
You should leave at the end
of this term. Take a job for a bit.
Go round the world.
You must be mad.
School's just getting
to the good bit.
You need to find out a bit about life
before you go up to the varsity.
I second that.
Why not the army?
Why not, indeed? First class.
I mean, one learns so much about life
in the army.
Yes.
Killing people.
Excuse me.
Mummy!
How dare you talk like that?!
How dare you
plan to send me around the world
without even consulting me?
It's alright, Ivy.
Oh, excuse me.
It was only an idea, darling.
It's just that Arthur thought...
Arthur!
We only want what's best for you.
If either of you seriously thinks
I would leave now,
after 10 years of hard labour
in the salt mines
of prep and public school...
You want to stay?
I'll be a God, Mummy.
What?
The school elite.
The creme de la creme.
Oh, yes. Of course.
It's the only thing that's made
the last 10 years endurable --
thnking one day I'd be top
of the whole stinking heap!
Well, if that's how you feel, darling.
I really must get back to my wedding.
Would you care for a drink, sir?
Ah, yes. A glass of sherry,
thank you.
Very good, sir.
Gosh, you are brave.
Did you think I wouldn't come?
I, um, didn't know. I hoped you would.
Well...
..here I am.
I, um, hope you're hungry. I'm ravenous.
I've had nothing to eat but a bit
of caviar and toast all day long.
Doesn't sound bad.
Oh! It's awful.
Listen, I, um...
..I can't call you Harcourt.
My name's Guy.
I know.
I found out.
Mine's James.
James.
That's a very nice name.
I nearly lost my nerve.
I passed a couple of masters
on the way here.
Don't worry about them. They won't
come in here. They can't afford to.
Listen, then,
do you like smoked salmon?
I love it.
I-I love...
.. I-I love food and drink and...
Shall we get terribly, terribly drunk?
If you like!
The only thing is, though,
sometimes when I get drunk, I...
..I say things I shouldn't.
Still, we ought to have something
to celebrate with, oughtn't we?
Your sherry, sir.
Are you ready to order?
Ah, not yet.
Bring me the wine list, would you?
Here we are, sir.
We've a nice little hock,
if you care for hock, sir.
No, no, no -- champagne.
I've been drinking it all day
and it doesn't do to mix one's drinks.
What's the best champagne you've got?
The Moet, I suppose, sir.
It's been a most unfortunate affair,
of course,
but on the whole, the school
has not come out of it too badly.
For that, we must be extremely
grateful to Barclay and Henderson
for the admirable way they've
handled their respective Houses
through what could have been
a most serious crisis.
Hear, hear.
We all know how quickly
scandal can spread.
Actually, my father won't have
anyone in the firm from Harrow
because of what he's heard.
Well, I can't imagine him wanting
anyone from Harrow, anyway.
But we do still
have to make it absolutely clear
to the outside world
this was
a completely isolated incident.
I cannot emphasise too strongly --
nothing even remotely like it
can ever be allowed to occur again.
Alright?
My real father died when I was 14.
How awful.
It was the Easter hols.
I was reading one night in my bed,
when I heard the most peculiar noise --
a sort of...
a sort of muffled squeaking.
Couldn't think what it was, at first.
Sounded... trapped or something.
So I... I went down the passage
and it seemed to be coming
from my parents' room
and there was a light
under the door so...
.. I assumed...
None of my business.
Gosh.
Then I... I distinctly heard
my mother say, "Help."
Help.
It was terribly eerie.
Complete silence
and there it was again. "Help."
I... I didn't know what to do.
No.
I went down the passage
and I knocked loudly on the door
and I said, "Are you alright?"
And she said, "Guy, quick, help."
She sounded
absolutely at her last gasp.
So I went in.
Listen, are you sure
you really want to hear this?
No. No,
not if you don't want to tell me.
No, I do.
My...
..my father had... had a heart attack.
Right in the middle of...
No!
Happens all the time, apparently.
Well, what better way to go
for the man, but for my mother...
Well... she was trapped.
How absolutely incredible!
It was awful.
My mother kept her eyes closed
the whole time.
Only wish I could've done so.
It was so embarrassing.
It must have been.
She never really
looked me in the eye again.
See... I always hated him.
He was... he was vile.
My mother...
Always been very fond of my mother.
But, well...
..things haven't been quite the same
between us since...
..since then.
Perhaps that's why she married again.
Perhaps it is.
Never thought about that.
You know what I'd like to do sometime?
Ride around Europe on a bicycle.
With a tent.
Sharing it
with someone you really like.
Mmm.
I've never spent the night with anyone.
Have you?
No.
Must be wonderful.
Have you ever been in love?
No. Have you?
No.
Must get in.
Goodnight.
Fetch!
Come here. Come here!
Susie!
Come here!
Sit!
Alright, Bennett, I've got you this time.
Oh! God, I thought you were Fowler.
Ah! Oh! Ah!
Hmm!
That drainpipe's a bloody disgrace.
I must have a word
with the Housemaster.
Pshh!
Tommy...
May I call you Tommy, Tommy?
If you want.
Oh! I'm in love.
That's not exactly news.
Well, I... I don't mean in love.
I mean...
I mean in love.
You're drunk.
You know, till now,
it's just been a game but...
..now!
What are you doing here?
I thought you didn't have to
be back till tomorrow.
And why are you dressed like a God?
Um, practice for next term.
You'd better be careful not to get
any more food on that waistcoat.
It's grubby already.
Damn the waistcoat!
I've been waiting for this since my...
Nothing's ever going to be as good
again till I'm ambassador in Paris.
Don't be so pathetic.
Life is ladders, Tommy, that's all.
Prep school to here.
1st Form to 6th.
Second assistant junior undersecretary
to ambassador in Paris.
Sir Guy Bennett, KCVO, KCMG.
Comtemptible sycophant
in the service of the bourgeosie.
What?
It's what Lenin called
the renegade Karl Kautsky.
Did he indeed?
Because he substituted eclecticism
and sophistry for dialectics.
Oh, well, that is bad.
Grovelling about the kings and queens,
walking backwards!
Kissing hands.
You're utterly imbued
with the spirit of servility,
that's what he'd have said.
You mean he wouldn't have liked me?
No.
What about James?
Who's James?
Harcourt. His name's James.
Quite frankly, I don't think he'd
have cared much for the pair of you.
God! First, they take away my torches.
Then when I take my life --
or at least my bum -- in my hands
and creep here to do some work,
they send you.
This place is impossible.
'Night.
Goodnight.
.. Who stole my heart away.....
Huh!
.. Who makes me dream all day
.. Dreams I know will never come true
.. Seems as though
I'll ever be blue.....
All up!
Who's last?
Wharton.
Find Menzies and ask him to come
to me in the garden, right away.
Yes, Barclay.
Go on!
Howzat!
Jim, good.
What is it?
I'm sorry, I've just discovered
something awful.
Mr Farquharson's thinking
of asking Fowler to stay on.
To be Head of House instead of you.
What?
You see, the House isn't going to have
enough prefects next term.
Why not? What do you mean?
It'll only be you and Bennett.
Two's not enough.
What about Devenish?
He's leaving.
His parents take a very dim view
of the Martineau business.
They want him to go to
agricultural college straightaway.
And as Fowler's a year senior to you
and as Judd refuses to be a prefect...
Judd!
Unless you can get him
to take a more responsible attitude,
you're a man short, Jim.
Fat chance!
I'm terribly sorry.
He's your only hope.
The answer is no.
I wish you'd reconsider.
I wish you'd let me work.
Look, I wouldn't ask you to do
anything you didn't want to do.
You just have to go through
the motions, that's all.
Prep duty, dorm, rollcall.
Nothing, really.
Menzies, do you have the makings
of a politician?
I'm only speaking
as one friend to another.
You have! Well, well.
You don't want Fowler to be
Head of House any more than I do.
He'll make your life a complete misery.
Too bad.
But I still refuse to collaborate
with a system of oppression.
Oh, for God's sake!
Oh, my God!
I can't look.
Are you alright, Bennett?
Shall I get Matron?
No. It was his smile.
It made me dizzy.
Everything beautiful is slightly lopsided.
There's a hollow
at the base of his throat
that makes me want to
pour honey over him and lick...
Bennett!
Hmm?
Wharton, washing up was supposed
to be finished 10 minutes ago.
Bennett, come with me.
Have you completely lost your mind?!
Yes, actually.
After all that's happened,
you talk like that in front of a junior?!
He doesn't understand.
Of course he does!
You'd better take a pull on yourself, Guy.
I'd rather do it with you.
For God's sake, will you stop?!
You've got to start showing
a little responsibility.
What on earth are you talking about?!
You don't know what's going on.
Devenish may be leaving.
Well?
Fowler may be going to stay on
as Head of House.
It can't be true...
Unfortunately, it can.
I need your help, Guy.
It's all Judd's fault
for refusing to be a prefect.
I want you to talk to him.
You're much more his friend than I am.
Shouldn't think
there's a hope in hell.
Well, there must be.
Remember,
if Fowler becomes Head of House,
he certainly won't
put you up for the Gods.
I'm relying on you, Guy.
Prove your worth for once.
Alright, Devenish, let's have a look.
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
Bennett.
Where?
Don't be silly.
Let me see your uniform.
Well, it won't do.
It won't do at all.
What's wrong with it?
Do you call those creases?
Well, I'm not very handy
with the iron, actually.
Do them again. Do everything again.
I'm not having you
let down the whole House.
Won't be the WHOLE House, Fowler,
I mean...
..the juniors aren't in the corps.
Nor is Judd.
Don't mention Judd to me.
Judd?
Judd...
Judd, Judd, Judd, Judd, Judd...
The moon shines bright.
On such a night as this...
..when the sweet wind
did gently kiss the trees
and they did make no noise...
..on such a night, Bennett, methinks,
mounted the Gascoigne walls
and sighed his soul toward
the Longford tents...
..where Harcourt lay that night.
I can't do it.
I just cannot be a prefect.
Why not?
I do have my reputation, you know.
Your what?!
I'm a school joke, I quite realise that.
But I am, don't you think,
a respected joke?
I do at least stick to my principles.
People appreciate that.
If I abandoned them now...
No. Sorry.
But you don't care what people think.
About me personally, no.
But they'll say it was all a fake.
No.
Say, "That's what we said all along.
It's all a form of showing off."
On the contrary,
they'll see the means justifying the ends.
What could be more communist
than that?
They'll think it was all a fake.
They'll think all communists are fake.
That's what they say about Stalin.
What's Stalin got to do with it?
That man is sweating blood
night and day
to drag his country into the 20th century
and create a whole new concept
of society at the same time.
I can't stand it when people sneer at him.
Jokes about the Tzar...
Quick! Quick!
Thought I might find you here.
It's alright. I couldn't sleep either.
That bloody dog of Wharton's
gets on my nerves.
I should like to go walkies myself.
Want to come?
I'm not exactly dressed for walking,
actually.
I was working.
Well... I won't disturb you.
Would you like my torch?
It IS yours.
Thanks.
This drainpipe's still alright, isn't it?
Afraid I can't tell you.
Barclay...
Yes?
Is the Housemaster really going to
ask Fowler to stay on?
Things do get about, don't they?
Is he?
I don't know.
To tell you the truth,
I don't actually care anymore.
I've had enough.
I haven't slept for nights and nights.
Really?
Frankly, I've got to the pitch
where I wonder why we bother.
Who?
Any of us.
Why we keep the whole thing going.
Sometimes I think none of us
really believes in it.
Of course you don't believe in it.
You're afraid to think of anything better.
Do you think so?
You know perfectly well
it's all nonsense.
You know it's positively wrong,
but you daren't act on your knowledge.
You daren't accept
the logical consequences.
Is that it?
You're afraid for your status,
your money, your class.
Everything that makes your life
safe and comfortable and privileged.
You're afraid to live
like an ordinary human being.
Perhaps I am.
Yes.
Leave the window open for me,
won't you?
My God...
..that man's really cracking up.
Liberals always do under pressure.
You know...
you're a really hard man, Tommy.
I've no time for him.
He just wants a nice easy life
with a nice easy conscience
and he's got no right to either.
I'm going to bed.
Are you going to join
the fight against Fowler?
I hate him so much,
it's difficult to be objective.
Well, the objective fact in this case
is that Fowler
is absolutely objectionable.
Please, Tommy.
If you appeal to me as your friend,
I'll never forgive you.
Menzies tried that.
I didn't mind it from him. He isn't a friend.
I'll think about it, but...
Oh, God, and I'll be in a rage
all day tomorrow.
Ah. Jacker Pot.
Militarism from 12:00 to 4:30.
Little boys all dressed up
and playing soldiers. God!
Tommy...
..if I lose his Jacker Pot...
..would you agree
to become a prefect then?
If you lose his Jacker Pot,
you probably won't be
a prefect yourself.
Goodnight.
Guy?
Careful! Barclay's about.
I know. He nearly saw me.
Thought I'd have a heart attack.
Alright, thank you, Wharton.
Now my sash.
Good.
Good luck, Fowler.
Thank you, Wharton.
Fall in!
Battalion -- atten...tion!
Battalion ready for inspection, sir.
Thank you, Sergeant-Major.
How's your father?
Very well, thank you, sir.
Good. Good.
Why did you do it, Bennett?
Do what?
You lost us the Pot!
Surely not just me, all on my own?
You were far and away
the worst-dressed soldier on the parade.
I'm not a soldier,
I'm a schoolboy and so are you.
You're a disgrace to the House
and to the entire school.
I'm hopeless with Brasso.
I only get a good shine on my nails. Look!
Let me see your belt.
You want me to undress
in front of all these people?
Give it to me!
I reckon that's worth a full six strokes.
Alright, Fowler. You can go ahead.
Thank you.
Come on, Bennett.
I appeal to Barclay and Delahay.
Of course.
It's my right. They're our House Gods.
It won't do you any good.
It's still my right.
Alright. If you insist.
If you let him off...
We won't.
Bennett's appealed to House Gods.
Gosh.
I wonder what they'll do to him.
Give him a jolly good beating,
I should think.
Well, um...
..I just thought you ought to know...
..that if one stroke of Fowler's cane
lands on my arse,
I shall go straight
to Mr Farquharson, and, ah...
..give him the names
of all the people I've...
..done it with
over the past three years, that's all.
Bennett, you can't do this.
Oh, I shall begin at the top.
Well... can I, um... go now?
Bloody little tart!
You never thought it
particularly bloody at the time.
My God, I'll thrash you myself!
It's only a game, Delahay.
There's no need to get so excited.
I thought sportsmen
were supposed to be good losers.
I'd never have dared do that.
It's only cheating.
Everyone cheats here the whole time.
I don't.
I bet you do.
When you've got the chance.
I don't even crib!
I don't mean work, I mean games.
Sportsmanship.
It's all hypocrisy.
Well... we all know what goes on
in the scrum when the ref's not looking.
Oh, well...
..if THAT'S what you mean.
Mmm.
Yes, of course.
It'll be getting light soon.
Mmm.
I must be going.
Come on.
You know...
..what I really hate about cricket...
..is it's such a damn good game.
Ah, Judd's Paradox.
Of course...
..cricket is a fundamental part
of the capitalist conspiracy, hmm?
Of course.
One only has to observe the team.
There's the proletariat
forced to labour in the field
while the bourgeoisie indulges in
the pleasures of batting and bowling.
Quite.
I mean, there's every reason
to suppose...
..that the game ultimately derives
from the wholly unjustified right
of the medieval lord
to the unpaid labour of villeins and serfs
at haymaking and harvest.
You're really beginning to get the idea.
Thanks.
Ah, there he is at the school shop.
Isn't he awesome, Tommy?
Drawing attention to yourself again?
He's not even waving back.
Course he's not.
You should learn from his discretion.
Oh, if only I could.
I can't get you to change your mind?
It's my father.
When he asked what I'd be staying for,
it was hard to say.
The First XI next term?
It's a long time to wait
on the off-chance.
If I was going to be a God,
but... as it is,
just being an ordinary prefect
doesn't really make it worthwhile.
Sorry.
By the way...
.. I've decided that greatest happiness
of the greatest number
will best be achieved
if I do agree to be a prefect.
Tommy!
Stop it.
I'll insist on the terms
set forth by Menzies
with one extra condition --
I refuse to take House prayers.
Oh, he won't care about that.
Oh, Tommy, my cup runneth over.
You really are a hero of the people.
I'm going to award you the Order
of Lenin, first class with oak leaves.
If I wasn't in love with James,
I'd be in love with you.
Don't be so emotional.
It's a purely rational decision.
Go on. Go tell Menzies
before you change your mind.
Alright, alright.
He's in the music school.
Go on. Hurry!
Going, going.
Wharton!
Yes, Bennett?
Want to earn yourself another ice-cream?
I wouldn't mind.
If you go to school shop, you'll
find a man from Longford -- Harcourt.
Do you know him?
By sight.
Good. Give him this.
Here's sixpence.
Why are you so keen on Harcourt?
If you don't know,
I'm certainly not going to tell you.
Now get along.
Oh!
I'll have that, if you don't mind, Wharton.
Now, come on! Give it to me!
Alright, Wharton. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Menzies, can I have a word?
Yes, of course. What is it?
I am willing to become a prefect...
Menzies!
..but there are some conditions...
Look at this.
What is it?
I've got him this time.
He can't get away now.
I'm taking this straight to Barclay.
What on earth's that all about?
Just one moment, Judd.
We can discuss this later.
Devenish, do you think it would
make any difference to your attitude,
or your father's attitude,
if you told him you would be in the Gods
next term, instead of Bennett?
I'm sure it would.
Perhaps you should
go and telephone him.
You mean there's a real chance?
Wharton!
Tell Bennett to come to Hall Table.
I can't do it.
What's the matter? Lost your nerve?
Alright, I'll do it. Come on.
Alright, Bennett. Bend over.
I don't understand.
Why didn't you
just use the blackmail again?
Because.
Because what?
Because if I'd gone to Housemaster...
..it'd all come out about James.
So what?
We'd have both been expelled.
Lucky you.
I couldn't do that.
I love him.
Oh, come on, Guy.
Look, I'm not going to pretend anymore.
I'm sick of pretending!
You think it's a joke. Well, it's not.
I am never going to love women!
Don't be ridiculous!
Martineau knew that about himself
when he was 10. He told me.
You can't possibly know that
at 10 or now.
Yes, you can.
Look, it doesn't...
come as any great revelation.
It's... more like admitting to yourself
something you've always known.
Owning up to yourself. It's...
It's a great relief... in some ways.
You can't trust intuitions like that.
Well, what else is there?
Are you a communist
because you read Karl Marx? No.
You read Karl Marx
because you are a communist.
I'm very sorry for you.
Thanks! If that's how friends react...
I'm sorry.
You're quite right.
That was patronising and unforgivable.
But you couldn't help it, could you?
Because in your heart of hearts,
like Barclay and Delahay
and Fowler and Menzies,
you still believe...
..in spite of your talk
of equality and fraternity,
you still believe...
..some people are better than others
because of the way they make love.
Well...
..think of that for a lifetime.
Think of the names.
Pansy. Nancy. Fairy. Fruit.
Brown-nose.
Look...
This hurts like hell. I'm...
I'm... I'm gonna walk it off.
Coming?
Good, that's settled then, Donald.
Thanks.
I mean, well, thanks.
Bennett can't complain.
I've warned him time and again.
Oh, good. Here they are.
Wonderful news.
Devenish is staying on after all.
It's most generous of you to offer, Judd,
but you can keep your principles
untarnished now.
But I've a disappointment
for you, Bennett,
though it can hardly
come as a surprise after recent events.
I shall be nominating Devenish
for the Gods next term instead of you.
You bastard.
You really gave me no choice, Guy.
Don't you ever
call me by my Christian name again.
Ever.
You were easily bought.
My father was a God himself
and when I told him...
Yes, your son will be a God, and
your son's son, unto the end of school.
Look, we saved the House
from Fowler.
We saved your conscience.
Oh, yes. All problems solved
for life. No commies and no queers.
Don't let's quarrel.
We've all got to live together
next term.
Let's try and do it
as amicably as possible, shall we?
It isn't the end of the world.
Isn't it?
When people like Menzies
rule the world...
..and you want to be ambassador
in Paris...
"Ah, Bennett, yes.
"Nice enough chap.
"Quite amusing, actually.
"We had high hopes of him once
but... oh, yes, you heard.
"Not... not quite one of us.
"Bogota, do you think? No.
Haiti -- isn't that coming up?
"That's much more his line.
You see, he was never a God.
"Only ever an ordinary prefect."
No need to be even that.
Oh, yes, there is.
If I'm spending the rest of my life...
..hiding my true nature...
..I'm taking every comfort that's going
when it IS going.
Oh, well, if that's your attitude.
And, besides, being absolutely...
..objective...
..it would dish me once and for all.
You can't have things both ways.
Why not?
OW!
Pretend to do one thing,
only really do the other.
Fool the swine. Play along with them.
Let them think what they like.
Let them despise you, but all along...
Oh, don't talk dribble.
..and have the last laugh
and be revenged.
That's just sentimental twaddle.
You wouldn't be in this mess
if you had any discretion at all.
What better cover
for someone like me than...
..total indiscretion?
Wouldn't it be wonderful
if communism were really true?
It is true.
What? Heaven on earth?
Earth on earth.
The JUST earth.
Of course, Tommy was killed
in the Spanish Civil War.
Tough as old boots, Tommy was.
Till the bloody fascists got him.
Have you ever wanted to go back?
No.
Is there nobody
that you'd want to see?
No.
Isn't there anything you miss at all?
I...
.. I miss the cricket.
.. Most dear
to them that love her
.. Most great to them that know
.. We may not count her armies
.. We may not see her king
.. Her fortress is a faithful heart
.. Her pride is suffering
.. And soul by soul and silently
.. Her shining bounds increase
.. And her ways
are ways of gentleness
.. And all her paths are peace...