Come on, give me your hand!
not think he does, Bobby.
go, the good Lord will not let you die for
some tequila.
What is the number?
Lambasino birthday.
eight, thirty-one, forty-two
.
Bingo!
Well, well, we have here ..!
this fly anywhere,
partner. What do you want?
And this is?
Remember I said that someone stole
my razor?
Motherfucker!
should Lambasino arrest.
C'mon, Ernie.
Dress.
Not want you ass kicked
so early in the week.
I have eyes?
feet in the snow.
what this is all about,
is that in the last 2 years,
Del Amo had the worst performance as a Border Patrol
throughout South Texas
Silence!
Frankly, gentlemen,
the attitude of this division,
stinks!
so bad that I have been asked to take steps
to improve the situation.
Mr. Lacy came from Washington DC
to teach a system that he has developed
.
His invention
help us all to achieve our goals.
Someone down those curtains.
Basically, it's a tracking system.
they see is a matrix representing an area
40 square miles
input is generated by geo-sensors
small electronic modules implanted in the ground,
sensitive to even the coins in a man's pocket.
do not even have a coin
's why crossing the border..
Enough
Wyatt.
Any next activity sensor,
generate a signal on the screen,
like this.
Here we see an imaginary immigrant
quadrant passing C5 to C6.
the ovulador regulated?
You're going .
what?
ovulador. As
prevents malfunction?
enough!
This signal is artificial, the geo-sensors
will be buried in their areas.
means we have to bury them?
Right.
Transmit a signal to the console when entering a
illegal.
sure to adjust the sensitivity for objects more than 60 cm.
Remember gentlemen.
sensor only detect objects more than 60 cm.
Sorry! I saw a rabbit in the field
big enough to jump
a pony.
Quiet please.
Just out of curiosity, how will these...
geo-sensors
affect us?
There will be fewer agents,
the taxpayer will pay less.
What he is saying is that after we bury
stuff,
two-thirds of us will
unemployed.
They tried this shit in Viet Nam
not work there, either they
work here.
Silence. Work in other sectors,
now follow the Master.
Open the curtains.
- I try to clarify something
- No you can not, Wyatt?.
just want to do one more question.
Let me try to understand,
third of us...
than fired,
sit in a room...
to monitor a machine that monitors
to another machine.
I did not go to the Border Patrol
to watch TV.
asked anyone about this?
Shut up!
Shut up, dammit!
Excuse me, sir, what Ernie is trying to say is that
might we have been asked.
entered the Patrol
to deal with computers and radar screens.
Many of us reject
promotions because we hate desktops.
think it's important to know what we want
because it seems that we have no alternative
.
Think I'm asking for your vote
This is an official decicisn.
And you're right, you have no alternative
.
Come on man, you
not believe this man, right?
Calm down, everything will be fine.
Hey, careful with my jeep.
Lombasino, do not fuck with me today, OK?
was joking, Ernie.
Carl, you say.
saw tire tracks in
forwarding Paseo. Pesqu?senlas.
something bother you, Ernie?
told you not to fuck with me, stupid.
Stupid.
You, cowboy, your locker seems
a drugstore
not mess, we are left with something
occasionally.
does anyone.
believe that if we deliver Brook
send it to the Central?
Amobls
home with things that we carry.
- is not that we are stealing, Bob
- What about my knife.?
That knife?
- Your
knife -. Oh, is your knife.
was lying for some time
Resentful.?
Fuck you...
Meanwhile, clean your locker or change
birthday.
- What's in the box
- Ask Brook?. Packet.
can not believe we boten
a damn computer.
will become of us after we bury
of those things?
never seen a computer that tracks
a man to 40 miles.
Unit 2 copies me
You're right, you have a good
education.
depend not work. But I... I...
I have two options:
Or lose my job, or...
.   Unit 2 copies me
or spend my life in that damn basement
watching a fucking TV screen.
Shut up, Shut
damn radio!
Yes, we are coming
Called Sheriff reports a landing
Alliance
Verif?quenlo
- Unit 2, understanding
Let's see those footprints found
Lombasino.
Tell me, Ernie.
, sometimes I have the feeling that all this
not bothered.
I hate more than you.
But I have more stamina
if you show me a way out, take it.
But as my dad
"If you can not get out, get."
I just said that if you can not fix
, send him to hell.
also said that.
do you think?
I have no idea
only tire tracks
No footprints. Or they flew
or are still inside.
llegales?
want me to call?
Brook believes we are in
Alliance Take a look..
No, no, okay
came to help..
We did scare shit!
Sorry, ma'am...
was time to appear
could have died..
Lucky spent here
Look at it this way..
Well, now that they're here, what?
We sell tickets to the dance
police?
Us Border Patrol
not have dances..
Hello!
Hello.
Count  why they are here.
damn car is fucked.
Mind if...
give out your ID?
Care, you will not run out of sight.
Look, we are honest people.
did the night shift. We are
telephone operators of San Antonio.
Wanted to shorten Durbin
way I am from there, but... we missed.
- And the damn car crapped
- Yes, yes, what you said before.
can fix it?
'll see what I can do.
Veras  you can do?
or retain the hell out?
Kidding
What is the problem?
fan belt cut.
fan beltcut
water pump blew.
can take them to Del Amo
And then what.?
the workshop I will not sell them until tomorrow
parts.
- What you want
- The Grouchy?.
're sick.
You bet.
fare like the story?
! You are the mechanical genius.
You tell him.
Buenos , call the help,
to tow the car serviced,
but probably is not ready...
until tomorrow.
'd better leave that
a good motel.
the grateful.
Ray, I'm starving,
have nothing to eat?
Care!
Sorry.
Let me help you.
Come Doris.
Del Amo calling units 2 and 3,
copied me? ! Logan
Wyatt, Units 2 and 3, answer
Damn
You leave me alone?
want to leave me alone!
40 other guys out there!
can not call one of them?
not want me to finish this?
Once finished, I'll be out of a job
!
not make you happy?
Here Wyatt
Moron
Where the hell is unit 3
Where these you
Sector 7 near Paseo Wash.
Logan also
I copies Wyatt
You repeat, sir ?
Logan's   you
Negative.
went to the Alliance pesquisar
plane that reported the Sheriff.
Highway Patrol reported a code 3 in Two Cats. . Cover them
Del Amo, Unit 2, over.
Wait, unit 2
If, Logan
Meet Wyatt position, sir?
Choose any of the plane
.   Airplane, Logan. Whoever said you were
make inquiry
Yes sir, right.
Up in Mesa Alliance. Without a doubt.
Well. On Friday you and Wyatt
take the night shift
That's the day after tomorrow, sir.
You know where it landed, right
Absolutely Where
sent Ernie says.?
Two Cats have a code 3
Del Amo calling units 2 and 3,
copied me
is.
What happened?
According to the driver of the tanker truck
not respect the "Stop".
came very quickly, thought the other
would stop at the intersection.
broadsided and flipped.
tanker driver was taken to hospital
, the other died.
many were in the truck?
21 in total. 8 dead, 5, and
were removed. There are 13 wounded.
know who it belonged to?
name of that: Pedroza.
As you know, Sheriff Wells,
my client is not obliged to answer questions
yet.
In fact, Mr. Hinshaw is so unfortunate
of Texas law.
Since
truck belongs to his client, may I ask what you want.
Look, the truck is mine
But if you check the records,
see I reported it was stolen
my ranch several days.
Surely by whom he led
It is he who should be interrogated..
Only the Lord knows if that's true
The driver is dead..
How unfortunate for justice.
always goes with your lawyer?
That question is irrelevant, Sheriff
you I would not accusations..
Mr. Pedroza
is a respected man in the community, Mr. Pedroza...
is scum.
Anoto that comment, official...
Wyatt. Ernest Wyatt
W-YATT
Be careful friend.
not call me friend.
You appear here with that shit
attorney in your pocket
while his people removed
plastic bags.
that truck he was never stolen.
you collect "wetbacks"
in Chihuahua and brings them here.
He promises freedom and sells
death.
is a fucking murderer,
a bloody butcher.
- Your own people
- You have a dirty mouth, boy.
- Let
- You have a dirty job.
Come on.
okay?
I'm sick.
trash Pedroza,
Brook and...
radarcitos.
Maybe  Brook is right.
We have no choice.
the fuck happened to you?
We have a choice. Output
remember we were talking about?
found.
seems
hit the wall and was buried.
And there was more rain and more mud
.
was covered for a while.
The lights were on,
driving at night.
- Wipers lit
- Yes
Change is in third.
quickly came to the desert
dark and raining..
Open it.
$ 800,000.
seems to come directly from the bank.
And if so why?
If this guy did something wrong and should be completely forgotten
.
- has to be false
- Nonsense..
We took these and verified.
But they're good, I can smell Ernie
.
are you doing?
I want to see who this guy was.
-was a bad boy
mafia who wanted independence,
B-A
dealer who had a deal.
No respectable citizen would walk through the desert with all that cash.
A piece of paper with some phone numbers
.
Texas driver's license.
Michael J. Curtis. Blyde Street 1130,
Apartment D, San Antonio, Texas.
Caucasian, brown hair, brown eyes
.
Issued in '62, in '66
expired.
You checked the patent?
Yes, of Texas, M-6474, 1963.
more here.
me a hand.
Fishing rod, reel, rifle
crap for hunting and fishing..
do you think?
is not right to take it.
Why not? For the rest of the world this
money disappeared 20 years ago.
Shit, Ernie! Not an hour ago, so
Brook and wanted to get the hell out Pedroza.
now have a ticket first
and do not know if it is okay or not?
only money man!
'll tell you what: we camouflage jeep
erase our footprints,
carry boxes to Kauffman,
checked the money and if OK,
split it half and get out of here ..
not know.
I'll have to think about it.
're the only man I know
ruining their own dreams.
never thought these things would we vote.
We are magic together...
Where are you going?
's your name, baby?
nice name.
Your drink.
going from El Paso to San Antonio, we
burning 582 miles of highway.
Oh, Mariita... he says.
bet I'm going to brown.
Wait, I have a good one.
A guy goes into his car and a cop stops
.
- are you doing? Asks
-. I do not understand, you mean?
- That takes you back in the car
- What?
guy looks back and the car is full of penguins
.
-
can not do that - come with me..
can not have them. I want to take them to the zoo immediately
.
guy says
Now - now, the zoo?.
guy says: Okay Okay
..
The next day the police again
see the car.
Le says: You, park
pull over.!
- As I said yesterday
- That he talking about?
- I said I can not have those things
- What things.?
told him to take these penguins to the zoo
?
says: The Today I took yesterday
go to the beach.!
- This is always so
- Like?
you come here often?
wanted to spend the best time of your life?
is always so good?
Ernie sometimes vomits.
, Ernie is different. For starters,
is 15 years younger.
still believe in God, country,
at work, on duty.
is a man of integrity.
straight as an arrow
I no longer do so..
best man  Unit.
you?
have good aim and
can direct traffic if necessary.
But I have what he has.
What is it?
That brave young
that can change things a notion.
If you do not believe that, because you still
Border Patrol?
likes. I like the freedom
's in it.
I like the fact that
Del Amo is so far away,
that nobody messes with us.
patrol sector is desirable that as little
anyone not interested
rules are twisted
keep us happy.
But it's nice to be in the desert
's beautiful.
attracts me the thrill of the chase
.
202 is the area code of DC
perhaps another San Antonio.
But both are disconnected.
Neither  card or social security...
Nothing.
If the guy was a thief, would walk with
more roles, whether false.
Or not?
is rare.
Even if they found the jeep,
could not trace the money to us.
We can.
We license the
home in San Antonio.
We're going to San Antonio tomorrow You
you trace the direction, money
Wait a minute.
These two girls work on the
phone company, right?
Why not ask them to
we check these numbers?
do not you ask him to Doris?
Who?
Doris, the sulky.
could do that.
is so worn.
not know, do not know, do not know
Shit!
think we should tell the Sheriff?
Is that what you want to do?
This is serious, Bobby.
$ 800,000 are serious.
Hey, you do...?
Buy Coins - Stamps
I help you?
Yes, perhaps you can tell me
this ticket.
won at poker last night I noticed
says "Silver Certificate",
Which generally says "Federal Reserve
". I thought it was fake.
who left the yard this?
There is nothing false in
Silver Certificate,
always it has been printed in the United States
.
You do not see many, the government stopped printing
in '62.
Let
Well  background, watermark,
good paper, signed S. Dillon.
.
good?
-
Insurance - That tells me this one.?
Bill Federal Reserve, '63,
series "Green Seal"
signing Devin Granahan, Series K,
printed ticket Dallas.
is also good.
sure?
If you can not tell a good one ticket
false
would not have lasted long in
this business, do not you think?
- Thanks
- back soon.
Satisfied
did I tell you?
has to be stolen.
type jeep
probably stole a Dallas bank.
what?
sound like an old woman.
"Well, I dunno, maybe
not be right."
may not be correct.
At least not for me.
I did not ask
you talk me into this.
Is that okay for me then?
'll tell you what:
unearth the money and turn it over to Brook.
may not punish you.
Look, I'm willing to take
money.
truth.
're so generous, Ernie.
Whenever we have the same right as any
.
Look, the guy said they stopped printing
Silver Certificate in 1962.
The other ticket is  '63, the same year the patent
Jeep.
Why not go to the library and we checked
if there was a theft or robbery
that year.
still need to verify that the type
home.
not find the house, leave me
library. Pick me up then.
luck?
A pair of armed robberies, guys
Frauds mail..
that you find out?
The house no longer exists. There is now a parking
.
the Patent Office does not have information
over 10 years.
So we're in the first month.
Let's go .
've had enough for today.
Will you take the money now?
You said 24 hours.
do not know if Ellen could track
those phone numbers.
Oh... shit!
plane.
That plane?
runway at Alliance
that we pesquisar.
are lies told to
Brook.
No, it is not
We have to go there tomorrow..
Who found?
I did.
You told Brook that had
found?
What would I do? Tell
I took the girls to the motel?
I told her I had found when I was looking
.
Tomorrow we have to find the fucking place.
There goes our day.
ahead.
Sherrif Wells,
Agent Logan.
, We met at Dos Gatos
Good to see you again.
Any relation to Matt Logan?
was my dad.
Motherfucker.
Let me show you something.
the top row.
3rd from the right is me
Who's with me?
my old.
! Have a seat.
Texas Rangers, son.
I, your father and the rest of us.
were the best he had.
now call
Department of Public Safety.
do you like a drink?
We have a report of a plane landing on
Alliance Mesa.
about 30 miles east of here.
son. Think I know where it is?
I know this better than
anyone except God territory.
And sometimes I wonder if not more.
Here.
changed.
Well, yes. We have a report of a plane landing on
Alliance.
done regularly. There is an old desert rat
, call Amarillo.
He has seen. And he complained that scares
his mule.
your father, God bless him.
better days.
Amarillo?
Who you ask?
He is  Wyatt is the agent I am the Logan
agent.
Border Patrol.
come from the office of Sheriff Wells.
says you have seen a plane landing at Alliance
Mesa.
then?
can download the old Sharps.
are the types of aircraft which
interest us.
you actually saw the plane land?
No.
But landings are regular.
Tuesdays and Fridays.
knows if you've never seen
the plane, sir?
a seismic fault,
top two officers crossing from north to northwest, short
.
flat side and clean
measured about 200 meters.
At 5:00
comes a Cessna 175,
to 60 knots, decelerated.
Flaps down, rudder
down by the wind.
know it's a Cessna 175
As I know so much detail?
spent 40 years of my life being
Convair company engineer.
Convair know it, son?
Yes, sir.
plane scares my mule.
not be surprised if we
morning to see that plane.
assume that brings drugs from South.
Thank you very much.
Better be careful.
Desert Go away.
Why?
gonna rain.
Crazy old.
heard that.
What is the problem?
No money trail
phones or license.
feel we should leave now..
arrest on a beautiful morning.
Ok, make the arrest and as
finished, empty our closets
seek the money and go.
Good morning, sir.
Wyatt and I are ready for the mission
Alliance.
I want to introduce you to the inspectors
Carson, Hawthorne and Skrunk.
These gentlemen
aircraft, Logan is responsible.
You receive orders
inspector Carson.
want a report on this
runway, Logan.
Called
Why is our arrest.
not issue credits, Logan, but
efficiency.
Our job is better if
interact with them.
addition, Washington has
interest in the matter.
this department owes favors Washington
enough, is not it?
I was teaching
our new tracker.
Carson
inspector is impressed with the sensors installed.
Good job, Wyatt.
We stayed at the Highland Tower, room 103
.
be a meeting at 9:30 o'clock
hope that report, Logan.
want to get the uniforms?
Yes, we will.
So
Brook men lead us into two groups.
A group from the west, establishing a perimeter
in this sector.
The other group, from the east,
will handle this quadrant.
Wyatt will lead the group this
Logan and West group.
understood everything, Wyatt?
take all transmitters.
Our three vehicles and jeeps
are hidden at the foot of the plateau.
Here, here and here.
Where hide the rotating wheel?
think this is a circus, Wyatt?
What he means is that in the desert
things are very visible.
especially from the air.
Five vehicles
there probably will cast all away.
would you, Logan?
Half a dozen men
can handle the track.
Divide and attack the
plane has just landed.
I do not care  the plane.
Want the vehicle to take us contact
stash.
's just a deposit. Catch the
tickets and will be closer to the source.
Or you can let them do the deal, the vehicle
let go
stop the plane and follow the vehicle until the tank
have a full reservoir and source drugs if you are lucky.
Logan  Ok, have it your way.
All clear here.
Logan, Robert E.
Born 06/08/41.
graduate of West Point, 1963.
Hero Green Beret in Vietnam,
3 Silver Stars,
recommendation for the Medal of Honor.
Had the world in the hands at 24.
And suddenly... poof
disappears.
Nothing is known of him until '72.
doing now?
Sweating in the desert
top of a jeep,
Saying "Yes, sir" to assholes like
Brook, who does not get to the heels.
That happened, Logan
Why wasting your life here?
I like quiet.
Bullshit, you fled
Why?
you do nothing
really valuable here.
Hell, when Nixon was president,
had a "wetback"
working for San Clemente.
damn president had a "greasy"
cooking for him. It was in the papers.
someone cared
Hell, no.
I do my job, Carson.
No, you fled
Admit it..
- was afraid of being someone
- No, I was afraid to be someone like you
Hiding here, away from the pressure
pressure
politics..
Oh, come on, politics!
whole fucking country is politics!
you work in the Border Patrol.
A Division of Immigration, which depends
Justice Department,
reporting directly to the Congress.
is believed that this is not political?
eludes you think
system because it hides in the background.
not work for the system to work
law.
law, by God! You work for the same law
paying our salaries.
The law of supply and demand.
Think, smart guy. His work depends
of those "wetbacks"
if not exist, would invent
If not, as would justify the millions we
provides Congress every year?
's the American way, friend
Supply and demand..
if supply is missing, create it.
Every day I wake up I thank
drugs, murder, subversion.
Because without them, we would all be out of work
.
Who are you?
Not a Federal
more behind a drug arrest.
are you doing here, really?
am a repairman, Logan
fix things..
Yes? What kind of things?
that need fixing.
We have visual contact with an approaching van
Plateau
Copying Ernie
're ready..
Here comes .
Prepare.
ready, Bobby.
I'm going out.
Let
Stop! Stop the plane.
Ernie, jump!
Ernie... dammit!
jumped the fuck not?
you told them.
warned them to escape,
motherfucker!
Is that what is here
killed Ernie, damn it.
I shot the plane, Logan.
These are my witnesses
What are yours, asshole.?
knew that bastard was not
here for a drug arrest.
the trouble to send
dressed that Washington is not taken.
He was sent to protect the source from there
Someone spoke of fucking money..
They are shitting.
Take the money and go to Mexico.
What is this?
tea.
Who is it?
's us, Ellen and Doris.
We told
be here or in the hospital.
you okay?
with a little cold.
hope it's okay to come unannounced.
sure were lucky to find us.
We leave tomorrow. We now
vacation or lose. Beer?
Well, where will they go?
Mexico
Ernie, do not invite me for a drink?
Make that 2 beers, Bobby.
Tracked those two numbers left a note in his office.
What?
numbers. One of them belongs to a certain
Beck in Washington DC
And the other was Dallas police
20 years.
left that information to someone
office.?
Price  friend who was in the bar.
What is the name...? Lamba...
Lambasino.
, that one.
We left the note said that the
deliver tomorrow.
would have brought here, but
not know if would be home.
tried to call last night, as nobody answered
, worried. So...
went to the office. The chief said
were on a mission.
were a lot of people where you work.
Lamborgino was happy because a Federal
carrada found a cocaine
even brought a corpse.
was nothing but a skeleton.
skeleton?
All were very agitated
told us to leave.
- I go to the bathroom
- Yeah, sure?.
I have to talk to Ernie
right back..
are up to the neck, man.
Nobody knows where those numbers came
.
wish I could explain this, but I can not
Something happens and Ernie and I must go.
're in trouble?
can not tell you anything more,
not want to get involved.
really go to Mexico?
.
knew.
Mira.
wich I do not and I speak a little Spanish
...
- Just
me know - I know what I feel..
Listen, I like you,
seriously.
But I can not take you with me now.
At least I do know that
okay?
.
want what you took
Jeep.
Eh...?
jeep in Merida Wash Your
you report, no.?
And what if I did?
I did not take anything
There was nothing to take.
Who the hell are you?
- Max, Lambasino left a note
- Maybe you are on the Board?.
is, and look there.
that brought about the skeleton?
Who knows
Carson has the information..
Logan Wyatt!
Dejo Unit, guys.
I transferred  Administration.
will work in Washington.
They sent all season
here.!
Congratulations.
Who is the new boss, sir?
Washington will decide during the next month.
Meanwhile, Carson
interim head freezes.
guess it's the American way.
Learn fast, Logan.
you seen lambasino and Roget?
No.
not been reported yet. They will be watching
Wash happens in Merida.
What happens in Merida  Wash?
not know? Shit, go see it.
Worth.
Nobody can go from here.
Really?
orders, sir.
Come on, man. We're on the same side.
We'm Wyatt agent, it's Logan.
I see you are  Border Patrol
But still can not let go
Sorry.
a military secret?.
not know. Suppose.
you have no idea what your peers are searching
there?
Ask
people who are in charge.
Not the kind of people who would ask me
. Thank you.
suits are men of Carson.
.
Hey, watch this.
A man wearing a horse.
Or a mule.
We should have heard this
Someone should have seen reported..
Look, here and here.
Two men, street shoes.
This here
recognize these tracks?
18 x 40, standard heavy duty
Trocha..
Probably  a jeep.
Lambasino and Roget?
city vehicle, standard gauge,
misaligned front end.
now?
tracked each State Auto Texas
need alignment?
seems Lambasino and Roget
followed.
No report this?
Bobby, I did all the road with the radio on
.
Nothing!
What's with that jeep that brought Carson
the 5th Army up here?
Why  driver only brought
a driver's license?
Where did all that money?
is the only man who reported this
is there, dead?
Why Lambasino and Roget
not reported?
Where is the city car?
seems that came and went.
So you found the footprints
coming over here, right?
Auto City
front end alignment.
a still from the old
in the desert, 10 miles from here.
They killed him and burned his house.
Lambasino and Roget were there.
followed that car. Traces of both
brought us here.
So that's your story?
Because "history" says?
chasing  know, right?
Did you know?
know?
pursuing you know?
That chasing who, Logan?
Del Amo, special unit 1
answer.
Hawthorne here, I copy.
I'm on site
No problems..
. Copied.
We were informed that Mr. Pedroza
sends a shipment of illegal.
Apparently  cross by
Balancing Rock,
and detect a car near Soledad Mountain
.
Well, that gives these two
something to do.
heard him, geniuses
Move your asses..
You  verifies what the car is mine Pedroza.
Soledad See you in 2 hours.
Largu?mosnos here.
Seek the money and go.
No sir, it's the chance to grab
Pedroza.
Fuck Pedroza and the car should go
hell now.
can not do it, Bobby.
Special Unit 2. In Soledad Mountain
no sign of Logan.
Del Amo, Unit 2
I copied?
Logan, told him to go to the mountain
. Where the hell is
I did, I'm here.
Soledad Mountain, told him out there
Where the hell was
Hell knows where I am?
back here now
Now
Where is Ernie?
returned over an hour ago. Pedroza
caught it and should be celebrating
He would not do that.
Back  , Logan
Tired
Said go here.
There is unit 1.
Special Unit One. White
located 150 m. south by southwest.
We advance on foot. Contact
as confirm death
Logan, Logan ..!
's going on?
Who the hell is that?
Why?
Fuck you, man.
Who were you?
Let me see your hands, please.
Why dug where they should not?
rifle did.
I got a license number
and said...
Curtis would appear that such a
in the afternoon or evening of 22.
"Go get him, wait"
had to give him money and a fishing kit
place for rifle.
Guide you to the border...
did what I was told.
But out of nowhere, you gave him the license number
my sheriff
and the nightmare began again.
Come on!
Do it here if you want, I'll leave
not take me back.
'll take you back.
want to upload to your jeep and
you go south... to Mexico.
Change your name, change your appearance
.
I give you this opportunity because
son Matt.
get on the jeep not flee.
be back to tell you what I know.
'll tell you something you do not know: you're
become murderer.
stabbed
your own mate for that money.
's been in for over an hour
radius.
I kill you just see
likely receive a medal.
say... say I killed Ernie?
you have caught, boy,
the same as the others.
want to die?
back there.
want to live?
Go! Take the money.
What about you?
not worry. Already come.
wait here.
will give you some time.
Whatever happens,
have happened years ago.
Come on, son. Do not become a martyr
, we already have too many.
Go, make the difference
Be the fleeing.
Well.
I'm going back.
Tell them, if given the opportunity.
tell you.