GUY: I don't wanna scare anyone...
but I'm gonna give it to
you straight about Jason.
His body was never recovered
from the lake after he drowned.
If you listen to the old-timers in town,
they'll tell you he's still out there.
- Camp Crystal Lake is jinxed.
- It's got a death curse.
Some folks claim they've
even seen him...
right in this area.
MAN: Who is that?
Oh, hi. What are you
doing out in this mess?
The girl who survived that night at
Camp Blood, that Friday the 13th...
she claims she saw him.
The boy. Is he dead too?
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMS)
We didn't find any boy.
ALICE: Then he's still there.
She disappeared two months later.
(CAT SNARLS)
(SCREAMS)
Legend has it that Jason saw his
mother beheaded that night...
(SCREAMING)
and he took his revenge.
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
(WHIMPERING)
A revenge that he'll continue to seek
if anyone enters his wilderness again.
(SCREAMING)
Jason was my son. And
today is his birthday.
(SCREAMS)
That's a good boy.
Good. Good Jason.
(SCREAMS)
Jason's out there.
(BOTH GRUNT)
No! Aah! Aah!
(CHRIS WHIMPERING)
CHRIS: You can't be alive!
Got another white coming in, Larry.
Let's keep the area clear.
MEDIC: Where are they?
What do you need and
where do you need it?
We got ten of them.
Yours is in the barn.
What's wrong with him?
He's dead. Yeah, they're all dead.
You can pull it up over there.
- All dead. Some emergency.
- Put her over there.
This the guy that's been
leaving the wet stuff?
This time he got seven
kids and three bikers.
This time they got him.
- VINCENT: Lainie?
- Hmm?
- Belt him.
- Yeah.
VINCENT: What's the matter
with you? He's dead.
MAN (OVER LOUDSPEAKER): Okay,
boys and girls, let's get going!
God!
WOMAN (OVER PA):
Dr. Wellsely to O.R. 2.
Here, sign it.
AXEL: Hmm? Mm.
- This your last?
- No, got one more over there.
- Real cute girl.
- Was.
She still is. All you gotta
do is go over there...
Nice talk. Real nice talk.
I get the top copy.
- LAINIE: Take care, Axel.
- Mm.
LAINIE: Man, he's crazy.
(LAINIE SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
WOMAN (OVER PA): Miss Aaron,
telephone, please. Miss Aaron.
- I'm free, doll.
- And a bargain at twice the price.
- Hey. What's the matter?
- I have a headache, Axel.
- For you, I always have a headache.
- Oh, I can fix that.
Oh.
Meet me in the cold room.
I'm closing up for the night.
What do you say? Okay?
MORGAN: Axel, I am not going to
fake any more orgasms for you.
You got the curse?
If I do, you're it.
Axel?
(WHISPERS) Axel.
(IN NORMAL VOICE) Oh, Axel.
Axel?
Aah! God, Axel!
I'm so glad you could come.
MORGAN: Axel, you are the
Super Bowl of self-abuse!
I just came to watch the news.
MAN 1 (ON TV): Now back to today's news.
The tragic story of mass slayings...
(WHISTLES)
(MOUTHS) I'm sorry.
MAN 2 (ON TV): And so begins yet
another chapter in a story...
most residents of Crystal
Lake had prayed was over.
A trail of mangled bodies has finally
led local authorities to conclude...
(POP MUSIC PLAYING ON TV)
I really came to watch the news.
MAN 3 (ON TV): We're still awaiting
positive identification of the body.
But to answer your question,
yes, the man responsible...
for the murders in Wessex
County this past week...
is at this moment in the Wessex
County Medical Center morgue.
- Yeah!
- Hey.
That's you they're talking
about on TV, pal.
I don't believe you, Axel.
- Then... shut... my... mouth.
- My... mouth.
MAN 2: ...in the wake of
what will always be known...
as the Crystal Lake massacres.
And now back to you, Bill.
(MORGAN SCREAMS)
Jesus Christmas!
Holy Jesus goddamn!
Holy Jesus jumping Christmas shit!
You better get that
sucker in the icebox!
I must be nuts! I mean, I really...
- Good night, Axel.
- Hey, where are you going?
I'll tell you where I'm
going, I'm going crazy!
Shit! Shit!
Hi, girls. Thanks for waiting.
Oh, no.
Shit!
(AXEL GROANING)
MORGAN: Get lost, Axel, I'm busy. I've had
more than enough of you for one night.
Read my lips. Leave me alone! Aah!
No!
(SCREAMING)
- I talked to Dad.
- How is he?
Oh. He said he was lonely. He
asked me to come out and see him.
MRS. JARVIS:
Did he tell you to take a number?
No, but he asked about you.
Did he?
Actually, you really should
go out there to see him.
Yeah, I know.
MRS. JARVIS:
I bet he could stand a visit.
What do you think?
- TRISH: I think you're getting horny.
- MRS. JARVIS: Oh!
MRS. JARVIS: Tommy, turn that down!
Mom, I got 98,000.
- How many robots is that?
- Thirty-five.
Now, why don't you try killing
a few more up in your room?
TOMMY: I can't. I need
a bypass patch cord.
MRS. JARVIS:
Maybe you can get one in town.
Trish will drive you.
Oh, honey, get a haircut, hmm?
TOMMY: Oh, Ma.
- That's a nice mask.
- TOMMY: Do I have to get a haircut?
You're getting pretty terrific
at making those things.
Thanks. I just customized it.
- Where's Gordon?
- He went out.
Oh. Someone left the
front door open.
We're in the country.
Well, what happens if
the psycho wanders in?
TRISH: He'd probably challenge
him to a game of "Zaxxon."
Hear any more about
the place next door?
Mm-hm. It's been
rented by some kids.
- Great.
- How many?
- Six.
- It'll be nice to have some company.
(TEENAGERS HUMMING UPBEAT TUNE)
TEENAGERS (SINGING):
Country boy, country boy
Sitting in the grass
Along came a prairie dog
And crawled right up his ass
Ask me no more questions
You broke up with BJ Betty?
So to speak. And would you lighten
up on her? She's all right.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, I'll say she's all right.
(SIGHS)
You should have treated her right.
I mean, that girl wanted
to be treated... right.
I did. I did. I treated her right.
I treated her right. That's
what's driving me so crazy.
I mean, first I would call her
and she would take my calls...
but she would have something
that she'd have to do.
And then she wouldn't
even take my calls.
I mean, can you figure that?
What the fuck happened?
Let me put it in the old computer.
- No, I'm serious about this.
- Hey, the computer don't lie.
Now, let's see.
What?
It says...
It says you're a dead fuck.
What? A dead fuck?
A lousy lay. You know?
- A dead pecker.
- JIMMY: Oh, I see.
Don't hold it back from me,
doc. I can take it.
- Give it to me straight.
- I did not say it. The computer did.
- Yeah, well, there is no computer!
- Aha! And there's no Betty either.
Then I'm a dead fuck.
Like I said, the
computer don't lie.
(SIGHS)
God, I'm horny.
- Where are we now?
- Lost.
We are lost.
SAMANTHA: Pretty creepy, huh?
Yeah.
All right, I think I got it.
Go straight ahead two
miles and hang a right.
SAMANTHA: Paul, let's pick her up.
PAUL:
Sammy, where we gonna put her?
TED: Hey, honey, you got a sister?
Ruff, ruff!
(TWIG SNAPS)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
TRISH: Oh, Mom, I thought
we were having pizza.
I thought so too, honey, but we've
got a refrigerator full of leftovers.
You're not smiling. You're not
in the mood for my tuna salad?
- Well...
- I'm not either.
I'm in the mood for...
- TOMMY: No.
- MRS. JARVIS: Yes.
I feel like...
- No!
- A Jarvis sandwich!
(ALL CHEERING AND CHATTERING)
- Wait, somebody's at the door.
- Oh, no, you don't.
- No, Mom, I heard that too.
- I'll go.
Gordon! Hey, Gordon. Where
have you been, huh, Gordon?
Have you been sneaking around? Do
you have a girlfriend or something?
MRS. JARVIS: Tommy, close the door.
(BARKS)
Listen, Gordon, we'll talk later.
(TEENAGERS CHATTERING)
All right.
- Hit me with the beer.
- You got it.
- See? What did I tell you?
- What? You told me you were horny.
No, see, I've come to realize that
a guy can have a good time...
without having to
have girls all about.
That's a sin, you dead fuck.
JIMMY: I really, really don't
want you to call me that anymore.
Aw.
(GORDON BARKING)
Hi. What a handsome mutt you are.
- His name's Gordon. I'm Trish.
- Hi, Trish.
I don't know how you do it.
Heh. I don't know how you don't.
I mean...
you do it with everybody.
Oh, I do not!
I do it with Paul.
- Really?
- Come on, Sara!
You know how guys are. They
lie about that all the time.
They say that about everybody.
They don't say anything about me.
I mean, I don't have...
- Ha, ha. A reputation?
- I didn't say that.
Oh. Look, I got my
reputation in sixth grade.
Well, what does Paul think?
Paul thinks I'm great in bed, so
that's where I keep him. Ha, ha.
What are the sleeping
arrangements here, anyway?
Paul and I are taking the bedroom
at the end of the hall...
so you and Doug can
sleep next door.
Really?
Yeah. It's okay, they're bunk
beds. Don't worry about it.
I'm gonna go to bed now,
Mom. Good night.
Don't forget, 6 a.m.
BOTH: Once around the lake.
Good night.
- MRS. JARVIS: Sleep well.
- You too, Mom.
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
(SHRIEKS IN MUFFLED VOICE)
(DOOR CLOSES)
JIMMY: I think when we get into
town I should give Betty a call.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING ON HEADPHONES)
Ted. Ted?
I think... I think when we get
to town I should call Betty.
Jimbo, calling Betty is definitely
a dead-fuck thing to do.
Look, first rule of love: Never get
rejected by the same girl twice.
I mean, that's useless. If you wanna
make a fool out of yourself...
always do it with someone new.
Well, I don't know anybody new.
Well, sex is a great
way to meet them.
Ooh. Oh, my!
(BOTH SHRIEK)
- Sorry.
- Don't worry about it.
- Hi.
Hi.
- You, uh... You girls live around here?
- How far is it to Crystal Point?
- Well, that's where we're going.
- Yeah. It's a long walk.
- We can take it.
- I'm going back to get the car.
- DOUG: Sara, do you want some company?
- This way?
Thanks. I'll just
meet you guys there.
All right.
They're cute.
Two of them. Two.
Count them, one, two.
- Yes, yeah, and two of us.
- TED: Exactly.
(GASPS)
(TED HOOTING)
Come on in! Ha, ha.
Oh. No.
No, we... we have no suits.
(TED HOOTS)
All right!
Skinny-dip! Ah!
(TED HOOTS)
(BOTH LAUGH)
TED: Whoo! Sam!
- TOMMY: Gordon, wait up!
- Gordon.
Gordon, wait up! Wait a minute!
Gordon!
(ALL HOOTING)
- PAUL: Jimmy!
- Come on, Jimmy!
(ALL HOOTING)
Come on, Jimmy!
(TEENAGERS LAUGHING AND HOOTING)
Whoa.
- Turn around.
- Can't I just...?
- Turn around!
- Trish, come on in!
No, thanks. I think
I'm overdressed.
- Hey, Trish!
- TRISH: Bye-bye.
TED: Party tonight!
TOMMY: Come on, Gordon,
we're too young for this.
Some pack of patootsies, huh?
Tommy.
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
TRISH: Oh, no.
What next?
(ENGINE STOPS)
Can you fix it?
- I need a screwdriver.
- Maybe there's one in the trunk.
I need the keys.
Thanks.
TRISH: Tommy, come on!
Come in, Sara, let's
see what you got.
- No.
- Come on, Sara. Strip and dip.
Sam, I said no.
Well, then, I'm gonna go under
and stay under until you do.
See you later.
Sam?
Sam!
God, Sam!
God.
Sam!
Sam! Sam!
(SCREAMS)
Aah! Samantha, you bitch!
- SAMANTHA: You like that?
- You bitch!
(GORDON WHIMPERING)
Turn it on, Trish.
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
TOMMY: Turn it on!
- Whoa!
- Hi. Rob Dyer. Sorry about that.
- TRISH: Oh. Hello.
- Hi. What's your problem?
- No problem.
- I mean with the car.
TRISH:
Oh, the car. Um, it won't start.
Well, get in. Give it a crank.
Look, I've tried
everything already.
The only thing it could
be is the solenoid.
If you had a screwdriver...
ROB: Okay, give it a crank.
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
(ENGINE STARTS)
You need a lift?
I didn't think anyone lived
this deep in the woods.
We do. What are you
hunting for up here?
Bear. Anybody up at the lake today?
You can't be hunting for bear.
How about kids? There any kids,
vacationers, people like that?
Yeah. A bunch of kids moved in
yesterday. Right next door to us.
- TRISH: This is it.
- ROB: Thanks for the lift.
(ENGINE STOPS)
Gordon!
Would you like to
come in for a minute?
I don't think I can.
TOMMY: Well, you gotta come in.
Come on, I got something real neat
to show you up in my bedroom.
Hi, Mom!
MRS. JARVIS:
Tommy, who's your friend?
Mom, this is Rob. Rob,
this is my mother.
- Hello, Mrs...
- MRS. JARVIS: Jarvis.
Amazing.
Come here, I wanna
show you something.
(TOMMY GROWLING)
(LION'S "LOVE IS A LIE" PLAYING)
No way, not tonight, no way
Not today
- Just 'cause you play it cool
- JIMMY: Would you care to dance?
- To this?
- It's good.
All right
JIMMY: Oh, well, good.
Don't ask me to stay
Don't think you got it made
No, no
You're wrong
- (LAUGHING)
- 'Cause you can't fake it anymore
I know what you're waiting for
I should turn away
And walk right out that door
Because I know love...
JIMMY:
Hey, how come you turned that off?
PAUL: Relax, Jimbo.
You're gonna love this.
(JOHNNY MERCER'S "TANGERINE"
PLAYING ON STEREO)
Wanna give Teddy bear a kiss?
Heh. Mm! Teddy. Teddy, uh...
I've gotta get another drink.
With her eyes of night
- Excuse me.
- You like this stuff?
TINA: You like slow dancing?
Tangerine
I could learn to.
Kiss me, you fool.
- Certainly.
- SAMANTHA: Ha, ha.
Uh, maybe we could
dance to this one.
Come on, let Teddy bear
show you how it's done.
Stay near the trail.
- It goes all the way around the lake.
- Yeah, I will.
- There's only three of you up here?
- Mm-hm.
My parents have separated. You
know, middle-aged crazies. Heh.
I kind of hope they
get back together.
Yeah, I hope so too.
(TRISH SIGHS)
- Looks like another rainy one, huh?
- Yeah.
Listen, if it gets
too bad out there...
or if you wanna take a shower
or whatever, we're always home.
And if we're not, Tommy
usually leaves the door open.
- Good night.
- Take care.
TED: Hey, how you doing with yours?
Nowhere, huh?
Check.
You gotta warm her up.
Watch me. Do what I do.
And, Jimbo, don't be
such a dead fuck.
I told you. I told you
that I didn't like that.
- Besides, you've got the hot one.
- Check.
- Hi.
- He thinks that's funny.
He thinks that's a funny
thing he's doing.
(ALL CHEERING)
(ALL CHATTERING)
- Okay, you ready, Tina? On three.
- All right.
- PAUL: One!
- SARA: One!
ALL: Two!
ALL: Three!
(ALL CHEERING)
PAUL: And the winner is... Tina!
DOUG: All right!
(ALL CHATTERING)
TINA: What do I win?
What do you want?
Jimbo, put on another record.
TED: Jimbo.
You don't mind, do you?
Actually, I was thinking
about taking a little swim.
It seems to be getting a
bit close in here for me.
- SARA: Sam...
- Sara. Sara, let's dance.
I don't wanna dance.
Well, let's mind our own business.
(TONY MARTIN'S "TO EACH HIS
OWN" PLAYING ON STEREO)
Look, I'll talk to Paul.
All right?
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
TINA: Mm.
- I wanna talk to you for a second.
- Man, I am going to kill him.
- I said I wanted to talk to you for a second.
- Not now, dead fuck.
That's what I wanted
to talk to you about.
Do you believe this guy?
- I mean, I had her. She was mine.
- Oh.
Well, you know what I suggest
you do about that, Teddy?
I think you should run that
through your little computer.
(TWIG SNAPS)
Paul?
I know you're out there, Paulie.
(TWIG SNAPS)
SAMANTHA: Paul?
Okay. Screw you, Paulie.
Come on, Paul.
I know you're out there.
Paul?
Screw you, Paul.
(SCREAMING)
Look, what's the matter?
I can't go through with this.
I'm sorry. I gotta go.
(LEAVES RUSTLE)
(ON STEREO) What good is a song
If words just don't belong?
You wanna dance?
Yeah. Yeah.
No good alone
To each his own
For me there's you
If a flame is to grow
I thought that you
wanted to be with Ted.
Well, I did.
But now I wanna be with you.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
That makes me feel like a rat.
Two lips must insist
On two more to be kissed
Well, do you wanna join them?
Jimmy.
Why don't we just go upstairs?
Upstairs. Heh.
Ahem. That's a teddy bear.
Wanna give Teddy bear a kiss?
PAUL: Fuck!
(PAUL SCREAMING)
(TWIG SNAPS)
Shit.
This is... This is a neat room.
This is your room.
No. Actually, it's Paul's room.
You're neat.
(SCREAMS)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
- JIMMY: Oh, what a shock.
- Sorry.
Hey, you guys! Look what I found.
(TED LAUGHING)
SARA: What is that?
(ALL LAUGHING)
God, what a pig!
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Tina? We gotta go.
You go.
Tina, I'm gonna leave without you.
Take an umbrella.
(THUNDER CRASHING)
TERRI: You slut!
(TERRI WHIMPERING)
(LAUGHING)
I'm going upstairs.
You tired?
No.
Do you mind sleeping in
the bottom bunk tonight?
Why, you wanna sleep on the top?
No.
(SARA CHUCKLES)
Give me a few minutes.
Okay?
Good night, Teddy bear. Ha, ha.
Good night.
- Ha, ha.
- Stop.
Tommy? I'm gonna towel off and
then I'm gonna strangle you.
Tommy? Trish?
(LIGHT SWITCH CLICKING)
Anybody home?
Gordon?
Where's Tommy?
Where's Trish?
Matter of fact,
where the hell are you?
Gordon?
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(GASPS)
Watch it!
Can we slow down a little?
The party's gonna go on all night.
I think I'm gonna lose my lollipop.
TRISH: Mom, we're home.
Mom?
- Where is she?
- I don't know.
TRISH: Mom?
(LIGHT SWITCH CLICKING)
- She's not here.
- Maybe she's still jogging.
TRISH: She's never gone
this long. And in the rain?
- I'm going out on the path.
- Me too.
No, you stay here in
case she comes back.
- I'll go!
- Stay here and fix the lights.
(TWIG SNAPS)
(GASPS)
- What the hell are you doing here?
- What are you trying to do, kill me?
Tina? Ahem.
TINA: Hmm?
Never mind.
Tell me.
Um...
Did I...? Was, um...?
Was I...?
Was I a dead fuck?
(TINA CHUCKLES)
- What?
- A dead fuck.
No.
You, uh...? You know what I think?
You know what I really think?
I think you were incredible.
(JIMMY CHUCKLES)
- And I wanna do it again.
- Yeah.
Don't you move. I'll be right back.
TED: Oh. Ha-ha-ha.
Check it out.
Why don't you run this through
your computer, Teddy bear?
Hey, congratulations, Jimbo.
JIMMY: Where's that bottle of wine?
Why don't we celebrate?
TED: I think maybe I drank it.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
I was great!
I was great. I was great.
Love, Teddy bear!
L-O-V-E.
Hey, Ted, where is...?
Where is that corkscrew?
That fancy corkscrew
for the wine bottle?
Ted?
(LAUGHS)
JIMMY: Hey!
Ted? Ted! Hey, Ted, where
the hell is the corkscrew?
Jimmy?
My sister Sandra was
a really great kid.
But the man that killed
your sister is dead.
No, he's alive.
Look.
Jason as a child, right?
Artist's conception of Jason as
described by a would-be victim, right?
And then the murders.
But he's dead.
Jason's body has disappeared
from the morgue.
- It was stolen.
- It was not stolen.
Two people at the hospital are
missing. This is coincidence?
He's alive.
Oh, my God. Tommy's at the house.
(LAUGHS)
Ha, ha. Teddy.
Oh, man.
Oh.
Oh. Ha, ha.
(CHUCKLING)
So you wanna give the
old Teddy bear a kiss?
Jimbo?
(CHUCKLES)
(GASPS)
DOUG: Sara, I think I'm in heaven.
I think I'm in love.
What?
I'll meet you in the bottom bunk.
DOUG (SINGING):
Tangerine, she is all they claim
With her eyes of night
And lips as bright as flame
Tangerine
(DOUG SINGING INDISTINCTLY)
She is
Sara? Change your mind?
Come on. Get in here.
There's plenty of room.
We can sing a duet.
Who is it, Paulie?
Paulie.
Hey, Paulie, is that you?
Hey, Paulie. Whoops. Dropped
my bar of soap, old buddy.
Lucky you ain't in
here with me, old pal.
Ho-ho-ho.
(GRUNTING)
I came to hear you sing.
So sing.
(GASPS)
Aah! Sam! Samantha!
Sam! Sam! Sam!
Sand!
Sam! Sam!
(GRUNTING)
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
TRISH:
Oh, Tommy. Thank God you're okay.
- Oh, Tommy.
- What happened?
- Where's Mom? Is she back?
- No, not yet.
TRISH: I'm gonna call for help.
TOMMY: Rob, what's going on?
- I'm not getting anything.
- I wanna go next door.
- TRISH: I'm going with you.
- No.
TRISH: I'm going with you.
- You stay here and lock the door.
- Tommy, hold the fort.
TRISH: Gordon!
- ROB: He's been here.
- TRISH: Wait. What if he still is here?
Take this. Take it.
I'm going downstairs. You
stay right here with Gordon.
- TRISH: No.
- Stay right here with Gordon.
(GORDON WHIMPERING)
Gordon.
Gordon!
Gordon?
(GORDON WHIMPERS)
(SCREAMING)
Rob! Rob, he's here! He's here!
Rob! Rob!
(SCREAMING)
Rob! Rob! Rob!
Rob, he's here! He's here.
- He's killed all of them, I know it.
- ROB: Come one, come on.
Shit. Give me a hand.
- Gotta get the knife.
- No! No. No!
ROB: Oh, my God!
(SCREAMS)
(ROB SCREAMING)
Oh, God, he's killing me!
He's killing me!
Run, Trish! Run! Trish!
(SCREAMING)
(ROB SCREAMS)
ROB: Trish, run!
(ROB SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERING)
(SOBBING)
(SCREAMING)
No! Get off me!
(PANTING)
(GASPING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(SCREAMS)
TRISH: Tommy!
- All the doors locked?
- Yes.
TRISH: Go get me a hammer
and nails right now.
- TOMMY: Is he here?
- Yes.
Tommy, hurry!
(TRISH SCREAMS)
(TOMMY SCREAMS)
TOMMY: Help me! Help me!
Help me! Help me! Let me go!
Help me! Put me down! Put me down!
Tommy, help me push this.
Where is he?
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
What's he doing? What's he doing?
(BOTH GASP)
(BOTH WHIMPERING)
(GRUNTING)
(WHISPERING) Listen, Tommy,
I'm gonna get him out of the house.
And when I do, I want you to
run like hell, do you hear me?
Run like hell, okay?
Oh, my God!
(TRISH SCREAMS)
- Trish!
- TRISH: Tommy, no!
(TRISH SCREAMS)
Trish!
(TRISH SCREAMING)
TOMMY: Trish!
Tommy?
Tommy, you were supposed to leave!
Tommy! Tommy, get the
hell out of here!
No!
You son of a bitch.
I'm gonna give you something
to remember us by.
(JASON GRUNTS THEN GROWLS)
(SCREAMING)
Jason!
Remember me, Jason?
Jason, don't you remember?
Remember, Jason?
Jason, remember?
Remember?
(WHIMPERING)
(GASPING)
(SCREAMING)
(JASON GROANS)
TRISH: Tommy.
(BOTH CRYING)
TRISH: Tommy!
(GRUNTING)
Tommy!
Die!
- Die!
- TRISH: Tommy!
Die!
- TOMMY: Die!
The shoulder will
need some surgery.
But we can wait till she's
a better candidate.
Now, you just get a
good rest, young lady.
You haven't answered my question.
Neither one of you is
answering my question.
Often, during extreme duress,
people are capable...
of extraordinary behavior.
That's what happened when your brother
violently attacked the killer.
At that moment it was perfectly normal
for him to act to protect himself.
He's going to be just fine.
But right now,
what you need is rest.
Can I see my brother now?
Sure. But only for a minute.
I'll send him in.
(WHISPERS) Tommy.
(English - US - SDH)