I know.
If this keeps up, we won't be
in London till Boxing Day.
I know.
get him there for the publicity.
Only told you three times last week.
How do I get through to you, birdbrain?
Yeah. Sure, I can stall 'em.
Till about 1 0:00.
And then after that,
we've blown it.
Well, isn't there
a short cut you can take?
I mean, this is supposed to be
the main publicity for the new album.
Well, do it!
You're not on your own, pal.
Does he have to do that now?
I know.
I know. I was talking about it
last week, but that isn't the point.
The point is that we are sitting
in the middle of a traffic jam...
the proportions of which
would astound you.
There are three miles
of roadworks and no way out.
- Unless, of course,
you can suggest something.
- Today's top temperature:
46 degrees Fahrenheit.
- And the same to you, sir.
Anyway, this should help you
take your mind off the gloom.
- Remember the summer of'66.
I know. I know.
-   Good day, sunshine
- I know.
- I know about it. I know.
-  Good day, sunshine
I need to laugh
and when the sun is out
I've got something
I can laugh about
I feel good in a special way
I'm in love
and it's a sunny day
Good day, sunshine
We take a walk
The sun is shining down
Burns my feet
as I touch the ground
Good day, sunshine
- Yes, Steve.
- We're up a gum tree, Macca.
- Why? What's up?
- The whole bloody game's up.
The tapes have vanished.
Oh, that. Not to worry.
Harry's got them.
He took them home
from the studio last night...
and he's personally delivering them
round to the factory this morning.
Well, that's just it.
He hasn't shown up yet.
I rang his ever-loving missus,
but she's worried because
he didn't come home last night.
- Did you try Sandra?
- She hasn't seen him either.
Okay. Don't tell anyone.
I'll be right with you.
Don't tell anyone?
- Ah, Mr. Stanley.
- Good to see you.
- Inspector, thanks for coming.
- It's a lovely day for a drive.
- Marvelous.
It's too late
to stop it now, I'm afraid.
The television campaign
starts this week...
supported by merchandising, point
of sale, T-shirts, badges and a poster.
Well, I can't ring
Geoffrey on this one.
There's no way I can tell him
that it's gone missing.
- They already knew.
- Hopefully, it will be forthcoming.
- Good morning, all.
- Good morning.
Yes, that's true.
But the position is very serious indeed.
Any extra liabilities such as this
will place a great strain
on your capital reserves...
and increase the possibility
of the company being taken over
by Rathbone Industries.
That's Rath. Rathbone Industries.
They all seem
to be here now.
It would appear that
a Mr. Harold Torrington
is an employee of these companies.
- Correct.
- You are aware, of course...
that he has a criminal record, which
includes burglary and petty larceny.
- Yep, we know.
- I understand the tapes...
entrusted to Mr. Torrington's care
are extremely valuable.
Based on last year's figures,
at today's prices, I'd say about
five or six million pounds.
They're the equivalent of--
They're the be all and end all.
- If they're lost, all is lost.
- And yet it would appear...
you were quite happy
to place such a valuable asset
in the hands of this man.
Yeah. We knew about him
when he joined...
but he swore he'd been straight
for a couple of years.
I'm telling you,
I believe him.
He is straight. This whole thing's
a mistake. Where was he last seen?
Tom and Beryl saw him leaving
the Old Justice about half 1 0:00.
- He had the tapes with him.
- And no one's seen
hide nor hair of him since.
- Nobody.
- I must remind you that in this case...
there are certain other agreements
to be taken into consideration.
Such as the arrangement entered
into with Mr. William Rath
of Rathbone Industries.
In fact, Mr. Rath has asked me
to point out to you...
that unless the tapes are found
by midnight tonight...
the consequences will be...
very serious.
I guess we have to console
ourselves with the fact...
that everything that can
be done is being done.
I mean, the inspector
is well on the case.
He's got an up-to-date description
of Harry... and the tape box.
And everything...
is being done.
Thank you.
The car is ready, sir.
Ah. Thanks.
Yeah. Well, thanks anyway.
He told me he was straight,
and I believed him.
I suggested at the time it wasn't
exactly the smartest move on earth.
- What's he gonna do with the tapes?
- Bootleg them.
There are plenty of people who'd pay big
quid to get their hands on those tracks.
Big Bob, for instance.
To name but a few.
What's all this about a takeover
by Rathbone Industries?
- I didn't know about that.
- Slight danger.
Nothing you need worry about.
Get hold of Big Bob, will you?
- He's about, isn't he?
- Yeah. I saw him last week.
You see, there's gonna be
all kinds of complications we
haven't even thought about yet.
Yeah?
What?
I haven't thought
about 'em yet.
- Hiya. All right.
- Hey.
- Listen, have you heard the news?
- What news?
- You know, about the tapes.
- What about the tapes?
Well, Harry, he's supposed to be
taking them down the factory.
- He's gone missing.
- Missing?
- And the tapes too.
- Harry and the tapes are missing?
They've been phoning him all night.
Nobody seems to be able to raise him.
- Who's looking for him?
- Don't know. Great news, isn't it?
- Oh, God.
Well, what are we gonna do?
- You know, I don't fancy
recording them again.
- No, no need to do that.
You don't think Harry would go and do
a stupid thing like that, do you?
Yes, I do.
- Ready to do one?
Hello,Joey.
Have you seen Big Bob?
It's Alan.
Yeah, have you seen him?
No, no, I don't mean that.
I mean have you seen him today?
- So, what are we doing?
- The medley.
- What medley?
- Okay, Paul, I'd like
to hear a run-through.
Okay. Ready?
Brushes.
Coming ready or not, boys.
Yesterday
All my troubles seemed
so far away
Now it looks as though
they're here to stay
Oh, I believe
In yesterday
Suddenly
I'm not half the man
I used to be
Very bloody appropriate.
There's a shadow
hanging over me
Oh, yesterday
Came suddenly
Why she had to go
I don't know
She wouldn't say
I said something wrong
Now I long for yesterday
Yesterday
Love was such
an easy game to play
Now I need a place
to hide away
Oh, I believe
In yesterday
To lead a better life
I need a love of my own
Here
Making each day of the year
Changing my life
with a wave ofher hand
Nobody can deny
That there's something there
I want her everywhere
And if she's beside me
I know I need never care
But to love her
is to need her everywhere
Knowing that love
is to share
Each one believing
that love never dies
Watching her eyes
And hoping
I'm always there
I will be here, there
And everywhere
Here, there
Light out wanderlust
Head us out to sea
Captain says
there'll be a bust
This one's not for me
Take us from the dark
Out where we can see
Captain's out
to make his mark
This one's not to be
Light out wanderlust
Help us to be free
Do it just for me
Wanderlust
Captain's out
to make his mark
This one's not to be
Oh, where did I
Go wrong, my love
What petty crime
was I found guilty of
What better time
To find a brand-new day
Oh, wanderlust away
Light out wanderlust
Help us to be free
Do itjust for me
Wanderlust
Captain says
there'll be a bust
This one's not for me
-  Oh, where did I
Go wrong, my love
What petty crime
was I found guilty of
-   Captain says
-  What better time
-   There'll be a bust
-  To find a brand-new day
-   This one's not for me
-  Oh, wanderlust away
Dropping a line
Maybe it's time
It's wanderlust
For me
Do you want to hear it?
Yeah.
It's gonna be
one of those days.
Cheers, Harry.
They tell me
you just got out.
I'm not a bloody criminal.
Look. No mask. I ain't got
any dynamite. Left it all at home.
No. Really, I was set up.
By this nutty copper.
You know, framed.
It's always been
like that with me.
Even at school
they had it in for me.
Boy Scouts.
I got sent home from camp.
Caught smoking.
I wasn't the only one.
They said I was a bad influence
on the others.
Same in prison.
This cop frames me. I said,
"But I didn't do it, Your Honor.''
Didn't believe me.
I'm not a bad boy.
Not really.
I'm just... manipulated.
I'll tell you what.
I'll give you a chance.
If you're fibbing and you do one
thing wrong, you'll be out. I mean it.
- But if you're straight
with me, you'll be in.
- Yeah, I want to be in.
Okay, that's it.
You're in. It's a pact.
- Packet of what?
- Pact. A deal.
- A pact.
Apact. Apact. Apact.
'Ere, mate. Stick your
moniker on there, will ya?
My wife likes your music.
I don't.
But I'll get lynched
if I goes home without it.
- That mightn't be such a bad idea.
- You're right.
What room are we in?
Ah, um, it's... 51 6.
Ta.
Oh, uh, okay.
I'll be in the corridor if you need me.
- What was that for?
- I don't need him around all the time.
- Yeah, but he's very loyal.
- So is my pet cocker spaniel.
- Don't let it get to you.
- Don't let it get to me?
Oh, no,
I won't let it get to me.
As far as I'm concerned,
it's a beautiful summer's day.
There's not a cloud in the sky.
And there's probably
a bluebird on my shoulder.
Yeah, well, that's
really gonna help, isn't it?
You lose your grip, I'll work
myself up into a frenzy, and we
can all go and throw tantrums.
Well, it's not my fault.
I didn't hire him.
Oh. I love it.
Come on.
Let's spit it out, shall we?
It's all my fault.
Bad judgment.
Once a villain,
always a villain, right?
My judgment wasn't so bad when I
brought you into the company, was it?
Then you sing the songs,
and I'll run the business.
Talking about running the business,
what I'd like to know is...
how did we get so heavily involved
with this Rath character?
Yeah, well, he's part of that group
that arranged the bank loan last year.
You remember? We had
a short-term cash flow problem.
I showed you the papers. 'Course,
I never expected to end up like this.
Mr. McCartney,
ready for your makeup.
Zip-a-dee-doo-dah
Zip-a-dee-ay
My, my, my
What a wonderful day
Oh, plenty of sunshine going my way
Zip-a-dee-doo-dah
Zip-a-dee-ay
There's a bluebird
on my shoulder
It's the truth
It's actual--
Okay, now you remember the bit
where you're in the china cup?
Good. That's good.
- Slow. Clap. Hold.
Step, step, hold.
And up and hold.
And hold and drop.
Not bad. Let's do it again.
Come on. Once again. Okay.
Hi. I don't believe
we've been introduced.
- What are you doing here?
- I'm here to write an article.
- Oh, yeah?
- It's on the relative value
of popular music...
as a therapeutic tool
for social services.
I'm on drums.
Members of the band on stage, please.
Can I get some
of your time later, to talk?
You can have hours, if you don't mind
waiting a minute. See you later.
"Ballroom Dancing, '"dress rehearsal.
Stand by.
And... action.!
One, two.
One, two, three, four!
Well, I used to smile
when I was a pup
Sailing down the Nile
in a china cup
With a recipe
for a lovely day
Sticking out my back pocket
That's it, kids.
But it wasn't always
such a pretty sight
We used to fight
like cats and dogs
Till we made it up
in the ballroom
Ballroom dancing
Made a man of me
One, two, three, four
I just plain adore your
Ballroom dancing
Seen it on TV
I got what I got
From ballroom dancing
Big B.D.
Here we go.!
Well, I used to fly
when I was a kid
And I didn't cry
if it hurt a bit
On a carpet ride
to a foreign land
At the time of Davy Crockett
Wave the sword!
But it wasn't always
such a pretty sight
We used to fight
like cats and dogs
Till me made it up
in the ballroom
Ballroom dancing
Made a man of me
One, two, three, four
I just plain adore
Your ballroom dancing
Seen it on TV
I got quite a lot
from ballroom dancing
Big B.D.
Come on!
Now look here!
Well, it went so fast
and we all grew up
Now the days that passed
in the china cup
Are the memories
of another day
And I wouldn't
want to knock it
But it wasn't always
such a pretty sight
'Cause we used to fight
like cats and dogs
Till we made it up
in the ballroom
Ballroom dancing
Made a man of me
One and two
and three and four
I just plain adore
your ballroom dancing
Seen it on TV
I got what I got
From ballroom dancing
Big B.D.
I say!
What's going on?
Well, the kids have flown
to a better life
Now the boy's a man
and the girl's a wife
And the summertime
never seems to last
When you're riding
on the rocket
But, but it wasn't always
such a pretty sight
We used to fight
like cats and dogs
Till we made it up
in the ballroom
- Be off!
-  Ballroom dancing
Made a man of me
One and a two
and a three and a four
I just plain adore
your ballroom dancing
Seen it on TV
I got quite a lot
from ballroom dancng
Big B.D.
Lunch?
Okay, lunch, everybody.
One hour. Back at 2:00.
Oh, thank you.
Have we finished?
This album's really fine.
- How's your food?
- I'm not really hungry.
No, me neither.
- Mind if I ask you some questions then?
- No.
- Tape doesn't bother you, does it?
- No, not at all.
So, has the album
been completed?
Yeah, we've finished
the album.
- Is there a release date?
- Oh, not yet. We've gotta
get the cover together.
- Have you heard any of it?
- No.
- Would you like to?
- I'd love to.
- What are you doing tonight?
- Nothing.
Why don't you come over to my place,
and I'll play you some tracks.
We can talk more, 'cause you'll know
what we're talking about.
- That would be terrific.
- It's only a rough cassette...
but it'll give you some idea.
- Hi, Sandra. How are you?
- Fine, thanks. Can't complain.
- Have you seen Harry lately?
- Yeah.
Did anyone tell you
what all this is about?
Well, yeah.
But it's not true.
I know it!
He was around the other evening feeling
great, going on about the new album.
Oh, no, nothing like that.
He was too up on it all.
I wouldn't have been able to tell you
if he was thinking anything like that.
I'm his shoulder
to cry on, you see.
I can always sense
how things are.
Well, I don't believe it myself,
but the pressure is most definitely on.
Don't worry.
Come on, San.
Let's get out of here.
See you later.
Why don't you come along?
Well, g'day, fellows.
Got some news?
We were rather hoping that you might
have some news for us, Mr. Stanley.
Um--
Ladies and gentlemen of thejury--
Ladies and gentlemen
of the jury--
Yes, sir.
Well, basically, we have been
keeping an eye on all of them.
- Oh,ju-just a minute, sir.
Hello? Hello, sir?
Well, yes, I do appreciate
that from where you sit...
it may seem a little... far-fetched.
Uh, no, sir. No, I--
I do not need a holiday,
thank you very much.
Oh, I shall be very glad to get
to the bottom of this myself.
Yes, sir. Right, sir.
- Good-bye, sir.
- Will you be all right?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
Just look after her.
You'd think that people would have
had enough of silly love songs
But I look around me
and I see it isn't so
Oh, no
Some people want to fill the world
with silly love songs
What's wrong with that
I'd like to know
'Cause here I go
Again
I love you
I can't explain
The feeling's plain to me
Say, can't you see
Ah, she gave it all
She gave it all to me
Say, can't you see
What's wrong with that
I need to know
'Cause here I go
Again
I love you
Love doesn't come
in a minute
Sometimes it doesn't
come at all
I only know
that when I'm in it
It isn't silly
No, it isn't silly
Love isn't silly at all
I love you
-  I can't explain
The feeling's plain to me
-  I love you
Say, can't you see
-  Ah, he gave it all
He gave it all to me
Say, can't you see
-  I love you
-  I can't explain
The feeling's plain to me
Say, can't you see
-  I love you
-  Ah, he gave it all
He gave it all to me
Say, can't you see
Whoo!
You'd think that people would have
had enough of silly love songs
But I look around me
and I see it isn't so
Oh, no
Some people want to fill the world
with silly love songs
And what's wrong with that
Okay, and house lights.
And cut the steam.!
- Nice one, mate.
- Thank you.
I'll see you in a minute.
I'm just gonna get
all this off. Okay?
G'day, fellows. Don't look so worried.
Everything'll work out great.
appreciate the urgency of the situation.
Time is of the essence,
Mr. Stanley.
- Don't hassle me!
- You have until midnight!
Don't you fellows
have anything better to do?
He was down
at the Old Justice last night.
Yeah. I was down there
with Beryl when he came in.
Seemed quite happy.
Had a couple of drinks.
Didn't look like he was
thinking of doing a bunk.
He wouldn't!
I know he wouldn't!
I assumed he was going
back home to his missus.
He only did it because of her.
But we don't think
he did it, do we?
There he is.!
Down here, lads!
Come on!
After him!
Dear, dear.!
Look at that. God.!
You better take Sandra
back to her place, I think.
Don't worry, love.
We'll sort it out.
- Thanks.
- Okay.
Someone we know?
Just coming round the corner.
He said he didn't see the van.
Terrific . That's all we need.
Zip-a-dee-doo-dah
Zip-a-dee-ay
My, my, my
What a wonderful day
Hello. All right?
Hi.
Ring Val.
Get the telexes.
Can I have a line?
Take a pic.
I'd love a copy.
- Send me your address.
- Okay.
- You could leave it for me too.
- Sure.
- How long are you over here for?
- As long as you guys--
- Any news?
- No. They're working on it, though.
I think this is
a pretty cool caper.
I wouldn't trust
any of them really.
Do you think you can get
some heat in here, or are we
practicing to be Canadians?
Yeah. Shall we try
"Not Such A Bad Boy''?
- Do we have to?
- Yeah.
This time.
All right.
One, two, three, four!
I laughed at the teachers
Who taught in my school
They kept one-armed bandits
In the swimming pool
They don't understand me
But they never will
And if I was there
I'd be telling them still
I'm not such a bad boy
No more, no more, no more
I followed the leader
Into her tent
But nobody told me
That she owed some rent
She wanted to love me
I wanted to go
Well, she taught me things
that I needed to know
You know,you know
I'm not such a bad boy
No more, no more, no more
Come on, boys.!
Oh,yeah
She wanted to love me
I wanted to go
But she taught me things
that I needed to know
She knows, she knows
I'm not such a bad boy
No more, no more, no more
I talked to my lawyer
He picked up my bail
Won't someone get me
Out this lousyjail
We're both in agreement
That crime never pays
And I should be out
in a couple of days
I'm not such a bad boy
No more, no more, no more
I'm not such
a bad boy no more
-  No more, no more
-  I'm not such a bad boy
No more, no more, no more
No more, no more,
no more.
Ow.!
- That was great.
- That's great, that.
Yeah, I know.
It's about time you noticed.
Mph. Well, thanks a lot, Tom.
- All right, love.
- Ta-ra.
Don't worry.
He'll turn up.
We're just gonna run through a couple of
numbers. We'll try " So Bad.'' All right?
Try that one.
- How's the new house, Eric?
- Shall we try " So Bad''?
It's all right.
Okay. One... and two.
A one, two, three, four.
There is a pain
Inside my heart
You mean so much to me
Girl, I love you
Girl, I love you so bad
And if you leave
the pain will go
But that's no good to me
Girl, I love you
Yes, I love you so bad
Well, it feels so good
Sometimes it feels so bad
This is worse than anything
I've ever had
There was a pain
But now you're near
and I don't feel a thing
Girl, I love you
Girl, I love you so bad
And she said
Boy, I love you
Boy, I love you so bad
Ooh
-   I love
-  Girl, I love you
-  Girl, I love you so bad
I love, I love
Well, it feels so good
Sometimes it feels so bad
This is worse than anything
I've ever had
There was a pain
But now you're here
And I don't fear a thing
-  I love
-  Girl, I love you
-  Girl, I love you so bad
I love
And she said
Boy, I love you
Boy, I love you so bad
Ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh
Girl, I love you
Ooh
- That wasn't bad for a first take.
- All right for me, loves.
I thought that was fine.
- Yeah, it's all right for you.
- Yep. Right.
- Telexes.
Oh, thanks. Mail.
Okay. One, two.
One, two, three, four.
Oh, I hear them telling me
that you're selling off the furniture
Even my personalized autographs
You might as well go all the way
and sell your granny to the zoo
And while you're at it
may I go to my psychiatrist
He's makin' money
out of makin' me laugh
But I don't mind
I wish that I could say
the same about you
Oh
Well, it seems to me
that you still got
-  No values
-  Oh, you know you're not so hot
- No values
- Yeah, you know you've got a lot but
-  No values
-  And I'll be glad
if you went away again
No values, hey
No values
No values at all
Oh, the city shark
is at the dark end of the alleyway
You pays your money
and you takes your choice
The Artful Dodger says
he wants to pick a pocket or two
Oh, but you you've taken up
a place in high society
Apersonal friend
of Messieurs Rolls and Royce
Got them all convinced that
everything you say to them is true
Oh
Well, it seems to me
that you've still got
-  No values
-  Oh, you know you're not so hot
No values
Well, you've got a lot but
And I'll be glad
if you went away again
No values
No values at all
Oh oh oh oh ohhh
Oh oh oh ohh
I like your wife's smile
I like her car
If I had your lifestyle
I wouldn't go far wrong
On the waters of life
you row your boat
Into the strongest tide
that you can find
-  On the darkest of nights
-  We were two of a kind
What do we know
before the tide went out
And left us stranded all ashore
How was I to know
-  Well, you ain't got
-  No values
-  Hey, you know you think you're hot
-  Oh, you know you've got a lot but
-  No values
And I'll be glad
if you went away again
No values, hey
No values
Hey, no values at all
Finish it this time!
Don't do it.! Don't do it.!
- Uh, sorry.
Uh, my fault. Let's have a break,
cup of tea or something.
Little break. Yeah?
I'm just gonna see Bob.
All right.
- Both of us?
- Yeah, you come too.
- Oh, great.
What's happening then, Big Bob?
Well, your man gave me a call.
So I slips into
something comfortable...
hops into me new pickup,
and here I am.
- Do you like it? Me new pickup truck.
- What?
Oh, yeah. It's nice.
What's it all about, then,
me old fruit?
You haven't seen Harry then?
Harry who?
HarryJames and the Golden Trumpet?
Or Hare Krishna?
No, Torrington.
Works for us.
Oh, him.
Can't say as I have. Not lately, anyhow.
Has he gone absent without leave?
No, it's just his missus
is worried about him.
Not been up to
his old tricks, has he?
He had quite a promising career
as a young lad, you know.
Could have done
very well with me.
He gave that up when he joined us.
Told me he had enough of the bent life.
Not easy. Tried it once.
Lots of willpower needed.
I gave up smoking
for two weeks.
- Yeah.
Anyway, listen, Bob.
I've got to shoot over to the BBC.
So, uh, thanks for comin'.
It was nice seein' you. See ya.
Here. How's your record
comin' on then?
- It's all right.
- Give you a fancy deal on the side?
Able to offer you very attractive
terms at the moment.
No tell, Bob.
It's all legal nowadays.
Well, what's it
all about then?
We're just wondering
about Harry, and someone said
he'd been to see you, and, uh--
- Look, I'll keep an eye out for him.
- Which one?
Me left one.
Guess what. The advance sales on the
new album have topped five million.
And that's
without the record.
How we doin' for time?
Ernest, tell the band that will be all
for today. Repeat: all for today.
Yes, sir. That will be all for today.
Repeat: all for today.
Hello, Ernest.
Are you there?
Here they come.
Why don't you go back to the office.
I'll be over later.
Don't worry.
We'll find him tonight.
Come here!
- Have you done this
to my pickup? Have you?
That's him.
That's the box he stole.
His fingerprints are
coming up on the screen now.
We sent a copy of those
to the United States.
the possibility, sir,
that this fellow Torrington...
is perhaps not working
on his own?
Well, he's not the only one
with a vested interest.
Well, I mean,
we've got, uh, Rath...
Steve Stanley, uh, didn't like
the look of that drummer.
Well, they could all have a motive.
Insurance, perhaps.
Yes. Insurance.
Are you receiving me, Ernest?
Say something if you can
hear me, Ernest?
The band is finished.
We have now left the warehouse.
Cops have seen everyone
connected with Harry,
and no one knows a bloody thing.
he's headed for the States.
There's some big
bootleg operations over there.
Big Bob didn't even know
what I was talking about.
The banks are worried.
They need assurances.
Still, could be worse,
I suppose.
Give my regards
to Broad Street, baby
'Cause you know that I'll be there
Oi!
- Can I have your autograph?
- Sure.
- Sign mine.
- Okay, but we're in a bit
of a hurry, all right?
Ta-ra. See you.
Afternoon.
this whole thing up,you know.
I mean, a man is missing.
He once, a long time ago,
had a bit of form.
And now here we are.
We've judged him, found him guilty...
sentenced him...
all in one day.
- Isn't that Paul McCartney?
- Anyway...
doesn't fit in with what
he's been telling me recently.
- Like what?
- Ah, he feels more secure now.
No scuffers
breathing down his neck.
Not so many nightmares.
Even talking about having kids.
I mean, does that sound to you like
a man who's planning to rob someone?
These things happen
on the spur of the moment.
Hello!
I'm Terry. We met a long time ago
at the Playhouse.
- I don't suppose you remember.
- I think so.
Oh, yes, yes. How nice.
Will you follow me?
- What are we doing?
- Interview and two songs.
Yes. We'll do the interview first,
if you don't mind.
Uh, in here.
One, two, three.
Okay,Jeff?
- Do you know William?
- Yes, of course.
Oh, great.
Wonderful of you to come on.
Grab a seat.
Get me Conway
at Billboard, will you?
Anyway, it's great that you're here.
- Any trouble parking the car?
It's two or three minutes before.
I've just got these
half dozen questions. So, um--
- I'm in your hands. No problem.
- Awkward as we go.
- Um, is that okay for you, Terry?
- Lovely.
Go on green.
Okay for level?
Aha. So, right then.
Well, Paul, it's great to have you
with us, and, of course...
all the listeners want to know,
how's the new record coming along?
Well, we finished mixing it last week,
and it sounds good.
Uh-huh. Eh, so we can look forward
to an imminent release?
-Well, um, it shouldn't be too long now.
-Oh, great.
Well, you can rest assured
that all of us here in radioland...
are eagerly awaiting
the arrival of your new songs.
- How many have you got
for us this time? Twelve?
- There's about 1 2 in all.
- Great. Uh, all your own lyrics?
- Yeah, I write my own stuff.
- Great. Fantastic.
Yeah, everything's going great.
that do occur occasionally.
The new album?
Yeah, it's very exciting for all of us.
- It should be out in the shops soon.
- Yours?
- Bless you for coming on.
- You'll be getting your copy
sometime in the next few weeks.
And of course I know that goes without
saying for all you lovely listeners too.
Right then.
Let's hear a little music, shall we?
Cut.
What a load of cobblers.
Oh!
Yes. Yes.
- Afternoon, men.
All right. Everything okay?
- Hello, Paul.
- Yes, fine.
- I'm afraid Jeffrey isn't here yet.
- Isn't he?
- Sorry.
- Oh, there he is.
-Hello. Sorry I'm late.
-Morning. It's all right. What happened?
- Can you hear me?
- Yeah.
Right. Now, um,
what's it to be?
- " For No One,'' right? " For No One.''
-" For No One.''
You find that all the words
of kindness linger on
When she no longer needs you
She wakes up
She makes up
She takes her time
and doesn't feel she has to hurry
She no longer needs you
And in her eyes
you see nothing
No sign of love
behind the tears cried for no one
A love that
should have lasted years
You want her
You need her
And yet you
don't believe her
When she says her love is dead
you think she needs you
And in her eyes
you see nothing
No sign of love
behind the tears cried for no one
A love that should have
lasted years
You stay home
She goes out
She says that long ago
she knew someone
But now he's gone
She doesn't need him
Your day breaks
Your mind aches
There will be times when all the
things you said will fill your head
You won't forget her
And in her eyes
you see nothing
No sign of love
behind the tears
Cried for no one
A love that
should have lasted years
Mmm-mmm
Good. Lovely. Well, that was
rather nice, wasn't it?
I'd like to press on straight away
with the second piece. What was it?
- " Eleanor Rigby.''
- Yes. Good. Right.
Shall we go and do it immediately?
Soon as you like.
Watch it.
And running out of time too.
So as soon as possible, please.
One, two, three, four. One, two, three.
Ah, look at all
the lonely people
Eleanor Rigby
Picks up the rice in a church
where a wedding has been
Lives in a dream
Waits at the window
Wearing the face that she
keeps in a jar by the door
Who is it for
All the lonely people
Where do they all come from
Where do they all belong
Father McKenzie
Writing the words to a sermon
that no one will hear
No one comes near
Look at him working
Darning his socks in the night
when there's nobody there
What does he care
All the lonely people
Where do they all come from
Where do they all belong
Ah, look at
all the lonely people
Eleanor Rigby
Died in the church and was
buried along with her name
Nobody came
Father McKenzie
Wiping the dirt from his hands
as he walks from the grave
No one was saved
All the lonely people
Where do they all come from
-  All the lonely people
-  Ah, look at all the lonely people
Where do they all belong
his hands as he walks from the grave
No one was saved
All the lonely people
Come over here to me.
Where do they all come from
Ah, look at all the lonely people
That's it. You're finished.
What are you gonna do now?
Out. I'm goin' out.
If I ever get out ofhere
Thought of giving it all away
To a registered charity
All I need is a pint today
If I ever get out ofhere
If we ever get out ofhere
Well, the rain exploded
with a mighty crash
As we fell into the sun
And the first one said
to the second one there
I hope you're having fun
Band on the run
And thejailer man
and Sailor Sam
Were searching everyone
For the band on the run
Band on the run
- Hello?
- Hello,Jim.
Oh, it's you.
What are you doing here?
Slumming, are we?
- Come in, son.
- Thanks.
Listen, you know
my mate Harry?
Did you notice him
in here last night?
- Is he the one who used to--
- Yes, but he doesn't anymore.
He was here for a while with
the rest of your crowd. Wasn't he?
Hmm. Did you notice
anything unusual?
No, nothing unusual.
Fancy a cup?
No, I won't, thanks.
I'm in a bit of a hurry.
Uh, did he have
anything with him?
- No, I think he left her at home.
- No, a box.
A big blue one?
That's it.
- Did he leave alone?
- I suppose so.
You know how busy
we can get here some nights.
- I think he was on his own.
- How did he look?
- Wild as ever.
Sure you won't have a drop?
- Won't take a minute.
- Okay. Go on.
Always running around.
Don't get a chance
to see anybody.
If you didn't
run around so much...
you might get
a better view of the world.
Here you go.
Haste makes waste,
and waste not, want not.
That's what they say,
don't they, son?
What is this town
if full of care?
We have no time
to stop... and stare.
You see, I may not
look to you like a poet.
At first glance,
you mightn't think it.
- But the longer you look--
You wouldn't like to look at
some poems of mine, would you?
Thanks all the same,Jim,
but, uh...
- I've got to be off.
You've been off for years.
Cheerio, good fellow,
and well met.
Good night, sweet prince.
The long and winding road
That leads to your door
Will never disappear
I've seen that road before
It always leads me here
Lead me to your door
Many times I've been alone
And many times I cried
Anyway you'll never know
The many ways I tried
But still they lead me back
To the long
and winding road
You left me standing here
A long, long time ago
Don't keep me waiting here
Lead me to your door
The wild and windy night
That the rain washed away
Has left a pool of tears
Crying for the day
Oh oh oh
Don't leave me waiting here
Don't keep me waiting
Let me know the way
Ooh
Yeah,yeah,yeah
Good night, all.
I'm off to Broad Street.
And give my regards
to Broad Street
Remember me
to Leicester Square
Give my regards
to Broad Street, baby
'Cause you know that I'll be there
Oi!
I can wait another day
Until I call you
You've only got
my heart on a string
And everything aflutter
But another lonely night
Na na na na
Might take forever
Na na na na na na na
We've only got each other to blame
It's all the same to me, love
'Cause I know
What I feel
To be right
No more lonely nights
Never be another
You're my guiding light
Day or night
I'm always there
And I won't go away
until you tell me so
No, I'll never go away
-   Yes, I know
-  I know
-   What I feel
-  I feel
-   To be right
-  Be right
No more lonely nights
Never be another
You're my guiding light
Day or night
I'm always there
And I won't go away
until you tell me so
No, I'll never go away
No more lonely nights
No, no
...seemed so far away
Now it looks as though
they're here to stay
Oh, I believe in yesterday
Well, suddenly
I'm not half the man I used to be
There's a shadow
hanging over me
Though I believe
in yesterday
Why she had to go
I don't know
She wouldn't say
I said something wrong
Now
God bless you, squire. Thank you, sir.
Oh, yesterday
all my troubles seemed so far away
Thank you, ma'am.
Never knew what to say
Oh, I believe
in yesterday
Help.!
- Help.!
- Harry?
Oh-- Oh! It's you.
What are you doin' here?
It locks from the outside.
I couldn't get out. Banged all night.
Fell asleep.
- Oh, you've got the tapes.
- Yeah, found 'em on the bench.
- They all right?
- Yeah.
It was dark.
And cold.
Train never came.
Thought it was a toilet.
You silly boy.
Come along.
- All right, here.
- Do you know what this is worth?
- Look at the time.
He's two hours late already.
- This might be him.
- Hello?
- Guess what I found.
- The tapes?
- And Harry, locked up
on Broad Street Station.
- What?
- It's a long story.
I'll tell you when I get back.
- I'll ring Stephen.
- Yeah, ring them all.
See ya later. Love you.
-  Ring 'em all Ring 'em all
-  Ring 'em all
Hey! They found the tapes!
They found the tapes!
Gentlemen... I'm sure
you'd like to be the first to know.
We got the tapes.
The long and the short
and the tall
You're a long way away, mate.
Oh, yeah.
I must have been daydreaming.
- How we doing? Yeah?
Still got plenty of time.
- Have you seen Harry?
- Yeah, he's around somewhere. Why?
Nothing really.
I can wait another day
Until I call you
Call you, call you
You've only got
my heart on a string
And everything aflutter
Ooh
But another lonely night
-   Might take forever
-  Forever, forever
We've only got
each other to blame
It's all the same to me, oh
No more lonely nights
You're my guiding light
I don't want
no more lonely nights
May I never miss the thrill
Ofbeing near you
Near you, near you
If it takes
a number of years
I'll turn your tears away
But another lonely night
Might take forever
Forever, forever
We've only got
each other to blame
It's all the same to me
Ooh-ee-ee,yeah
No more lonely nights
You're my guiding light
Oh, no more lonely nights
Yeah, no more lonely nights
No more lonely nights
You're my guiding light
I don't want
no more lonely nights
Oh
But another lonely night
Ooh
Might take forever
We've only got
each other to blame
But it's all
the same to me
No more lonely nights
You're my guiding light
Babe, I don't want
no more lonely nights
I couldn't take it again
I ain't lonely
I couldn't take it
I couldn't take it again
No more
May I never miss the thrill
Ofbeing near you
Near you, near you
And if it takes
a number of years
I'll turn your tears away
I can wait another day
Until I call you
You've only got
my heart on a string
And everything aflutter
Aflutter, aflutter
But another lonely night
Might take forever
Forever, forever
We've only got
each other to blame
But it's all
the same to me
To me, to me
No more lonely nights
You're my guiding light
No more, more, more
No more lonely nights
No more lonely