Say...
what's the directions you got
to McDermott?
Just go straight down here...
hang a left, catch highway 30,
and take it all the way out.
Straight on out,
and you can't miss it.
OK. Thanks a lot.
Get your ass out of here, lady!
You fool! imbecile!
And take these with you!
Damn it!
You son of a bitch!
I hope you run into a truck!
What's more,
you got lousy taste in music!
Are you going to be all right?
What do you want?
I saw you get thrown out
of that van.
You landed kind of hard.
Are you sure you're OK?
Rotate out of here, Jack!
If you say so.
- Hey, you-Ace.
-The name's Harkin.
Excuse me, Harkin.
Where are you headed?
West. How about you?
San Francisco.
- Want a ride?
-Sure.
Here.
I can handle it.
You ain't
some kind of a weirdo, are you?
I don't think so.
- What's your name?
-Sunny.
How come that guy threw you
out of there like that?
Well, what do you think?
I don't know.
That's why I asked.
I ain't going down on a guy
at sixty-five miles an hour...
just for a crummy ride.
You got something besides this?
I'm tired of this.
Oh, you don't like country?
Why don't you try
something different, OK?
Just pop it in.
Now, this I can handle.
So, why you got four pairs
of skis back there?
I'm skiing
the world championships...
freestyle at Squaw Valley.
I got one for bumps,
one for aerials.
The little short ones there
are for ballet...
and one's for just plain speed.
Speed?
I could use some of that.
You got a girlfriend, Ace?
I used to,
but I spent all my time skiing.
She got tired
of being number two.
Hey, how old are you?
Eighteen, in April.
Ran away from home, right?
Wrong. You got to have a home
to run away from.
What?
I'm getting a room
for the night.
Hey, buddy, you figure you can
get in my pants this way.
I--I ain't figuring nothing.
Do you want to spend the night
out here in the truck?
It's OK by me.
Hey, Harky, you got something
I can wear to bed?
My mother forgot
to pack my pajamas.
Thank you.
You know
there's only one bed in here.
So?
Pick a side and stay there.
So, how come you didn't
try nothing last night?
I was tired.
You didn't exactly
invite me, anyway.
Are you for real?
Are you a virgin?
Are you?
Well,
you had your chance, fella.
I ain't half bad, you know.
So, what happens
in Squaw Valley besides skiing?
Beats me. I never been there.
You see,
I don't really have to be...
in San Francisco for a while...
and, well, maybe do you
just think I could--
Want to tag along?
Yeah. Why not?
OK, but no funny stuff.
I don't put out for everyone
I pick up.
Anybody home?
Damn it.
Someone's at the front desk.
I'll be right back.
Checking in?
Yeah. Banks, Harkin.
Freestyler?
It's the last room we had.
I was getting worried about you.
I'll bet.
Welcome to Squaw.
And call me
if you need anything.
Yeah, could you wash
our truck for us?
First thing in the morning.
Thanks. Come on, Harkin.
Wow! Get a load of this!
I can't believe it.
This looks like a cathouse.
Whoa! This is great!
And you were going
to stay here alone?
It was the only place
I could get.
Hey, Harkin, check this out.
How does it work?
I don't know. I think it's got
some jets or something...
that forces the water up.
A friend of mine stayed
in a place like this once...
but it was only for an hour.
Oh, don't stop!
- Oh, that feels good!
-I want more!
- Oh, do it!
-You like that, huh?
Yes, I do! Oh, I want more!
Touch me!
What do you say
we get something to eat?
Want to try these on?
Don't you like the way I dress?
I thought you might
look nice in them.
Am I gonna have
to wash dishes, Ace?
Un-uh. It's my treat.
Well, how can you afford
all of this?
The room, the food,
this sweater?
Well, my ma knit the sweater...
and I've been working all summer
for the money to make this trip.
I milked forty head of cattle
twice a day.
Whoa! Get a load of him.
- Oh, my God!
-You know him?
That's Rudolf Garmischt!
He won the gold medal
in Lake Placid in 1930...
and he's the world freestyle
champ the last 2 years running.
Damn sexy, too.
He's the best...
the world's greatest skier.
Mr. Garmischt?
I think you're the greatest.
So ein stupide Amerikaner.
Hey, Adolf!
Somebody's talking to you!
That will work in Europe, yeah?
There, the women are beautiful,
but also intelligent.
Rotate on this,
you nazi bastard!
Nice coat. Uh...rat?
You shouldn't have done that!
That was Rudolf Garmischt!
He's a jerk!
Always has been.
Greetings. Dan O'Callahan.
I've seen you
in all the ski magazines.
Dan here used to be
one of the best.
I still am.
What's your name?
I'm Harkin Banks. This is Sunny.
I came here to compete--
if I qualify.
You got to be pretty good
to make it on this circuit, kid.
You here to qualify, too?
- I ain't into skiing.
-Well, that's no problem.
Plenty of things to do here.
So, you met Rudi, huh?
Well, he might be a great skier,
but he's a world-class asshole.
Well, see you on the mountain,
huh, kid?
Yeah, I'll be there.
Pleasure.
That guy wants
to get into my pants.
What?
He's got
another thing coming...
if he thinks
he's gonna make it with me.
I ain't into older men,
you know?
Where did you get
all this stuff?
Watch out, watch out.
Hey, watch it, buddy!
You jerk!
Come on, Ace,
I'll buy you a drink.
You got it.
All right!
Nice hand for The Breakers!
OK, get down here 'cause
you know what time it is?
Wet T-shirt contest time!
I'm Lester the Molester...
and I run the baddest, meanest
wet T-shirt contest there is!
But what do you need
to have a wet T-shirt contest?
Yeah, girls!
Let's get some girls up here!
Come on,
give me some girls up here!
All right!
We need more girls than this,
though, don't we?
More!
Yes, we do,
but in order to find girls...
I gotta get out my girlfinder!
Now, let's go for the girls!
Where are you, girls? Come on!
Better close this up--
don't want anybody to get hurt.
Hold this for me back there,
would you, darling?
Let's find some more girls.
How about this girl over here?
How about you, honey?
You want to get up here?
Hey, guys,
let's get that girl up here.
Oh, she's covering up.
Let's go into the back here.
How about that girl?
Guys, get her up here!
Come on! Bring her up here!
- I got fifty bucks on you.
-No way!
Come on, baby! Let's go!
Oh, my lord!
How do you do, darling?
I'm new in town...
and I don't know
how to get to your house.
How about you, honey?
You look like you're
in the mood for a contest.
The guys are all
pulling for you.
You would be great in this!
I say, what do you say?
All right, all right!
Come on up here. Yeah.
OK, come on,
we need some more girls!
How about this girl back here?
Come on up here!
Yeah! Yeah! Come on up here!
Another volunteer!
Put me down! Come on,
put me down! Put me down!
How about this for a volunteer?
All right!
Let's see them titties!
You guys thought you'd have
seltzer bottles...
but I'm the one
who gets to do it.
Aw, this is great fun!
It's water time.
Get me a volunteer!
Take it off! Take it off!
Come on, wake up!
Oh once
We were dreamers on the rise
We were the sun
Where the sun never shines
And we were gold
Where the nightbird only flies
That's a long time, you know
For that kind of wind to blow
Long time ago
We were dreamers on the rise
Entwined
We said we'd begin again
And we made a vow
That we'd remain as friends
And we'd fallen down
We said we shall rise again
That's a long time, you know
For that kind of wind to blow
Long time ago
We were dreamers on the mend
And if three
Wishes came into my life
I'd say one
Was to gaze into your eyes
And I'd say two
Would be turning back our lives
Three's a long way to go
For that kind of wind to blow
Long time ago
We were dreamers on the rise
We were dreamers
On the rise
You play well.
Thanks. I wrote it myself.
You got more going for you
than skiing any day.
Yeah? My sister says that
I'm as good as John Denver.
She's not all wrong, Ace.
Yeah, well, she's just a kid.
Well, long day tomorrow.
I guess I'd better be
hitting the hay.
Mind if I join you?
Sure.
You son of a bitch!
You're not gonna fall asleep
on me two nights in a row!
Whoo! All right!
Nice turns!
Squirrel, look at this kid!
Yeah, the boy is good,
but I wouldn't worry about it.
Aspirin, drinky!
Hey, Dan! How you doing?
Not so loud, huh, kid?
I was up all night
doing a crossword puzzle.
You want a sip?
A strike!
Hey, listen, kid, I saw your
qualifying run this morning.
- Not bad.
-Thanks. When are you running?
Oh, well, us vets--
we did it yesterday.
They don't post the results
till tonight...
so we're just gonna go out
and boogie, you know?
Just clean out the system.
Well, Harkin Banks,
I want you to meet the Rat Pack.
This is Squirrel Murphy.
Yeah, best run
of the morning, man!
What, were you
on 'shrooms or what?
He's a little crazier
than he looks. Come on.
Oh, and that's Kendo.
He's got a way with words, huh?
We call him Kamikaze.
When you see him ski,
you'll know why.
Oh, and that's Fergy,
the motormouth-shut up.
And then Banana Pants.
You can call her Michelle.
She's taken.
I am?
Cute, huh? Oh, and Slasher.
Slasher. Slasher.
Say hi to Harkin Banks.
Hey, Harkin.
Good, huh? Well, Harkin here
is gonna put the fear of God...
into Rudi Kazooti Garmischt.
He asked if you want to ski
with us this afternoon.
We're gonna hit
some radical terrain--
Avalanche City, Outta Bounds,
Squirrel Mountain.
Hey, sounds great.
Well, then
let's climb aboard...
in an orderly fashion--
spread out!
Good.
Hey, how you doing, Sylvia?
I'll be doing better once you
introduce me to your friend.
I saw him qualify on Red Dog.
He's real good.
You guys better watch out.
Are you gonna
introduce me or not?
Well, of course.
Hey, Hark, come here.
Harkin Banks,
I'd like you to meet Sylvia.
New on the circuit?
We're gonna go do Broken Arrow.
You want to ski with us?
Oh, I gotta get the house ready
for the big party tonight.
Oh, well, we'll see you tonight.
Can I bring you anything?
Bring him.
I might make him
the guest of honor.
Well, you know,
he's got a friend.
So, bring his friend.
OK. Can I bring you
anything else?
Just you, Daniel-Just you.
She always makes it
to the qualifying rounds.
That way she can check out
the new talent.
She is beautiful.
You got a good eye, kid.
Watch out! Watch out!
Rudi, you're a goddamn
low-life cretinous slug!
You people, stay out of our way!
You may ski on that side
or on that side...
but stay out of the middle here.
Hey, Rudi, you can kiss my ass--
not on this side,
not on that side...
but right in ze middle.
Come, Heinz.
We finish this later.
What is it with that guy?
Sylvia used to be
Rudi's girlfriend...
till someone long-dicked her
in Europe.
He figures it was me.
Couldn't blame a guy,
though, could you?
Uh-uh. Sylvia's sure got
what it takes.
That's why
she's got the Rudettes...
drooling all over her.
- Rudettes?
-Rudi's gang.
They're so far up his ass,
they don't know...
where he leaves off
and they begin.
Hey, what do you say
we tear up this mountain?
OK, let's hit it!
All right, let's go!
Come on!
I swear to God,
it's the funniest thing...
you ever saw was Squirrel--
Hey, you guys
talking about me again?
Squirrel skiing with his pants
split up the middle.
Hey, it was too hot
to wear underwear.
So he skis down right in front
of the TV cameras, right?
He passes,
and he bows to the judge.
He flashes the biggest moon
you ever seen in your life.
It must have been
a hell of a jump, Squirrel...
to rip your pants off.
Hey, Kendo's right.
I cranked off the triple,
I flew a hundred yards.
Fuckin'-A, man.
That jump was totally awesome.
Guys, I'd like to propose
a little toast...
to Squirrel Murphy.
He's been on the world
freestyle circuit for 4 years.
He's made $392,
been laid twice.
Once every other year--
not bad, Squirrel.
And I would like to toast
Snake-legs Banks...
the Bonners Ferry flash...
the newest member
of the Rat Pack.
- All right!
-All right!
There it is.
- Do you see mine, Dan?
-Yeah, you're on it.
- What about me, Dan?
-Slasher, Kendo, Squirrel.
All right.
What about Fergy and Dagger?
That's it.
What the hell?
Fader, come back here,
goddamn it!
4 years on the circuit, and
he gets cut-you believe it?
Dagger and Fergy skied better...
than most of the Europeans
on the tour.
That doesn't seem fair.
It isn't.
Fender--
Dan, I know what you're gonna
say, but we're running a show.
Well, how come you cut
Fergy and Dagger?
- They just didn't make it.
-Didn't make it?
They ski better
than half the Europeans.
You call yourselves promoters?
It's a business. Accommodations
have to be made, O'Callahan.
What the hell
is that supposed to mean?
You know, I remember
when this used to be a sport.
We've got
fourteen European sponsors...
paying for TV coverage
for one name skier.
Lose that name,
and the circuit folds.
All right, now we're saddled
with European sponsors.
That means
certain Europeans qualify.
And certain Americans
don't qualify?
Hey, guys, we haven't had...
an American winner
in over five years.
Now, look, Dan, there hasn't
been an American freestyler...
who could beat Garmischt
in five years.
We landed the meet here
because of him!
Oh, I see.
So, it's a business,
is that it, fellas?
O'Callahan, it's show business.
Yeah? Well, why don't you
explain that...
to those kids
that have traveled...
over a thousand miles
to get here.
What are you getting
so bent out of shape for...
O'Callahan? You made it.
You've been over the hill
for five years.
Now, Dan.
I don't like that guy.
Come on, I'll buy you a beer,
we'll talk about it, hmm?
Fader, come on,
we go back a long way.
You're an old
free-dagger yourself.
Dan, I'm between a rock
and a hard place.
It's bullshit.
Bullshit.
- What was that?
-A burst of courage.
What's that mean?
It's a prescription
for crowd scenes.
You don't need that.
Look, Harkin, it's my business
what I swallow, OK?
Well, what was it?
What difference does it make?
Well, I don't like it.
Well, tough.
What do you think...
we spend one night together,
and you own me?
Good evening, Harkin.
So glad you could make it.
Your friend?
Yeah. Sylvia, this is Sunny.
Sunny, Sylvia.
You were terrific today, Harkin.
I haven't seen a skier
like you in years...
and I've seen them all.
I'll bet you have.
Thanks.
- Are you a skier?
-No.
Just a spectator, then?
Right, except I haven't
found the mountain yet.
Ah, well, it's the big hill
with the snow all over it.
I'll keep an eye out for it.
- She's very interesting.
-Yeah.
Well, it's a really nice place
you have here.
Thank you.
I've scheduled you
for a private tour later on.
I don't think I want you
to miss anything.
- Hey, kid.
-Oh, hey, Dan.
Wild party. Better keep an eye
on your girlfriend.
- She's not my girlfriend.
-Right.
I'm Squirrel Murphy.
Georgette.
I suppose a fuck's
out of the question, huh?
Ask me
when I'm in a better mood.
The air is so clean
in the mountains.
Yeah. It's just like back home.
- Where's home?
-In Bonners Ferry, Idaho...
where the men are men,
and the sheep are nervous.
Well, you wouldn't
make me nervous.
A little excited, maybe.
Let me buy you a drink.
Come on.
- I don't understand.
-I don't either.
A toast to Dom Perignon
and the World Cup.
Who's he?
A famous French skier.
I never heard of him.
So, what happens now?
First,
we take off our clothes...
and then we fuck our brains out.
Hey, who needs a drink?
Miss, could I--
Fergy. will you let the lady
sit down, please?
What can I get you?
I don't know.
How about something hot?
Hot.
Uh, may I recommend
my specialty-the leg spreader?
It starts with a little vodka...
and a touch of scotch.
You're gonna love this.
Then...
a little bit of brandy.
This will pick you up.
A skosh
of Mother's Myers's rum...
and the blessings
of a lemon twist.
Try that on for size.
It's working.
Now, that's a girl
I can take advantage of.
Now, Squirrel.
I hope that's your leg.
It feels very good, ja?
Excuse me.
Please, don't worry.
We are all friends here.
Be my guest.
I think you need some fluid.
Some more.
Please, you finish.
You know, I'm very sorry...
that we didn't get along
so well...
the first time that we met.
It was a long day,
and I had a headache...
and I must apologize
for the way that I acted.
But I hope
that you understand...
that I'm really not
such a bad guy.
Just-just relax.
That is why we are here.
Just relax.
Aw, man.
Aw, Dan, what happened?
Well, I was fixing a drink,
and I hit a tree.
Compound spiral.
Hey, Dan, you think maybe
I can use your skis...
while you're laid up?
Well, it might not be that bad!
Let's party!
Who wants a beer?
Guys, let's get out of here!
Hey, let's go!
Get ready to party.
Who wants a beer down here?
Well, look who's here--
Mr. Personality.
Was ist los? lhr schweinhund.
No kidding?
Hey, Rudi, have a beer on me.
Say, little rookie...
do you know what I had
for breakfast this morning?
Wheaties.
Very clever, but no.
No, it was quite a feast, ja.
How do you say
in your language--
I had Sunny side up,
and I had Sunny side down...
and I had Sunny side
all the way around.
You toad-sucking son of a bitch!
Don't worry.
I threw the little fish back
when I finished with her.
Rudi,
you hit a new low this time.
Oh. You're hurting my feelings,
my good friend.
- Hey, Garmshit.
-Garmischt.
Yeah, Garmshit. Why don't you
ask the rookie here...
about his bubble bath
with Sylvia last night?
That's right. Rudi.
You've been backdoored again...
but this time,
right in the same house.
Yeah, you just ain't staying
on Sylvia's top forty, shorty.
Ja, we will see you showoffs,
you comedians, tonight, ja?
If you are not cowards.
And I especially hope
that you, little rookie...
won't be too shy to join us.
I'll be there.
Be where?
Rudi challenged us...
to a broom-ball match
tonight at the Arena.
All right.
Welcome, everybody,
to the first major event...
of the F.l.S.
World Cup competition...
here in Squaw Valley, U.S.A...
site of the 1960
Winter Olympic Games.
We're here on East Broadway...
to see the finest
freestyle skiers in the world...
going for the gold
in three events--
ballet this afternoon...
moguls tomorrow,
and aerials on Sunday.
Into the starting gate...
Good luck, Slasher.
Go get 'em, buddy!
...from
Breckenridge, Colorado.
Curtis, W.
Well, Curtis, you can take
your starting position.
Take your starting position.
Why don't you turn that down?
Next up is number 101...
- Herr Garmischt.
-Ja.
- Good luck.
-Luck?
I don't need luck.
Take your starting position.
That was Rudolf Garmischt...
in a beautifully
choreographed routine.
And now for
the judges' scores--
9.5, 9.3, 9.5, 9.2, 9.3.
That's today's best score.
All right, Banks,
good luck to you.
You can take
your starting position.
Thank you.
That was Harkin Banks
in a beautiful first run...
in the F.l.S. World Cup.
Let's hear it
for this newcomer...
in his first
international competition.
Hey! My man!
You did it! You did it!
3.7, 3.6, 3.4, 3.6, 3.2.
Aw, come on.
You had the best run
on the hill, man.
You got screwed.
- Well, where are you going?
-San Francisco.
It's time for me to move on.
Well, where were you
last night?
You sure ask a lot of questions.
Well, I was worried.
- I'm sure.
-I was.
You were with Rudi,
weren't you?
And what difference
would it make?
What do you mean,
what difference would it make?
And what were you doing
in the hot tub with Sylvia?
You surprise me, too, H.
- She gave me this stuff.
-Oh, that's bullshit!
I didn't know what I was doing.
Tell me about it.
- Don't forget your shampoo.
-It's already packed.
I think you should stay, Sunny.
Here. Don't forget this.
Give it to your girlfriend,
Miss Plastic Tits.
Company, halt!
Ready...
They look nervous.
Hey. guys. anything goes.
That's right. Take no prisoners.
Eins, zwei, drei, vier!
- Squirrel.
-All right.
Maybe we should spot them
a couple goals.
What do you think, guys?
They're not gonna play serious,
are they?
I don't think so, no.
- Break!
-Break!
- You guys ready?
-Yeah!
- You ready?
-Jawohl!
OK, play hard, play fair,
and keep your sticks down.
Great job!
Come on!
You busy for dinner?
- Get out of here!
-Out of the way!
Come on!
You know something, guys?
I'm getting too old for this.
Did you see that Garmischt
blind-side me?
They were vicious, but we tried.
Yeah. Hey, we were small,
but we were slow.
Funny.
Yeah, next time!
Next time, we'll have uniforms!
Hey, you guys want to go
for a nightcap at the Lone Star?
Oh, hey, listen, man.
We'll join you later.
Me and the kid,
we got something to do.
This game's not over yet.
Let's show 'em
a little Irish hospitality.
Rudi! He's gonna love this.
Son of a bitch!
Come on.
Luck of the Irish.
- How did you do that?
-It's my lock.
Come on.
Look what we found.
All right, guys. Watch this.
What the--Heinz!
Rat Pack.
Can I give you a hand
with that?
No, thanks. I got it.
- You sure?
-Yeah, sure.
Son of a bitch!
You!
I saw you fall.
I thought I'd just stop
and give you a few pointers.
Yeah, you've got a couple,
so why don't you...
point 'em that way
and crawl out of my sight?
Aw, you gotta learn
to bend your knees.
Get your mama to bend her knees.
I don't have time.
That way you could
suck up the bumps.
You do know how to do that,
don't you?
Here, let me give you a hand.
I can see why Harkin likes you.
Oh, I get it. Switch hitter--
first Harkin and now me.
You really are a sicko, lady!
Maybe you and Harkin--
we could all get together later.
Harkin can do
whatever the hell he pleases!
All I was doing was having
a little fun with him.
You can have him back.
Ooh, if I could only ski,
I'd take this pole and--
If you get bored with Harkin,
send him over later on.
I still have a few tricks
up my sleeve.
Oh, so what, bitch?
Good morning,
ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome
to the mogul competition...
the second event
of this championship weekend.
After the ballet competition...
Rudolf Garmischt of Austria
is in first place...
followed by Werner Bleiner
of West Germany in second...
Heinz Hartmann of Austria
in third...
Kendo Yamamoto of Japan
in fourth position...
and newcomer Harkin Banks
of the United States...
in fifth place.
Right behind Banks in sixth
is Dan O'Callahan...
of the U.S.,
followed by Squirrel...
I'm after Rudi.
The luck of the draw.
It's a tough act to follow...
but if you ski like you did
when you qualified...
you could be the kid
we're looking for.
And now the current
world champion...
Rudi Garmischt,
to the starting gate.
Garmischt,
any time you're ready, huh?
Just a moment.
Go, Rudi!
A spectacular run
by Rudi Garmischt!
In a moment,
the judges' scores.
One thing about Rudi,
he sure can ski.
9.7, 9.3, 9.7, 9.9, 10.
49.1! Beautiful!
He might have been great once.
He wasn't that good today.
Kid, let me tell you something.
He didn't win the World Cup
three years in a row...
because he's bad.
Next up is Harkin Banks,
number 149.
Go get 'em, kid.
Hey, Banks, nice run in ballet
the other day, huh?
- Thank you.
-Yeah, it's all right.
Well, it's any time
you're ready now.
Good luck.
All right!
Yeah, all right!
You did it!
Harkin Banks!
A beautiful run...
in his first
international competition!
- All right!
-Here come the judges' scores.
7.3, 3.3, 9.0, 3.0, 7.9".
For a total of 41.0.
Bullshit! Bullshit!
Come on!
What's the matter
with you guys?
- You suck!
-Squirrel.
Attention, please.
Will all finalists
in the aerials...
please report to the top
of the jump immediately.
Competition will begin
in thirty minutes.
Thank you.
Hey, guys, there are
only four seats to a gondola...
so someone's gonna have
to ride by himself.
Let's throw
one or two fingers...
to see who stays behind.
You ready?
One, two, three!
Sorry, Squirrel. Come on, guys.
The best two out of three?
What's your name?
Squirrel.
That's cute.
- What's yours?
-Vicki.
You missed a spot.
What, here?
You never know where
you're gonna get burned.
You don't want to miss
any spots.
No, you sure don't.
Squirrel, all right!
All right, Squirrel!
Welcome, everybody.
As we go into the final event
of this F.l.S. World Cup...
Rudolf Garmischt
is in first place...
Harkin Banks in second...
Heinz Hartmann
in third position...
Kendo Yamamoto in fourth...
and in fifth place,
in a surprise return to form...
Squaw Valley's
favorite freestyler...
Dan O'Callahan.
Ah, Mr. Yamamoto. How are you?
Good, good. So, what jump
have you got for us today?
All right.
Yeah, we got Yamamoto ready.
He's gonna throw a sai, a sush-
mits-sushi mitsabish--
yama-what?
Did you get that?
That's close enough.
OK. All set?
You can go.
Banzai!
All right!
A beautiful jump
by Harkin Banks!
That's gonna put him
within striking distance...
of Rudi Garmischt.
All right.
The pressure's on, Rudi.
Ladies and gentlemen...
we are now down to
the last two jumps of the day.
The results of these jumps...
will determine the overall
F.I.S. World Cup champion.
Well, kinda looks like...
you got your work cut out
for you today, huh, Rudi?
I have nothing to worry about.
What's your pleasure?
A lay tuck tuck triple.
OK. Yeah,
we got Garmischt all set.
He's throwing a triple.
A lay tuck tuck triple.
Right.
OK, Rudi, you can go anytime.
That was Rudi Garmischt...
with a spectacularly executed
triple jump.
Not bad.
No shit.
A 9.8, 9.9, 9.8, a 10,
and a 9.9.
It's gonna be hard
to beat that one.
...for a total of 49.4.
Yeah! Nice going!
What's this "Kiss-ass blaster"?
My jump.
Yeah, well,
I got to know what it is...
before I can let you go down.
It's a twist and triple.
A twist and triple?
I've never seen
one of those before.
Are you qualified for that?
Well, I'm gonna do it.
Good luck.
Let's hear it
for Harkin Banks--
a beautiful triple
by this exciting newcomer...
from Bonners Ferry, Idaho!
Hey, look at that!
9.7, 9.8, 9.9, 9.3,
and a 9.3.
That makes Rudolf Garmischt
all-around world champion...
with a clean sweep
of all events.
Second overall is Harkin Banks
in his first F.l.S. competition.
Hey, Rudi, how's it feel to win
and be second best?
Hey, come back here,
you goddamn coward!
We win the trophy!
Congratulations.
Cut it out!
You know something, Rudi?
I think it's time
we settle this once and for all.
Hey, Squirrel,
spot me fifty bucks.
Fifty?
Make it forty.
Chinese downhill.
Forty bucks a man.
Winner takes all.
Ja. It is the only way--
Chinese downhill!
Oh, and, uh, Rudi...
why don't you bring the trophy?
I think it should go
to the real champion.
I am the champion.
The Chinese downhill
will decide everything.
Ja. It is agreed.
Chinese downhill.
What the fuck
is Chinese downhill?
Good luck, kid.
See you at the bottom.
Oh, boy.
All right.
Listen up, everybody!
And now for the rules...
of the international
Chinese downhill--
there are none.
It's every man for himself.
Anything goes.
The first man
to cross the finish line...
and grab the trophy
wins the downhill.
And the winner takes all--
2,300 bucks!
Everybody,
on your marks, get set...
Out of the way!
Sayonara!
Wipe-out!
Scratch an itch?
Watch out!