THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
HI,
IT'S SUSAN BERLANGER.
HAVE I GOT ANY MESSAGES?
MR. SCHNEIDER CALLED
FROM NEW YORK.
PARIS AND AMSTERDAM
ARE SET,
AND ROME IS
A STRONG POSSIBILITY.
ANYTHING ELSE?
FRANK CALLED
FROM DALLAS.
HE'LL BE BACK FRIDAY.
THINK ABOUT
WHAT HE ASKED YOU.
HE'S GOING BACK
TO DALLAS SOON.
IF YOU'RE
GOING TO DO IT,
YOU SHOULD DO IT
BEFORE THEN.
YOUR CALLS ARE ALMOST
AS INTERESTING AS A HOOKER'S.
OH, THANKS.
JACK WANTS TO KNOW
IF YOU'LL MEET HIM
FOR COFFEE.
ONE SHOULDN'T DATE
HER ANSWERING SERVICE.
IT'S LIKE DATING
YOUR GYNECOLOGIST.
WHY'S THAT?
YOU KNOW TOO MUCH
ABOUT ME.
WE'VE NEVER MET.
I LOVE YOUR VOICE.
MY VOICE
LOVES YOU, TOO.
GOOD NIGHT, JACK.
I'M NOT FRESCHETTI'S
KIND OF DANCER.
IF I STAY, I'LL BE
IN THE CORPS FOREVER.
WHEN THE SEASON'S OVER,
I'M GOING TO NEW YORK
TO TRY MY LUCK.
WELL, WHAT
DO YOU THINK?
YOU NEVER FALL
INTO THE PIT,
SO YOU MUST BE
PRETTY GOOD.
I MEAN, I CAN'T DANCE
LIKE YOU PLAY THE FLUTE.
I PLAY ALL RIGHT.
I DON'T KNOW WHY
YOU STAY IN THE PIT
WITH YOUR TALENT.
THIS AGENT
IS BOOKING ME
EUROPEAN RECITALS.
I'D HAVE TO PAY
MY EXPENSES.
IF I GET
GOOD REVIEWS,
HE'LL BOOK ME
SOME HEAVY DATES HERE.
THEN THE BIG BUCKS?
I DON'T KNOW
IF I WANT IT ANYMORE.
DON'T YOU WISH
SOMEONE WOULD
CARRY YOU OFF
AND TAKE CARE
OF YOU?
THE ONLY GUYS
WHO EVER CARRY ME OFF
ARE WEARING TIGHTS
AND EYE SHADOW.
HAD ANY PROPOSALS
LATELY?
FRANK.
HE LEFT A MESSAGE
ON MY SERVICE.
HOW ROMANTIC.
HE'S PRESSING ME
TO SET A DATE.
YOU CERTAINLY
SEEM EXCITED.
IT'S A BIG DECISION.
ALL THIS CAREER TALK
MAKES ME HAVE TO PEE.
HI.
HELLO.
LISTEN, UH, IS YOUR FRIEND
COMING BACK?
LISA?
MMM-HMM.
I'LL DO THIS FAST.
DO WHAT?
THERE'S NO REASON
FOR YOU TO SAY YES.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT IT IS.
CAN YOU PRETEND
TO KNOW ME
SO I CAN MEET LISA?
YEAH, WHY NOT?
I SAW HER TONIGHT
AT THE BALLET.
SHE KNOCKED ME OUT.
ALL OF A SUDDEN,
HERE SHE WAS.
HOW SHOULD WE DO IT?
YOU GO BACK TO THE BAR.
WHEN LISA COMES BACK,
STROLL BY AND SAY,
"HI, SUSAN."
ARE YOU A DANCER?
YOU BETTER GO.
SHE'LL BE BACK SOON.
I NEED YOUR NAME.
SHE MIGHT CATCH ON
IF I DON'T KNOW
YOUR NAME.
SAM CARPENTER.
TELL HER WE MET
ICE-SKATING.
I'LL HANDLE IT.
THAT DIDN'T TAKE LONG.
I GOT NERVOUS.
THERE WERE TWO WOMEN IN THERE
PUTTING SOMETHING LIKE
SWEET N LOW UP THEIR NOSES.
EVEN IF YOU MARRY FRANK,
WHY GIVE UP PLAYING?
SUSAN, HI.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
WHO ARE YOU?
HUH?
SHE'S NOT
GOING TO BUY THIS.
LISA, THIS IS SAM.
HE WANTED
TO MEET YOU.
HE ICE-SKATES
AND EVERYTHING.
THIS IS MUCH BETTER
THAN PRETENDING WE KNOW
EACH OTHER.
SHE'S CHARMED BY
THE WHOLE THING.
SIT DOWN, SAM.
UH... ARE YOU USING
THIS CHAIR?
I KNEW YOU WOULD
HIT IT OFF.
I'VE GOT
AN EARLY REHEARSAL.
YOU'RE A MUSICIAN.
TALK TO HER,
NOT ME.
I HAVE AN EARLY
REHEARSAL MYSELF.
YOU BOTH WANT
A RIDE HOME?
IT'S OK WITH ME.
SURE.
HERE,
I'LL TAKE THAT.
LEAVE A FAT TIP.
WE'RE KNOWN
AS BIG SPENDERS.
MY LIMOUSINE'S
RIGHT OUTSIDE...
THE DOOR.
HAS HE BEEN
WITH YOU LONG?
WHO?
YOUR CHAUFFEUR,
MARIO ANDRETTI.
MUST BE HARD
TO KEEP A GOOD ONE.
HE KEEPS HIS CAR
IMMACULATE.
IT'S THE BUILDING
RIGHT HERE.
WHY DON'T THESE CABS
HAVE SEAT BELTS?
I'M WEARING ONE.
HATE TO SEE YOU DRIVING
AROUND WITHOUT ONE.
I'LL SEE HER INSIDE.
THERE'S BEEN
UNPLEASANT THINGS
HAPPENING
TO WOMEN LATELY.
TELL THE DOORMAN.
HE'S BEEN DOING THEM.
SEE YOU TOMORROW?
HOW ABOUT A MOVIE?
I'LL CALL YOU.
GOOD, HE'S ASLEEP.
YOU CAN GO NOW.
THANK YOU.
AH, LISTEN.
I'M SORRY.
ABOUT WHAT?
THAT THING
WITH LISA.
PLEASE
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
DAMN ELEVATOR'S
STUCK AGAIN.
ANYTHING I CAN DO?
CAN YOU REPAIR
AN ELEVATOR?
NO.
THEN THERE'S NOT MUCH
YOU CAN DO.
WELL,
NICE MEETING YOU.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
GOOD NIGHT.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
NIGHT.
WONDERFUL.
YES?
LET ME HELP YOU.
I CAN DO IT.
I'D LIKE TO, OK?
IT'S HARD WHEN YOU
DON'T HAVE RAILING
TO HOLD ON TO.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
JUST GOING TO HELP.
THIS IS EASIER.
WHAT FLOOR?
37.
I'M JUST KIDDING. 3.
THAT'S NICE PERFUME
YOU'RE WEARING.
IT'S POLO,
BY RALPH LAUREN.
I THOUGHT IT SAID POLIO.
THAT'S WHY I BOUGHT IT.
AM I TOO HEAVY?
NO, YOU'RE FINE.
IS THAT WHAT
IT WAS, POLIO?
IT WAS VIRAL
ENCEPHALITIS.
PEOPLE THINK
I'M TALKING ABOUT
A ROMANIAN
TENNIS PLAYER,
SO I JUST SAY POLIO.
IT SAVES A LOT
OF CONFUSION.
THANKS FOR THE LIFT.
YOUR METER'S
RUNNING,
AND MY PHONE'S
RINGING.
YEAH, ALL RIGHT.
WELL... WELL,
GOOD NIGHT.
HI, MOM.
IT'S JACK.
AM I INTERRUPTING
ANYTHING?
UNFORTUNATELY, NO.
I WAS JUST COMING IN.
IT'S AFTER 1:00.
AREN'T YOU A LITTLE LATE?
DON'T WORRY ABOUT ME.
MY MOTHER WOULD RESENT
YOU MOVING IN
ON HER TERRITORY.
THAT WAS MY REASON
FOR CALLING.
SHE CALLED EARLIER.
SHE SAID DON'T
FORGET DINNER TOMORROW.
HOW COULD I?
SHE SAID
YOU FORGOT LAST SUNDAY.
LAST SUNDAY
WAS A BAD DAY.
TOMORROW'S
MY DAY OFF.
DO YOU WANT
TO HAVE LUNCH?
I'M SERIOUSLY THINKING
OF GETTING MARRIED.
I'M NOT AGAINST
MARRIAGE.
I MEANT TO SOMEBODY ELSE.
I JUST HAVE TO MEET YOU.
I HAVE THIS MENTAL PICTURE
OF YOU.
I JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE
THAT I'M RIGHT.
YOU'RE NOT.
YOU'RE WAY OFF.
BROWN HAIR, RIGHT?
BIG BROWN EYES.
LAUGH LINES
IN THE CORNER.
I'VE GOT ONE EYE
RIGHT ON MY FOREHEAD.
BUT IT'S BROWN, RIGHT?
JACK.
YOU KNOW THAT RESTAURANT
YOU ALWAYS EAT AT, 555-3131?
CHARLY'S?
I'LL BE THERE TOMORROW
BETWEEN 12:00 AND 1:00.
I'LL BE WEARING
A RED TIE.
I CAN'T MAKE IT
TOMORROW.
GREAT. I WON'T KNOW
IF YOU'RE THERE.
GOOD NIGHT, JACK.
WHY DID YOU WANT
TO COME HERE?
THE MOVIE'S
ACROSS TOWN.
I HAD A CRAVING FOR
THEIR TUNA SALAD.
NO PLACE MAKES IT
LIKE THEY DO.
SO HOW DID IT GO
WITH SAM?
WE WENT BACK
TO MY PLACE
AND PLAYED KISSY FACE
FOR FIVE MINUTES.
THEN HE SAID GOOD-BYE
AND LEFT.
MUST BE A CHEST MAN.
WHAT?
I DIDN'T DO ANYTHING FOR HIM.
YOU DON'T THINK HE'S TURNED
OFF JUST BECAUSE YOU'RE--
BUILT LIKE A BOY?
I THINK HE'S
INTERESTED IN YOU.
ME?
HE KEPT ASKING ME
ABOUT YOU.
REALLY?
UH-HUH.
THERE GOES
A VERY ATTRACTIVE YOUNG MAN.
WHO?
THEY GUY WITH
THE RED TIE.
WAS HE?
YOU CAN GO
RIGHT IN, MISS.
YOU DON'T
HAVE TO STAND IN LINE.
WHY NOT?
I DON'T MIND.
ARE YOU CRAZY?
IT'S THEATER POLICY.
YOU'VE GOT TO GO IN NOW.
BUT I DON'T
WANT TO.
IF MY BOSS SAW YOU,
I'D BE IN TROUBLE.
COME ON.
WAIT!
SHE CAN'T COME UNLESS
YOU NEED HER ASSISTANCE.
WHAT IF SHE
NEEDS MINE?
BEG PARDON?
SHE'S BLIND.
OH, I'M SORRY... I,
I DIDN'T, UH...
CAN I HAVE
YOUR TICKET?
OH.
OH, I'M SORRY.
WHO'S THAT?
YOU BUMPED INTO
THE NICE THEATER MAN.
OH, SORRY.
LISTEN, THIS PICTURE
HAS SUBTITLES.
HOW WILL SHE--
I'LL READ THEM
TO HER.
WHAT?
SHE'S HARD OF HEARING.
DOES THIS FILM
HAVE DANCING?
I LOVE TO LISTEN
TO DANCING.
HELLO.
THIS IS YOUR
ANSWERING SERVICE.
WHERE'S JACK?
I DON'T KNOW.
I JUST STARTED TODAY.
BIG ED WILL BE BY
AT MIDNIGHT.
WHO?
BIG ED.
BIG ED?
AREN'T YOU BAMBI?
SUSAN BERLANGER.
OH! HOLD ON.
SAM CALLED.
SAM?
THIS IS SUSAN,
RIGHT?
YEAH.
THEN SAM CALLED--TWICE.
HE DIDN'T LEAVE A NUMBER.
ANYTHING ELSE?
SOMEONE'S AT THE DOOR.
NO.
THANKS.
OH, MY GOD!
GORILLA-GRAM
FOR MISS SUSAN BERLANGER.
THAT'S ME.
COME ON IN.
GO AHEAD.
THESE ARE...
THESE ARE FROM JACK.
OH.
♪ I WANT A GORILLA
JUST LIKE THE GORILLA ♪
♪ THAT MARRIED
DEAR OLD DAD ♪
♪ A DEAR OLD-FASHIONED GIRL
WITH HEART SO TRUE ♪
♪ SHE'D NEVER THINK
OF BITING YOU...♪
YOU WANT TO HEAR
THE REST?
NO.
IT WAS GOOD, THOUGH.
ONE SECOND.
YEAH, WELL, ANYWAY...
WAIT A SECOND.
THANK YOU.
BUT WHY GET MARRIED?
WHY NOT?
YOU'RE ONLY TWO WEEKS AWAY
FROM YOUR FIRST
RECITAL TOUR.
I'LL PUT IT OFF.
RIGHT.
I MEANT
THE TOUR.
YOU CAN'T PUT OFF
MR. SCHNEIDER HAS
WORKED ON IT FOR MONTHS.
YOU MAY NEVER
GET ANOTHER CHANCE.
SHE'S RIGHT, SUSAN.
WHO IS
THIS LUCKY MAN?
FRANK BEDHAM.
THE STOCKBROKER?
HE WAS HERE
FOR THANKSGIVING.
WE'D BE MOVING
TO TEXAS.
ALL THE WAY
DOWN THERE?
WHAT IF...
WHAT IF THINGS
DON'T WORK OUT?
WHY CAN'T YOU
BE HAPPY FOR ME
AND STOP WORRYING?
I'M NOT 12.
SHE SAID SHE WANTED
TO BUY OIL STOCK.
I REMEMBERED
THAT RIGBY OIL
WAS A GREAT BUY
AT 28 BUCKS A SHARE.
I HIGHLY
RECOMMENDED IT.
SHE SAID, "ALL RIGHT, HONEY,
I'LL TAKE HALF."
I SAID, "YOU WANT TO BUY
HALF A SHARE?"
SHE SAID, "HELL NO, SUGAR,
HALF THE COMPANY!"
ANYBODY WHO SLINGS
THE B.S. LIKE THAT
WILL DO JUST FINE
IN TEXAS.
FRANK.
WHAT?
COME HERE.
YOUR BOSS' FLY
IS OPEN.
YEAH, IT IS.
SHOULDN'T YOU
TELL HIM?
ME? LOOK, MAYBE
HE ALREADY KNOWS.
HE'S JUST GOTTEN
DIVORCED.
MAYBE HE THINKS
HE'S BEING SEXY.
WHAT IF HE MAKES
ANOTHER TOAST LIKE THAT
AND SOMETHING
POPS OUT?
HI, EARL.
I GUESS WE'RE GOING TO
LOSE OUR BOY SOON.
SUSAN MIGHT COME,
TOO.
THAT'S A MARVELOUS
IDEA.
HAS SHE SAID
YES YET?
NO.
FRANK, HAND ME
AN HORS D'OEUVRE.
OH, YEAH, SURE.
HERE YOU GO.
FRANK!
OH, EARL,
I'M SORRY.
LET ME HELP YOU.
THERE WE GO.
EARL IS VERY FOND
OF YOU.
IF HE ISN'T,
HE SHOULD BE
AFTER TONIGHT.
THERE'S SOMETHING
WE HAVEN'T DISCUSSED.
EVERY TIME
I BRING IT UP,
YOU CHANGE THE SUBJECT.
WILL YOU MARRY ME
OR NOT?
I JUST WANT
TO TAKE CARE OF YOU.
BRAVO!
THOSE WERE FOR YOU.
I WAS WONDERING IF
YOU WOULD GO OUT WITH ME.
I DON'T DO THAT.
GO OUT?
I'M NOT INTO THAT.
ARE YOU INTO EATING?
OCCASIONALLY.
I WAS THINKING
OF GOING TO CHARLY'S.
IF YOU WERE THERE, TOO,
EVEN AT THE SAME TABLE,
IT WOULD BE COINCIDENCE,
NOT LIKE GOING OUT.
WHAT'S GOOD HERE?
THE EARLY-BIRD SPECIAL.
I WONDER WHAT THAT IS.
WORMS, PROBABLY.
I'M HAVING THE LOBSTER.
LET'S BOTH HAVE THAT.
SHELLFISH MAKES MY FACE
SWELL UP LIKE A BALLOON.
I HAD THIS COLLEGE ROOMMATE
WITH THE SAME PROBLEM.
HE'D EAT SOMETHING
AND GET ALL PUFFY.
HIS FACE WOULD SWELL UP
LIKE A--
LIKE A BALLOON.
RIGHT.
I'M GOING TO GO
BEFORE I'M TEMPTED
TO ASK YOU WHAT
YOUR MAJOR IS.
WESTERN HISTORY.
WESTERN CIV?
NO, I MEAN WESTERN HISTORY.
THE STUDY OF THE OLD WEST.
YOU CAN'T MAJOR
IN THAT.
YOU CAN AT UTAH STATE.
YOU'RE FROM UTAH?
NO, ACTUALLY,
I JUST WENT TO SCHOOL THERE.
I GREW UP IN VEGAS.
NOBODY
GROWS UP IN VEGAS.
MY DAD WAS
A BLACKJACK DEALER.
MY MOM PLAYED THE ORGAN
AT ONE OF THOSE
CHEAP WEDDING CHAPELS.
UH-HUH.
THERE'S A STORY
THAT MY MOTHER PLAYED
AT HER OWN WEDDING.
SHE PLAYED
HERE COMES THE BRIDE
AND THEN
RACED DOWN THE AISLE.
HOW DID IT GO
WITH LISA?
WELL...
NOT TOO GREAT.
I MEAN, LIKE YOU...
YOU ORDER PRIME RIB,
BUT WANT THE DUCK
SOMEONE ELSE GETS.
READY TO ORDER?
I'LL HAVE THE DUCK.
ME, TOO.
SORRY.
THAT'S OK.
I CAN TAKE THIS OFF.
I'LL TAKE
THISOFF.
YOU WANT ME
TO GO OUT?
NO, I DON'T WANT YOU
TO GO OUT.
IT COMES OFF EASY.
SEE? IT'S OFF.
OK.
THIS ISN'T
GOING TO WORK.
WHY DON'T WE
JUST FORGET IT?
WHY?
IT'S LIKE WHAT
YOU SAID BEFORE--
PRIME RIB AND DUCK.
BESIDES, I'M
GETTING MARRIED SOON.
MARRIED?
YEAH.
WHAT THE HELL
WAS THIS ABOUT?
IT WAS A TEST.
EITHER I FLUNKED
OR YOU FLUNKED.
SOMEBODY FLUNKED.
I'M SORRY.
UH...
OH.
I TRIED CALLING,
BUT THE PHONE
WAS BUSY FOR HOURS.
I GOT WORRIED.
SILLY OF ME.
FRANK?
THIS IS SAM...
UM...
CARPENTER.
RIGHT.
THIS IS FRANK...
BEDHAM.
RIGHT.
DO YOU LOVE THAT GUY?
I HARDLY KNOW HIM.
WHY DID YOU DO IT?
IT JUST SEEMED
LIKE THE RIGHT GUY
AT THE WRONG TIME,
I GUESS.
IT'S OK.
HEY, I REALIZE
THAT THIS IS SOMETHING
THAT WILL HAPPEN
FROM TIME TO TIME.
LOOK, THERE ARE
LOTS OF MARRIED COUPLES
THAT HAVE THEIR AFFAIRS,
AND IT DOESN'T
REALLY MEAN ANYTHING.
LOVE AND FRIENDSHIP--
THAT'S ALL THAT MATTERS.
NOT SEX. RIGHT?
IF SOMETIMES YOU HAVE TO
SLEEP WITH SOME GUY--
OR YOU DO.
OR I DO--
IT'LL BE OK.
AS LONG AS IT'S NOT
THE SAME FELLA, RIGHT?
IT SOUNDED LIKE
A GOOD SOLUTION FOR US.
YOU REALLY THINK WE
WOULD HAVE FOOLED ANYONE?
YOU KNOW...
IT'S JUST POSSIBLE
THEY'LL ACCEPT YOU
THE WAY YOU ARE
DOWN THERE IN TEXAS.
WE'LL FIND OUT
WHEN I WALK INTO THE OFFICE
WITH SOME COWBOY
AND INTRODUCE HIM
AS MY FIANCE.
I LOVE YOU.
I LOVE YOU, TOO.
I'VE DECIDED TO DO
THAT EUROPEAN TOUR.
WHAT MADE YOU
CHANGE YOUR MIND?
DID YOU GO OUT
WITH SAM?
YEAH.
HOW DID THAT GO?
HAPPENS TO
THE BEST OF US.
JUST ONCE,
I'D LIKE TO KNOW
IT WAS BECAUSE I WAS
A BAD CONVERSATIONALIST
OR BECAUSE HE DIDN'T
LIKE BROWN HAIR
OR I HAD DOGGIE BREATH
OR SOMETHING.
YOU'RE NOT THE ONLY
IMPERFECT PERSON IN THE WORLD.
I USED TO STUFF KLEENEX
IN HERE BEFORE DATES.
THEN I'D WORRY ABOUT WHETHER
THE GUY WOULD COP A FEEL.
UNLESS THE GUY WAS DESPERATE
TO BLOW HIS NOSE,
I WAS IN TROUBLE.
THIS IS MY STOP.
CALL ME AND WE'LL TALK.
PARDON.
BUT, MADEMOISELLE,
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
LET ME FINISH
TALKING,
OR I'M GOING
TO CAVE RIGHT IN.
THERE'S A HOTEL
IN MEGEVE.
I'VE GOT
RESERVATIONS THERE.
I'VE GOT ENOUGH MONEY
TO COVER MYSELF
FOR A WEEK.
THAT'S A SKI RESORT.
THAT'S WHY
I PICKED IT.
IT'S A GREAT PLACE,
RIGHT?
OH, YES,
IT'S VERY BEAUTIFUL
BUT I STILL DON'T
UNDERSTAND.
IF YOU HELP ME
WITH THIS,
I CAN BE LIKE
OTHER PEOPLE THERE.
AND THAT'S WHY THIS WAS
SUCH A GOOD IDEA,
BUT IT'S JUST NOT SOUNDING
SO GOOD RIGHT NOW.
OK. I'M FINISHED.
YOU CAN TALK NOW.
WELL, THIS IS
NOT VERY... ORTHODOX,
WHAT YOU ARE
SUGGESTING.
YOU MAY BE TAKING
A BIG EMOTIONAL RISK.
AS A DOCTOR, I DO NOT
REALLY APPROVE OF THIS.
OK,
THANK YOU.
BUT AS A FRENCHMAN,
I MUST
CONGRATULATE YOU
ON AN INGENIOUS IDEA.
THEN YOU'LL DO IT?
OF COURSE, WITH PLEASURE.
I'M AFRAID I'M GOING
TO HAVE TO CANCEL
THE AMSTERDAM RECITAL.
WELL, UH...
I'M HAVING MY APPENDIX OUT.
NO, NO, NO.
I'LL BE FINE.
IT'S JUST THAT OBVIOUSLY
I'LL HAVE TO CANCEL
AMSTERDAM AND ROME.
NO, DON'T CALL DADDY.
I'LL DO THAT.
I DON'T WANT HIM TO WORRY.
OF COURSE
I'LL LET YOU KNOW.
I'LL CALL YOU
WHEN I GET BACK.
JE PEUX VOUS AIDER, MADEMOISELLE?
NO. I'VE GOT IT.
I ALMOST DIDN'T COME
DOWN TO MEET YOU.
THE TRAIN WAS LATE
LEAVING PARIS.
I JUST DON'T WANT
TO MISS MY TURN.
COULD YOU MOVE IT A BIT
FASTER, PLEASE, MISS?
I'M DOING THE BEST I CAN.
HI.
I HAVE A RESERVATION.
SUSAN BERLANGER.
BERLANGER.
HOW DO YOU
SPELL THAT?
SUSAN BERLANGER.
B-E-R-L-A-N-G--
SLOWER.
BERLANGER.
B-E-R-L-A-N-G-E-R.
AH!
BERLANGER!
RIGHT! BERLANGER!
QUATRE CENTS HUIT.
WOULD YOU MIND
FILLING THIS OUT?
EXCUSE ME.
THEY TOLD ME IN PARIS THE RATE
WAS 400 FRANCS A DAY.
THIS SAYS 600 FRANCS.
THERE MUST BE SOME MISTAKE.
NO. THAT IS
THE LOW-SEASON RATE.
THIS IS
THE HIGH SEASON.
THE HIGH SEASON?
IF YOU DON'T WANT
THE ROOM--
I WANT THE ROOM.
IT'S NOT YOUR PROBLEM.
NEVER MIND.
THERE IS A BIT
OF DIFFICULTY.
WHAT KIND OF DIFFICULTY?
THE YOUNG LADY WHO
HAD YOUR ROOM BEFORE
DOES NOT WISH
TO MOVE OUT.
SHE HAS TO MOVE OUT.
I HAD THE RESERVATION.
IT SAYS RIGHT THERE--
BERLANGER.
PLAIN AS DAY.
I AM VERY SORRY.
MON AMIHAS NOTARRIVED YET FROM PARIS.
MON AMI?
UHH...
A FRIEND.
I WAS SUPPOSED
TO MOVE IN WITH HIM,
BUT NOW I HAVE NO PLACE
TO GO.
I CAN'T HELP THAT.
IT'S YOUR PROBLEM
IF YOUR AMIISN'T HERE,
NOT MINE.
CE N'EST PAS
SA FAUTE
SI VOTRE AMI
N'EST PAS LA.
I'M SORRY.
BON! IF THERE IS
ANYTHING ELSE I CAN DO,
JUST LET ME KNOW.
SO WHEN IS
YOUR FRIEND COMING?
YESTERDAY
HE SAID TODAY.
I HAVEN'T HEARD,
SO I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE HE WAS
ON THE TRAIN.
MAYBE
THAT'S HIM NOW.
ALLO?
CHERI... MAIS
QU'EST-CE QUE TU--
AH, OUI.EH...
THAT'S OK. I DON'T
UNDERSTAND FRENCH.
I'LL BE IN THERE.
ET QUAND?
TU ES A PARIS?
TU VIENS QUAND ALORS?
C'EST GRAVE?
AH, OUI, JE--
TU M'APPELLES? D'ACCORD.
CLAUDE CAN'T COME
UNTIL TOMORROW.
I SEE.
HIS WIFE IS ILL.
I'M SORRY
TO HEAR THAT.
SHE'S ALWAYS
GOT SOMETHING--SIMONE.
IT'S NOTHING SERIOUS,
JUST THE FLU.
BUT HE FEELS GUILTY
ABOUT LEAVING HER.
YOU KNOW HOW IT IS.
LISTEN,
THERE ARE TWO BEDS.
YOU CAN STAY HERE
FOR A COUPLE OF DAYS.
YOU MEAN IT?
SURE.
THANK YOU!
I WILL PAY MY PART.
I INSIST.
WELL, IF YOU INSIST.
WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN YOURFRIEND COMES?
MY FRIEND?
I DON'T HAVE
A FRIEND.
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
NOT TO SKI, OBVIOUSLY.
THAT'S--THAT'S RIGHT.
I USED TO SKI...
COMPETITIVELY.
I CAME TO WATCH
THE RACES.
ARE YOU FAMOUS?
NO, I'M SUSAN.
NICOLE CHALON.
BERLANGER.
YOU COME HERE OFTEN?
IT'S MY FIRST TIME.
YOU'LL LOVE IT HERE.
COME WITH ME TONIGHT
TO A BIG PARTY.
CLAUDE ISN'T HERE,
SO I'LL BRING YOU.
TERRIFIC!
ROSSIGNOL IS GIVING IT.
WHO'S ROSSIGNOL?
YOU DON'T KNOW
ROSSIGNOL?
THE SKI PEOPLE.
OH!
OH... UH...
THAT ROSSIGNOL.
OF COURSE.
ROSSIGNOL!
TERRIFIC SKIS,
THOSE ROSSIGNOLS.
I USE THEM ALL THE TIME.
♪ LET ME TELL YOU ABOUT
THE GIRL I KNOW ♪
♪ SHE'S BEEN TO PARIS, FRANCE,
SHE CAN REALLY DANCE ♪
♪ JUST LIKE A BIG TOP,
SHE'S GOT NO STOP ♪
♪ SHE PICKS YOU UP,
AND THEN SHE LETS YOU DROP ♪
♪ LISTEN
HELLO.
♪ LET ME TELL YOU ABOUT
THE GIRL I KNOW ♪
♪ SHE'S REALLY HIP
♪ SHE CAN GO GO LIKE...
I'M ALLERGIC
TO ANIMAL HAIR.
ALLERGIC TO FUR.
ALLERGIQUE.
OUI, OUI.
MY FIRST LINE
IN FRENCH.
CONGRATULATIONS.
♪ OOOH...
MAYBE TONIGHT ♪
♪ YEAH, WE'LL FIND-- ♪
WINE?
SURE.
DEUX VINS ROUGES,
S'IL VOUS PLAIT.
I LOVE THAT.
FRENCH IS SO GREAT.
IL N'Y A RIEN A FAIRE.
LISTEN TO HIM.
IT'S NO BIG DEAL TO YOU,
BUT TO ME, WHEN A GUY
SOUNDS LIKE THAT,
ALL HE HAS TO SAY IS,
"YOUR PLACE OR MINE."
IF YOU'RE GOING
TO BE DIFFICULT ABOUT IT,
LET'S FORGET IT.
OOPS!
YOU SPEAK ENGLISH!
I'M FRANCOIS.
HI. I'M
SUSAN BERLAN--
BERLANGER.
ENCHANTE.
ME, TOO.
NICOLE!
AH, SOPHIE!
VIENS!
EXCUSEZ-MOI.
SO, HOW DID YOU
DO THIS?
THIS?
WELL, YOU KNOW...
OH, JUST A SECOND.
LOOKS LIKE YOU
HURT YOURSELF, TOO.
THIS? NO, NO.
THIS HAPPENED IN AN AUTOMOBILE
ACCIDENT YEARS AGO.
WHAT ARE YOU
HERE TO DO?
I DO SOME SKIING.
MOSTLY I'M PROMOTING
OUR NEW LINE.
LINE OF WHAT?
SKIS. ROSSIGNOLS.
ROSSIGNOLS.
YOU'RE WITH ROSSIGNOL?
YOU--
YOU'RE MR. ROSSIGNOL?
THIS IS YOUR PARTY?
YES.
WELL,
I LOVE YOUR SKIS.
THANK YOU.
STEVE!
HAVE YOU MET SUSAN?
NO, NOT YET.
HI.
STEVE HAVLICEK.
STEVE WILL WIN THE MEN'S
SLALOM FOR US TOMORROW.
I USE HIS SKIS.
IF I WIN, IT'S "US."
IF I LOSE,
I'M ON MY OWN.
THE COURSE WAS
ICY AS HELL TODAY.
I ALMOST FELL
A COUPLE OF TIMES.
YOU ARE TOO TENSE.
TRY DANCING.
IT WILL LOOSEN YOU UP.
I'LL SEE YOU AGAIN,
SUSAN.
BYE.
IN THE MEANTIME,
ENJOY YOURSELF.
SO, UH,
HOW ABOUT IT?
DO YOU WANT TO DANCE?
ME?
NO, I CAN'T.
I MEAN... DANCE.
BECAUSE YOU'RE GIMPY?
YEAH.
IT'S NOT STOPPING HER.
COME ON.
UH...
YOU'LL BE GREAT!
I DON'T WANT
TO DO THIS.
♪ BUT YOU SEE
THAT IT WON'T BE LONG ♪
♪ YOU'LL GROW OLD
IF YOU KEEP HOLDING ON ♪
♪ YOU KNOW YOU'VE CHANGED,
AND YOUR WORDS, THEY LIE ♪
♪ THAT'S SOMETHING
YOU CAN'T DENY ♪
JUST RELAX. RELAX.
GO WITH IT.
♪ I'D RUN,
RUN OUT OF HOPE ♪
THAT'S IT! THAT'S IT!
♪ SHORT ON HOPE,
BUT LONG ON LOVE ♪
ALL RIGHT!
♪ IF YOU WANT ME
♪ THEN WHY DON'T YOU
SAY IT? ♪
♪ YOUR LOVE IS GONE,
ANYWAY ♪
SUSAN, COME ON.
♪ I KNOW THERE'S
SOMETHING GOING ON ♪
WHOO!
LET'S SHOW THESE FRENCHIES
HOW TO BOOGIE! YEAH!
♪ I KNOW THERE'S
SOMETHING GOING ON ♪
♪ I KNOW IT WON'T BE LONG
♪ WON'T BE LONG
BEFORE YOU'VE GONE ♪
♪ VOULEZ-VOUS?
♪ TAKE IT NOW
OR LEAVE IT ♪
♪ NOW IT'S ALL WE GET
♪ NOTHING PROMISED,
NO REPENT ♪
♪ VOULEZ-VOUS?
♪ AIN'T NO BIG DECISION
♪ IF YOU KNOW
WHAT TO DO ♪
♪ BUT I CAN STILL SAY
VOULEZ-VOUS♪
♪ VOULEZ-VOUS?
♪ OOH! ♪
♪ MY RIDE
♪ ONE DAY,
I STOPPED DOWN THE ROAD ♪
♪ MY RIDE
♪ TO GET
SOME LOVIN' TO GO ♪
♪ MY GIRL
♪ SHE HAD A BACK-SEAT AMOUR
♪ SO TAKE MY RIDE
♪ LAST NIGHT
♪ I FELL ASLEEP IN MY BED
♪ WOKE UP
♪ WITH THINGS
SURROUNDING MY HEAD ♪
♪ MY RIDE
♪ I LOOKED AROUND
FOR THE KEYS TO START MY RIDE ♪
♪ BECAUSE I'VE GOT TO GO
GET BACK TO MY RIDE ♪
♪ BACK TO MY RIDE
♪ MY RIDE
♪ I THOUGHT
IT CAN'T BE YOUR FACE ♪
♪ MY RIDE
♪ NOW IT'S
A LATE TIME OF DAY ♪
♪ MY RIDE
♪ NOW THERE'S
A BACK-SEAT AMOUR ♪
♪ PEOPLE EVERYWHERE
♪ SCENTS OF LIPSTICK
♪ THEY'RE JUST
HANGING IN THE AIR ♪
♪ GIVE ANOTHER SMILE
♪ ACROSS THE ROOM, YOUR EYES
ARE GLOWING IN THE DARK ♪
♪ AND HERE WE GO AGAIN
♪ WE KNOW THE SONG,
WE KNOW THE END ♪
I'M POOPED.
LET'S GO.
♪ MASTERS OF DECEIT
♪ WE'VE DONE IT ALL BEFORE... ♪
YOUR ROOM OR MINE?
COULD YOU SAY THAT
IN FRENCH?
SLOWLY.
10 SECONDS.
LOOK STRAIGHT DOWN.
GO!
HE HADN'T EVEN GONE
60 FEET.
HE HAD TROUBLE
COMING OUT OF
THE STARTING GATE
LAST NIGHT, TOO,
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
BUT HE GOT THE HANG OF IT
THE SECOND TIME AROUND.
MAYBE IF YOU
TELL THAT TO THE JUDGES,
THEY'LL LET HIM
TRY AGAIN.
ARE YOU SEEING HIM
TONIGHT?
AND WRECK HIS CAREER?
WHAT'S IT LIKE
WITH A CAST ON?
IT MAKES ALL
THE DIFFERENCE.
MADEMOISELLE CHALON?
OUI. C'EST MOI. EXCUSE ME.
HOW MUCH
WILL THIS COST ME?
YOU'RE THE FIRST
PRETTY GIRL I'VE MET
WHO DIDN'T LIKE TO
HAVE HER PICTURE TAKEN.
I'M NOT THAT PRETTY.
I'M PETER NICHOLSON.
SUSAN BERLANGER.
WHEN YOU DO WHAT I DO
FOR A LIVING,
YOU SEE THINGS OTHER
PEOPLE DON'T NOTICE.
LET ME SHOW YOU
WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
SEE THIS GIRL HERE?
SHE'S HIDING SOMETHING.
YEAH. SEE HER EYES?
THEY'RE A DEAD GIVEAWAY.
YOU CAUGHT ME.
I'M A RUSSIAN SPY.
I'VE GOT A CAMERA
IN MY CAST,
AND I'M TAKING PICTURES
OF ALL THE LATEST SKI BOOTS
SO WE CAN COPY THEM.
YEAH?
PETER.
HERE COMES
SUZY CHAPSTICK.
I'M TAKING
PRACTICE RUNS.
YOU COULD GET
SOME SHOTS FOR THE MAGAZINE.
BOBBIE,
THIS IS SUSAN.
BERLANGER.
HI.
YOU'RE IN THE RACES?
YES.
YOU GIVE UP A LOT
FOR TRAINING, RIGHT?
PETER, I'VE GOT
TO GET GOING.
LOVELY MEETING YOU,
TOO.
THERE'S A GIRL
WITH NO SECRETS.
IN THAT OUTFIT,
I'D SAY NOT.
I'LL FIND OUT YOURS,
THOUGH.
WHO'S THAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
SOME GUY.
CLAUDE CAN'T COME.
HE'S GOT THE FLU.
WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO NOW?
I DON'T KNOW.
WHY DON'T YOU
STAY WITH ME?
AT THESE PRICES,
THE LONGER YOU STAY,
THE LONGER I CAN STAY.
WELL, OK!
I HAVE NOWHERE ELSE
TO GO, ANYWAY.
I KNOW IT'S
NONE OF MY BUSINESS,
BUT HOW DID YOU
FALL IN LOVE
WITH A MARRIED MAN?
I DIDN'T KNOW
HE WAS MARRIED.
WHEN DID
HE TELL YOU?
30 SECONDS LATER,
BUT IT WAS TOO LATE.
THE TIME APART
ISN'T IMPORTANT.
IT'S THE TIME TOGETHER
THAT COUNTS.
YOU TAKE
WHAT YOU CAN GET.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
THE COURSE IS ICY.
YOU HERE TO SKI
OR PLAY GAMES?
HI, STEVE.
HI.
MISS!
UH, SUSAN!
YES.
HI. I'M
BILL HOLLAND.
HI.
STEVE TOLD ME
ABOUT YOU...
WHAT ABOUT ME?
OH, WELL, THAT
YOU AND HE...
YES?
YOU KNOW,
ABOUT LAST NIGHT.
WELL... UH...
I WAS JUST WONDERING
IF YOU AND I
COULD, UM...
THE ANSWER IS NO.
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
I THOUGHT MAYBE
AS AN AMERICAN...
AS AN AMERICAN?
WHO DO YOU THINK
YOU ARE, ANYWAY?!
I'M THE COACH.
THE WHAT?
WOULD YOU MIND STAYING
AWAY FROM STEVE
JUST TILL
AFTER THE MEET?
HE'S GOT A REAL SHOT
AT THE DOWNHILL.
THAT'S ALL
YOU WANTED?
YEAH.
SO... IF YOU
WOULDN'T MIND.
MIND?
I'D CONSIDER IT
MY PATRIOTIC DUTY.
THANKS.
THINK NOTHING OF IT.
VOUS VOYEZ,
C'EST MERVEILLEUX?
I'LL BE IN HOCK
FOR SIX MONTHS.
PARDON?
I DON'T HAVE
THE MONEY.
MAIS C'EST DOMMAGE.
IT'S JUST
TOO EXPENSIVE.
MAIS VOUS POUVEZ PAYER,
MEME AVEC UNE CARTE DE CREDIT.
WHAT?
A CREDIT CARD.
CREDIT CARD.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
ALLERGIC TO FUR.
WHATEVER GAVE YOU
THAT IDEA?
AREN'T YOU TOO WARM?
NOT REALLY.
AREN'T YOU SUPPOSED TO
TAKE PICTURES OF SKIERS?
I TAKE PICTURES
OF WHATEVER INTERESTS ME.
OH.
BEEN TO THE TOP?
NO.
LET'S GO.
ARE YOU EXPECTING
SOMETHING INTERESTING?
YOU CAN NEVER TELL.
ATTEND!
CA VA.
OH! BONJOUR, SUSAN.
BONJOUR.YOU
GOING SKIING?
YES.
DO YOU
KNOW PETER?
SURE.
HOW YOU DOING?
FINE.
I HAD
A TERRIFIC TIME
AT YOUR PARTY
THE OTHER NIGHT.
JUST TERRIFIC.
SO DID I.
HOW DID YOU
LOSE IT?
LOSE WHAT?
OH, MY GOD!
WHERE IS IT?
I WAS IN IRAN
ON BUSINESS.
MY CAR RAN OVER
A LAND MINE.
I WAS THERE
DURING THE IRAQI WAR.
COMBAT PHOTOGRAPHER?
YEP.
YOU LIKE THE IDEA
OF DANGER?
NO. I WAS
AVOIDING THE DRAFT.
HOW COULD YOU ASK HIM
ABOUT HIS LEG LIKE THAT?
WHY NOT?
HE OBVIOUSLY DOESN'T MIND
TALKING ABOUT IT.
YOU COULDN'T
KNOW THAT.
DOES YOUR CAST
MAKE YOU AN EXPERT?
MAYBE.
OH, YEAH?
WHY IS THAT?
THAT'S WHY.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
OH, COME ON, PETER.
THAT'S NOT FAIR.
PLEASE DON'T.
NO. THIS ISN'T FAIR.
REALLY.
HELP!
WHAT'S THE FRENCH
WORD FOR HELP?
LA H--ELP!
ELPEZ-VOUS!
COME ON.
YOU CAN'T DO THIS.
YOU HAVE
THE ADVANTAGE.
YOU HAVE THE ADVANTAGE!
I'M GOING TO RUN!
SLOWLY COMING AT ME,
AS IF YOU'RE REALLY
GOING TO GET ME!
I'M NOT
GOING TO DO IT.
YOU'RE NOT?
NO.
YOU'RE LETTING ME
GET AWAY WITH IT?
I WANT TO
TELL YOU SOMETHING.
WHAT?
OH!
AAH!
I'LL SEE IF I CAN
FIND US A TABLE.
CAN I BORROW THIS?
THESE, TOO.
CERTAINLY--
I WANT TO
AVOID SOMEONE.
SUSAN.
SPEAK FRENCH.
YOU DON'T
KNOW FRENCH.
SUSAN,
IS THAT YOU?
EARL COOPER.
PARDON?
FRANK'S BOSS.
YOU WERE
AT THE HOUSE.
MAIS NON...
CHAMPS ELYSEES.
AH, MY
FRIEND SAYS
SHE NEVER
SEES YOU BEFORE.
NON PARLER ANGLAIS,
MONSIEUR.
VOULEZ-VOUS
FRANCAIS?
SHE SAYS
SHE DON'T SPEAK
ENGLISH, MISTER.
I, TOO, AM ONLY
SPEAKING LITTLE BITS.
SHE LOOKS LIKE SOMEONE
I KNOW IN AMERICA.
IL DIT QUE
VOUS RESEMBLEZ
UNE DE SES AMIES.
I SEE THAT
YOU'RE NOT HER.
YOU CERTAINLY
LOOK LIKE HER.
SORRY
TO BOTHER YOU.
PARDON,
MADEMOISELLE.
COMMENT ALLEZ-VOUS LE CROISSANT?
LE CROISSANT?
WHY ARE YOU
AVOIDING HIM?
HE COULD RUIN
EVERYTHING.
FRANCOIS!
OVER HERE!
RUIN EVERYTHING?
IT'S A LONG STORY.
IS HE WATCHING US?
NO. YOU'RE OK.
MAYBE.
EXCUSE ME.
FINALLY!
I'VE BEEN LOOKING
ALL OVER FOR YOU.
HI, BOBBIE.
I THINK YOU
KNOW EVERYBODY.
FRANCOIS ROSSIGNOL.
YES, HELLO.
HELLO.
AND, OF COURSE,
SUSAN.
HOW YOU DOIN'?
YOU ALL SIT DOWN.
I'LL FIND SOMETHING
ELSE TO SIT ON.
HOW ABOUT THIS?
DID I DO
SOMETHING?
DID YOU SEE THE SLALOM?
NO, I DIDN'T.
I WENT UP
TO THE SUMMIT.
I HEARD YOU WERE
LOOKING REALLY GOOD.
I WIPED OUT
ON THE THIRD GATE.
UNTIL THEN.
THANKS FOR
BEING THERE, PETER.
SHE SEEMS
A LITTLE UPSET.
YOU SHOULD
GO AFTER HER.
I GUESS
MAYBE I SHOULD.
EXCUSE ME.
WHY DID YOU
SEND HIM AWAY?
I DON'T
WANT PROBLEMS.
YOU WERE
HAVING FUN TOGETHER.
I'M NOT
INTERESTED IN FUN.
I'M INTERESTED IN
HAVING A GOOD TIME.
I MEAN, I DON'T WANT
TO GET INVOLVED.
WHY ARE YOU AFRAID
OF GETTING INVOLVED?
I'M NOT AFRAID.
I JUST DON'T WANT TO.
I DON'T WANT TO
SPOIL MY VACATION.
BY HAVING FUN.
RIGHT.
ARE YOU IN THE GRAND PRIX
DES ECLOPES TOMORROW?
THE WHAT?
WHAT DO
THE AMERICANS CALL IT?
THE... THE GIMP RACE.
ALL THE BROKEN LEGS
AND ARMS
GET TOGETHER AND HAVE
THEIR OWN SKI RACE.
IT'S GREAT FUN.
I DON'T THINK SO.
WHY NOT?
YOU HAVE TO TRY.
COME ON, SUSAN.
I'LL EVEN LEND YOU
THE RIGHT SKIS AND POLES.
BESIDES, THE WINNER
GETS 3,000 FRANCS.
HI.
THEY SAY THAT
YOU'RE VERY GOOD.
I NEED SOMEONE GOOD
BECAUSE I'M ENTERING
THIS GRANDE
INVALIDS THING,
AND I DON'T WANT TO
LOOK LIKE A JERK.
HOW MUCH DO YOU KNOW?
I KNOW THAT
THIS IS SNOW,
AND THIS IS MY SKI,
AND THESE DOOHICKEYS
PUSH ME ALONG.
BUT YOU HAVE
SKIED BEFORE?
WHEN I WAS 7.
I DON'T
HAVE TO WIN.
I JUST WANT
TO GET BY.
WHEN IS THIS RACE?
2:00
THIS AFTERNOON.
SO WE HAVE TIME,
RIGHT?
OK.
YOU FOLLOW ME.
NO PROBLEM.
WHOA!
THIS IS EASIER
THAN I THOUGHT.
TELL ME WHY
I'M DOING THIS.
I FELL
ALL MORNING.
IF YOU DON'T WANT
TO DO IT, DON'T.
NO, I'LL DO IT.
AT LEAST
I'LL TRY.
DO YOU REMEMBER
THE PARTY
THE OTHER NIGHT?
THE HOST,
ROSSIGNOL?
YES.
DIDN'T YOU THINK
HE WAS ATTRACTIVE?
I DID.
HE'LL BE
AT THE RACE.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
I ASKED HIM.
YOU COULD
HAVE FUN TOGETHER.
HE'S ALONE.
AND I'M ALONE.
EXACTLY.
THIS IS
GREAT STUFF.
THANK YOU.
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
FIND IT INTERESTING.
SUSAN, GOOD.
YOU ARE DOING IT.
I'M GOING
TO TRY.
HELLO.
NICOLE,
THIS IS PETER.
HI.
YOU REMEMBER
FRANCOIS?
HELLO AGAIN.
BONJOUR.
NICOLE OWNS AN ART
GALLERY IN PARIS.
WHERE DO
YOU LIVE?
PARIS.
NO KIDDING.
WELL,
THAT'S GREAT.
I'M GOING TO TRY
THIS THING.
I'LL BE THE PINK
SNOWBALL
ROLLING DOWN
THE MOUNTAIN.
DON'T YOU WANT
YOUR SKI?
YEAH.
I'LL TAKE IT.
I'M GOING THAT WAY.
YOU SEEM NERVOUS.
HOW WOULD YOU FEEL
GOING DOWN THIS MOUNTAIN
ON ONE SKI?
NERVOUS.
OK.
NOBODY ELSE
HAS MADE IT.
THANKS
FOR TELLING ME.
YOU ONLY
HAVE TO FINISH.
FORGET SPEED.
JUST GET THROUGH IT
AND YOU'VE WON.
WHO CARES
ABOUT WINNING?
I WANT TO GET THROUGH IT.
THAT'S WHAT
I JUST SAID.
I WON'T MAKE IT.
YES, YOU WILL.
GO SLOW.
SLOW?
AS SLOW
AS YOU WANT.
IF YOU FALL DOWN,
YOU'RE DISQUALIFIED.
REMEMBER, SLOW.
VOUS-ETES PRETE DE DEPART?
ATTENTION.
TROIS.
DEUX.
UN.
PARTEZ.
MAIS, MADEMOISELLE,
ALLEZ-Y.
GO!
WHOA!
STOP!
SLOW.
YEAH.
YOU'RE DOING GREAT.
JUST KEEP IT UP.
THAT'S IT.
MAYBE A LITTLE MORE
SPEED, HUH?
NO, THIS IS
FAST ENOUGH.
OH.
OHH!
HA HA HA!
SHUT UP!
THANK YOU.
OH!
AHH!
I GOT IT!
OH!
AAH!
HEY!
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I SKIED
ALL THE WAY DOWN!
YOU SURE DID.
YOU WERE EXTRAORDINARY.
I WAS SLOW, HUH?
MAYBE
A LITTLE BIT.
I SHOULD WORK
ON MY TIME.
BRAVO.
THANK YOU.
HOW ABOUT
SOME PICTURES?
GREAT.
MY FRIEND BACK HOME
WOULDN'T BELIEVE IT.
PETER!
WHY ARE YOU
TAKING PICTURES OF THIS
WHEN THERE'S
A REAL RACE GOING ON?
WHO SAID THIS WASN'T
A REAL RACE?
YEAH, WHO SAID?
AND BESIDES, I WON IT.
SO GET YOUR ASS
OUT OF HERE
SO I CAN GET
MY PICTURE TAKEN.
SORRY.
IT'S OK.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD
GO AFTER HER.
I DON'T THINK SO.
WHY DON'T WE
ALL GO UP
AND WATCH THE REST
OF THE RACES?
IT'S THE FINALS.
I DON'T WANT
TO FIGHT THE CROWDS.
WHO SAID ANYTHING
ABOUT CROWDS?
WHEN I SAID "GO UP,"
I MEANT... GO UP.
HOW HIGH WILL
THIS THING GO?
WELL, UH... THE ALTITUDE RECORD
IN A BALLOON
IS JUST OVER
53,000 FEET.
LET'S GO FOR IT!
YOU'RE JOKING.
THAT'S WITH
OXYGEN TANKS.
WE DON'T HAVE OXYGEN TANKS.
I WANT TO GO FOR
SOMETHING!
I WANT TO DO THINGS
I'VE NEVER DONE.
LIKE WHAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
I HAVEN'T DONE
A LOT.
HAVE YOU EVER
BEEN TO SWITZERLAND?
NO.
LET'S GO!
HOW FAR IS IT?
ABOUT 10 KILOMETERS,
OVER THAT MOUNTAIN.
WE'VE GOT
TO TRY FOR IT.
OK.
I WAS SO SCARED.
I THOUGHT I'D
GET SICK.
I'VE NEVER DONE
ANYTHING DANGEROUS
LIKE THIS.
YOU KNOW?
I FEEL SO...
ALIVE?
ALIVE.
HMM.
YEAH.
I KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE FEELING.
NO, YOU DON'T.
THANKS FOR TODAY.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
AND TONIGHT. I HAD
A WONDERFUL TIME.
I'D INVITE YOU IN,
BUT NICOLE...
THAT'S OK.
LOOK, SUSAN...
WHAT I DO TAKES ME
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
I'LL BE HERE A FEW DAYS,
AND THEN NEXT WEEK
IT'S AFRICA,
AND THEN
MAYBE AUSTRALIA.
WHY ARE YOU
TELLING ME THIS?
I MOVE AROUND A LOT.
I DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME
FOR INVOLVEMENTS.
OH.
NEITHER DO I.
I TRAVEL
A LOT, TOO.
I NEVER KNOW
WHERE I'LL BE NEXT.
THEN YOU KNOW
HOW IT IS.
YEAH.
WELL, GREAT.
GOOD NIGHT.
LA MEME CHOSE.
HOW LONG DO YOU PLAN
TO STAND IN THE DARK?
I WAS JUST THINKING.
ARE YOU ALONE?
OF COURSE
I AM ALONE.
BECAUSE...
I THOUGHT MAYBE...
YOU THOUGHT
MAYBE WHAT?
I THOUGHT MAYBE
YOU AND FRANCOIS...
ISN'T HE
A NICE GUY?
YES.
HE'S SO ATTRACTIVE,
INTELLIGENT, AND WITTY.
HE'S GOT EVERYTHING.
EXCEPT TWO LEGS.
WHY DIDN'T
YOU TELL ME?
I DIDN'T THINK
IT MATTERED.
YOU DIDN'T?
YOU COULD HAVE SAID
SOMETHING TO ME
SO I'D BE PREPARED.
PREPARED FOR WHAT?
I CAN'T BELIEVE
THIS BOTHERS YOU.
IT DOESN'T
BOTHER HIM.
OK. SO IT'S
MY PROBLEM, NOT HIS.
I'M SORRY.
I GUESS I SHOULD
HAVE TOLD YOU.
UNUSUAL GIRL.
DEFINITELY UNUSUAL.
THEN WHY ARE
YOU DOWN HERE?
I DON'T
NEED PROBLEMS.
HA!
ARE YOU FAMILIAR
WITH DEJA VU?
SURE. WHY?
SUSAN SAID THOSE WORDS
TO ME THE OTHER NIGHT...
ABOUT YOU.
WELL, MAYBE
WE'RE BOTH RIGHT.
WHO NEEDS PROBLEMS?
OH, CATCH ME!
I CAN'T WAIT
FOR THE NEXT OLYMPICS!
HEY!
AAH!
HA HA!
YOU TWO-LEGGED GUYS
SURE ARE KLUTZY.
SKIING IS NOT SUPPOSED TO BE
A CONTACT SPORT.
AT LEAST NOT
ON THE SLOPES.
YOU OK?
WAIT A MINUTE.
I HURT MY WRIST.
OH.
LET'S SEE WHAT WE CAN DO
TO MAKE IT BETTER.
MY LIP HURTS, TOO.
MMM.
THERE.
IN FACT,
I'M HURTING ALL OVER.
OH. THAT FEELS
SO GOOD.
WHAT I LIKE BEST
ABOUT SKIING
IS TAKING OFF
MY BOOTS AFTERWARDS.
SKI BOOTS CAN BE
BETTER THAN SEX.
BAD SEX.
THERE IS A SAYING.
"GOOD SEX IS GREAT.
"BAD SEX IS, UH...
STILL PRETTY GOOD."
OH!
WHY DON'T I ASK THE COOK
TO MAKE US SOME FONDUE.
NO. ANOTHER TIME,
THANK YOU.
SUSAN AND I
HAVE TO GO.
THERE'S SOMETHING
WE HAVE TO TAKE CARE OF.
YEAH.
SO, UM...
WE HAVE ANOTHER
ENGAGEMENT.
THAT WAS MUCH BETTER
THAN FONDUE.
EVEN BETTER THAN
TAKING OFF MY SKI BOOTS.
WHOO!
YOUR CAST IS COLD.
YOU KNOW
WHAT THEY SAY--
"COLD CAST, WARM HEART."
NOT BAD.
THANK YOU.
I WANT TO SEE
UNDER YOUR CAST.
IT'S DRIVING ME CRAZY!
IT'S THE ONLY PART OF YOU
I CAN'T SEE.
SORRY.
I GOTTA SEE IT. PLEASE?
I'M SAVING IT
FOR SOMEONE SPECIAL.
YOU WHAT?
I NEVER PLANNED
ON THIS.
HE WAS THE LAST GUY
IN THE WORLD...
LISA, WHAT AM I
GONNA DO?
TELL HIM!
I CAN'T DO THAT.
WHAT IF SOMEONE
SPRANG THIS ON YOU?
THERE ISN'T ANYONE
WHO ISN'T HIDING SOMETHING.
LISA!
THIS IS MAJOR!
THIS ISN'T STUFFING
MY BRA WITH KLEENEX.
WHAT AM I DOING?
I'M LEAVING IN
A COUPLE OF DAYS.
SO WHY TELL HIM
AND RUIN IT?
WHY RUIN
A COUPLE DAYS' HAPPINESS
WHEN IT'S YOUR LIFE
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT?
YOU LOVE THIS GUY?
I DON'T KNOW WHY
I'M BOTHERING YOU.
IT SEEMS TO ME
YOU HAVE A CHOICE.
EITHER YOU TELL HIM,
OR YOU MAKE SURE
YOU NEVER SEE HIM AGAIN.
EVER.
THAT'S WHAT
I FIGURED.
I'M SORRY
I WOKE YOU.
I GOTTA GO.
BYE.
CLAUDE CALLED.
OH, HE DID?
HE WANTS ME
TO COME BACK.
CAN YOU
GIVE ME THAT, PLEASE?
THANK YOU.
WHAT ABOUT FRANCOIS?
HE DESERVES SOMEBODY
BETTER THAN ME.
LOOK. HE'S
A TERRIFIC MAN.
I TOLD YOU,
IT'S MY PROBLEM,
NOT HIS.
YOU'RE UNDERESTIMATING
YOURSELF, NICOLE.
YOU GIVE ME
TOO MUCH CREDIT.
OUI. CES DEUX LA.
MERCI.
KISS PETER
GOOD-BYE FOR ME.
I WILL.
HAPPY DAYS.
RIGHT.
I'M SORRY,
FRANCOIS.
ABOUT WHAT?
I JUST FEEL
RESPONSIBLE.
DON'T.
I'VE ADJUSTED.
I'M FINE.
YOU SURE?
I'M SURE.
I HAVE TO LEAVE
IN THE MORNING.
I'M FLYING TO ZURICH
ON BUSINESS.
IT'S ALL OVER,
ISN'T IT?
YOU'RE GOING.
NICOLE'S GONE.
PETER IS HERE.
THAT'S ANOTHER STORY.
THERE'S SOMETHING
I HAVEN'T TOLD ANYBODY.
I MEANT HE'S HERE.
RIGHT NOW.
WELL, IT LOOKS LIKE
THE GOLDEN COACH
IS ABOUT TO TURN
INTO A PUMPKIN.
WHAT?
THE MOMENT OF TRUTH
IS ABOUT TO ARRIVE.
IT SURE LOOKS GRIM
AROUND HERE.
WHAT'S UP?
I HAVE TO LEAVE
TOMORROW.
LET'S LIVE IT UP
TONIGHT.
THE FOREIGN PRESS
HAVE TAKEN OVER
THIS RESTAURANT
IN ST. GERVAIS.
WE'LL GO DOWN THERE.
WE'LL SHAKE IT UP.
NICOLE WENT BACK
TO PARIS THIS MORNING.
WE'LL FIND SOMEBODY ELSE
SO YOU CAN HAVE FUN.
DON'T LEAVE
ON A DOWN NOTE.
WHY NOT?
MAYBE HE WANTS
TO BE DOWN.
WHY DOES EVERYTHING
HAVE TO BE HAPPY?
MAYBE HE
ISN'T HAPPY.
MAYBE I'M NOT,
EITHER!
WHY IS SHE MAD AT ME?
SHE LOST ME WHEN SHE WAS
TALKING ABOUT PUMPKINS.
I'D LIKE
TO GO WITH YOU,
BUT I CAN'T.
WELL, I GUESS
THIS IS, UH...
AU REVOIR.
I EXPECT WE'LL
SEE EACH OTHER AGAIN.
I WOULDN'T BE SURPRISED.
AS FOR YOU...
FRANCOIS.
I WANT YOU
TO TAKE THIS.
GIVE HER SOME TIME,
AND THEN CALL HER.
I DON'T WANT
TO DO THAT.
IT WOULDN'T
BE FAIR.
FAIR?
YOU CAN'T MAKE PEOPLE
BE MORE THAN THEY ARE.
I GUESS
I KNOW THAT.
WHAT'S
THIS THING?
IT'S FOR GETTING
TO ST. GERVAIS.
LET'S TAKE
A TAXI.
THEY'RE NOT RUNNING.
GET ON!
IT'LL BE FUN.
ISN'T THIS GREAT?
IT'S OK.
CAN WE PULL OVER
FOR A MINUTE?
WHAT'S UP?
THERE'S SOMETHING
I HAVE TO TELL YOU.
OH, MY GOD.
YOU'RE PREGNANT ALREADY.
NO.
I SHOULD HAVE
TOLD YOU BEFORE.
LET'S PLAY NOW.
WE'LL TALK LATER, OK?
PETER!
I'M NOT
THE PERFECT PERSON
YOU THINK I AM.
PERFECT?
YOU'RE SKINNY,
YOU GOT A BUSTED ANKLE--
IT'S MORE THAN THAT!
I'M TRYING TO
TELL YOU SOMETHING!
WHAT?
I'VE GOT THIS...
THERE'S
A GUY AT HOME.
AND...
HE'S ASKED ME
TO MARRY HIM.
I TOLD HIM
I NEEDED TIME
TO THINK.
AND WHAT
I'VE DECIDED IS,
I'M GOING
TO DO IT.
YOU'RE GOING TO...
YOU MEAN,
ALL THE WHILE WE WERE...
YOU WERE--
YEAH.
WELL, THAT'S...
THAT'S JUST GREAT.
YOU SAID YOU
DIDN'T HAVE TIME
FOR PERMANENT
RELATIONSHIPS,
REMEMBER?
YEAH. RIGHT.
PETER!
I WANT
TO GET OFF!
PLEASE STOP, PETER!
I WANT
TO GET OFF!
THAT'S WHAT YOU SAID!
IF YOU DON'T STOP,
I'LL JUMP.
SURE.
NO, I'M GONNA!
AAH!
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING?
IF YOU'RE TRYING
TO KILL YOURSELF,
DON'T INCLUDE ME
IN YOUR PLANS!
YOU'RE OUT!
FINE!
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
BACK!
DON'T BE STUPID.
I'LL GIVE YOU A RIDE.
I'D LIKE TO
GET THERE ALIVE.
WELL, ALL RIGHT!
ALL RIGHT!
OU VOUS ALLEZ?
GOOD QUESTION.
PARDON?
HELLO, MR. SCHNEIDER?
IT'S SUSAN BERLANGER.
I'M CALLING BECAUSE
I'M FEELING BETTER.
YOU WHAT?
THE REVIEWS
FROM PARIS?
I'M SORRY.
I CAN'T
UNDERSTAND YOU.
I THOUGHT
YOU SAID--
THEY DID?
YOU'RE KIDDING!
I DON'T BELIEVE IT!
I REALIZE THAT
AMSTERDAM IS OFF,
BUT WHAT ABOUT ROME?
CINCINNATI?
OH, OK.
WELL, WHEN?
IN A COUPLE
OF WEEKS?
YEAH, THAT'S FINE.
I'LL DEFINITELY
BE THERE.
THANK YOU,
MR. SCHNEIDER.
BYE-BYE.
CINCINNATI
INSTEAD OF ROME.
GOD IS GETTING ME
FOR THIS.
YOU THINK YOU COULD MOVE IT
A LITTLE FASTER, MISS?
I'M DOING
THE BEST I CAN, OK?
I DIDN'T KNOW
HOW TO TELL YOU.
I'M WONDERING
IF YOU'D BELIEVE
THAT THESE THINGS
ARE THE RAGE IN PARIS.
OUR TRAIN IS LEAVING.
I KNOW.
ALL MY BAGS
ARE ON IT.
MINE, TOO.
THERE'S NOT ANOTHER ONE
TILL TOMORROW.
I KNOW.
WE'LL JUST HAVE TO FIND
SOMETHING TO DO UNTIL THEN.
I'M SURE WE CAN
THINK OF SOMETHING.
OH, YEAH?
YEAH.
THEN WE'LL
GO TO PARIS
AND SEE IF THERE'S
SOMETHING TO DO THERE.
GREAT. OH, SHIT!
WHAT?
I HAVE TO BE IN CINCINNATI
ON TUESDAY FOR A CONCERT.
I'LL GET
MY CAMERAS BACK.
I'LL FIND SOMETHING
TO PHOTOGRAPH
IN CINCINNATI.
GREAT.
AND WHILE YOU'RE THERE,
BE THINKING OF WHAT YOU CAN
TAKE PICTURES OF...