Number 21.
Number seven.
Number 32.
Number eight.
Number 15.
Number 41.
And number 12.
That's our 15 lucky numbers.
Winners, please bring up
your cards. Losers, there'll
be another game in a minute.
Congratulations, Louise.
Next.
I got the money
from the second grade.
Good work, Charlie.
A nickel bet...
four cents.
The measly allowance
these kids get is hardly
worth the trouble.
Where's the 20 cents
Tommy Perkins owes us?
Doesn't have it yet. He said
his parents will pay him
next time he loses a tooth.
Want me to help him lose it?
Nah. Save the rough stuff
for 50 cents and up.
Eight winners, on a dollar.
Hang on, Harvey.
Let me check my copy.
You've only marked
seven, Harvey.
What are you trying to pull?
See? Forty-one's marked
on my card.
I just didn't press hard enough
through the carbon.
That's all. So pay up.
I run a clean game, Harvey.
Take your dollar back and leave.
Look, Cessna,
you can't throw me out of...
Beat it.
Hey, we didn't need
his cooties anyway.
Nene, pass out the cards
for the next game.
Charlie?
Yeah.
Think you can get bets
from the fourth grade too?
Sure. I'll tell Mrs. Cooper
I gotta "check" the radiator.
All right, it's keno time again.
Pick your numbers, everybody.
Sixty balls in the air, and I grab
the first 15 to pop out the bottle.
Eight out of 15 pays
2-to-1 on a quarter.
Nine out of 15, 3-to-1.
Ten out of 15...
Mr. Ruggles.
So this is where the sixth
grade spends its recess.
You can skin your knees
on the blacktop.
Shut up, Dickie.
This is a school, not a...
uh, Turkish bath.
Everyone out.
You snitched!
I'll tell my father.
Forget it, Skip. The house
was losing today anyway.
I just don't understand you,
Dickie.
Why don't you apply
your leadership potential...
and all of the energies
which you devote
to running these scams...
to legitimate school activities?
They don't pay as well.
So what's it gonna be?
A note from our parents?
No trips to the zoo?
Oh, no.
I think we are past that stage.
Suspended.
Hey, Ruggles did us a favor.
All they ever teach us is
a bunch of junk we could never
use in business.
I mean, who cares what
the capital of South Dakota is?
We always get caught.
Don't start that, Nene.
We always
get caught.
Look, this time
it was just as well.
Charlie was charging us
eight bucks an hour for
protection and collection.
And those second and third
graders were bad credit risks.
We got bigger things
in store for us.
I bet they're right around here.
Hey, wait up.
Come on, Dickie.
You always stop here.
Will you look at this, Nene?
It looks the same way
it did yesterday,
except they put more traps
in the gopher holes.
You know what this means?
A resort right here in Ramona.
It'll mean people'll
be coming here from
all over California...
from all over the country.
It's a gold mine, Nene,
right in our own backyard.
You and me have been hustlin'
for nickels and dimes
long enough.
This is our chance to start
making the big bucks.
No way, José.
I'm retiring.
I said I'm retiring.
From now on
I'm only selling cookies
for the Camp Fire Girls.
Nene, is that what
you want out of life?
Cookies? A Kool-Aid stand?
A lousy paper route?
Is that what
it's about for you?
It is for now.
I'm only in the fourth grade!
So you'll waste your time
goofing around
on the playground.
Before you know it,
you'll be in high school.
Then you gotta get good grades
so you can go to college.
Then you gotta get
good grades in college
so you can get a job.
And you know what? You'll be
working for somebody else
making them money.
"Only in the fourth grade."
You better start wising up
before it's too late.
Too late? Dickie,
I'm three years and two weeks
away from my first period.
That's no excuse.
This is the land
of great opportunity.
For kids too!
You think the Declaration
of Independence...
says "life, liberty
and the pursuit of happiness"
for grown-ups only?
I don't know. We don't study
the Declaration of Independence
till next semester.
If they let me back in.
Okay, be a housewife.
Just don't say
I didn't warn you.
We're a little lost.
Do you think you could
help us out?
We'll try, sir.
Do you know where
Oak Tree Lane is?
Sure do...
Yes, sir.
You go back the way you came,
turn left at the end
of this road,
then, uh, just keep going
till you see the sign.
How far?
Pretty far.
Just keep going south.
I thought it was
in Country Estates.
Well, it is, sir, but they
own a second piece of land
just outside Ramona.
I directed a man there
just yesterday.
Okay, thanks.
He was nice enough
to give me a quarter.
Pretty smart for your age,
aren't you?
Thank you very much, sir.
A lousy dime.
Dickie,
you sent them to...
Of course I did.
Those guys are feds.
Come on.
We gotta implement
Condition Red.
That little shit.
Condition Red! Condition Red!
Condition Red!
Come on!
We gotta go right now!
They're coming!
1523.
Oh.
Looks more like a barn
than a castle.
Cessna's too smart to have
anything plush on the outside.
We've come a long way
to nail this clown.
Let's go.
Looks like a converted stable.
Sounds like
it's not converted yet.
Yes?
Mrs. Cessna?
No, I'm her daughter June.
My parents are out now.
Can I help you?
I'm Phillip Porzinski.
This is Mel Sloman.
We're with
the Board of Taxation
in San Diego.
San Diego?
Do you know a sailor named Bill?
He said he'd be back from
Thailand in the spring.
I'm Bette Cessna.
You wanna come in and wait
till my folks get home?
Uh, no, honey.
I think we've seen enough.
Um... Yes, we will come in
and wait.
Okay.
Come on.
Oh, my God.
Would you like something to eat?
We've got oatmeal,
puffed oats
and oat pudding.
Uh, no, thanks, honey.
We've already eaten.
Can we leave?
Um, if you don't mind,
we would like a tour
of your home.
These are all our stalls.
This is Big Red.
Buttercup.
Blackjack.
My little sister, Nene,
and my brother, Dickie.
- Slowpoke.
- Wait a minute.
You kids sleep in here?
Dickie and Nene do.
Me and June have
this one over here.
But I'm gonna get my own stall,
when I have my... my...
There, there, June.
It's okay.
That's about it for the tour.
Unless you wanna see
the manure pile.
We've seen enough, sweetheart.
We'll be heading back now.
Y-You kids take care
of yourself.
Mel, don't be in such
a hurry to leave.
- Mr. Porzinski?
- "Por-zhin-ski."
"Por-zhin-ski."
Please, look for Bill.
I can't remember
the full name of his ship,
but I know the first
three letter are "U-S-S."
I'll do the best I can.
Thank you.
Porzinski, Sloman.
Hello, Mr. Cessna.
What, uh...
What's going on here?
We just wanted to look at your
new surroundings, Mr. Cessna.
Uh, and they were
just leaving, Daddy.
We'll report your circumstances
back to the board.
And, uh, just make
payments as you're able
and don't worry.
Yahoo! We did it!
We did it!
Hello, junior!
All right.
Just how did this little
masquerade come about?
Whoa.
All right, Dickie.
Come on.
You've suffered enough.
Let's go. One of
the colts got loose.
Dickie.
Now, I don't enjoy
giving you pen duty,
Dickie.
But when you behave
the way you did yesterday,
you don't give me much choice.
Getting in trouble at school
and talking your sisters into
tricking government agents.
But, Dad, last week
you said those guys
were a couple of sons...
All right, all right, all right.
Maybe I called 'em a few names
I shouldn't have.
At least in front of you.
But I still intend
to play by the rules.
Now, if I am to lose that case,
heaven forbid,
I'll pay those tax guys
everything they think
I owe them.
That's my responsibility.
Now, you've got
responsibilities too...
to Nene.
She gets 20%.
She also gets suspended
from school, thanks to you.
Sorry about that, Dad.
But I think school's overrated.
You know, we go in there
and study guys like
Ford and Rockefeller...
who dropped out of school
to make millions.
And you always say
"find a way." Well,
I needed some extra money,
and that keno game was perfect.
Not if it breaks
the school rules.
Now, Dickie, you've gotta stop fleecing your
classmates in keno games and numbers rackets.
Start showing 'em
a little respect.
Even Harvey Peterjohn?
Even Harvey Peterjohn.
Now, can I have your promise?
You won't cook up any more schemes at school.
Okay, Dad, I promise.
No more schemes...
at school.
Slicing!
Yow! Dad!
Harvey, I thought I told you
to keep your eye on the ball.
They don't grow on trees.
Brutus thinks it's in here too.
Brutus is probably commenting on your backswing.
You've lost enough balls today.
From now on,
you just caddie.
Come on.
Brutus!
Nene!
- How many balls today?
- Twenty-three.
And one case of pneumonia.
I should've stayed retired.
Come on. This is the best deal
I ever offered you...
equal partners.
Equal punishment!
It's in the bag.
Mr. Clark, Richard Cessna
is here to see you.
Don't tell me
the riding stable's
screwing up too.
Uh, Richard Cessna Jr.
and his sister Jeannine.
Florence, I've got
a 3,000-acre development
to take care of.
Uh... Just buy a couple
of raffle tickets...
or whatever it is
they're pushing
and get rid of 'em.
It's not a raffle.
It's a service.
Hold it!
Just where did you get
all these golf balls?
They were all over, sir.
Golfers are too lazy
to crawl around
after lost balls.
So, uh, me
and my sister here...
me and my partner...
are kids,
and we enjoy doing it.
So, uh, well, we know
you need used golf balls
for your driving range,
so we thought
we'd show you how many
we could collect in a week,
and you'd be real impressed
and put us on your payroll.
- Is it a deal?
- Okay, uh, listen.
I already pay
a couple of fellas
to take care of that.
Come on, Harvey.
Get that dog!
Well, if it isn't
the suspended Cessnas.
- You wanted to see me, Jim.
- That's right, Orville.
There's a mistake on
the new rates you sent me.
Just let me get rid
of these kids.
No, mistake, Jim.
Get him out of here.
There is no mistake.
Orville.
This would be a 50% increase.
My operating expenses
have really mushroomed.
I am sorry, Jim.
These children
better wait outside.
I don't know about
those children,
but I encourage Harvey here
to listen to anything that
has to do with my business.
Put your fingers in your ears.
Okay, bullshitter!
Why don't you
just put a mask on
and break into my safe?
- Look here, Jim.
- You're just trying
to rob me blind!
Just because you're
the only fertilizer company
in this whole goddamn town,
you're not gonna screw me royal!
Understand?
Harvey, what we have here
is a dissatisfied customer.
And rather than take his abuse,
we tell him to buy
from a competitor,
if he can find one.
Come along, Son.
Dad, look.
It's one of our balls.
I said come along.
That mutt pissed on
my putting green!
I oughta take that
disgusting dog of yours
and shove him up your ass!
God!
All right.
What was I saying?
I oughta take
that disgusting dog
and shove him up...
I remember.
Take your fingers
out of your ears.
I was saying...
I already pay a couple of fellas
to take care of my golf course.
That includes
looking for lost balls.
So you see, if there aren't
any balls for them to find...
they're being paid
for a job they can't do.
In other words,
each ball you have there...
is costing me around
20 cents in unearned salary
to my employees.
From now on, you stick
to the school yard.
"It's in the bag."
Leave the golf course
alone.
Let's face it, Dickie.
It's a grown-up world.
They own everything.
They run everything.
We're just here
to mow the lawns.
Let's go home, Dickie.
We have chores to do.
Nah, you go ahead.
I'll stay and watch 'em
seed the banks for a while.
Nene, look out!
Sorry, kid.
Don't worry, Nene.
It's chemical fertilizer.
Dad?
Hello, Son.
Yeah, Dad, what does your,
uh, contract with the Country
Estates say about manure?
It says
it's my responsibility
to get rid of it.
Dickie, some joker's been
springing my gopher traps.
Well, what if you... what if I...
wanted to keep it?
- Keep what?
- Well, all the manure.
Son, if you're looking for
a hobby, I think you'd be
better off collecting stamps.
How many horses
do we take care of?
Well, with the riding horses
and the show horses,
thoroughbreds,
I think it comes to 172.
Why?
Too big for just me and Nene.
Dickie, another one
of your schemes?
Oh, no, Dad.
This is legit.
Nene! We're back
in business!
All right. I think
we're ready to start out.
Remember, keep your feet
in the stirrups.
Bette, I gotta talk to you.
Dickie, can't you see
I'm busy here?
Oh. Did you tell 'em
about the moose trail?
- Dickie.
- Excuse me. What trail?
We could start you
around that way,
and there's a good chance...
you might see a wild moose
feeding in the woods.
It's only a dollar apiece extra.
We will take the moose trail,
thank you.
Look, to be honest,
I really don't think
it's worth the extra dollar.
The moose trail, thank you.
- Let Nene do it.
We gotta talk.
- Darn right we do, you creep.
You know what Dad'll do
when he finds out...
you're pulling that
moose trail stunt again?
In times of emergencies,
you gotta take risks.
Me and Nene need every buck
we can get for our new business.
We need you to come in with us.
Ha! I haven't recovered
from last summer's losses.
Hey!
Bette, this isn't some
two-bit keno game.
This is legit,
and we can make a fortune.
They're coming.
You gonna go in with us, Bette?
N-O. No.
Why not?
Because...
I've already got chores
to do each day,
and I wanna devote
the rest of my time
to getting good grades.
Well, now what
kind of talk is that?
I wanna be a doctor,
and medical schools
only take the best students.
Nitwit, it'll be 20 years
before you can become a doctor.
So what?
You watch the news.
Neutron bombs, nuclear plants,
pollution.
What do you think
the world's gonna be
like in 20 years?
There won't be any air
you can breathe, and you won't
have any gas for your car,
and all your food will be
full of chemicals.
Look, don't wait.
Get the money now while
there's still some stuff
you can spend it on.
Nice try, but I think
I'll take my chances.
They're coming. Shh!
Look, Bette, now, we can't
do this without you.
Now, I know you've got
this crush on Neil Brody.
- That's a crock of shit.
- Shh!
Hey, it's all
for a good cause.
But if you come in with us,
I promise I can set you up
with Neil.
How? He doesn't
even know I'm alive.
Look, Neil's the editor
of The Daily Bugle, hmm?
And what we're gonna do
is gonna be a real story.
When he asks us
for an interview, well...
Dickie.
Understand...
I still don't like...
the childish, two-bit stunts
you've pulled in the past.
This is different.
Count me in.
But don't breathe a word
about my diary to anyone,
especially Neil.
Would Macy's tell Gimbels?
Dickie! The head!
Nene, how could
you let me do that?
Me?
Frank.
I thought we were
gonna go to the movies.
I know, Juney,
but I had to buy
some parts for my car.
I'm flat.
Then just pretend
I'm flat too.
Come on, Juney.
There's nothing
we'd do at the drive-in
that we can't do right here.
Right?
I don't know.
I wanna go
to the drive-in.
No.
Mmm.
What? Mmm? What?
Let me see. Let me see.
Frank, stop it.
No.
Yes.
- Juney, come on.
- Dickie.
You're never going
to get June to join us.
That's what Nene said
about you.
Dickie!
Uh, hi, June.
Hi, Frank.
Daddy said you're not
allowed out of your room.
You almost scared
those tourists
back to Tokyo.
Well, I know, June.
But I gotta talk to you
about something important.
It can wait.
No, it can't.
Yes, it can, Dickie.
No, it can't, Juney.
If you don't out of here,
you little worm...
Listen, wait.
Dickie, come here.
Uh, listen, if you decided
it's not so important after all,
it could be worth
a quarter to you.
Really, now.
Look, Frank, I've been hearing
June beefing about you
being short of cash.
You know,
and since I've been doing,
you know, okay,
here's 10 bucks.
Have a good time at
the drive-in tomorrow night.
Have a little snack.
But tonight you gotta leave
me alone with my big sister.
Geez.
All right?
Is it a deal?
Uh, Dickie, I can't take this.
Frank, do you have
any other way for paying
for tomorrow night?
No, but...
Go ahead.
I want to see what
this little rodent is up to.
Whew.
Okay.
See you tomorrow night?
Bye.
Bye, Frank.
Okay, Dickie, what's up?
You've never given away money in your life.
And I ain't startin' now.
Wait till that bum sees
my interest rates.
He's not a bum.
June, he's a teenager.
He's smoking dope.
He ain't got no job.
He ain't got no motivation.
And the only dough he gets
is what his old man gives him,
and he blows that on camshafts.
You wanna wear his ring,
you'll have to buy him
some Cracker Jacks.
Why are you telling me all this?
June, you got a lot
of vital needs.
New clothes, skin creams,
gum, record albums.
Your allowance can't cover it,
and Frank's no help.
But if you come in
with us...
Us?
Oh.
We could all become as rich
as Orville Peterjohn.
What are you talking about?
Orville Peterjohn's
the richest man in Ramona.
Mm-hmm. And how'd
he get that way?
He's selling fertilizer.
Uh-huh.
And what do we throw away
piles of every day?
Oh.
Dickie, it can't be that simple.
That's what they said
about the guy who invented
the Frisbee.
Since we're gonna be
competing with a corporation,
first we gotta be a corporation.
Well, that means president
and vice president,
secretary.
I wonder what little big shot
wants to be president, Dickie.
Well, that's one nomination.
Any others?
What are we going to call
our corporation?
Well, that's
the next order of business.
It should be something
with a real ring to it.
You know, something big.
How about...
the Cessna Girls and Dickie?
Wait a minute.
We're running a business here,
not a circus act.
I've got it.
The Shovel-uppers!
Don't you get it?
We're gonna be shoveling up
the manure.
Now, look, we need
something with class.
You know, like AT&T, I.B.M.,
ARCO.
Hmm.
Dickie,
I don't know if
we should go that far.
After all, we are just kids.
"Contract.
"Official contract between
Kidco, Dickie Cessna,
president,
"and San Diego Country Estates.
"Number One:
"San Diego Country Estates
hereby officially
hires Kidco...
to supply it with
homemade fertilizer... T.F."
True or false.
Oh. I see.
All right. "Number two:
"San Diego Country Estates
hereby agrees to pay Kidco...
the cheap sum of four dollars
a cubic yard for
said fertilizer... T.F."
Well, that will depend on
the answer to number one.
"Number three:
"Said sum will be paid:
A. in advance.
"B. Most in advance,
"some at the end of the month.
"C. Some in advance,
most at the end of the month.
D. None of these."
I've been reading contracts
for 35 years.
I've never read one
quite like this.
"Number four:
"San Diego Country Estates
agrees to: A. Give,
B. Loan, C. Rent...
"Kidco a motorized golf cart
for the purpose of...
helping them finish
all deliveries
before their bedtime."
You've got a lot
of them out there.
And I get $10 every time
I rent one.
So, I think
I'll circle "C. Rent."
for number four.
"Number five: This contract...
cannot be canceled
unless Kidco screws up."
That's your safety clause.
Well.
I must admit, you sure as hell
show a lot of initiative.
Let's face it.
You're just a bunch of kids.
I can't risk it.
Mr. Clark, when you wanted
to build the Country Estates,
what if everyone told you,
"You've got a lot of initiative,
but you're just a grown-up"?
- That's different.
- Why? We can't help
how old we are.
You need a job done,
and we say we can do it.
And you can't hate us any worse
than you do Mr. Peterjohn.
And we're doing it for you
for a lot less money.
We're just asking you
to give us a chance.
Please.
Do you know what a raspberry is?
Hello. Orville?
Jim Clark here.
How are you? Listen, Orville,
I've been thinking
about your new prices,
and I've come to a decision.
Yeah. Here it is.
Uh, listen carefully.
- Louise.
- Yes, sir.
Something stinks around here,
and I don't like the smell.
I want it investigated.
Right away, sir.
That's it. Eat...
Whoo!
That about cover everything
I owe you, Homer?
Yep.
Looks like thanks to Dickie
I'm becoming your best customer.
Yep.
Nice talking to you.
Come in.
It's after 10:00, Son.
Time to put away your homework.
I did that a long time ago.
This is Kidco business.
I think you know I'm proud
of you and your sisters for
starting your own business,
but, well...
Do you know what
an obsession is?
Well, sure.
It's like when a guy
looks up girls' dresses.
Well, yeah, that's
one kind of obsession.
But an obsession means
that you get so wrapped up
in one thing...
that you forget
all the other important things
in your life.
And I wouldn't want to see
that happen with you and Kidco.
Would you?
No, Pop.
Okay. Kidco can wait
till tomorrow.
Come on. Let me
hear your prayers.
There's never enough
hours in the day.
Now I lay me down to sleep.
I pray the Lord my soul to keep.
And if I die before I wake,
I pray the Lord my soul to take.
And Nene, Bette and June
can split up my share
of the business.
Good night, Dad.
Sleep tight, Son.
Does being in Kidco take up all
of your time on the weekends?
No, not all of it.
Dickie and Nene have
the first shift on Saturday.
That means I'm free
every Saturday afternoon.
Neil?
For example,
if someone wanted to take me
to the Saturday matinee at
the Ramona, I'd be able to go.
Okay, I guess that'll do it.
We could talk more after school.
No, I think I've got
enough for a story.
You have a nice summer, Bette.
Ah, 196 cubic yards of manure...
at four dollars a yard,
that's $784.
Pretty good first month.
Wait till Neil sees me
in a permanent!
He'll take me
roller-skating! Whoa!
We're running
a business here. We're
reinvesting this in Kidco.
All of it?
We need more wagons
and shovels.
We gotta establish credit,
and we gotta take out
advertising.
What do we need
advertising for?
Yeah!
There happens to be a ton of
flower and vegetable growers
between here and San Diego.
Now come on.
Let's go.
- Who are they?
- Customers.
The power of advertising.
A balance of $30.
Give her that money.
And thank you, Tiny.
No, thank you,
little lady.
It was worth driving
a few extra miles
to save 30 bucks.
- Hey, I'll see you next week?
- Can we make it two weeks?
We have to give
the horses time to do
their best work.
Okay, we'll see you
in two weeks.
- Come on, Mama. Let's go.
- See you later, Tiny.
So long, Tiny.
Uh... God, Juney.
Frank,
I've been shoveling shit
all afternoon.
I have an English paper
to write for Monday.
I'm too tired.
Juney, you haven't been the same
ever since you started working.
Frank, if you weren't
always so broke,
I wouldn't have to work.
All right, Frank.
A $10 loan, plus
two dollars' interest,
plus 50-cents-a-day
late penalty, uh...
Screw off, Dickie.
I think it's time
for a young man...
about to enter his teens
to have his own bank account.
Harvey, we are going
to start you off...
with a brand-new
$10 bill.
Well, this must be
your big day, Harvey.
Yes, sir. A penny saved
is a penny earned.
Oh. Here you are.
Oh, Mr. Sones,
excuse me.
Jenkins, can't you see that
I'm busy with Mr. Peterjohn...
and, uh,
little Mr. Peterjohn?
Yes, I see, sir.
But I thought you'd want
to know about the new account.
You see, sir, they want
to deposit $30,000...
in cash.
Jenkins, get security over here.
Security's taken care of.
Dad, that's my account!
Earn your own money.
Uh...
So it was a real prosperous
summer for Kidco.
Mm-hmm.
As a matter of fact,
we're thinking of getting
into communications.
So if someone wanted
to ask me on a date,
and they just so happened
to be a newspaper man,
I could write it off
as a business expense.
- Mm-hmm.
- He wouldn't even
have to pay a penny.
Okay, thanks.
Nice talking to you, Bette.
I am losing farmers who've been
buying from me for 20 years.
I don't know
what we can do.
Oh, yeah? Well, I'll tell you
one thing I can do.
I can bounce
a bumbling detective
who can't take care of...
four little brats peddling
homemade horseshit.
You are fired!
Harvey!
Yeah?
I want to see you.
But I'm in the bathroom, Dad!
Now.
Harvey!
I want you to arrange
something for me.
Dickie.
What do you want,
Harvey?
I...
Harvey,
I'm a busy kid.
Oh.
Dickie, it's such a hot day.
I thought maybe
you'd like to come
to my mansion for a swim.
Uh, and bring
your lovely sisters
with you.
Well, we've got
a pretty full schedule,
but I think we could
stop in for a minute.
Good.
Hamburgers and hot dogs
are being served!
Let's go, kids.
Brutus!
I don't know what's
got into him today.
Normally, he loves children.
You young ladies,
uh, sit over there.
Robert.
Uh, Dickie, sir.
Milk shakes. Don't forget
the milk shakes.
This is really swell of you,
Mr. Peterjohn.
My pleasure.
As another businessman,
I wanted to help celebrate,
uh, Kidco's success.
We're businesspersons.
As another businessperson,
I also have to do something
about that success.
You see, you are taking away
my customers.
Relax!
I have a proposition
that I think is going
to make us all happy.
I want to buy all the fertilizer
you produce every month...
at the price
you charge for it now.
You don't lose a penny.
I get back my accounts.
Fair enough, isn't it?
Mr. Peterjohn, does that mean
that we'd be working for you?
No.
It doesn't mean
you have to work for me.
I could put Harvey in charge.
Sorry, Mr. Peterjohn,
but we work alone.
We don't need any grown-ups
coming in and taking over.
I want you to understand
something, all of you.
To me, you're not just
enterprising kids...
To me, you are competition.
Well, may
the best corporation win.
We'd better get going now.
Come on, girls.
We got a lot of work to do.
Um, bye,
Mr. Peterjohn.
See you in school, Harvey.
I bet they don't even write
thank you notes.
Those weren't
meant for you.
We got the spelling bee champ,
we got the kid from Annie,
and we got the 13-year-old
going to UCLA.
But we still need one more.
What about this?
It's from the Sahuarita
Elementary School Bugle.
Three sisters and a brother
run a corporation
called Kidco.
They collect horse manure
and sell it as fertilizer.
It's... It's...
It's great, but it's not
exactly appetizing, is it?
Executive Secretary Bette Cessna
confided to The Bugle...
that this summer Kidco cleared
more than $6,000 a month.
Hmm.
All right, listen. We're gonna
be on television. In a few
minutes, I want you to really...
We got 10 seconds.
I want a big applause, okay?
Let's rub our hands together,
get 'em ready. Get 'em warm.
That's super.
That's great!
You're doing a good job.
We haven't got much time.
I want to hear it big and loud.
When I ask for you to respond,
I wanna really hear you.
Five seconds. Get ready.
All right, let's hear you!
All right. Okay,
everybody, welcome.
Welcome to Kids "R" Amazing.
We're delighted to have you
here with us. And, listen.
We have four of
the most amazing guests
with us here today.
Would you like
to meet 'em right now?
Yeah!
Dad, can't we watch
something else?
Shut up, Harvey, or I will
lock you in the basement.
All right.
Let's bring 'em on with
a big round of applause, okay?
Kidco, come on, gang.
Hi there.
And who are you?
We are Kidco!
All right!
I understand that,
but what is your name?
Dickie Cessna,
president and founder.
When my research
into Kidco...
uncovered your involvement
with the Cessnas,
I realized you would probably
want to see this program.
I appreciate your
getting in touch with me,
Mr. Peterjohn.
Please. Orville.
Oh, you take care of all
the money. What about you?
Nene, vice president.
Oh, all right.
Kids, come on in and take
your seats. We'll explain
things to our audience.
You see, in order to understand
how Kidco works,
we sent our Kids "R" Amazing
camera crew to their hometown
to bring back some film.
Would you like to see
what they brought back?
Yeah!
All right!
Look right up here.
Dickie, Nene, Bette and
June live in this house in Ramona, California,
a small town 40 miles
northeast of San Diego.
Their dad,
Richard Cessna Sr.,
works at the San Diego
Country Estates where he
takes care of 170 horses...
used for trail rides,
horse shows
and thoroughbred racing.
170 horses make
a huge amount of...
you know what.
And Kidco mixes it with straw,
let's it compost...
and sells it to farmers
and landscapers as fertilizer.
All right!
That's great! That's marvelous.
Okay, let's get some questions.
Hi there. What's your question?
What are you gonna do
with your money?
All right.
What are you gonna do
with your money?
Well, we were thinking
of a college.
Isn't that great, everybody?
They're gonna use their money
to buy the greatest gift in the
world... a college education!
No! No, no!
We wanna buy a college!
We don't think they're
teaching the right stuff,
so we wanna take 'em over!
I think we've seen enough.
Harvey, turn it off.
And take Brutus out of here
and give him a bath.
But... I...
Mr. Peterjohn...
Orville.
Let me assure you...
that I am going to examine
that son of a bitch Cessna...
with a fine-toothed comb.
And when I'm through with him,
he's gonna be nailed
on more violations
than have been invented yet.
Actually, Phil, if I were you,
Cessna Sr. wouldn't be
the one I'd investigate.
"The enclosed letters
and cards...
"represent the greatest
viewer response...
in the four-year history
of Kids "R" Amazing."
Wow!
Whoopee!
Careful with
the return addresses now.
These kids took the time
to write to you, you can all
take the time to write back.
Listen to this one.
"I'm 10 years old and
the newly elected president...
"of the Dickie Cessna Fan Club,
"Cleveland Heights, Ohio,
chapter.
Dickie, could you please
send us an autographed picture
and a lock of your hair?"
I got a marriage proposal!
Oh! Nene!
Uh-oh! Uh-oh!
"Dickie Cessna."
"Dickie." Looks like
I'm the people's choice.
Well, no wonder,
you little bigmouth.
You hogged
the whole interview.
Yeah, Dickie.
"President
and founder."
I thought we all
found Kidco.
Come on! You two didn't
even want to be in it.
Well, we're in it now,
you creep,
and we work
just as hard as you do.
Well, the public's
never wrong, June.
Maybe it's my fiancé!
I'll get it.
And you kids take it easy.
Don't worry about me, Dad.
I got two days of reading here.
I'm back.
Hi.
Nice place
you have here, Cessna.
I saw it on TV just last Sunday.
All right,
Porsinski.
Porzinski.
All right. My kids
played a prank on you.
We really don't live
in a stable.
That still doesn't mean
I owe you tax on a sale
made outside California.
When you sold those horses,
they were drinking
out of the river.
That means their heads
were in California.
And their legs were
still in Arizona.
And four legs are bigger
than one head.
Cessna, let's forget
about it... for now.
What?
We have bigger fish to fry.
But the children were
intending to pay income tax.
It's too early for it.
This is sales tax,
Mrs. Cessna.
It's supposed to be
collected on every sale
and paid quarterly.
And they've
been selling manure
for the past three quarters.
They owe the state
six percent sales tax,
plus penalties
for late payment,
plus interest.
- Penalties?
- Hey, we're just kids!
Do you have a sellers' permit?
A what?
'Cause if you don't,
that's a misdemeanor.
And that means more penalties...
and an injunction against
future sales till you get one.
For God's sake, Porzinski.
These are children.
They're also a corporation,
and they're acting
in violation of state law.
What the hell's this?
A court order...
for all of Kidco's records.
You ain't taking
my Led Zeppelin albums.
This is a different kind
of record, Nene.
Sloman.
Not at all.
It was my duty
to alert you tax boys.
Those kids were beginning
to give fertilizer a bad name.
Okay, Phil.
Talk to you later.
Bye now.
Harvey, we live
in a great country,
just as long as we know...
that the government
is there to serve us.
- You got that?
- Yes, Dad.
Talk of the school yard, huh?
Yeah.
Dickie finally got his.
Harvey,
you are about to learn
a very important
business principle.
What's that, Dad?
When you have your opponent
on the ropes,
you don't back off.
You put him out.
Yes. In San Diego, please.
Field office,
the California State
Board of Agriculture.
If we break
the cease-and-desist order
in our manure operation,
the Department
of Agriculture says
they'll take us to court.
And if we don't pay
penalties by November 1,
the Board of Taxation
says they will too.
If we pay 'em
everything we owe 'em,
we're gonna have to
declare bankruptcy.
Do you think we qualify
for food stamps?
What do you think
we should do, Dickie?
- Dickie?
- I don't know.
Everything's falling apart.
The government's after us.
We can't make any money anymore.
You were right
a long time ago, Bette.
Childish, stupid stunts...
That's all Kidco is!
Dickie.
I said that about
the other things you did.
Not Kidco.
As a matter of fact,
Kidco's the best thing
I've ever been a part of.
Me too, Dickie.
I liked the keno game better,
but they always caught us.
But Kidco's kaput, finished!
This contract says:
"Unless Kidco screws up."
It doesn't say anything
about giving up.
I don't think we should.
Me neither.
Me neither too.
You're right.
Who do those dumb butts think
they're pushing around?
I don't know what I'd do
without you three.
Is that so?
I, uh, guess I got a little
carried away lately.
Yeah.
The TV show
and the letters and all.
Do you know what
an obsession is?
It's like when you get
so wrapped up in one thing...
That you become
a royal pain in the ass.
Yeah.
You could say that.
Well, I'm sorry.
So are we gonna
stick together and fight?
With our last ounce of manure.
San Diego District Court,
State of California,
is now in session.
The Honorable
Oliver T. Willoughby
presiding.
You may be seated.
The clerk will read
the information.
"The People versus
the Corporate Officers
of Kidco, Incorporated."
Defendants will please stand
when called.
Richard Cessna Jr.,
President.
I'm pleased to see young people
show such an interest...
in the judicial process,
but let's remember:
This is a trial,
not a kickball game.
The clerk will proceed.
Jeannine Cessna, Vice President.
Bette Cessna, Secretary.
Executive Secretary.
June Cessna, Treasurer.
"The defendants
are charged with...
"violation of the revenue
and taxation code of
the state of California,
"Article 2, Section 6071:
"operating a business
without a sales permit.
"Section 7151: failure
to furnish a quarterly
sales tax return...
"and violation of the
food and agricultural code
of the state of California.
"Article 2, Section 11702:
"fertilizer production
without pest control.
"And Section 12821:
failure to list ingredients
contained in fertilizer."
How could we have
done all that and still got
our homework in on time?
The defendants may be seated.
And who's representing
the People?
George Tuskie, Your Honor,
from the attorney general's
office.
Mr. Tuskie. And who's
representing the defendants?
Me and Bette,
Your Honor.
And we object.
He's only representing
some of the people.
A lot of these people
are rootin' for us.
We will have order
in this court!
Your Honor,
the prosecution urges
the court...
to overrule the defendants'
intention to serve as counsel.
We feel it will render
these proceedings farcical.
I object! What does
"farcical" mean?
Will the proposed counsel
for the defense...
approach the bench?
It's my duty to warn you
of the possibility...
of negative consequences
of you representing
yourselves.
You, uh... You know what
"negative consequences"
means?
Could be a bad idea?
That's right.
There's an old saying:
"A man who represents
himself in court
has a fool for a client."
No offense, Your Honor,
but if we'd have believed
in old sayings like that,
we never would have
made a penny.
"Youth is wasted on the young."
"Children should be seen,
but not heard."
They all sound like
they were made up by
some old fart who hated kids.
Now.
Be that as it may,
a licensed lawyer
still has the advantage...
of seven years of training...
four in college,
three in law school.
Us kids could never
trust anyone...
who'd go to school
an extra seven years
on purpose!
Uh...
The Supreme Court
has been quite liberal...
on people's rights
to defend themselves...
and only requires
that they be literate.
I assume you're both literate.
You can read and write?
Your Honor, I know we're kids,
but give us a break.
All right then.
All the requirements
having been met...
Objection, Your Honor.
On what grounds, counselor?
It'll be plain silly.
I'll risk silliness,
Mr. Tuskie,
to guarantee these defendants
their rights.
The court accepts
Richard Cessna Jr.
and Bette Cessna...
as cocounsel for the defense.
Hooray!
But it does not accept
this outcries from the gallery.
Bailiff, let's get
these noisemakers
out of here.
So, Mr. Grundy, despite
their flagrant violation
of the code,
initially you sought
no criminal action against
the officers of Kidco.
That's correct.
They are children.
But then you changed
your mind.
Last month they resumed
their fertilizer production,
uh, still having failed
to obtain a license...
or to list the contents
of their fertilizer.
They left us no choice.
Thank you, Mr. Grundy.
Your witness.
Uh, we don't want him,
Your Honor.
Kidco's records list 345...
separate entries
of sale of manure...
since March of this year.
And they paid tax on...
None of them.
- Thank you, Mr. Pozinski.
- Porzinski.
Your witness.
We don't want him either,
Your Honor.
Mr. Sloman,
were the officers of Kidco
advised that they were
required by law...
to obtain a seller's permit
if engaged in the selling
of taxable items?
Yes, they were.
They were?
And did they obtain
this permit?
No, they didn't.
Thank you, Mr. Sloman.
Your witness.
Mr. Sloman, some of
my baseball cards are missin',
and Bette thinks you might
have taken 'em by mistake when
you cleaned out Kidco's records.
If you find any,
could you send 'em back, please?
Uh, sure.
Uh, could I trade you
the Maris for the Hornsby?
Thank you.
No more questions, Your Honor.
Your Honor, the State's
witnesses have confirmed...
not only the defendants'
violation of the law,
but a lack of repentance
bordering on outright defiance.
And if these
youthful miscreants...
I object!
Transgressors?
I still object.
Troublemakers?
Okay. We know that one.
If these youthful
troublemakers...
are not punished
for their actions,
then we will all be guilty...
of contributing to flagrant
violation of the law...
by the wide-eyed children
of this nation.
Kidco would like to welcome
two distinguished guests...
to this board meeting...
who made it pretty clear
that we'd better invite them.
Mom, Dad.
Okay.
First order of business: what
are we gonna ask our witnesses?
Dickie, you don't know that yet?
Mom, when I had to
give an oral report on
The Last of the Mohicans,
I read it the night before,
and I still got a B-plus.
Now, kids, I know we've
been through all this before,
but your mother and I
have friends who are
experienced attorneys.
They'd be more than happy
to lend you a hand.
But, Dad, they ain't kids.
Look, we got ourselves
into this, and we're gonna
get ourselves out of it.
We ain't gonna go running
to any grown-ups
to do it for us.
That's what Kidco is all about.
Don't worry!
We'll think of somethin'.
Dickie!
Hi, Neil.
Have you seen
the San Diego paper?
We're in it?
In it?
You're on the front page!
They're all out there
to interview you. One of 'em's
from the network news!
Well, Ollie, it looks like
you're on TV tonight.
I'm already all over
the morning papers.
"All over the morning paper"?
Ollie, you're all over.
That story was picked up
by the wire services.
"Kidco Sells the Manure,
but State Wants Its Own Pile."
Chicago Tribune.
"Government Sniffs
as Kids Pile Up the Loot."
The New York Times.
"Kids Gelt Smelt."
Jewish Daily Forward.
You can guess
who the public's
gonna side with.
I can't help that, Sid.
Tuskie built up a very
strong case yesterday.
Ollie. I'm not
getting through to you.
You have to run for reelection,
and nobody's gonna vote
for a mean old man...
who sends four little kids
up the river.
Sid, aren't you
exaggerating a little?
Am I?
What happened to the witch...
who tried to stick
Hansel and Gretel
in the oven?
June, stay away
from the cameras.
Why?
We're supposed to be kids.
Kids ain't got bazongas
like that.
Mr. Ruggles, how many times...
did you see me
and defendant Nene
in your office last year?
Well, there was
the football pool,
the roulette table,
wholesale cafeteria food,
fire-drill bingo,
keno,
We Forge Pink Slips,
Rent a Third Grader.
Seven that I recall.
And how many times
since we started Kidco?
Well, none, I'm amazed to say.
No more questions, Your Honor.
Mr. Clark,
you've employed Kidco
for nine months.
Would you say
we've done a good job?
Yes. I would.
Your Honor, the prosecution
objects to this whole line
of testimony.
Whether or not
the officers of Kidco
did a good job,
whether or not they get in
any less trouble at school,
these are not the issues
that are being tried here.
Counsel?
My cocounsel brother
will handle that objection.
Your Honor?
We see kids
getting in trouble
all the time,
and we see stories
in the papers and on TV...
about all
the juvenile delinquency.
Who knows?
If me and Nene wouldn't have
got into Kidco, we might have
kept up our evil ways...
and wound up in reform school.
But we went straight,
Your Honor.
Now we work hard,
stay off the streets,
and we don't break any windows!
This big jerk...
Your Honor, I object.
This jerk says if we don't
get punished for what we did,
it'll encourage other kids
to break the law.
But what did we do?
Well, maybe we're
just kids, Your Honor.
But instead of
giving us trouble
about taxes,
the government oughta be glad
we're out working on our own,
setting a good example
and not stealing any hubcaps.
Your Honor,
what is the point
of this oration?
Your Honor, what is the point
of making kids take a test
they could never pass...
to get a pest control license
they could never get anyway?
- '- Cause they don't give 'em to kids.
- Your Honor.
Your Honor, if Kidco's
put out of business...
on account of licenses
and taxes and crummy laws,
what about all the other kids?
They'll figure doing a good job
and staying out of trouble...
will only get you
in worse trouble.
And then they'll
take a lot of drugs
and become a bunch of bums.
And when they grow up,
we're gonna have a nation
full of good-for-nothings.
And I bet some foreign country
will come in and take us over.
Hundreds of years from now,
people will look back and say,
"The United States
was the greatest place
in the world,
and then they had to
go and bust Kidco."
Order, or the court
will be cleared.
Your Honor,
you still haven't ruled
on my objection.
The counsel for defense
will apologize...
to the counsel
for the prosecution...
for calling him a jerk.
Your Honor, my prior objection.
The testimony
of the defense's witness...
and this little diatribe
that we've just heard...
They have no bearing whatsoever
on any of the charges
brought before this court.
I see your point,
Mr. Tuskie. Uh...
We will, uh, take
an extended noon recess.
And I encourage
the counsel for defense...
to take this time
to develop a line
of questioning...
that will more directly
address the issue...
of their innocence or guilt.
- Ooh!
- Mr. Tuskie.
Right. The kid
shot his mouth off,
but no harm done.
In fact...
I'd say if you wanted
to be here for the kill,
it could be this afternoon.
Okay, Orville.
See you soon.
Phil. I assume, uh,
we're recommending
leniency in this case.
Oh, I don't think so, Mel.
Was that little shit lenient
when he sent us
all the way to Tijuana?
Aw, come on.
Mr. Cessna!
Excuse me, please.
Neil, there must be
a hundred kids out there.
I'd do it myself,
but I'm kinda busy today.
Dickie!
I'm a journalist
covering a trial.
Who's gonna believe
I'm objective...
if I start selling
these Kidco T-shirts?
Look, it's
five dollars a shirt,
including the sales tax.
And we'll give you
20% commission.
I could always say
I was working undercover.
- Can I get an interview?
- Juney!
Frank.
I had to be with you, Juney.
Forget what I said about Kidco.
I love you.
What about
all the money
you owe me, pal?
You know we're in
triple figures by now?
I think I'll go help Neil.
Bette!
Aw, let her go, Dad.
We're all done here.
All done?
What about your defense?
Nothing more we can do.
Mr. Woodward said he'd get
here as soon as he could.
Woodward?
All right. Counsel for the defense.
The court trusts you heeded
its advice during the recess.
We've got no worries,
okay?
Counsel.
- Woodward will be here.
- Counsel?
Yeah, Your Honor,
but, uh, we might need
a little more time.
He's here.
The defense calls
Mr. Homer Woodward
to the stand.
Is Homer Woodward
in the courtroom?
Yep.
Take the stand, please.
Do you swear to tell the whole
truth and nothing but the truth,
so help you God?
Yep.
Be seated.
Thanks for coming,
Mr. Woodward.
Could you please tell everyone
if you own Woodward's Feed Store
in Ramona?
Yep.
And does my dad buy hay, oats
and straw from your store?
Yep.
And does my dad pay sales tax on
everything he buys from you?
Yep.
Your Honor,
the prosecution has not accused
the defendants' father...
of not paying sales tax
on horse feed.
Good,
because all Kidco sells is
straw composted with manure,
which used to be hay and oats.
Your Honor,
well, even us kids know
that if your dad pays tax...
on the stuff going
into the horse,
we shouldn't have to pay
more tax on the same stuff
comin' back out.
I mean,
we're getting taxed
at both ends.
George! George.
Order, order! Order!
Mr. Tuskie, the defense
does make a strong argument...
that tax has already
been collected...
on the item they're selling.
Surely our state agencies...
don't seek to tax
the same item twice.
Your Honor, the prosecution
wishes a moment to confer.
Uh...
George, I'm gonna nail
that little slimy...
Forget it, forget it.
Quiet, Mel.
You don't have a case.
Your Honor?
Your Honor!
On behalf of
the Board of Taxation,
we made a mistake.
What good is spending...
What did you do?
Forget it.
It's over. Let's go.
Come on.
I'll buy you a drink.
The Board of Taxation
acknowledges its error.
The charges against Kidco
are dismissed!
The charges are dismissed
against Kidco.
Dismissed!
Yes, yes, yes!
Dismissed.
Your Honor. Your Honor!
Your Honor.
Mr. Tuskie.
Your Honor, the charges
that the officers of Kidco...
failed to obtain a license...
and to reveal the contents
of their fertilizer...
still remain before this court.
Bummer.
George, there must be some
compromise we could work out.
Mr. Grundy has said
that he doesn't want
his department...
to appear too heartless.
So then he might be willing
to grant a special permit
to Kidco...
till the officers come of age.
Of course, the prosecution
would expect a little something
in return for these concessions.
Well, what do you have
in mind, George?
A guilty plea
on both remaining counts,
with the court's assurance
that they'll be fined
for each offense.
Judge, Grundy doesn't want
to be embarrassed by this case
any more than you do.
But the State's not
coming away empty-handed.
Would, uh, Kidco be willing
to accept this compromise?
Well, I don't know, Judge.
We'd better talk it over
with Nene and June first.
I understand.
You have until tomorrow morning
to give me your answer.
So, when we're done
paying the fine,
we have a balance of $38.
But from now on,
you'll be protected.
You'll have the State
off your back.
Mom, we didn't work that hard
and make all that money
just to lose it.
We know that, Son.
It's after 7:00!
Nene.
Do you have to watch
The People's Court
tonight?
Bette, the network news is on.
Our interview!
The outcome
has not yet been determined.
This is it!
We now switch you
to Maggie Alexander at
the Ramona County Courthouse.
People are always telling kids
to get off their butts
and do some work.
Well, us kids did.
Then we got busted for it.
And if we let 'em do it to us,
the paperboys will be next.
So you feel
that you're fighting for other
children as well as yourselves?
That's right!
We got a lot of letters
when we went on TV before.
And we'd only wish
that all those kids
could come here to San Diego...
to show those bureaucrats
that they can't push
us kids around.
Hey.
It has been brought to
the court's attention...
that the defendants
want to change their pleas...
to the remaining charges.
Before those pleas are entered,
I wish to commend...
the California State
Board of Agriculture...
for its intention
to make special allowances...
that will enable Kidco
to resume...
its fertilizer production.
However, this court
must still rule...
on the conduct
of Kidco's officers
in the past.
And so, albeit
with great sympathy,
I will hear their new plea
to charges...
of violating the code...
of the California State
Board of Agriculture.
The defendants will rise.
June Cessna, how do you plead?
Guilty.
Bette Cessna, how do you plead?
Richard Cessna Jr.,
how do you plead?
Guilty.
Jeannine Cessna,
how do you plead?
Guilty, but it stinks!
The court accepts these pleas...
and, in accordance with the laws
of the state of California,
fines the defendants
the sum of no more than...
but no less than the total
of their illegal earnings...
from fertilizer sales to date.
Rough morning.
I think they should have
some time alone now.
Excuse me, Mr. Cessna.
We'd appreciate you
not going outside.
It could start a riot.
What?
Kidco! Kidco!
What are they shouting?
- Hey!
- Wait!
Get out of the way, kids.
I'm trying to get
to my car, please.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Kidco! Kidco!
Harvey, I thought I told you
not to come here today.
I didn't want to be
the only kid in school.
Bye, Dad!
Kidco! Kidco! Kidco!
Neil!
What are those?
Orders for Kidco
T-shirts.
- How many did you get?
- How many kids are out there?
They're not gonna disperse
unless you say something
to them.
Go ahead.
Come on.
Okay.
Neil!
Kidco! Kidco! Kidco!
- Hello, everybody!
- Hello!
My sisters and me
want to thank you all
for showing up today.
And we just wanna tell you
that you just made us enough
money to pay our fine.
Maybe now those bureaucrats
will pick on someone
their own size!
I also want to take
this opportunity...
to announce plans
for a new Kidco poster.
Not only our name on it,
but a picture of our president,
so come and get your orders in!
Kidco! Kidco!