'My sweet Jesus.'
'We pray once more
for Ed and Jack Biddle.'
Hear my plea for your
lost lambs, father.
Suffering injustice
at the hands of evil,
unrighteous men.
Give those boys strength, Jesus.
Show them mercy.
'Fill their hearts
with the hope'
'that only you can
give, dear Jesus.'
'You know their innocence.'
'If there is a way,
if it is your will..'
'...do not let them die.'
'They do not deserve
to die, Jesus.'
'Dear father'
'hear my plea
for your lost lambs.'
'Hear my..'
'Go back to bed now.'
'All of you! Go on.'
'Get back to bed, Clarence.'
'Go on.'
'Peter.'
'I dreamt that I was lost
in snowstorm.'
'And I couldn't breathe.'
'Somebody pulled me out
to a clear spot.'
Lord, Kate.
'Poor Peter.
I wear you out.'
- No.
- 'Peter?'
'Here, drink this.
It'll help you sleep.'
Peter.
I know what the dream means.
I'm gonna get better.
God was telling me
'he's not gonna let me die.'
Yes, yes.
Yes. Drink this now.
Go on.
'Drink this.
It'll help you sleep.'
'Go on, now. Go on.'
'Express!
Biddles' appeal today!'
'Morning Express!'
Thank you, son.
Here we go..
Move it along, please.
...at the hands of evil,
unrighteous men..
Alright, Mrs..
Move!
Hurry, kids.
Get out of the street.
'Free the Biddles!
Free the Biddles!'
I'm sorry, Jessie.
I asked, and they said no.
I just want to see him.
I know you do. Sorry.
Let's go over there.
Sir, sir?
Excuse me, sir.
- I made this for Ed.
- For you.
No, thanks. I can't.
It's against the rules.
Would you please
give this to Jack?
- Just for us.
- I'm sorry, I can't.
Please, sir?
'Good morning, pinhead!'
'Thank you!'
Bloody kids!
'No, I'll never shoot another!'
'Clarence Soffel,
you've been so bad!'
'Please, please.
Please don't kill me!'
I'll take you away
to Murderers' Row
and lock you up
forever and ever.
I'll never shoot anyone again!
Please!
'Let's hope that the governor
will see it our way.'
Clarence! Scat!
Hurry! Hurry!
I'm sorry, boys. Really sorry.
We did the best we could.
I mean, yes, you get the two of
us hanged for the one murder.
That's a pretty neat trick.
- Thanks.
- Come on, boys.
Hey, fellas, don't forget
to send us your bill.
'Margaret, Eddie, Clarence.'
'I understand you were playing
in an area'
where you're not allowed,
and now you're late for school.
Is that right?
Three little criminals.
Do you children understand
how hard your sister works
to take care of you
and me and your poor mama?
And when you do something
that's disruptive and wrong
'you have to be punished,
don't you?'
- Yes, sir.
'Answer papa, Margaret.'
I'm thinking.
Well, I think the sentence
can be suspended
'this time, court is
dismissed.'
Mama! Mama, you're up!
Are you better?
Yes, I'm better.
I'm all better.
Mama, what are you doing
out of bed?
I'm all well.
Daddy suspended us
from our punishment.
Did he?
'Irene, tell Maggie
to fetch the doctor.'
Oh, no. Really, Peter.
He never knew
what was wrong with me.
I don't see what he can do
for me now.
How can anyone be sick in bed
for three months
and suddenly get up one
morning and say she's fine?
- It doesn't make sense.
- Please, Peter.
I don't need to see the doctor.
Well, then everyone better
get off to school then.
Come on, come on,
they're late already.
Come on, lamebrain.
- Who appointed you warden?
- You Clarence.
You hush up.
Good afternoon.
Harold.
It's good to have you back,
Mrs. Soffel.
Would you like a Bible?
'I've been getting sick'
'of all these boys
and their ugly faces.'
It never changes,
does it, George?
No, ma'am,
I suppose not.
'Why don't you come up here'
'and visit with me, cutie?'
- You hush up!
- Good afternoon.
Why, Lenny, I thought
you left us last September.
Mrs. Soffel, they can always
find something to blame
on an honest fellow like me.
But you'll be pleased
to hear I went to church
four times when I was out.
It doesn't look like
it did you much good.
I need a quarter from you,
George, for the pool.
You get on with your work.
He gives me the willies.
Betting on when
somebody's gonna hang.
- Mrs. Soffel.
- Hello.
Thanks.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
'Why, Charlie, leave 'em be.
They ain't hurting nothing.'
Warden Soffel believes
a man's cell reflects
a man's moral character.
'We haven't got
any moral character, Charlie.'
We're murderers.
Ain't that right, Jackie?
Does your brother always
fight
your battles for you, Jackie?
Hey!
Get in there! Go on!
You're dead.
Oh, I hear it's the other way
around, Eddie.
Stand back from the door
for inspection.
- Ed!
- Jesus!
'No!'
'Stop it!'
Stop it!
Get up!
- Mrs. Soffel, you're bleeding!
- No.
- You're hurt.
- No, no. It's his blood.
Easy!
'Leave him be, you bastards!'
You'd better give me your arm,
ma'am. You look a little pale.
No. No, thank you,
Mr. Reynolds.
Here, wipe your face.
- Go on, go on. Go on.
- Thank you.
Mrs. Soffel,
Warden Soffel's wife.
Go tell the warden we got a
prisoner who needs cooling off...
'You started it!'
We've got four more cells
down there!
'Never mind, Jack.'
'A couple of hungry days
will do Eddie's soul good.'
'Where'd you get that scar
on your face, Mr. Biddle?'
When they arrested me
and Jack.
'They shot you?'
No, ma'am, I shot myself.
I meant to kill myself.
'Don't you read the papers?'
Well, I'm very sorry.
What are you sorry for?
Would you like a Bible,
Mr. Biddle?
What are you sorry for?
- 'Cause we're gonna hang?
- 'Yes.'
Don't you think murderers
ought to be hanged?
I don't believe in hanging.
Take it.
- You want a Bible, Jack?
- No. I want a smoke.
No, thank you, ma'am.
We're gonna die,
but we're not that desperate.
Mrs. Soffel, the warden says
to put him in.
Well, Jack, at least
I won't have to listen
to you snore tonight.
That's right.
Mrs. Soffel?
What kind of flower would you
say that is, right there?
I don't know.
Would you say that
that's a violet?
I think it's a violet,
don't you?
- Yes.
- I think so, too.
George said you met
the Biddles today.
- Don't you think Ed's handsome?
- Not especially.
'There's the supper bell,
finally.'
Margaret.
What is all this?
That's Ed. That's Jack.
And that's Ed's girl,
Jessie.
She's an actress.
This is a very pretty book
that your grandma gave you
and you were meant
to press flowers in it.
I'm making a record
of all the injustice
the Biddles have suffered.
They don't belong in prison.
They do
if they killed somebody.
Mama, Ed and Jack
are innocent.
It was their partner
who shot the grocer in the head.
A jury found them guilty,
sweetheart.
'And after considering
and asking..'
'Are you listening?'
'And asking the Lord
for guidance'
'the judge gave them
their sentence.'
But, mama, the Biddles committed
90 robberies in 90 days
and never hurt one citizen.
Doman's a dope addict.
'That's enough!'
Come on, Margaret.
Go to bed.
It's a wonder you don't have
nightmares, young lady.
Do you know that?
I do.
I dream about the boys.
Mm-hmm. Get into bed.
I'm afraid papa will
have a curse on his head
for hanging them.
Go on, go on, go on.
Let me tell you
one more thing.
No.
I want you to be quiet
and go to sleep.
They had to pick
the grocer's brain off the wall.
You've got one big imagination,
you know
that's going to get you
into a lot of trouble.
Yes, I'm afraid the devil is
winning the battle for my soul.
Then I think
you better say your prayers.
Through the river
and into the fire
little girls go
when they expire..
Father in heaven..
- Father in heaven..
- ...as night draws near..
- ...I beseech thee to hear..
...I beseech thee to hear
my humble prayer.
Keep me ever from doing wrong,
keep me..
Keep me safe, keep me strong.
And keep me a Christian
my whole life long.
- Amen.
- Goodnight.
Are you gonna go to sleep?
Alright.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
Goodnight.
Goodnight, Peter.
Kate.
I was just...wondering
now that you're feeling
better..
...you'll be continuing
to use your own room?
I think I better for now.
It was just a question.
Eh, left, left, left.
Farther apart, Johnny.
Two in a row?
That what you want to see?
- That what you're asking for?
- 'I'll give you a cigar.'
Watch now, brother.
'Come on, lads. Push up.'
Stevens!
Six.
'Just take two
out of the cart, Agnes.'
'I think that's all
we'll need for now.'
- 'Alright..'
- Thank you.
How about a blanket, Mr. Biddle?
The cold's getting fierce now.
Thank you, ma'am.
Mr. Biddle?
I'll just, just leave it here,
for you. Ready, Agnes?
Why don't you peddle that
to somebody stupid enough
to believe it?
What did you give it
to me for, anyway?
I would've thought
God's word might have been
some comfort to you,
but I see I was wrong.
'"And behold a pale horse..'
"...and his name
that sat on him was Death.
"And hell followed with him.
'"And they were given power
over the Earth to kill..
'"...with sword,
and with hunger'
'and with death."'
That sounded pretty good, Ed.
Maybe you should've
been a preacher.
Did you mean to put the fear
of God in me, ma'am?
No. No and I wouldn't have
suggested starting
with the Revelation,
I usually recommend
something more soothing
for the prisoners.
'Do you?'
Yes, I do.
'There's a very lovely section
in Luke.'
Will you read it to me?
Yes.
Umm..
'"Blessed are ye
that hunger now'
'"for ye shall be filled.'
'"Blessed are ye
that weep now'
'for ye shall laugh."'
'This is..'
'This is one
of my favorite parts.'
'"Blessed are ye..'
"...when men shall hate you..
'"...and when they shall
separate you'
'"from their company..'
'"...and reproach you..'
'...and cast out your name
as evil."'
'Don't people treat you and your
brother like that, Mr. Biddle?'
- Leave me out of it.
- 'Mrs. Soffel?'
'It's nearly my dinner hour.'
'Why don't you run along,
Agnes.'
'I'll be right there.'
'"Rejoice ye in that day,
and leap for joy'
for, behold, your reward
is great in heaven."
'What's my reward?'
Your heavenly reward.
You mean, God makes you
miserable in this life
so he can make you happy
in the next?
- Is that it?
- No. No.
I think it means, I think
it means that when you suffer
don't give up hope.
- Hope to go to heaven?
- 'Yes.'
Can you see me up there,
floating around
on a cloud, playing my harp
for the all saints?
- You wanna go to heaven, Jack?
- I don't know.
You know anybody
who's been there?
'No, I, I picture heaven..'
I picture heaven
as a place of peace.
Death would be peace.
'No, death is nothing.'
Why would God give us
this short life
with all of its troubles and not
give us a better one afterwards?
- ''Cause he doesn't care.'
- God cares.
God cares even for you.
Even for a dirty killer like me?
That isn't what I meant.
Do you think I'm a killer,
Mrs. Soffel?
Are you, Mr. Biddle?
Ed.
Are you a killer?
In my heart..
...I am.
'I want nothing more
than to send the filthy liar'
'that put us in here,
to his heaven.'
So I suppose
I am a murderer..
...in my heart.
'Ain't l, Kate?'
If you truly want
to commit murder...then, yes..
'...I think you are a murderer
in your heart.'
Then I guess
I'm not worth saving.
'Mrs. Soffel?'
I'm not.
I'm not, I'm not a murderer.
Quiet!
So they come up here
to put out the fire.
Then we grab them,
and we get their keys.
What if..
What if they don't come, huh?
I mean, what if they
just let us burn?
What?
What are you writing now,
our wills?
Six.
Jack?
'Jack?'
What?
'Where would you be now..'
'...if you hadn't met up
with me and Walter?'
Oh, go to sleep.
'I told them you were
innocent.'
'And they believed Walter.'
'Didn't I try?'
Yeah, I know you did.
I can't die until
I make it up to you.
Stop talking about dying!
You're always talking like if..
Just go to sleep.
'I'm not gonna
let 'em hang you.'
'Believe me?'
'Little brother?'
- Ed.
- Well, do you believe me, Jack?
Sure.
Sure, I believe you.
- Mama?
- 'What is it, Irene?'
You left the heater
burning in the parlor.
I-I turned it down.
Thank you.
Did you just get home?
'Billy walked me
from fellowship meeting.'
Goodnight.
'Um, has Billy heard'
'from his school?'
Well, no, not yet.
But he's bound to get in.
It's turning into quite a
romance between the two of you.
It's not a romance,mama.
I plan to marry Billy.
Well, we all have a lot
of time to think about that.
He's giving me an engagement
ring for Christmas.
- 'Irene.'
- Papa knows.
Irene, you're barely 16.
'And you were 17
when you married papa.'
Goodnight, mama.
You shouldn't sit by
the window, you'll catch cold.
My goodness, Maggie, I think
it's nearly frozen stiff.
'I know, but it smells musty.
Lordy be.'
Let's take it indoors.
- Hope I didn't startle you.
- 'No.'
That's a pretty dress
you got on.
'Back, Mr. Biddle!'
You'll come and read
to me again, won't you?
I come to the prison
every Tuesday and Thursday.
Maggie, the rug beater.
Maggie.
'"You may ask why,
in spite of all hope'
'"do we maintain our
innocence?'
"Every intelligent mother
in Pittsburgh knows the reason.
Because it is true.
We would not..."
'Job's friends are arguing'
that if God has made
Job suffer so much
he must be guilty
of some great sin
because God doesn't
punish the innocent.
God punishes the innocent
all the time. Why is that, Kate?
- God means to test our love.
- By torturing us?
You don't have to tell me
that innocent people suffer.
I've been walking through this
prison for quite a few years...
- Oh, so you know all about it.
- I know enough.
You don't know
what it means to be in here.
'So don't pretend that you do.'
At any rate, nobody is
completely innocent.
'We all sin.'
God punishes you for
your sins, doesn't he, Kate?
I think you suffer.
'I don't come here to discuss'
'my sins with you.'
'There's a vision that I
have..'
'...of them..'
'...taking us out to hang.'
'And they take Jack up first..'
'...so I have to watch.'
That was a very good
letter you wrote.
'Ed?'
Maybe you'll hear
from the governor soon.
You'll make a prayer?
- 'Shall we do this again?'
- 'Do you like it?'
One, two, three, whoo!
- One, two and..
- Three!
- 'What happened, mama?'
- 'I don't know.'
Come on, everybody,
let's go around.
Clarence, stop that.
Please, come on.
Margaret, come on.
Let's hurry. Come on.
'Good news, boys.'
'You wrote this?'
'That's right.'
- Would you read it to me?
- 'Sure.'
Don't laugh.
"Just a little violet
"from across the way.
"Came to cheer a prisoner
"in his cell one day.
"Just a little flower
"sent by a loving hand.
"Has a kindly meaning
"that true hearts understand.
'"Just a little violet'
'"plucked with tender care.'
'"God has smiled upon it'
'"and the sender fair.'
'"And soon that little token'
"wrapped in hands so neat
"rests quietly within a grave
o'er which a heart
that's true does beat."
Why would you write
that for me?
What makes you think I did?
Take it. In exchange
for what you gave to me.
A man at the gazette gets
50 cents for one of those.
'What will your
lawyers do now, Ed?'
'They're through with us.'
- Sorry.
- 'What for?'
I think I should go now.
God didn't answer
your prayer, did he, Kate?
- My prayer?
- Well, didn't you pray for us?
Yes.
Well, then tell me
why does God want us
to die, Kate?
- Tell me the reason why.
- I can't do that.
Me and Jack, we're innocent.
We're innocent as snow.
- You know that.
- How can I know that?
Well because you know me
and I'm telling you, that's why.
- No! I have to go.
- You nearly had me saved.
- Let go of me, Ed!
- What are you doing?
- 'Let go!'
- 'What do you want from me?'
'What do you come
over here for?'
'I'll call the guard
if you don't let go of me!'
Give me your hand!
Press there!
There, you feel
how strong my neck is?
'Me and Jack, we aim
to break out of here.'
Damn you, Ed! You're crazy.
Are you gonna tell on us?
- Oh, God.
- God? God won't hear you.
You're not in church now.
I'm so-I'm sorry.
No.
You're our only friend
and I've hurt you.
No.
Guard?
Oh, dear father,
please forgive me.
Forgive me for being
such a terrible sinner.
I'm so ashamed, dear father.
Please help and guide me.
Give me the strength
to overcome these thoughts.
Oh, God, I know I'm weak.
Forgive me for..
- 'Maggie.'
- Ma'am.
- 'Mr. Kelly.'
- Good morning, ma'am.
Good morning.
She ain't been to see you
for five days, has she?
She won't tell on us,
I promise.
What do you think you're doing?
What..
"My husband and I are dedicated
to the reform of criminals.
"But capital punishment does
not allow reform or mercy
and no chance to right
a miscarriage of justice."
'My God, Kate! The governor?'
"I join other Christian men
and women in this great city
"in urging you to grant
the Biddles' case
a-a-an official review."
Have you lost your senses?
You didn't write it.
I did. I signed it.
Quite a few people
have written, Peter.
'They are not married
to the warden'
'of the Allegheny
County Prison!'
'Do you need
to see the doctor?'
No!
Because that's how
you're acting!
Do you want me to lose my job?
- 'Do you?'
- No.
Maybe you need a rest.
Perhaps mother
could come to visit.
Or you could go to her
or you could go
to your sister's.
Peter.
Do you think I'm unbalanced?
'Do you?'
Kate?
'Kate, if you won't go'
then I forbid you to visit
the prisoners...
Please, dear, not now!
You don't seem to be able to
separate your duties
from your sympathies...
It's not sympathy!
I think it's wrong!
That is not for you to decide!
Alright. Alright.
Write to Elsie or your
mother.
Wherever you wanna send me.
'Let's go in to supper.'
'Clarence.'
God is great, God is good
let us thank him
for our food. Amen.
- 'Amen.'
Good evening, Warden.
Going out tonight?
Yes.
Oh, no.
George!
- 'George!'
- What?
- Wait, just a second.
'We have to go to the Row!'
- 'Hurry, George!'
- Oh, Mrs. Soffel, please!
I could lose my job!
Please, George,
please hurry, there's a fire!
- What?
- There's a fire!
Wait..
Hurry!
'McGarey! There's a fire!'
Help! Fire! Fire!
Holy Christ!
Get him out!
'Help him!'
'Get him out!'
'Stop it! Help him, George!'
'Help him!'
- 'George, I can't..'
- Alright, alright.
'Get him out!'
Open that stupid door!
'Ed!'
Ed!
- You should've let me die.
- Hush, don't talk. Don't talk.
I thought you abandoned us.
You should've let me die.
I won't. I won't.
You trust her?
You trust me?
How's she gonna help us?
God will provide a way.
God? Now you believe in God?
'She does.'
'This is my damage report.'
'Check it over
and I'll sign it.'
And if anyone asks,
I was out, that's all.
I thought you were going
to Elsie's this morning.
It seems to me
if we're going to hang people
we can at least give God an
opportunity to save their souls.
I quite agree with you. That's
why we have a prison chaplain.
Go home, Kate.
Mr. McNeil..
All I did was read
to a few poor desperate men
and save your prison
from burning down.
'Is that so unreasonable?'
Alright.
But Mr. Biddle will have to
remain in solitary for a while.
If you and God don't object.
'"Believe to the saving
of the soul."'
'Now I'm going to read...
chapter XI.'
'Hebrews, chapter XI.'
'"Now faith is the substance'
'"of things hoped for.'
'The evidence
of things not seen."'
'Would somebody like
to read the next verse?'
'Alice, you read
the next verse.'
'"For by it the elders..'
- 'Uh, ob..'
- '"Obtained."'
'"Obtained a good report.'
'"Through faith we un..'
'Understand..'
'"Understand..'
'"...that the worlds
were framed'
"by the word of God.
"So that things which are seen
'"were not made
of things which.."'
My dear Kate
when the sun
came up this morning
I felt very good,
like a man reborn.
You are a living flower
filled with light..
...and I'm a dying one.
But you are willing
to share your light with me.
By now they have
put me in the hole.
But do not come.
We must be careful.
I knew a man in Ohio pen
who sawed through
the bars on his cell.
He held them in place
with candle wax..
...so no one knew.
Until he flew the coop.
Jack and me could do the same
if we had saws.
If you agree to this..
...hold your hand
over your heart
wherever you are
and pledge to do it.
Wherever I am,
I will hear your pledge.
Heaven shines on you, my Katie.
Your Ed.
They brought you out?
Gave me a bath.
- 'Are you alright?'
- Now I am.
I got what you wanted.
'I hope we can continue
our Bible lessons, boys.'
Yes, ma'am.
I'd like to start
with a selection
from first Corinthians
chapter XIII
verses one through four.
It's in my boots.
Come close.
Watch the door, Jack.
Read your Bible.
Um..
"Though I speak with the tongues
of men and angels
"and have not charity,
I am become as sounding brass
"or...a tinkling cymbal.
"And though I have the gift
of prophecy
"and understand all mysteries
'"and all knowledge,
and though I have all faith'
"so that I could remove
mountains
"and have not charity
I am nothing."
Clarence, wait.
Good. One.
No, no.
Yes.
- 'What are you doing?'
- Hey.
There's two oranges missing
from the larder. Eddie?
Clarence?
Clarence? Thank you very much.
'Thank you, Clarence.'
Let's start again at the
beginning, Margaret, alright?
Um, this, uh..
One, one and two.
One and two.
Sorry. One and two. Good.
'Good.'
"They shall cease,
whether there be knowledge
"it shall vanish away.
"And now abideth faith, hope..
'"And now abideth faith, hope,
charity, these three'
'but the greatest
of these is charity."'
Charity?
Love.
'One, two, three. Lights!'
'Come on down.'
Yeah, alright,
but you be very careful.
Let's slow it down.
Push the other way. That's it.
- Can I have a try, papa?
- I know, it scared you.
Well, it's a fast train,
isn't it?
- 'Can I try?'
- 'Yes, alright, in a minute.'
'Now not too fast
around the curves.'
A little more speed.
Attaboy!
- I want to play.
- Now, boys.
You're going to have
to share the train.
Clarence, let Eddie have a turn.
- Stop it.
- They're my controls!
Papa said I could have
the controls.
He gave it to me first.
Why don't we sit over here?
It came upon..
'Irene, may I see your ring?'
Show your cousin the ring,
my dear.
Oh. Here it is.
Isn't it beautiful?
- Isn't it a lovely stone?
- Billy chose it for me.
From angels bending
near the earth
To touch their harps of gold
Peace on the earth
good will to men
From heaven's all
gracious king
The world in solemn
stillness lay
To hear the angels sing
Still through..
Number three.
Ed?
'Ed?'
I told the warden that you two's
been so good
we should move you back
into your own cells
as soon as they'd been fixed.
'See?'
Old Jimmy's been
looking out for you.
We appreciate it.
- Ma'am.
- McGarey.
Good King Wenceslas looked out
on the feast of Stephen..
'You'll have to hide those
as soon as you can.'
'I will.'
Bye, Jack.
Thanks.
Ed?
I checked the schedule. There's
only two guards on duty tonight.
You better go.
Go on. Go, go.
- Bye.
- No, wait.
Ed, aren't you gonna ask her?
Ask her.
Ask me what?
Alright. Last night
we decided we need a gun.
- No. No guns.
- Ed, talk to her!
'I'm not going to bring
you a gun, Ed Biddle.'
Alright. Alright.
I'm asking you.
If you care anything for
me...
Oh, Ed, don't you think
I know why you flirt with me
and why you hold my hand?
You think you can sweet-talk
me into anything, don't you?
Well, I did, didn't I?
I want you to know something,
Ed Biddle
I'm not one of those schoolgirls
who's standin' outside
crying all over you.
Well, then why don't you
tell us? Goddammit!
- Why don't you call the guard?
- You think like this...
Guard! Goddamn it, God.
Call a guard!
Shut up!
'"Dear father..'
'"As they are about to leave
this world, father'
"grant them the courage
to face thy judgement.
"Help them to accept
thy love and forgiveness.
- Guide them to the kingdom."
- You're crazy, you know that?
'You act like nobody's
gonna get killed around here.'
Well, tomorrow
we could be dead. Not you,
Us.
- Come on, Jack, let go of her.
- You can both go to hell!
You think you know me, do
you?
- 'Give me the bar.'
- Do you think you know me?
- No.
- Shut up!
'Here's your dinner, boys.'
Come along, let's hurry.
It'll be very nice
to visit Aunt Elsie.
You can play with Jeannie
and I'll see you in a few days.
Eddie, I want you to let
Clarence sit next to you
in the cab, now give me a kiss.
Clarence, put your hat on.
Give me a kiss goodbye.
Bye. Buh-bye. Margaret,
I'll miss you. Bye-bye.
Irene, hurry up!
Aunt Elsie is waiting.
I'm going to the New Year's
dance with Billy tomorrow.
I'm not asking.
I am telling you to hurry.
Well, I want to ask papa.
Irene.
'Read all about it!
Biddles hang tomorrow.'
'Biddles hang tomorrow!'
I'm glad you sent
the children away for tomorrow.
- Elsie will have a houseful.
- Hmm-mm.
- How is it?
- Fine.
It's..
Quite fine.
- When will Maggie be back?
- In the morning.
Do you know
the other day a woman stopped me
in the street to tell me that
I was as good as a murderer.
As if I were
the judge, the jury
and the executioner,
all rolled up into one.
"I just do my duty, ma'am."
I said to her.
Whatever the courts
and the jail board
and the governor lay down,
you see
I have to carry out.
Oh, I know those boys
are guilty and deserve to
die.
Peter, do you think
we could go off someplace?
Away from the prison. I need
to get away for a month maybe.
- You, you and me?
- Yes, yes.
And we could leave the children
with Elsie.
And we'll go off
on our own someplace.
- I don't have any, I don't...
- Please, take me someplace.
Peter, Just for a month or maybe
a few weeks and I promise you.
When we come back
I'm going to be a good mother.
I'm going to be a good wife
and I'll never get sick again.
Peter, please.
Peter, please?
Kate, I know it's a hard
life
here. I know that.
- No, it's not that.
- But it is a good position.
We won't be here forever.
If you can just be patient.
- Hmm?
- Yes.
Yes, Peter.
'Help!'
'Guard!'
'Wait!'
'Hey, what are you,
what are you doing?'
'Stop fighting
and just give me your leg.'
- Quiet night?
- Mm-hmm.
- It's a pretty picture.
- Every man should have a hobby.
Jack!
- Get up, get up.
- 'Get him off me!'
He's heavy.
Come on, help me.
Push, push, push!
- No!
- You'll come with me.
Now is your chance.
You gotta go, Ed.
With you.
'Ed?'
Ed?
Ed, we've gotta go.
- Come on.
- No, I can't.
- Come with me.
- No, no.
'Ed, come on!'
Go, go.
Ed, no!
No.
Come with me.
Whoo!
Jessie, aren't you coming
to work today?
No, I'm not coming in today.
Just go ahead without me.
'Alright,
we'll see you tomorrow.'
I could use a map of some kind
to plan out where we're going.
We're in good shape.
Don't you worry.
How's she gonna travel with you?
Look at her. Look at her shoes.
'She's just gonna
hold you back.'
She's right, Ed.
Did we break out of prison
just to get caught?
'Lost your faith in me, Jack?'
- No.
- 'Cause that's how it sounds.
'Jack, you ought to go out on
your own and save yourself.'
What's the use
of getting killed over her...
Shut up, Jessie!
Thank you, sir.
We'll pay you back if we
can.
'I am proud to do it.'
'I wish I could help you
gentlemen out some more.'
I tried to see you in prison
and they wouldn't let me.
I would have done anything.
I'm sorry, Jess.
Put these on.
Maybe you should abandon me.
What?
The point was to get you free.
You and Jack.
You wanna go back?
I don't know.
Right about now my children
are gonna know that I'm gone.
If you want to go back,
I'll take you back.
- Whatever you want.
- Jessie is right.
How can you travel with me?
I'm so stupid.
Why'd you come with us
if you don't know?
'Look at her.
You're gonna go with her?'
Look at what she's done.
You know what she's done.
- No, I want my babies.
- Ed, let her go.
- Let me out!
- Babies? You want your babies?
Shut up.
Will you shut up? God.
I'm sorry.
- I'm so sorry.
- God!
Are we going or ain't we?
Excuse me!
'Excuse me, please.'
'Ed was vicious.'
'He clubbed me, how many times
was it, George?'
'Maybe 15, 20 times?'
'And I don't understand it.'
No, sir, I don't, I don't,
I can imagine..
Buck! Buck!
The Biddles can't stay caught.
Looks like you're
going after them a second time.
It'll be the last time,
believe me.
"Edward and John Biddle
"prisoners in the B range
of the Allegheny County Prison
"escaped this morning
at approximately 5:00 a.m.
"Apparently having sawed through
the bars of their cells
"and overtaking two guards,
who were not seriously hurt.
"At the moment,
there are no clues
"to the killers' whereabouts.
"Detective Buck McGovern,
who as you all know
"arrested the Biddles
last spring
"will head the search.
'A reward of $5000
is offered.'"
Has your wife been located,
warden?
Sir, what has she got
to do with it?
My wife, uh, Mrs. Soffel,
is missing at the moment.
'But we expect
to hear very soon'
'from her sister
in Mount Washington'
'where I suspect
she has joined her children.'
'She's starting to slow down.'
Yeah, we must be coming
into Perrysville.
If we get separated,
we'll have to meet there.
Yeah!
- Now, remember what I told you.
- Yes.
- What?
- Push out, away from the train.
I'll be right there
to catch you.
Come on.
Alright, Kate.
Alright, just a minute.
Alright, ma'am.
Now you've just gotta jump.
Come on.
Alright, Jack.
You go ahead. You go first.
Kate! Now, Kate!
Now! Now!
Kate!
'Now, ma'am.'
'Oh, mother of Christ!
Go ahead, jump. Go on.'
Jump!
Go ahead. Ready?
Attagirl!
Ed! Ed!
- Oh!
- Miss?
Oh, I'm sorry,
I thought you were my husband.
- Oh! Oh!
- It's me.
Scared her by accident.
My wife. My wife.
We just got married today.
'Oh! Well..
...it don't serve you to lose
your man the day you marry him.
New brides tend to be skittish.
You take care of her now.
'Yes, sir. You bet I will.'
Good luck,
and a happy New Year to you.
Thanks!
- Happy New Year.
Well, happy New Year!
Hey, Jack, would you care
to kiss the bride?
Jack!
For Christ's sake,
why don't you just go tell
the whole countryside
we're here?
Read this.
They're paying $5000
to the man who kills us.
We just won't let anyone collect
that reward, will we, Ed?
Oh!
Oh.
Better get those boots off.
Yeah!
'See if we could build
a little fire?'
'It's so cold.'
We've only been on the road
a couple of hours.
I saw a coal bin
out the back.
Think you could get some
coal?
Jack.
Jack, you listening to me?
Maybe you just ought to try
listening to me for a change!
What?
Don't you think
you better take that off?
I've worn it 18 years.
Come on!
Oh, my God!
"John and Edward Biddle
under the sentence of death
"escaped from the county jail
this morning
"under most sensational
circumstances.
"They're believed
to have been assisted
by the wife of Warden Peter,
Kate Soffel."
Oh, my God!
It's so exciting!
"With whom they made off
during the night.
"It is believed
Mrs. Soffel is now alone
"for criminals as desperate
as the Biddles
will certainly not burden
themselves with a woman."
'I hope Mama's not alone.
I hope she is with the
Biddles.'
No, you don't, Margaret.
Don't you know what this means
if she's with them?
She can never come home again.
Papa won't allow it.
Not if she's with
that Ed Biddle right now.
'That's not true!'
I hope they've killed mama.
I hope she's dead.
'Kate?'
I wasn't sure if it was going
to be you or the police.
Did you think I'd desert
you?
I wasn't sure.
I spent most of my life
in prison, Kate.
And, uh, sometimes, I just..
...forget how to act
with people.
Well, you're not
in prison now, Ed.
Coming with us?
Oh, Ed!
All aboard!
- Let's hurry.
- Hurry where?
- Yes, where?
- North, to Canada.
Giddyup!
Tickets.
'Tickets, please.'
Easy!
No!
He came out of nowhere!
Jack, you go
and hitch up the horses.
Ed, see if he's hurt.
Only be careful!
Sit down. Easy.
'How is he?'
I know you.
He's fine!
You go wait in the sledge
with Jack!
I'll be right there, Kate.
Go on!
You trailed us
from Perrysville, huh?
Yes, sir.
I borrowed a horse.
You know who I am?
Biddle.
You tell anyone you saw us?
- No, sir. Not a soul.
- Sure?
Yes, sir.
The Pittsburgh police, they..
God!
You can't ever beat it, can you?
'What?'
Nothing. I'm sorry.
- It's alright.
- You got a smoke?
Mind if I take one
for my brother?
- 'No.'
- Thank you.
You wanted to catch us?
For the money?
Well, money, and to be the man
who got the Biddles.
Look..
...I'm gonna knock you out.
'But don't make any noise
like you're hurt or nothing.'
'Don't make a sound,
do you understand?'
- Yes, sir.
- Alright.
Now don't worry.
I know what I'm doing.
- You out?
- Almost.
Hang on, I'll try again.
We're safe.
He didn't tell anybody
he saw us.
Let's go.
Giddyup there!
Bless and keep these men,
Father, in the righteousness
of their mission to hunt
down
the killers of innocent
men...
Amen, reverend! That's enough.
Get your guns and ammunition,
men!
- Sheriff Hoon!
- Aah, what do these women want?
They want to ride
with the posse
to make sure no one hurts
the Biddles.
You get out of here!
Get back home where you belong!
'Pardon me, sir.'
Oh, hello there. You lost?
Oh, no, sir. I'm traveling with
my wife and my brother here.
And, uh, if you could spare us
some blankets or some food
'I'll buy 'em from you.'
You better get that woman
in the house right away.
'Yes, sir.'
'You've got no business
taking your wife out'
on a day like today.
Well, we got relatives
expecting us up north now.
'Got an uncle in Erie.
He's awful sick.'
- 'Erie?'
- 'Yes, sir.'
'You've got a good piece of
travelling to get to Erie.'
About how far, sir?
Well, we're due west of Butler.
And I'd say it's 100 miles
from Butler to Erie.
Here she comes now!
- How you feeling?
- 'Better.'
Uh, it's beautiful here,
isn't it?
'But maybe we should hurry,
Ed.'
There's no rush.
'That dress fits, don't it?'
- 'You better keep it.'
- Oh, no. I couldn't, really.
'It belonged
to my oldest girl Charlotte'
when she was young.
Now she's had five babies
and she's big as a barn.
Keep it.
'And you're welcome to stay
as long as you're able.'
I, uh, put a fire
in the back bedroom upstairs.
You can go up there
and lie down.
'Have a rest.'
It's up to my brother.
Well, I suppose
we all could use a rest.
- Good!
- Thank you very much.
You're welcome, dear.
Thank you.
Thank you, John.
Ooh, uh, would you like
to read the paper?
Mr. Stevenson don't seem
to read no more.
Our grandnephew, Harry,
reads to him sometimes.
So you ain't read the news
the last couple of days?
'No. Harry ain't been over.'
- Oh, I'll read it to you.
- 'Would you?'
- Yeah.
- 'Oh, thanks!'
'How late is it?'
I don't know the time.
'Past noon?'
Possibly.
You know one thing I never did?
- That is smoke a pipe.
- 'Me neither.'
Maybe if I would had
some kind of regular life
I'd have smoked one.
- How does it look?
- Fine.
Well, maybe I'll smoke one
when we get our farm, huh?
Come keep me warm, Ed.
It's like
the snow's inside my skin.
You know something
I'd tell my children
if they ever felt scared?
- I am not scared.
- No, I know.
Of course you're not.
What would you tell your kids?
Mm? Something sweet, I bet.
I'd say..
Do you wanna hear it?
I'd say, "Look up at the
sky..
"...day or night, 'cause
in the sky you can see the sun.
"And at night, you can see
the moon and the stars.
"And these are God's eyes..
"...proof that
he's always above you.
Watching over you,
protecting you."
- And they'd believe that?
- I did.
I suppose God won't protect
me
anymore, will he, Ed?
'Cause of me?
No.
'Cause of me.
We'll protect each other,
alright?
Alright.
Put your hands on me, Ed.
I'm so cold.
...Ed.
Make my heart warm.
'I didn't see anybody
I didn't know only.'
You generally notice
when people come by the store?
'I certainly do.'
We're looking for two men
and a woman.
The two men in their mid
20s,
and the woman, 35...
'Oh-oh-oh, now-now-now,
wait-wait a minute now.'
'I think I did see them.'
- 'When was this?'
- 'Oh-oh, earlier this
morning.'
- 'Driving a sled?'
- 'Yeah, yeah, yeah, they was.'
'Could you tell
how old they were?'
'Well, the fellows
was all bundled up.'
'Pretty hard to tell.
She must've been, oh..'
'...oh, 30, 35 maybe.'
- 'Driving two horses?'
- 'Yeah, yeah, yeah. Cutters.'
'Did you see which direction
they were going?'
Kate?
All those things
they said I did.
'What?'
- Mu.. The murder.
- 'Ssh-ssh..'
What they're gonna hang me
and Jack for.
'No, Ed, don't talk.'
Kate?
How do you prove
you love someone?
Prove it?
If there was some way that
they could get you away from me.
- Uh..
- If they get us?
- Yeah.
- Will they?
There's one thing
that you have to know.
Jack never killed anybody.
That's why I have to die.
God abandoned us.
You said that.
Yes.
So if you'll forgive me..
...it'll be alright.
Ed.
I forgive you, Ed.
Don't you let them
take me alive, Ed.
Promise me.
Promise me, Ed.
I won't.
I won't. I promise I won't.
I won't let them
take you from me.
The police is out, aunt!
The police is out!
Harry, we had company
for dinner.
Mr. Wright and his brother
and his sweet wife.
Poor thing!
Aunt, that was the Biddles!
'What Biddles?'
The killers the police
are looking for.
'I bet you gave dinner
to the Biddles.'
They are here yet, Harry!
Still!
Oh!
Ssh.
You a Biddle?
The police is looking for
you.
Oh, Mr. Watson!
Call the officers back!
We gotta go.
Get me the Prospect police!
Yes, ma'am, the police!
My poor husband's
in that house with them.
You men take some guns
and go in after those boys!
You go yourself,
Mrs. Stevenson.
I ain't getting killed!
Here they come.
- Alright?
- Yeah.
Move! Get back!
Did you see that?
You better stand back!
We're two desperate fugitives,
and she's ruthless and insane.
There's nobody..
Sorry, mister, and thanks a lot.
Goodbye! And good luck
to you young folks!
- So long.
- Bye. Bye.
Hyah!
Bye!
Hyah! Giddyup!
I didn't hear no shot, Buck.
Turn them around, John.
- What? Back the way we came?
- Now.
Hey, Ed?
'Yeah.'
They got bears in Canada?
I don't know, I suppose they do.
Do they, Kate?
Oh, I imagine so.
- What about polar bears?
- Yes.
I'd give anything
to see a polar bear.
Ed. Ed!
Look over there!
Uh, heck, Ed, what do I do?
Just keep on driving, Jack.
'Giddyup, there!'
'Hyah! Hyah!'
'Hyah!'
Hyah! Huh!
Hyah! Hyah!
'Hyah! Hyah!'
Hyah!
Hyah! Hyah!
Ed! Oh, no. Ed.
Jesus!
Ed? Ed?
Tell me what to do, Kate.
I want you
to keep your promise, Ed.
I can't go back.
Ed, I want you to do it.
Do it, Ed.
You know I love you,
don't you, Kate?
- Yes.
- Yeah?
Say you love me.
Say you love me too.
- I do.
- Huh.
I love you.
I, I...I never meant
to hurt you, Kate.
Yes! Yes!
Hyah. Hyah!
Hyah!
Hyah-ah!
They're coming straight for us.
Hold 'em steady, John.
Hyah! Go! Go!
Hyah-ah!
Ed! Come on. Get up.
Get up.
Huh.
Turn those horses out!
'Hold your fire!'
Hold your fire!
Hold it!
'Hold it!'
Jack. Jack?
Ed?
I'm sorry.
'I'm sorry, Jack.'
Let me die.
Leave 'em be, Buck.
They can't hurt nobody no more.
Holy God in heaven!
It's the woman!
She's been shot,
but she's alive!
'There's someone here for you,
Mrs. Soffel.'
I don't wanna see
that preacher.
I don't need his prayers.
It's not the preacher.
Oh.
Papa doesn't know I'm here.
Billy brought me.
I look so awful.
Oh, Irene,
do you hate me?
Well, don't you have
a brush or..
They won't give me one.
I'm so dangerous.
Bill, Billy and I got married,
mama.
- Mm-hm.
- I wanted to tell you.
Oh.
'Your change.'
'Ice cream.'
'Ice cream!'
Oh, Becky, can I have some?
- There she is.
There she is.
Mrs. Soffel.
Good morning, Mrs. Soffel.
Let me introduce
the superintendent of prisons
Mr. Coates.
And the district attorney
Mr. Robinson.
You know, ma'am
you once ruined
an important program of mine.
'I had a pass to see
the Biddles hang last winter.'
'I was really
looking forward to it.'
I'm ready to go in now.
Well, at least
it's not as cold now.
Spring has come early this year.
Last year we had to wait
a long time for spring.
Remember?
No.
I was sick last spring.
Well..
...I hope you'll be comfortable
while you're here.
Agnes..
...thank you.
Just a little violet
from across the way
came to cheer a prisoner
in his cell one day.
Just a little flower
sent by a loving hand
has a kindly meaning
that true hearts understand.
Just a little flower
plucked with loving care.
God has smiled upon it
and the sender fair.
And soon that little token
wrapped in hands so neat
rests quietly within a grave
o'er which a heart
that's true...does beat.