HE'S MAKING NOISES.
I'M GOING
TO GO TAKE A LOOK.
HEY, BOBBY.
WHAT IS IT, SON?
ARE YOU HOT?
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
HONEY?
LET'S JUST COOL OFF,
OK?
THERE WE GO.
GET A LITTLE WATER.
[BREATHING HEAVILY,
WHIMPERING]
GOD...
MAKE HIM WELL.
HE'S HAD EVERYTHING.
MEASLES, MUMPS...
BUT THIS FEVER...
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S BAD.
PLEASE TAKE
CARE OF HIM.
I LOVE HIM SO MUCH.
THANK YOU.
♪ I GOT THE HORSE
RIGHT HERE ♪
♪ HIS NAME
IS PAUL REVERE ♪
♪ AND HERE'S A GUY
WHO SAYS ♪
♪ IF THE WEATHER'S
CLEAR ♪
♪ CAN DO ♪
♪ THIS GUY SAYS
THE HORSE CAN DO ♪
♪ IF HE SAYS
♪ CAN DO ♪
EVERYBODY WANTS HELP.
OH, WELL...
I HOPE HE ISN'T GONNA BE
ANOTHER DISAPPOINTMENT.
HEY, MIKEY.
HOLD THE ELEVATOR!
YOU ARE TOO YOUNG
TO BE RETIRED.
IT'S NOT HEALTHY.
YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY
RIGHT.
BYE, DARLING.
Woman: HI, IT'S ME.
I'M JUST CALLING
ABOUT DINNER PLANS.
I'M AT THE OFFICE.
BYE.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
EXCUSE ME.
WENDY SHELTON.
CAN YOU TALK?
NOT RIGHT NOW.
I HAVE PEOPLE.
CAN'T TAKE NO MORE.
STUCK HIS HAND
UP THE TEACHER'S DRESS.
AREN'T YOU SUPPOSED
TO BE AT CHARLIE GRAY'S?
I WAS LOOKIN'
FOR SOMETHIN'.
I KNOW THEY'RE GOING
TO LIKE YOUR MUSIC.
HIS FATHER
WAS THE SAME WAY.
CALL ME WHEN
YOU KNOW SOMETHING.
GREAT.
I LOVE YOU, TOO.
BYE.
YOUR HUSBAND
A BUM, TOO?
HE'S A SONGWRITER
AND MUSICIAN.
THEY'RE ALL MUSICIANS,
AIN'T THEY?
[PIANO]
[PLAYING PRETTY SONG]
LET THIS BE THE ONE.
PLEASE, LET THIS
BE MY BREAK.
THE WORST IN 15 YEARS.
ABSOLUTELY.
YEAH, GOOD LUCK
TO YOU, TOO.
WHAT?
ROOM 211 WANTS
TO CHECK OUT.
TOMORROW MORNING,
IF IT CLEARS.
NOW. HE INSISTS.
HE'S AN OLDER
GENTLEMAN.
TELL HIM IT'S
OUT OF THE QUESTION!
NOBODY LEAVES
THE BUILDING.
I TOLD HIM. HE WANTS
HIS BILL DRAWN UP.
ABSOLUTELY NOT!
COULD YOU
TALK TO HIM, DAVE?
I HAVEN'T GOT TIME
FOR THIS NONSENSE!
THIS GUY'S
A WEIRDO, DAVE.
ALL RIGHT.
AND DON'T CALL ME DAVE!
WHAT'S
THIS IDIOT'S NAME?
HARRY TOPHET.
TOPHET.
MR. TOPHET!
MR. TOPHET,
THIS IS THE MANAGER!
COME ON IN!
NICE WEATHER, HUH?
MR. TOPHET...
I'LL NEED MY CAR.
I TOLD HIM
COPS WERE--
MR. TOPHET--
ALL COPS COULD
USE AN EXTRA $20.
SIX PEOPLE HAVE ALREADY
DIED IN THIS STORM!
GOOD, GOOD, GOOD.
I DON'T WANT TO BE
RESPONSIBLE FOR ANOTHER!
I'M GOING TO INSIST THAT
YOU REMAIN IN THIS HOTEL!
YOU'RE NOT
INSISTING ANYTHING.
WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
GET MR. TOPHET'S CAR.
GET HIS CAR!
I LOVE TO SCARE
THE HELL OUT OF PEOPLE.
[CHUCKLING]
I'D LIKE
TO SPEAK TO ARNIE.
YEAH,
THIS IS CHARLIE.
LET ME TELL YOU
WHY I CALLED!
YOU GUESSED?
YOU'RE A MIND READER!
HE GUESSED.
HE MUST BE
A MIND READER.
YOU LISTENED TO IT?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
SURE.
BE HONEST WITH ME.
YOU HATED THE TAPE, HUH?
NO, LISTEN, WHY BEAT AROUND
THE BUSH, RIGHT?
CHRIST!
YOU THOUGHT THE LYRICS
WERE TOO HIGHBROW?
TOO HIGHBROW FOR HIM,
THAT JERK!
PLEASE BE QUIET!
THERE I DISAGREE
WITH YOU.
HE HAS A GOOD VOICE!
NOT GREAT.
I HAVE TO LISTEN
TO THIS?
IF YOU DON'T WANT IT,
YOU DON'T WANT IT.
WE GO BACK
A LONG WAY, RIGHT?
SIX MONTHS.
I RESPECT YOU.
YOU RESPECT--
YOU GOT ANOTHER CALL?
RIGHT. BEAUTIFUL.
HE HATES IT.
HE SAID HE WOULDN'T
PLAY IT FOR HIS DOG.
YOU EVER HEAR THAT
BEFORE?
THAT'S A NEW ONE
ON ME, CHARLIE.
UNBELIEVABLE.
BOBBY...
LET ME TELL YOU
SOMETHING
AS A MANAGER
AND PERSONAL FRIEND.
YOUR CAREER DOESN'T
SEEM TO BE TAKING OFF.
I'M AWARE!
LISTEN TO ME.
YOU'RE PUSHING 30.
I'M PUSHING 50
WITH TWO KIDS IN COLLEGE
AND 10% OF YOUR INCOME
WHICH, OVER THE PAST YEAR,
HAS AVERAGED--
273 BUCKS A MONTH.
UH-UH, $272.60.
WHICH MEANS
I GET $27.26 A MONTH.
BOBBY, I KNOW I PROMISED
NOT TO ASK YOU THIS AGAIN.
WHAT?
THIS IS
A BEAUTIFUL GIG.
DO THIS FOR ME, PLEASE!
WHAT, CHARLIE?
IT'S A WEDDING
IN BRENTWOOD.
A NEUROSURGEON, BOBBY.
IT PAYS $500.
IT WAS
DANNY STEIN'S GIG,
BUT HE GOT BUSTED
LAST WEEK.
500 BUCKS?
YOU'LL DO IT?
YEAH, WHAT THE HELL?
YOU ARE DOING
100% THE RIGHT THING!
WHAT?! WHAT?!
YEAH, YEAH. SURE.
I JUST NEVER THOUGHT
THINGS WOULD
TURN OUT LIKE THIS!
THERE AREN'T MANY STARS
IN THIS BUSINESS.
IT'S ENOUGH
TO MAKE A LIVING.
THINK ABOUT THAT.
IT JUST HURTS.
I'D SELL MY SOUL
TO THE DEVIL
TO MAKE IT
IN THIS BUSINESS,
JUST FOR THE CHANCE.
♪ THAT OLD BLACK MAGIC ♪
♪ HAS ME IN ITS SPELL ♪
♪ THAT I WEAVE SO WELL ♪
♪ THOSE ICY FINGERS
UP AND DOWN YOUR SPINE ♪
♪ THE SAME OLD WITCHCRAFT ♪
♪ WHEN YOUR EYES MEET MINE ♪
UH-UH. THE COMPUTER'S
ON THE BLINK AGAIN.
I'VE HAD
THIS GUY FOR YEARS.
HIM, TOO.
LOOK AT THAT FACE.
WHAT A PUSSYCAT.
I'D SELL MY SOUL
TO THE DEVIL
TO MAKE IT
IN THIS BUSINESS.
INTERESTING.
SORRY, PAL.
HE ASKED FOR ME.
THAT'S THE RULES.
HE ASKS FOR ME,
HE'S MINE.
AND NONE OF
YOUR TRICKS EITHER.
I CAN'T DISCUSS IT.
IT'S ONE
LOUSY WEDDING.
I'LL MEET YOU LATER
FOR DINNER.
I'M PUSHING 30.
I SHOULD GO
TO LAW SCHOOL.
YOU'RE A MUSICIAN.
I'M NOT ANYTHING.
YOU MARRIED A LEMON.
I MARRIED A PEACH.
DON'T HUMOR ME.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
FORGET ABOUT IT.
THE MACHINE'S ON.
[RING]
YOU HAVEN'T EVEN
TASTED YOUR WINE.
JOSE AT THE LIQUOR STORE
SAID IT WAS GOOD.
HAWAIIAN CHABLIS?
I JUST NEVER SAW WINE
WITH AN EXPIRATION DATE BEFORE.
SO...
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
HOW MUCH WAS
THAT WINE?
WITH TAX, $1.89.
YOU WERE ROBBED.
WHAT WOULD
I DO WITHOUT YOU?
YOU'D DIE.
THINGS ARE GOING
TO GET BETTER.
YOU STILL HAVE FAITH
AFTER FIVE YEARS?
NO MORE SELF-PITY.
I'VE GOT TO PLAY.
GO ON. I'LL GET
YOUR COAT.
I'LL CHECK
THE MACHINE.
[REWINDING]
[ORCHESTRA
AND ORGAN MUSIC PLAYS]
[SOUND OF THUNDER]
WHO CALLED?
LISTEN TO THIS!
TO WHAT?
JUST LISTEN!
[DIAL TONE]
[CLICK]
LISTEN TO WHAT?
I HEARD MUSIC.
UH-HUH. HONEY...
HURRY UP.
YOU'LL BE LATE
FOR THIS GIG.
HERE'S YOUR JACKET.
YOU LOOK GORGEOUS.
BUT I HEARD--
THAT'S OK.
LET ME SEE IT.
FINE.
UH--
[BAND PLAYS
THE HOKEY POKEY]
♪ THAT'S WHAT
IT'S ALL ABOUT ♪
♪ YOU PUT YOUR
RIGHT FOOT IN ♪
RIGHT FOOT OUT ♪
♪ YOU PUT YOUR
RIGHT FOOT IN ♪
♪ AND YOU SHAKE
IT ALL ABOUT ♪
♪ YOU DO THE HOKEY POKEY ♪
♪ AND YOU TURN
YOURSELF AROUND ♪
♪ THAT'S WHAT
IT'S ALL ABOUT ♪
♪ YOU PUT
YOUR LEFT FOOT... ♪
KLUTZES,
KEEP THE BEAT!
WHAT IS THIS?
A GOLDEN
WEDDING ANNIVERSARY?
♪ YOU DO THE HOKEY POKEY ♪
♪ AND YOU TURN
YOURSELF AROUND ♪
♪ THAT'S WHAT
IT'S ALL ABOUT ♪
HIP!
♪ YOU PUT YOUR
RIGHT HIP IN ♪
RIGHT HIP OUT ♪
♪ YOUR PUT YOUR
RIGHT HIP IN ♪
♪ AND YOU SHAKE
IT ALL ABOUT ♪
♪ YOU DO THE HOKEY POKEY ♪
♪ AND YOU TURN
YOURSELF AROUND ♪
♪ THAT'S WHAT
IT'S ALL ABOUT ♪
♪ YOU PUT YOUR
LEFT HIP IN ♪
LEFT HIP OUT ♪
♪ YOU PUT YOUR
LEFT HIP IN ♪
♪ AND THEN YOU
SHAKE IT ALL ABOUT... ♪
YOU DANCE LIKE
MY LATE HUSBAND.
IRVING?
YOU KNEW IRVING?
SURE. HE BOUGHT OUT
HIS PARTNER IN 1960
BY TELLING HIM
THEY WERE GOING UNDER.
QUIET!
RIGHT AFTER
GETTING A BIG ORDER
BY BRIBING THE BUYER.
OH, MY GOD!
IRVING'S ONE
OF MY BEST WORKERS.
♪ THAT'S WHAT
IT'S ALL ABOUT ♪
THANK YOU.
I AM INFORMED THAT
YOUR ESCARGOTS ARE SERVED.
SO BON APPETIT.
WE'LL BE BACK,
AND REMEMBER--
WHATEVER YOU CAN'T EAT,
I TAKE HOME.
YOU KNOW WHAT ELSE
IRVING DID?
WHAT?
HE HAD THIS DAME
IN ALTOONA--
WILL YOU SHUT UP?
YOU MISERABLE OLD FART.
I LOVE ESCARGOT,
DON'T YOU?
OOH!
IT'S THE LITTLE
THINGS I ENJOY.
WANT THIS?
HOW ABOUT YOU?
EECH!
WANT TO
TAKE THIS HOME?
ARE YOU KIDDING?
SMART BOY.
EXCUSE ME.
I DON'T WANT TO DISTURB YOU.
YOU'RE PROBABLY BUSY.
THAT'S OK.
YOU HAVE A REQUEST?
I'D LIKE TO
SPEAK WITH YOU FOR A MOMENT.
YEAH, SURE.
WHY NOT?
I'M NOT
DISTURBING YOU?
NO, NO. NOT AT ALL.
GOOD.
MR. TOPHET?
TOPHET.
CALL ME HARRY.
HARRY.
I HAVE AN AGENT.
IS HE ANY GOOD?
WELL, THAT'S HARD
TO SAY, REALLY.
NO, IT'S EASY TO SAY.
IS HE ANY GOOD?
THINGS HAVEN'T
BEEN GREAT.
CHARLIE GRAY,
RIGHT?
HOW'D YOU KNOW?
HE'S. PATHETIC.
YOU DESERVE BETTER.
LIKE YOU, RIGHT?
LIKE ME.
IF I WERE RUNNING THINGS,
YOU WOULDN'T BE PLAYING
THESE CRUMMY WEDDINGS.
YOU'D PLAY
CARNEGIE HALL,
MADISON SQUARE GARDEN,
THE ORANGE BOWL.
YOU AT THE PIANO
IN THE ORANGE BOWL,
WITH 80,000 SUNTANNED GIRLS
SCREAMING YOUR NAME,
SLIDING OUT OF THEIR PANTS.
EVERYBODY WOULD BE
HUMMING YOUR SONGS.
IT WOULD BE PLAYED
AT AIRPORTS, IN ELEVATORS.
FABULOUS.
YOU'D BE RICH--
A HOUSEHOLD WORD.
UH, MR. TOPHET--
YOU COULD AFFORD
TO HAVE THAT BABY.
I GET INVOLVED
IN ALL PHASES
OF MY CLIENTS' LIVES.
THAT'S WHY I'M THE BEST.
WHO DO YOU REPRESENT,
IF YOU'RE SO TERRIFIC?
ALL THE BIG NAMES.
THEY ALL COME TO ME,
SOONER OR LATER.
TOPHET. TOPHET.
I READ THE TRADES,
AND I--
I KEEP MY NAME
OUT OF THE PAPERS.
I'M MORE EFFECTIVE
THAT WAY.
IS IT A DEAL?
A DEAL?!
I DON'T KNOW YOU.
I CAN'T JUST
DROP MY AGENT.
I CAN MAKE THINGS HAPPEN.
AMAZING THINGS.
SEE THAT WAITER?
YEAH.
WATCH THIS.
HOW DID YOU KNOW THAT--
HARRY?
MR. TOPHET?
NOT BAD, HUH?
YOU'LL BE
HEARING FROM ME.
MR. TOPHET?
I'M FLIPPING OUT.
SHE'S WAITING FOR YOU.
THERE YOU GO.
THANKS.
IF YOU'D
BEEN THERE--
HAVE YOU DECIDED?
WHAT'S GOOD TONIGHT?
OSSOBUCO.
VERY SPECIAL TONIGHT.
I MADE IT MYSELF.
I'LL HAVE IT.
SPAGHETTI
AND SAUSAGE.
YOU ALWAYS
GET THAT.
WHENEVER I DON'T,
I HATE MYSELF.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
LET'S SPLURGE.
A BOTTLE OF BAROLO.
YOU GOT IT.
AH, TABLE NUMBER 10...
WHAT ABOUT THIS GUY?
IT WAS STRANGE--
MY COUSIN'S IN NOVELTIES.
HE MAKES TRICK CARDS.
THIS CARD ANSWERED ME.
HE CAN MAKE
ANY KIND OF CARD.
CAN HE MAKE WAITERS
LOSE THEIR PANTS?
WAITRESSES.
HE'S BEEN DIVORCED TWICE.
THIS GUY REALLY
SPOOKED ME.
MAYBE HE PAID THE WAITER.
AND WRECK THE PLACE?
WHY GO TO THE TROUBLE?
BECAUSE HE WANTS
TO REPRESENT YOU.
THAT'S THE PART
I CAN'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU AMAZE ME.
SOMEBODY FINALLY
APPRECIATES YOU.
YOUR ENTIRE REACTION
IS ONE OF SUSPICION.
IT'S JUST CREEPY.
BELIEVE ME,
IF YOU'D BEEN THERE...
TRY THIS GUY.
IT WOULDN'T HURT.
I'M FADING.
SEE YOU
IN THE MORNING.
YEAH.
GOOD NIGHT.
WENDY?
IT'D BE NICE IF
THINGS COULD CHANGE.
MM-HMM.
YOU COULD
STOP WORKING.
MM-HMM.
YOU COULD START
DOING THE LAUNDRY.
WE COULD
HIRE A MAID.
MMMM.
I COULD HAVE
AN AFFAIR WITH HER.
I COULD LEAVE YOU.
NO, YOU WOULDN'T.
WHAT ABOUT THE BABY?
WHAT BABY?
♪ I LOVE YOU, LOVE YOU,
LOVE YOU, I DO ♪
♪ YOU'RE THE ONLY GIRL
THAT I ADORE ♪
♪ I LOVE YOU, LOVE YOU,
LOVE YOU, I DO ♪
♪ AND EVERY DAY I LOVE YOU
MORE AND MORE-- ♪
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
♪ SOMEDAY ♪
♪ I MAY ♪
WONDERFUL.
THANK YOU!
THANK YOU,
CLEVELAND!
GOOD NIGHT!
I LOVE YOU!
MORE! MORE! MORE! MORE!
NO MORE.
GOOD NIGHT!
I LOVE YOU!
THANK YOU!
WHAT ARE
YOU DOING?
NO MORE.
YOU DIDN'T
FINISH!
I SAID, &quot;NO MORE!&quot;
NOBODY COMES IN.
OK.
GET THEM OUT
OF HERE.
LET'S GO, GIRLS.
MR. WAYNE'S
EMOTIONALLY SPENT.
COME ON. LET'S GO.
COME ON, MOVE.
MOVE, MOVE, MOVE, MOVE!
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
[RING]
TONIGHT'S THE NIGHT.
I'M SORRY.
I WANT AN EXTENSION.
NO. SEVEN YEARS
WAS THE DEAL.
I GOT A TOUR
TO FINISH.
A DEAL'S A DEAL.
IT'S FINISHED.
SO NOW WHAT HAPPENS
TO ME?
IT WILL BE PAINLESS.
DON'T WORRY.
YOU'LL NEVER REMEMBER
YOU WERE BILLY WAYNE.
BUT I WANT TO REMEMBER.
LISTEN TO ME!
YOU CAN'T DO THIS!
I'M BILLY WAY--
THINGS HAVE A WAY
OF WORKING OUT.
MAY I HELP YOU?
CHARLES GRAY AND
BOBBY SHELTON
TO SEE
GARY FRANTZ.
WON'T YOU
BE SEATED?
THAT'S VERY
THOUGHTFUL.
BOBBY?
I THOUGHT THESE GUYS
TURNED US DOWN.
THEY DID. TWICE.
AND NOW THEY'RE
INTERESTED?
I DON'T KNOW. I JUST
GOT THIS CALL OUT OF THE BLUE.
THEY SAID IT WAS URGENT.
WE BOTH HATE THE TAPE.
WHY ARE WE SEEING HIM?
ONE CUT WILL BE SENSATIONAL
FOR RICHIE MORRISON.
RICHIE WRITES
HIS OWN STUFF.
I BUY IT.
WE MAKE IT RICHIE'S.
RICHIE
CHANGES A FEW WORDS.
THAT'S NOT NICE.
WHO IS TALKING NICE?
IF HIS
MANAGER'S SMART--
HIS MANAGER
IS CHARLIE GRAY.
YOU'RE KIDDING.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
I KNOW
BOTH THESE GUYS.
THEY RESPECT ME
TREMENDOUSLY.
YOU KNOW WHY?
NO, WHY?
BECAUSE
I'M NOT A PIG.
I PLAY FAIR.
I COULD DEMAND
LOTS OF MONEY.
WHAT'S THE POINT?
YOU NEED
REALISTIC GOALS.
Tophet:
I'M WITH MR. SHELTON.
HE'S OVER
THERE, SIR.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
HI.
HELLO.
YOU'RE
CHARLIE GRAY.
YES, I AM.
EXCUSE ME.
BOBBY,
IT'S YOUR CHOICE.
STAY WITH THIS LOSER
AND BE A NOBODY
OR COME WITH ME
AND BE A SOMEBODY.
WHO'S THIS GUY?
HE'S GOTTEN YOU NOTHING
BUT WEDDINGS AND MITZVAHS.
I'LL GET
WHAT YOU DESERVE--
CONCERTS, GOLD RECORDS,
THE COVER OF TIME.
BOBBY,
THIS IS YOUR LAST CHANCE.
BELIEVE ME.
EXCUSE US, PLEASE.
WHAT IS THIS?
WE'VE BEEN TOGETHER
FOR A LONG TIME.
WE'RE NOT
REALLY MAKING IT.
I'M GONNA GIVE
THIS GUY A TRY.
IT COULD BE
MY LAST CHANCE.
[INTERCOM BUZZES]
HELLO.
YEAH.
GENTLEMEN,
YOU CAN GO IN NOW.
YOU DID RIGHT.
I'M PROUD OF YOU.
BOBBY.
GARY FRANTZ.
GREAT OF YOU
TO COME.
MEET JOE ORTIZ
FROM OUR A&amp;R
DEPARTMENT.
THIS IS MR. TOPHET.
WHERE IS
CHARLIE GRAY?
I REPRESENT HIM.
MY NAME IS
HARRY TOPHET.
HARRY TOPHET?
I SEE. NICE TO
MEET YOU, SIR.
SHOULD I SPEAK
LOUDER?
NOT UNLESS YOU CAN'T HEAR
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
GREAT.
I'M FUNNY.
TOPHET, TOPHET,
TOPHET...
DIDN'T YOU
HANDLE AL JOLSON?
BEETHOVEN.
BEETHOVEN!
I LOVE IT.
ISN'T HE
SOMETHING?
COME ON. SIT.
HEY. ARE YOU OK?
OK. WHO
WANTS COFFEE?
NO. NO THANKS.
NO? HARRY?
I DON'T DRINK COFFEE.
SOME TEA, MAYBE?
LET'S STOP BULLSHITTING
AND GET DOWN TO BUSINESS.
OH, BEAUTIFUL.
OK, OK.
I'LL BE TOTALLY
UP-FRONT WITH YOU.
IN THE MUSIC
BUSINESS,
THERE ARE PUSSYCATS
AND LOTS OF COBRAS.
WE'VE MET ALL TYPES.
CAN I BE COMPLETELY
HONEST WITH YOU?
FINE.
OK, BOB,
HERE'S THE THING.
WE LISTENED TO
THIS TAPE--
WHAT--FIVE TIMES?
AT LEAST.
YOU NEVER HEARD
THIS KID'S TAPE--
NOT FIVE TIMES,
NOT ONCE.
SAY AGAIN.
YOU HEARD
BOBBY SHELTON.
THIS KID
IS BILLY WAYNE.
HARRY!
SHH!
WHAT?
HERE'S THE DEAL
I'M PROPOSING.
YOU'LL FIND IT FAIR.
WAIT, WAIT,
WAIT. WHAT DEAL?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU'RE PROPOSING
A DEAL?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THIS IS IT.
THIS IS WHAT?
SHH.
IS THIS A GAG?
3.5 MILLION
FOR TWO ALBUMS?
YOU SON OF A BITCH!
HUMILIATING ME!
SIGN THIS,
AND THEY'LL STOP LAUGHING.
AND THE WORLD IS YOURS.
WHOA! &quot;24-HOUR
LIMOUSINE SERVICE
&quot;TO BE PROVIDED
YEAR-ROUND
FOR THE ARTIST
AND HIS ENTOURAGE.&quot;
[BOTH LAUGHING]
HARRY,
I'VE HEARD OF COJONES,
BUT THIS IS TOO MUCH!
YOU'RE CRAZY!
IF I'M CRAZY,
THE DEAL IS VOID.
TRUST ME.
MAKE ME YOUR MANAGER.
&quot;A MILLION DOLLAR
BONUS
FOR EACH
GOLD RECORD.&quot;
HOW LONG IS THIS FOR?
FIRM SEVEN-YEAR
CONTRACT.
NO OPTIONS.
[THUNDER]
[ORGAN MUSIC]
[MEN LAUGHING
IN BACKGROUND]
I DON'T KNOW.
OK, I'LL LEAVE IT OPEN.
LET'S MAKE IT
A TRIAL PERIOD.
DO IT.
[LAUGHING STOPS]
GENTLEMEN, YOU'VE
GOT YOURSELVES A DEAL.
WE GOT BILLY WAYNE!
CONGRATULATIONS!
I'M THRILLED!
WELCOME TO OUR
HAPPY FAMILY.
BILLY WAYNE
ON ASTRAL.
IF ONLY MY MOTHER
WERE ALIVE--
JOE, WILL YOU
CALL PUBLICITY? NOW.
I AM SO THRILLED.
I CAN'T--
SEND OUT A RELEASE.
WE GOT AWAY CHEAP.
NEXT TIME,
I'LL MAKE IT EXPENSIVE.
DO YOU
HEAR THAT?
I LOVE THIS GUY!
BILLY WAYNE ON ASTRAL.
TWO-ALBUM DEAL.
PRESS CONFERENCE?
LET ME TALK TO HER.
SANDY.
LET'S GO.
I'LL CALL MY WIFE.
WE'VE GOT A PLANE
TO CATCH.
WAIT A MINUTE.
WHO ARE YOU?
MY GOD!
GUESS AGAIN.
HI, BOBBY.
YOU'RE HOME.
HI.
WHAT HAPPENED
AT THE MEETING?
NOTHING MUCH.
THOUGHT I'D
BARBECUE SOME CHICKEN.
WHAT HAPPENED
AT THE MEETING?
IT WAS A LOT OF CRAP.
THEY WEREN'T INTERESTED.
ONE SONG THEY WANTED
TO RIP OFF.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
MANY UNHAPPY PEOPLE
AND MISERABLE CHILDREN.
NOTHING NEW.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
HELLO.
[VOICE DISTORTED]
HI, WENDY.
SOMETHING REALLY WEIRD
HAS HAPPENED.
I'M IN BUFFALO!
WHO IS THIS?
IT'S BOBBY!
YOU WANT BOBBY?
NO. THIS IS BOBBY.
WELL,
HE'S RIGHT HERE.
IT'S FOR YOU.
HELLO?
HELLO.
YES?
WHO IS THIS?
THIS IS
BOBBY SHELTON.
WHO IS THIS?
HELLO.
HELLO!
I TOLD YOU
NOT TO CALL.
WHAT THE HELL
HAVE YOU DONE?
WHO IS THAT?
HE'S YOU.
HE'S NOT ME. I'M ME.
YOU'RE BILLY WAYNE.
WHO IS THAT GUY?
NOBODY SPECIAL.
WE MADE A DEAL.
NOW HE'S YOU.
HE THINKS HE'S ME?
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND WENDY
ACCEPTS HIM?
COMPLETELY.
HE'S YOU.
WHO WOULD WANT
TO BE ME?
WHAT DOES HE GET?
WENDY.
COME ON.
RELAX. RELAX.
THE THEATER'S
SOLD OUT.
YOU'RE POPULAR
IN BUFFALO.
BUFFALO?
BEST I COULD DO
ON SHORT NOTICE.
MY HEAD
IS KILLING ME.
OH, I'M SORRY.
IT IS
A BIG ADJUSTMENT.
HERE, LET ME SEE
WHAT I CAN DO.
[CRACK]
AH!
HOW'S THAT?
THAT FEELS
BETTER.
THANK YOU.
PEOPLE THINK,
BECAUSE I'M THE DEVIL,
I'M INSENSITIVE.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
SOON YOU'LL LOVE
YOUR NEW LIFE.
WHAT IF I WANT
THE OLD ONE BACK?
A DEAL'S A DEAL.
YOU SAID THIS WAS
A TRIAL PERIOD.
I LIED.
YOU WANT ANYTHING,
I'M IN 666.
WAIT A MINUTE.
ONE MORE QUESTION.
OK, SHOOT.
WHY DO I STILL
THINK I'M ME?
WHAT HAPPENS WHEN
MY CONTRACT EXPIRES?
THAT'S
TWO QUESTIONS.
YOU WERE
ALLOWED ONE.
SMILE. ISN'T THIS
WHAT YOU WANTED?
CHECK ON ALL
THE OVERHEADS.
NICE.
ALL RIGHT.
HOUSE LIGHTS TO HALF.
LET'S GO EVERYBODY,
IT'S TIME.
TOPHET.
YOU'LL KNOCK
THEM DEAD.
WHAT AM I SINGING?
DON'T WORRY.
IT'LL COME TO YOU.
SHOWTIME. HI.
WE OPEN WITH
ONLY UP TO ME?
WHAT'S THAT?
THAT'S A SONG
OF MINE?
ONE OF YOUR
BIG HITS.
SMASH.
IT IS?
HERE HE IS, THE MAN
WITH THE DANGEROUS EYES...
MR. BILLY WAYNE!
GO.
GO!
♪ DREAMIN' ♪
♪ DREAMIN'
OF ALL WE CAN BE ♪
♪ IF IT WAS ONLY
UP TO ME ♪
♪ I WOULD BUILD THIS
WORLD ON A DREAM ♪
♪ IMAGINATION ♪
♪ IS JUST CREATION
SEEN AS A CHILD ♪
♪ VISIONS ARE FASHIONS
THAT ARE COMING INTO STYLE ♪
♪ WE ARE CHILDREN
OF A MAGIC ♪
♪ THAT'S THE BEST
WHEN IT JUST RUNS WILD ♪
♪ IF IT WAS ONLY
UP TO ME ♪
♪ I WOULD BUILD
THIS WORLD ON A DREAM ♪
♪ WHEN I CLOSE MY EYES
AND OPEN MY HEART ♪
♪ SOMEONE SPEAKS
TO ME INSIDE ♪
♪ I KNOW THAT YOU
COULD HEAR IT, TOO ♪
♪ IF ONLY YOU
EVER TRIED ♪
♪ I CAN SEE THESE THINGS
SO CLEAR IN MY MIND ♪
♪ THE WAY I WANT
THEM TO BE ♪
♪ I KNOW THAT YOU
COULD SEE THEM, TOO ♪
♪ IF ONLY YOU
WOULD BELIEVE ♪
♪ IF IT WAS ONLY
UP TO ME ♪
♪ I WOULD BUILD THIS
WORLD ON A DREAM ♪
♪ DREAMIN', DREAMIN' ♪
♪ DREAMIN' OF ALL
WE CAN BE ♪♪
THANK YOU!
THIS IS FUN.
THIS IS ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
♪ HERE I AM,
A MAN ON THE WIRE ♪
♪ FEELIN' LIKE
MY BODY'S ON FIRE ♪
♪ HIGH ABOVE THE GROUND ♪
♪ NEVER LOOKIN' DOWN ♪
♪ STARIN' STRAIGHT AT YOU ♪
♪ THROUGH MY
DANGEROUS EYES ♪
♪ CATCH ME IF YOU CAN
JUST FOR FUN ♪
♪ YOU CAN'T HOLD
A MAN ON THE RUN ♪
♪ WHEN YOU SEE
ME COMIN' ♪
♪ LOCK AWAY THE WOMEN ♪
♪ LONELY STRANGERS JUST
LOVE MY DANGEROUS EYES ♪
♪ I'M NOT LIVIN' LONG ♪
♪ I'M JUST LIVIN' GOOD ♪
♪ I'M NOT STAYIN' LONG ♪
♪ LET'S HAVE
A GOOD TIME ♪
♪ WHILE I'M
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD ♪
♪ HERE I AM,
A MAN ON THE WIRE ♪
♪ FEELIN' LIKE
MY BODY'S ON FIRE ♪
♪ HIGH ABOVE
THE GROUND ♪
♪ NEVER LOOKIN' DOWN ♪
♪ STARIN' STRAIGHT AT YOU ♪
♪ THROUGH MY
DANGEROUS EYES ♪
♪ CATCH ME IF YOU CAN
JUST FOR FUN ♪
♪ YOU CAN'T HOLD
A MAN ON THE RUN ♪
♪ WHEN YOU SEE
ME COMIN' ♪
♪ LOCK AWAY THE WOMEN ♪
♪ LONELY STRANGERS JUST
LOVE MY DANGEROUS EYES ♪
♪ WHERE I GO
FROM HERE ♪
♪ DOESN'T WORRY ME ♪
♪ WHEN I DISAPPEAR ♪
♪ I'M ONLY GONE
TO A BETTER PLACE TO BE ♪
♪ YEAH, YEAH, YEAH ♪
♪ HERE I AM,
A MAN ON THE WIRE ♪
♪ FEELIN' LIKE
MY BODY'S ON FIRE ♪
♪ HIGH ABOVE THE GROUND ♪
♪ NEVER LOOKIN' DOWN ♪
♪ STARIN' STRAIGHT AT YOU ♪
♪ THROUGH MY
DANGEROUS EYES ♪
♪ CATCH ME IF YOU CAN
JUST FOR FUN ♪
♪ YOU CAN'T HOLD
A MAN ON THE RUN ♪
♪ WHEN YOU SEE
ME COMIN' ♪
♪ LOCK AWAY THE WOMEN ♪
♪ LONELY STRANGERS JUST
LOVE MY DANGEROUS EYES ♪
LOVE MY DANGEROUS EYES ♪♪
THANKS, GENTLEMEN.
WELL DONE.
WHERE
ARE WE GOING?
HOME, BILLY.
WHERE DO I LIVE?
HOME, SWEET HOME.
I LIVE THERE?
&quot;I LIVE THERE?&quot;
FABULOUS.
LIKE A PIXIE.
WELCOME HOME,
MR. WAYNE.
TREMENDOUS TOUR.
WE READ ABOUT IT.
THANKS.
BILLY, TAKE IT
EASY FOR A WEEK.
I'LL CALL YOU
TOMORROW.
OK, LET'S GO.
CAREFUL WITH
YOUR HEAD, SIR.
IT WAS QUITE
A TOUR, EH, SIR?
YES, YES,
QUITE A TOUR.
HOW MANY ROOMS
IN THIS PLACE?
THERE ARE 24, SIR.
OH, YOU HAVE BEEN
AWAY A LONG TIME.
COZY.
SHALL I PUT THESE
IN YOUR BEDROOM?
YES, GOOD.
NO, WAIT A MINUTE.
SHALL I TURN ON
THE JACUZZI?
THAT'S WHAT
I HAD IN MIND, WILSON.
WILSON!
SIR?
THAT'S YOUR NAME.
OF COURSE, SIR.
OF COURSE.
ROSITA BROUGHT
LOBSTER TODAY.
THEY'RE
IN THE TANK.
TANK?
IN THE KITCHEN,
SIR.
AHH...THAT TANK.
SURE, GREAT.
GOOD WORK BY ROSITA.
UH...
HMM?
WHERE IS THE KITCHEN?
OH, IT'S SO GOOD TO
HAVE YOU HOME, SIR.
WILL YOU
NEED THE CAR?
I'LL HAVE HIM WAIT.
HAVE HIM WAIT.
VERY GOOD, SIR.
WILSON.
SIR?
THAT'LL BE ALL.
MY FIREPLACE.
MY PIANO.
MY DINING ROOM.
AND THIS MUST BE...
MY KITCHEN.
MY TANK.
GUYS...
WHERE AM I?
WHO AM I?
IF I'M
NOT ME ANYMORE,
WHY DO I STILL
THINK I'M ME?
THAT'S THE PART
I CAN'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU.
ME.
WELCOME HOME.
HOW DO YOU LIKE IT?
WHERE'D YOU GO?
IT'S BEEN FIVE MONTHS.
YOU THINK YOU'RE
MY ONLY CLIENT?
I'M RUNNING
A BIG OPERATION.
I NEED TENANTS.
I MUST FOMENT RACIAL
TENSION, FAMINE, WAR.
IT'S FUN,
BUT I'M POOPED.
HOW--
HOW CAN I? DON'T
I HAVE ANY FEELINGS?
RIGHT.
IF I DIDN'T EXIST,
GOD WOULD HAVE CREATED ME.
I MAKE HIM LOOK GOOD.
THERE REALLY IS
A GOD?
SURE. HE RARELY MAKES
PERSONAL APPEARANCES
LIKE I DO.
YOU MEAN SOMETIMES
HE ACTUALLY...
SHOWS UP HERE, LOOKING
LIKE EVERYBODY ELSE?
NOW AND THEN.
BUT HE'S NOT WHAT HE WAS.
VERY DISAPPOINTED MAN.
BITTER.
I TRY TO GET
HIM INTERESTED.
IT'S NO FUN
HAVING THIS TO MYSELF.
I SAY TO HIM,
&quot;COME FOR THE OLYMPICS,
SEE A SHOW,&quot;
GET OUT, YOU KNOW, BUT...
HE JUST TALKS
ABOUT THE OLD DAYS
WITH MOSES, ABRAHAM,
KING WENCESLAUS.
IT'S SAD.
HEAVEN'S HALF EMPTY.
HAD TO CLOSE
THE BIG DINING ROOM.
OH, COME ON.
WOULD I LIE?
HAD TO RELEASE
HALF THEIR STAFF.
PRIESTS,
CLEANING LADIES--
THAT'S ALL THEY GET.
BUT YOU'RE
DOING GREAT?
KNOCK WOOD.
SOMETIMES IT'S TOO MUCH.
SO GOD JUST QUIT?
IS THAT WHAT
YOU'RE SAYING?
WHEN IS THE LAST TIME
HE DID SOMETHING?
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
I'LL TAKE YOU
TO CHASEN'S.
I DON'T
LIKE CHASEN'S.
PICK A PLACE.
GENARO'S.
I WENT WITH WENDY.
IT'S A DUMP.
I LIKE IT.
CHASEN'S
GOT THAT GREAT CHILI.
NO. I'M GOING
TO GENARO'S.
YOU'RE MAKING
A MISTAKE.
LISTEN,
YOU'LL GET UPSET.
TODAY'S THE 15th.
IT'S MY ANNIVERSARY.
WELL, I'LL CHECK.
LET ME SEE.
YES, MR. FARBINGER,
I CAN CONFIRM
THE RESERVATION.
FOR HOW MANY?
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL SEE YOU THEN.
BYE.
CAN I HELP YOU?
HI, LOUISE.
HOW ARE YOU?
DO YOU HAVE
A RESERVATION, SIR?
NO, I DON'T.
I'M SORRY.
I HAVE NOTHING NOW.
[RING]
EXCUSE ME.
GENARO'S.
YES?
FOR HOW MANY?
ALL RIGHT.
YES, I'LL
TAKE CARE OF IT.
BYE.
MR. WAYNE!
I AM SO HONORED
TO HAVE YOU HERE.
UH, OF COURSE I HAVE
A TABLE FOR YOU.
WILL YOU FOLLOW ME?
SURE.
THAT'S BILLY WAYNE!
HEY, BILLY, BILLY!
RIGHT THIS WAY,
MR. WAYNE.
OH, LOUISE.
IS THIS OK?
IF IT'S OK WITH YOU.
I'M HAPPY.
THE VEAL CACCIATORE'S
VERY GOOD.
JUST A BOTTLE
OF BAROLO FOR NOW.
OF COURSE.
I'LL GET IT FOR YOU.
HERE'S YOUR CHECK,
MR. SHELTON.
ENJOY YOUR DINNER?
WENDY WON'T ORDER ANYTHING
BUT SPAGHETTI AND SAUSAGE.
WHENEVER
I DON'T GET IT,
I HATE MYSELF.
COULD YOU GET
OUR CAR FOR US? THANKS.
I LOVED YOUR--
I LOVED
YOUR LAST ALBUM.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
WHEN'S THE NEXT ONE
COMING OUT?
HERE, SWEETHEART.
NEXT YEAR WILL BE
A VERY SPECIAL ANNIVERSARY.
YEAH.
YOU'RE ON TOUR?
IT MUST BE A GAS.
YOU'LL BRING
THE BABY HERE.
WE'LL TAKE THE BABY
EVERYWHERE.
THE STROLLER
COST ME 90 BUCKS.
HAVE A NICE EVENING.
WENDY!
YES?
THAT'S BILLY WAYNE.
HE KNOWS YOU.
YOU'RE PREGNANT.
IT LOOKS LIKE IT.
HAVE WE MET?
I'M BOBBY SHELTON.
PLEASURE
TO MEET YOU.
BOBBY SHELTON.
I THINK
I'VE HEARD OF YOU.
REALLY?
WE HAVE A MUTUAL
ACQUAINTANCE,
STEVE KANTOR.
OH, YEAH, SURE.
HAVE YOU BEEN
MARRIED LONG?
SIX YEARS TODAY.
CONGRATULATIONS.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
WENDY?
WHEN ARE YOU
EXPECTING?
THREE MONTHS.
THREE MONTHS?
YOUR LAST RECORD
WAS TERRIFIC.
THAT'S GREAT.
BOBBY, WE REALLY
SHOULD RUN.
MAYBE I COULD USE YOU.
HEY, THAT
WOULD BE GREAT!
WHERE HAVE WE MET?
CHARLIE GRAY'S
MY AGENT.
HE'S A GOOD AGENT.
IS HE?
I GUESS YOU BETTER
TAKE HER HOME.
SHE PROBABLY
NEEDS HER REST.
I FADE PRETTY EARLY.
I'LL BET.
YOU STILL WORKING?
YEAH. WELL...
NICE MEETING YOU.
AGAIN?
A REAL HONOR
TO MEET YOU.
YEAH.
GOOD NIGHT.
YOUR WINE IS READY.
THAT'S MY BABY
SHE'S CARRYING.
THANKS A LOT.
THANK YOU, SIR.
THANKS FOR THE OFFER!
SHE'S PREGNANT.
IT'S MY BABY.
CONGRATULATIONS.
LET ME OUT
OF THIS DEAL.
NO.
PLEASE!
YOU CAN
GET HER BACK.
YOU'RE A STAR.
WORK ON HER.
SHE'LL DUMP THAT GUY.
WENDY WOULD
NEVER DO THAT.
TRY IT.
IT'S A ROTTEN IDEA!
IT STINKS!
THIS WHOLE
THING STINKS!
CAN'T YOU
UNDERSTAND?
I'M THE FATHER
OF THAT CHILD.
SORRY.
A DEAL'S A DEAL.
STOP THE CAR.
I'LL GET OUT
OF THIS DEAL.
STOP THE CAR!
STOP THE CAR.
OH, NUTS.
I DON'T WANT TO
SEE YOU ANY--
I HATE IT
WHEN HE DOES THAT.
HOW MAY I HELP YOU?
I'M HERE
TO FIND GOD.
THIS IS HIS HOUSE.
IT IS? GREAT.
SEEN HIM AROUND?
SEEN WHO?
GOD.
HE'S IN THIS BOOTH.
WHEN YOU'RE
SPEAKING TO ME,
YOU'RE SPEAKING TO HIM.
I DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR ALL THAT.
I'M NOT TALKING
FIGURATIVELY HERE.
I'M TALKING ABOUT
SPENDING FIVE
MINUTES WITH GOD.
TWO MINUTES.
SHOOT.
YOU GOT TWO MINUTES.
OK, LET ME
TELL YOU WHAT HAPPENED.
ABOUT FIVE
MONTHS AGO,
I MADE A DEAL
WITH THE DEVIL--
UNKNOWINGLY,
OF COURSE.
NEEDLESS TO SAY,
I HAVE GOTTEN
COMPLETELY
AND TOTALLY SCREWED.
BEG YOUR PARDON,
FATHER.
LET ME UNDERSTAND YOU...
YOU MADE A DEAL
WITH THE DEVIL?
THERE REALLY
IS A DEVIL.
HE LIGHTS CIGARS
WITH HIS THUMB...
HE GAVE MY IDENTITY
TO SOME YO-YO
WHO'S LIVING
WITH MY WIFE.
SHE'S PREGNANT
WITH MY CHILD!
SHE THINKS HE'S ME,
BUT I'M ME!
BUT I'M NOT
BILLY WAYNE!
I'M HIM! BOBBY! ME!
I NEED GOD
TO GET BACK TO HER.
EVEN
THE DEVIL ADMITS
THERE REALLY
IS A PERSON GOD.
I UNDERSTAND, REALLY.
PERHAPS I COULD REFER YOU
TO OUR COUNSELING SERVICE.
BELIEVE ME,
I WISH IT WAS
THAT SIMPLE!
SO DO I.
I'M SORRY, FATHER.
THE DEVIL TOLD ME
GOD'S A LONELY GUY.
IS HE?
HEAVEN'S
HALF EMPTY.
THEY CLOSED
A BIG DINING ROOM.
THEY ONLY GET
CLEANING LADIES
AND PRIESTS.
I WANT HIM TO KNOW
THAT HE'S NEEDED.
I NEED HIM.
DO YOU
UNDERSTAND?
FATHER?
WE'D LIKE
A FEW WORDS WITH YOU.
WHAT FOR?
WELL--
START IT UP!
MOVE IT OUT!
SIR, PLEASE, DON'T.
[CHANTING IN HEBREW]
HI.
EXCUSE ME.
CAN I ASK YOU
A QUESTION?
HERE, PUT IT ON.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT IS IT?
I'M NOT
A CRAZY PERSON.
DO YOU KNOW
WHERE MIGHT GOD BE?
YEAH.
YOU DO?
THERE HE IS.
WELL, IN A SENSE.
I'M LOOKING FOR
GOD THE PERSON.
I'M TRYING
TO GET MY WIFE BACK.
YOU WANT GOD
OR A LAWYER?
I KNOW THIS
SOUNDS CRAZY,
BUT ONLY GOD CAN BREAK
MY DEAL WITH THE DEVIL.
DEVIL?
[SPEAKING YIDDISH]
HEY, WAIT A MINUTE!
THE DEVIL DRESSES
IN FANCY CLOTHES
AND PRETENDS THAT
HE'S A TALENT SCOUT!
I WAS SINGING
AT THIS WEDDING...
HE MADE ME A BIG STAR.
YOU'VE HEARD OF ME--
BILLY WAYNE? SEE?
THE BIGGEST ROCK SINGER
IN AMERICA!
BUT I'M NOT ME.
I NEED TO FIND GOD.
YOU NEED REST.
LISTEN TO ME!
YOU ARE
A RELIGIOUS MAN.
I'M IN
TERRIBLE TROUBLE.
I NEED GOD'S
DIRECT INTERVENTION!
YOU CAN'T HAIL
GOD LIKE A TAXI.
THEN HOW?
HE FINDS YOU.
THERE'S NO TIME!
YOU'RE YOUNG.
YOU'VE GOT TIME.
NO!
NO, I DON'T.
I'M SORRY.
LISTEN TO ME.
ARE YOU LOOKING
FOR THAT MAN
THEY CALL
THE LORD OUR GOD?
ARE YOU SEEKING HIM?
IS HE HERE
IN LOS ANGELES?
IS HE IN
THE FARMERS' MARKET
SQUEEZING MELONS?
NO, HE AIN'T!
SO WHERE IS HE?
IS HE IN THE SUBURBS
WEARING GREEN PANTS
AND PLAYING GOLF?
NO!
IS HE IN VERMONT
BAKING BREAD
AND SELLING
REAL ESTATE?
NO, HE AIN'T!
HE'S IN THE DESERT.
THE DESERT?
LOOK TO HIM.
LOOK FOR HIM
IN THE DESERT!
HE SENT YOU?
AMEN.
WAIT!
WAIT A MINUTE!
HE SENT YOU?
HUH?
WHAT DESERT? WAIT!
WAIT! WHAT DESERT?
WHAT DESERT?
COME ON GARY,
TELL ME,
HOW COME BILLY GOT
INTERESTED IN VEGAS?
HE YEARNED
FOR THE DESERT.
I SAID, &quot;MAKE $300,000
WHILE YOU'RE AT IT.&quot;
VERY SENSIBLE.
NICE TALKING TO YOU.
MY PLEASURE.
HI.
YEAH.
I--I--I NEED
SOMEONE PAGED.
WELL...[LAUGHS]
IT'S ACTUALLY
LIKE A LITTLE CODE.
WOULD YOU ASK THE LORD
TO PICK UP A HOUSE PHONE
AND CALL
ROOM 8216, PLEASE?
[LAUGHS]
YEAH, THE LORD.
HA HA HA.
THAT'S RIGHT.
UH...
NO...NO, NO.
JUST &quot;THE LORD.&quot;
YEAH, HE'LL KNOW.
HA HA HA HA.
RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
OHHH.
MR. PETER DeMARIS,
COME TO THE BELL
CAPTAIN'S DESK.
MR. PETER DeMARIS,
TO THE BELL
CAPTAIN'S DESK.
GARY MURPHY,
PLEASE PICK UP THE HOUSE PHONE.
PAGING
MR. ELLISON JOHNSTON.
TELEPHONE CALL
FOR THE LORD.
WILL THE LORD PLEASE
GO TO A HOUSE PHONE?
THIS IS THE LORD.
YOU HAVE A CALL FOR ME.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
[RING]
HELLO.
THIS IS HIM.
HIM WHO?
HIM HIM.
THIS IS TOPHET!
I RECOGNIZE
YOUR VOICE!
LOOK OUT
YOUR WINDOW.
PRETTY NICE, HUH?
I MADE IT MYSELF.
THAT OLD PREACHER...
YOU WERE SPEAKING
THROUGH HIM.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WHY ARE
WE HERE...
IN LAS VEGAS?
I HAVE MY REASONS.
DON'T QUESTION THEM.
YOU'RE IN ENOUGH
TROUBLE ALREADY.
CAN I GET
OUT OF IT?
YOU MADE A DEAL
WITH THE DEVIL.
HOW DUMB COULD YOU BE?
I DIDN'T KNOW
IT WAS THE DEVIL.
YOU'RE NOT TALKING
TO YOUR SIXTH GRADE TEACHER,
YOU KNOW.
TO ME, YOU WERE A STAR
BECAUSE YOU HAD DECENCY.
NOW YOU'RE JUST AN ARTIFACT.
YOU'RE RIDICULOUS.
I KNOW.
I KNOW THAT NOW.
I GAVE HINTS.
THE MUSIC.
THAT WAS YOU!
EACH TIME!
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'VE BEEN WATCHING YOU.
WHY?
ASK YOUR FATHER.
I CAN'T.
MY FATHER'S DEAD.
THEN I'LL ASK HIM.
GOD!
WHAT?
I THOUGHT
YOU'D LEFT.
THE RAINBOW
DISAPPEARED.
I'M TRYING TO
SAVE ON ENERGY.
PLEASE, GOD...
PLEASE, HELP ME.
HELP YOU DO WHAT?
GET MY LIFE BACK.
WENDY...
MY BABY.
I'M NOT A MISSING
PERSONS BUREAU.
I'LL DO ANYTHING.
ALL PRAISES BE
TO ME IN THE HIGHEST.
PRAISING WOULD HELP?
WOULDN'T HURT.
OH, DON'T HANG UP!
DON'T HANG UP!
LORD, I PRAISE
THEE IN THE HIGHEST.
THE TOP.
THE BEST PRAISE.
YOU ARE...
ALL WISE...
ALL KNOWING...
ALL NATURAL.
WHATEVER YOU WANT
ME TO DO, I'LL DO.
PLEASE,
GET ME OUT OF THIS.
IF YOU'RE LISTENING,
HOW ABOUT
ANOTHER RAINBOW?
OR SOME LIGHTNING?
ANYTHING.
A LITTLE
CREEPY MUSIC.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
BILLY!
YOU IN THERE?
YEAH.
YOU'RE ON IN
HALF AN HOUR!
I'M COMING.
THERE'LL BE TIME
FOR CHICKS LATER.
OK...OK!
YOU OK?
YEAH, I'M FINE.
YOU'LL KILL THEM.
DEAD, THEY'RE
GOING TO BE.
I WISH
I WERE DEAD.
DON'T EVER SAY THAT.
PUT THAT THOUGHT
OUT OF YOUR MIND.
WE'LL GET YOU HELP
IF YOU'RE DEPRESSED.
HELL WITH TOPHET.
TOPHET?
YOU SHOULD FIRE THAT
MISERABLE OLD BASTARD.
ESPECIALLY AFTER
WHAT HE SAID HE...
I WASN'T GOING
TO TELL YOU THIS.
WHAT DID HE SAY?
I DON'T WANT TO
GET INTO IT NOW.
WHAT DID HE SAY?
HE THOUGHT YOU WOULD BUMP
YOURSELF OFF WITHIN THE YEAR.
SO THAT'S
HOW IT WORKS.
WHAT?
DID HE SAY IT
LIKE HE KNEW IT?
LIKE IT WAS FACT.
IF HE WASN'T 110,
I'D HAVE PUNCHED HIM.
THAT'S WHAT
HAPPENS TO ME.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
SHOW TIME! 15 MINUTES!
HEY, OK,
SHOW TIME.
WANT ANYTHING?
NO...NO.
NO, THANKS.
I COULD USE TEA
WITH HONEY.
TEA. LA VOCE?
YEAH.
WHAT KIND OF TEA?
ANY KIND OF TEA.
YOU GOT IT.
PRETTY.
MAY I HAVE
THIS CHAIR?
$10 ANTE,
UNLIMITED BETTING.
FINE.
IT'S A PRETTY
ROUGH GAME, POP.
I'LL TAKE MY CHANCES.
FULL HOUSE.
ACES UP.
AW, GIVE ME
A BREAK ALREADY.
THAT'S YOUR
THIRD IN A ROW.
BEGINNER'S LUCK.
YOU AIN'T BETTING
LIKE NO BEGINNER.
OK, I PLAYED
ONCE BEFORE.
MAY I SIT IN?
BEEN EXPECTING YOU.
THIS'LL JUST BE
THE TWO OF US.
ISN'T IT ALWAYS?
WE HAVEN'T PLAYED
FOR QUITE A WHILE.
THE 10 0F SPADES
IS BENT.
OH? SO IT IS.
CAN'T FOOL YOU.
THOSE CIGARS ARE
GOING TO KILL YOU.
I LOVE SMOKE.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
THE WAY YOU DRESS
IS EMBARRASSING.
WHAT ARE WE
PLAYING FOR?
I WANT THE KID
BACK. SHELTON.
YOU MEAN BILLY WAYNE.
I MEAN BOBBY SHELTON.
YOU WANT THE KID BACK.
I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT'S IT
WORTH TO YOU?
PLENTY. WHAT DO
YOU WANT FOR HIM?
THE POPE.
CRAZY.
THAT'S MAD.
BRING BACK
THE BLACK DEATH.
I CAN'T LOOK
AT HIM, CAN YOU?
SMALLPOX?
FORGET IT.
I DON'T HAVE
TO DO THIS.
SHELTON CAME TO ME.
RULES ARE RULES.
BUT YOU LIED TO HIM.
YOU TOLD HIM IT WAS
FOR A TRIAL PERIOD.
IS THAT ACCORDING
TO THE RULES?
TECHNICALITIES.
YOU DON'T HAVE
CLEAR TITLE.
NEITHER DO YOU.
LOOKS LIKE
WE'RE IN A GRAY AREA.
LOST YOUR NERVE?
OK.
I'M A SPORT.
HE'S YOURS
IF YOU WIN.
AND IF YOU WIN?
HE DIES.
THEN HE'S A FOLK HERO,
LIKE ELVIS,
JIM MORRISON, JANIS JOPLIN.
THEY'LL TRIPLE
HIS RECORD SALES.
WORK ALL
THE MEMORIAL BITS.
BILLY WAYNE
POSTERS, T-SHIRTS,
RINGS, WIND-UP DOLLS.
THERE'LL BE
LAWSUITS, FIGHTS.
IT'LL BE FABULOUS.
OK.
ONE HAND TAKES IT.
WE PLAY
ABSOLUTELY STRAIGHT.
OF COURSE.
HOW CAN WE
TRICK EACH OTHER?
TRICKY HAND.
THAT GOOD, HUH?
NOT BAD.
HOW MANY CARDS?
I'LL TAKE TWO.
DEALER TAKES ONE.
I RAISE YOU.
RAISE ME?
WITH WHAT?
THE PEOPLE
ON MY LIST.
ALL THOSE I'VE
BEEN WATCHING OVER.
MILLIONS OF 'EM.
IF I LOSE,
THEY'RE FAIR GAME.
IF I WIN, YOU CAN'T
TOUCH THEM EVER,
EVEN IF THEY
ASK FOR YOU.
WHENEVER BILLY'S READY.
JUST WATCH A LITTLE TAPE,
THEN WE'RE ALL SET.
HAVE A GOOD ONE!
I CAN'T TOUCH
ANY OF THEM?
EVEN IF
THEY BEG FOR ME?
I LOSE, YOU GET BOBBY
AND ALL THE REST.
BILLY!
GOT YOUR TEA.
WELL?
BILLY! COME ON,
OPEN UP!
BILLY!
WELL?
BILLY! BILLY!
TOO RICH FOR ME.
I FOLD.
YOU CAN HAVE HIM.
WHAT DID YOU HAVE?
YOU BLUFFED.
YOU HAD NOTHING.
[STAMPING FEET]
WHY DID I FOLD?
I PUT THE FEAR
OF ME IN YOU.
BILLY!
[DISTORTED VOICE
CALLING, POUNDING]
BILLY!
GET A DOCTOR!
SOMEBODY GET A DOCTOR!
COME ON! DOES
ANYBODY HEAR ME?
GET A DOCTOR!
WHAT'S GOING ON?
BILLY TRIED TO
BUMP HIMSELF OFF.
HOW ABOUT
DOUBLE OR NOTHING?
NO. I GOT
WHAT I WANTED.
WHY DID YOU TAKE
SUCH A RISK FOR THIS KID?
YOU WOULDN'T UNDERSTAND.
BESIDES, I HAD
TO TAKE YOU DOWN A PEG.
YOU'VE BEEN TOO COCKY.
DON'T BE A SCOLD.
YOU'D BE LOST
WITHOUT ME.
WHAT WOULD YOU DO
IF I CLOSED UP SHOP?
I'D MANAGE.
YOU DON'T GET
TO BE AS OLD AS I AM
UNLESS YOU CAN ROLL
WITH THE PUNCHES.
YOU STAYING?
FOR A WHILE.
I TRY TO SPEND
A FEW WEEKS IN VEGAS
EVERY YEAR.
I'M GOING
TO NEW HAMPSHIRE.
THE LEAVES ARE CHANGING.
GOOD TIME TO GO.
NEXT YEAR, I'M BRINGING
BACK THE GYPSY MOTH.
YOU'RE IMPOSSIBLE.
BELIEVE ME,
I'M POSSIBLE.
IS HE DEAD?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND IT.
THERE WAS
NOTHING I COULD DO.
I'M ME AGAIN.
TOPHET!
IT'S ME, BOBBY.
GOD.
YOU LOOK
LIKE THE DEVIL.
REALLY? I'VE BEEN
WORKING TOO HARD.
THERE'S SUCH
A RESEMBLANCE.
HE ALWAYS WANTED
TO LOOK LIKE ME,
TALK LIKE ME,
BE LIKE ME,
BUT I'M GOD.
YOU DON'T DRESS
LIKE GOD.
WHAT SHOULD
I WEAR, A ROBE?
IT'S 108
DEGREES OUTSIDE.
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
YOU'RE YOU AGAIN.
YEAH, I AM.
YOU DO THAT?
OF COURSE.
HOW?
I WON YOU BACK
WITH A BUSTED FLUSH.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
IT'S NOT NECESSARY
THAT YOU UNDERSTAND.
WHY ARE YOU SO
INTERESTED IN ME?
I OWED IT
TO YOUR FATHER.
MY FATHER?
AN HONORABLE,
HOLY MAN.
REMEMBER WHEN YOU
HAD SCARLET FEVER?
KIND OF.
IT WAS
A LONG TIME AGO.
APRIL 16th, 1960.
YOU WERE DELIRIOUS.
A LITTLE
AFTER 3 A.M.,
YOUR FEVER HIT 105.
YOUR FATHER WALKED
INTO YOUR ROOM,
KNELT BY YOUR BED
AND PRAYED TO ME.
BEAUTIFUL
LITTLE PRAYER.
YOU KNOW, HE LOVED
YOU VERY MUCH.
I KNOW.
WHEN HE STOPPED PRAYING,
HE STARTED SINGING,
♪ I'VE GOT
THE HORSE RIGHT HERE ♪
♪ HIS NAME IS
PAUL REVERE ♪
♪ THERE'S A GUY WHO SAYS
IF THE WEATHER'S CLEAR...♪
GOD.
♪ CAN DO ♪
♪ THE GUY SAYS
THE HORSE CAN DO ♪
YOU WERE THERE!
MAKING A HOUSE CALL.
I STILL WATCH
OVER PEOPLE.
IN THE OLD DAYS I COULD
WATCH OVER EVERYBODY--
IT WAS MORE PERSONAL
WITH NOAH AND THAT GANG.
HEARD THAT STORY?
THE FLOOD?
IT WASN'T A FLOOD.
THESE THINGS
GET SO BLOWN UP.
YOU KNOW THE PRESS.
IT WAS RAIN.
MAN INVENTS STORIES
TO EXPLAIN THE UNKNOWN.
THERE'S NO UNKNOWN.
THERE'S ME.
EVERYTHING UNKNOWN,
I KNOW. THAT'S IT.
I HAVE TO GO.
ANYTHING...
ANYTHING I CAN DO?
GO TO YOUR WIFE.
HAVE THE BABY.
BE A LOVING FATHER.
FIRM, BUT LOVING.
RESIST TEMPTATION.
BE A PERSON, A MAN.
I WILL.
NEXT TIME, I WON'T
BAIL YOU OUT.
REMEMBER THAT LINE
IN CASABLANCA:
&quot;LOUIS, I THINK
THIS IS THE START
OF A BEAUTIFUL
FRIENDSHIP&quot;?
I NEVER GO
TO THE MOVIES.
GO AHEAD,
TOUCH ME.
NOW GO BACK
TO YOUR WIFE.
THANK YOU, GOD.
KEEP THE CHANGE.
THANK YOU.
[DOG BARKING]
HI. HOW WAS
THE PARTY?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
IT WAS THAT BAD?
I'M JUST INCREDIBLY
GLAD TO SEE YOU.
WHAT IS IT?
JUNIOR WAS
KICKING TONIGHT.
HE WAS?
SHE WAS?
MISSED POP,
JUST LIKE ME.
NO KIDDING.
YOU MISSED ME?
DID IT SEEM LIKE
I WAS GONE LONG?
IT SEEMED LIKE AGES.
IT WAS.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
I'M GREAT.
I'M THE GREATEST.
COME ON.
LET'S GO TO BED.
COME HERE, YOU.
YOU'RE REALLY
MR. ROMANCE TONIGHT.
ARE YOU LOADED?
I'VE HAD A LIFE-CHANGING
EXPERIENCE.
I CAN'T TELL YOU
HOW MUCH I LOVE YOU.
YOU HAVEN'T SAID THAT
IN THE LONGEST TIME.
WHAT?
I THINK
I HEARD HER.
I'LL TAKE A LOOK.
SWEETIE, YOU'RE
BURNING UP.
GOD, I HOPE THIS ISN'T
SOMETHING BAD.
IT'S GOING TO BE
OK, SWEETIE.
YEAH.
HOW'S THAT?
A LITTLE BETTER?
HMM?
♪ I'VE GOT THE HORSE
RIGHT HERE ♪
♪ THE NAME IS
PAUL REVERE ♪
♪ AND THERE'S
A GUY WHO SAYS ♪
♪ IF THE WEATHER
IS CLEAR ♪
♪ CAN DO ♪
♪ THIS GUY SAYS
THE HORSE CAN DO ♪
♪ IF HE SAYS
GOD?
SING.
♪ CAN DO ♪
♪ I'M PICKING
VALENTINE ♪
♪ 'CAUSE ON
THE MORNING LINE ♪
♪ THE GUY HAS GOT HIM
FIGURED AT FIVE TO NINE ♪
♪ BUT LOOK AT EPITAPH ♪
♪ HE WINS IT
BY A HALF ♪
♪ ACCORDING TO THIS
HERE IN THE TELEGRAPH ♪
♪ FOR PAUL REVERE
I'LL BITE ♪
♪ I HEAR HIS FOOT'S
ALL RIGHT ♪
♪ OF COURSE,
IT ALL DEPENDS ♪
♪ IF IT RAINED
LAST NIGHT ♪
♪ EPITAPH ♪
♪ PAUL REVERE ♪
♪ VALENTINE ♪
♪ I GOT THE HORSE ♪
♪ RIGHT ♪
♪ HERE ♪♪
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
WARNER BROS.
CAPTIONED BY THE NATIONAL
CAPTIONING INSTITUTE
--www.ncicap.org--