Lonnie?
Lonnie, come on.
Isn't she
going to be late for camp?
She always makes the bus.
I watch her from upstairs,
sometimes.
Lonnie!
Here I am.
My first meeting's at 9:00.
It's already 8:30.
I don't have to be down
until 10:00.
Or maybe it's 9:30.
Is gymnastics at 2:00
or 3:00?
I think he said 9:00.
2:00. Linda's mother's
taking you.
Lonnie,
you better hurry up.
-You're gonna miss your bus.
-No, I won't.
Are we staying home tonight?
Uh, yeah, I'm not through
until 7:00.
Yeah, me neither.
Nor 7:30, maybe.
We're doing back walkovers.
Dinner at 7:30, then?
We better make it 8:00.
Oh, I can't keep
Katherine that late.
Leave dinner in the oven.
Or maybe back handsprings.
But then we can't have fish,
it'll dry out.
Well, then, don't have fish.
Maybe handsprings
are next week.
But she
already bought the fish.
Snapper.
What takes you so long
every morning?
What do you do up there?
Get dressed.
Ah, you wear
the same thing every day.
Camp's over in a week,
isn't it?
What are you gonna do then,
when you can wear
anything you want?
We'll never get to see you.
I'll wear the same thing
all my life.
So we have to have the fish.
Well, then, have the fish.
I hope handsprings
are this week.
Well, it'll dry out.
Then, don't have the fish.
Don't have the fish.
All right.
We'll have the fish.
I hate fish.
You better do your hair and go.
It's done.
Lonnie,
take off that scarf,
and put on the bandeau,
the way I like it.
I'm wearing it this way today.
Lonnie, would you do it
and stop fussing?
It looks cute with the bandeau.
I don't wanna look cute.
Don't talk back
to your mother.
That's cute.
Hey, you're playing
or what?
Pervert!
Come on.
Jump!
Johnny, move it, man.
What are you, scared?
What's the matter?
You scared, chicken-lips?
Shut up.
- Shut up.
- Shut up, will you?
Shut up, will you?
Come on, you jump.
You fall on your face?
Come on.
Hey, come on, sucker,
that ain't bad.
What's the matter with you?
Johnny, you should back off.
Just jump.
Come on.
Jump!
-Your sister's --
-What'd you say?
Your sister's...
You wouldn't know
what to do with it.
I'll see you suckers later.
- Come on, Johnny.
- Johnny, come on.
Come on, don't go.
Hey, Red Raider.
Oh, come on, Johnny.
Johnny, come on.
- Johnny.
Forget you, man.
-Come on, give me the ball.
-Hey, where are you going?
I'm going with Johnny.
What about the game?
Forget about the game,
we got better things to do.
Ma! I forgot my keys!
Look who's here.
Hey, Johnny,
your sister's looking hot.
Yeah, if you like baby fat.
Hey, Karen,
where did you get the war paint?
Shut up.
Well,
I think you look good.
You look real good.
Hey, Karen, I think you got
a piece of dirt on your face.
It's a beauty mark.
Hey, Karen, we're just kidding.
Hey, Red Raider.
My name's Lonnie.
You live here?
Yeah.
Which floor do you live on?
All of them.
All of them?
Your father is the super?
What?
You got all four floors
to yourself?
Yeah.
It's our house.
You got a big family?
Four people.
That's it?
Yeah.
So can I come in or what?
Why?
I don't know.
She's coming over
for a while.
Who's she?
Katherine.
She takes care of us.
Come on.
Do you wanna play something?
Huh?
I've got some games.
Like what?
Life, Risk.
No, that takes too long.
Monopoly? Stratego?
Candy Land?
That's stupid.
Scavenger Hunt? Domain?
Holy shit!
Oh, Christ.
It ain't funny!
Sorry.
So, which do you wanna play?
I'm not in the mood.
Where'd you get this?
It was a present.
Real?
I guess.
You can tell if it's fake,
if the probe part comes off
when you scratch it.
Hey!
I guess it's the real thing.
I bet it cost a lot.
I'm going.
She dresses funny.
Yeah.
I like it.
Come on.
What?
I wanna teach you something.
I can't. I got to get on.
Do what you want.
Sounds boring to me.
Wait a second.
I don't feel good.
I'm going home.
It's okay. My mom will call.
Wait a second.
Hang up.
This is a cinch.
They'll know.
They'll figure it out.
Trust me. Shh.
Uh...
Yeah, hold on a sec.
Say, "I'm concerned
about her health."
-It's what she always says.
-Huh?
-Just say it.
-Uh...
I'm concerned about her health.
Lonnie, Lonnie, yeah.
This is Missus, Missus...
- Sloan.
Yeah.
She's sick or something.
I'm sure she'll be all right.
Yeah.
Yeah. Listen,
don't worry about it.
Don't worry about it.
Jesus, they already
got you dead and buried.
-So?
-So, no problem.
Okay, you ready?
For what?
Well, if you wanna hang around
with me,
I got to teach you stuff.
-Okay?
-Okay.
Just don't look anyone
in the face
or you're cooked,
and that includes me.
Got it?
Yeah.
So, go.
And get good stuff.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Don't take all day.
Can I help you with something?
No, I'm just looking.
Chicken.
I'm cutting out here now.
You forget something?
-No.
-Maybe paying?
You in on this, too, kid?
No, it's just me.
She didn't do anything.
Yeah, but you did.
Let's have it.
Show him what you got.
In your back pocket.
And what's in the bag?
Come on, all of it.
What about you?
I told you. It's just me.
Next time,
steal it from your mother.
Now get the hell
out of here and stay out.
I'm never going in there again.
That guy sees everything.
Not everything.
Wow.
I've done better before.
How'd you get all this?
Simple.
I like this color, though.
Look.
Purple passion,
that's good.
What I really want
is fiery red.
That's my color.
Hey, I got perfect lips,
you know.
Two points, perfect.
No, you ain't got it.
Sister Mary Margaret
is always getting
pissed off at me
for wearing so much makeup.
You know what I told her?
Told her
that if God made me perfect,
I might as well show it.
You know what I mean?
She threw me in Father Stitch's
office for that one.
You have nuns for teachers?
Yeah. Don't you?
I don't think so.
Every one of 'em,
and they all got
the exact same glasses.
You know,
those plastic gray kind?
The kind with the chain
around the neck?
And they all wear
them cripple shoes.
They don't get married,
you know.
Yeah, I know.
But I seen Father Stitch
and some of them nuns.
My music teacher was in love
with my science teacher.
How'd you know?
You could tell.
Whenever we had music,
he'd come in
and ask her some dumb question.
Like, "Do you have an eraser?"
Or "When's the period over?"
Big deal.
And he leaned over her,
way over her.
What are you, queer?
Did they ever kiss?
I guess.
Where?
How do I know?
They ever make out?
Are you kidding?
Sister Evangeline
was making out
with Father Stitch
right in the chapel,
at the altar.
Karen?
This is Lonnie.
She lives around the block.
Nice to meet you.
What do you want?
I want you to try this on
so I can hem it.
That thing?
I'm not wearing that.
What do you want me to look
like, some wrinkly nun?
Don't talk about the sisters
like that, do you hear me?
This is a confirmation,
not some party of yours.
Slip it on.
-Now?
-Now.
I thought I told you
to be here at 3:00.
It ain't 3:00 anymore.
-Sorry.
-What?
Apologize right to your father.
I said I'm sorry. Okay?
Sorry don't fix water pipes.
Look at me.
I had stuff to do, Dad.
Stuff?
Yeah, things.
Oh, things.
I sure don't wanna mess up
whatever things you got going.
Yeah, right.
Come here.
Over here.
Here.
If I got things to do,
your things ain't worth shit,
you hear me?
Smith from 4B called,
the toilet's backed up.
They called twice already.
Jesus, what the hell, are they
swim in it?
Hmm?
Or maybe they dance on it?
Oh, stop that.
Mother Mary, stop it.
I have work to do.
You're gonna look real nice.
Hey, Sloan.
Uh...
Thanks.
For what?
For covering for me
over at the store.
That's okay.
Okay.
See you tomorrow, then.
I can't. I have camp.
So? Skip out.
Tomorrow's an overnight,
two straight days.
I'm not supposed to be home
in-between.
So? Take an overnight
at my house.
It's better than sleeping
on a hunk of mud.
How can I?
I don't know. Figure it out.
How was camp?
Good.
Mm-hmm.
I mean, okay.
You know, the same.
We had nature today.
Oh, great.
You had nature yesterday.
Oh, yeah.
I guess I mixed it up.
We had boating today.
Mm-hmm.
It was pretty good.
I mean, it was fun.
That's the first positive thing
I've heard you say
about camp in a month.
Maybe we should sign you up
for three or four more weeks.
No!
I mean, you can't.
It's over
at the end of the week.
Just keep you out of trouble
until school starts.
I'm not in any trouble.
Just to keep you off the streets, you know.
I'm not on the streets.
He's only joking, Lonnie.
I know.
Diane.
What?
Can you keep a secret?
Yeah.
I have to tell you a secret.
What?
You have to promise
not to tell anyone.
How can I promise
if I don't even know what it is?
You have to or I
can't tell you.
Is it about that girl?
And what if it is?
Then, I'll keep it.
-It is.
-Tell me.
I skipped camp.
I know.
And I'm gonna do it again.
What are you doing, honey?
What?
Nothing.
Just sitting.
I got it.
Don't worry, I got it.
Well, if you got it,
then, get it.
Hello?
Yes, it is.
She's still sick.
-Two days?
-Yeah.
All right.
Look what I got.
The passkey.
Could you believe it?
He was right there
in the room, and I got it?
Come on.
What if someone's there?
It hasn't been rented yet.
Come on.
What are you doing?
Just looking.
We're just looking,
Mr. Bruckner.
Are utilities included?
You need to fix the plumbing
yourself?
Should we take it, dear?
It's roomy,
but it's got a good view
of the garbage cans.
We can put the TV in here.
Yeah.
I'll put the a Tangier over here
and the piano over here,
and the Davenport over there.
Are you gonna eat
or are you gonna stare at me
for an hour?
No, no, no, the food's
not on the table yet.
Charles, serve the Vichyssoise.
What?
The soup, the Vichyssoise.
It's perfect.
What are you doing?
I'm eating my steak.
It's just the way I like it,
thick and juicy.
No. We're having pressed duck.
Charles, bring us
the pressed duck, please.
Well, what do we got
to drink, Charles?
White wine, please.
White wine?
Yeah.
White wine with poultry.
It's perfect.
I want a chocolate shake,
Charles.
Fine.
Bring her a chocolate shake.
And we'll have bananas flambe
for dessert.
Bananas for dessert?
Yeah. It's very elegant.
Your bananas is rotten,
and this whole dinner stinks.
Shh.
I think I hear him coming.
Lucky.
Let's get out of here.
Hurry up.
Simple.
Go ahead.
I'll be there in a minute.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Oh?
-Where is the key?
-I don't got it.
I'm showing a new
tenant the apartment,
and I ain't got the key,
so let's have it.
Okay. Okay. Here.
Don't you ever go in
a tenant's apartment again.
-It was empty.
-I don't care.
If I ever catch you
in an apartment again,
you're gonna wish you were
somebody else's kid.
And that goes
for your friend, too.
-Karen.
-Shut up.
Just shut up.
I called Father Stitch.
Where are you going?
You haven't finished.
You didn't confess.
Go on.
How can I help you?
What brings you here
this afternoon?
We...
I mean, Kar...
I mean, my friend...
Go on.
Scary, huh?
Just stick with me,
them priests is weird,
just stick with me.
Haven't you ever been
to confession before?
I've never been
to church before.
You haven't?
Aren't you Catholic?
No.
What are you, then?
I don't know. Nothing.
What do you mean, nothing?
I'm not anything.
You're gonna go to hell, then.
-What?
-If you're not anything,
you're gonna end up in hell.
You got to confess.
You told the priest
what we did, right?
No.
Oh, boy, you're gonna burn.
Burn?
Burn in the pit of fire.
In the pit of fire?
I mean, just 'cause I didn't
tell a guy what we did?
Well, I told him, so I'm okay.
Well, let's go back.
That's not all you got to do.
Come on.
I got this at first communion.
The one I got now is better,
but it'll do.
Come here.
Like this.
No. Left to right.
Okay. Hail Mary--
put your finger...
on that bead there.
Okay.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed is the fruit
of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners
now and at the hour
of our death, amen.
Okay?
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed
is the fruit of thy womb Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners
now and at the hour
of our death, amen.
-Amen.
-Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed is the fruit
of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners
now and at the hour
of our death, amen.
Amen.
Just keep doing that
every night.
Am I still gonna go to hell?
Who knows?
Just keep praying.
Especially when you sin,
and then it'll all be okay.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed is the fruit
of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners
now and at the hour
of our death, amen.
I gotta rewire 4C.
Yeah?
Yeah. And that young lady?
She's taking 3B.
When?
It still needs a cleaning.
-Who?
-Another week.
Who? That lady from before?
Don't put the plate in your
mother's face, she's eating.
-I want some more.
-Well, then ask her if you want.
It's all right. I'll get it.
She said she doesn't
have too much.
A couple of chairs, a bed.
-Just her?
-Uh-huh. Yeah.
She lives alone?
Did you catch that nail polish?
Gold.
Would you like some more tomato?
No. Thank you.
Don't you like the food?
Honey, if she doesn't want
any more, it's all right.
Well, I know that.
I just asked that.
-Because she wanted the food--
-Dad.
Here comes...
Hey, you haven't finished
your dinner.
I'm gonna meet somebody.
You ask for more and then
you leave it on your plate.
Take it easy, Red Raider.
I ain't gonna steal your food.
Hey, cut it out.
Lower your voice.
You shouldn't let
him leave the table like that.
He's a wise guy.
Yeah.
Who asked you?
Lonnie?
Yeah?
Come on.
Where?
Just come on.
Wait here.
Why?
Just wait.
Here.
For keeps?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Well, au revoir.
What?
It's French for good-bye.
Au revoir?
Right, au revoir.
Au revoir.
Hey, your friend ain't bad,
give her a couple of years
and send her by.
You're a pervert.
I hear they ain't letting
you confess
'cause what you've been
telling them is too sick.
Very funny.
Leave her alone.
She likes me.
How do you know?
She came over,
she spent the night.
How do you know
she wasn't over to see me?
I saw her looking up
at me at dinner.
She likes me.
She don't need you.
Leave her alone, she's mine.
Lonnie?
What are you doing?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mess anything.
-No.
-I'll clean it up.
I didn't know you use make up.
I mean, I didn't know
you were interested
in that kind of stuff.
I'm not. I mean, not really.
No, it's okay.
I just didn't know, that's all.
Oh, this came
for you last week.
I forgot to show it to you.
It's the invitation
to the Summer Dance.
It's next week.
-Next week?
-Uh-huh.
I don't wanna go this year.
Oh, Lonnie,
you loved it last year.
I didn't love it, it was okay.
Well, you're going this year.
You have to invite someone,
maybe someone from camp.
Forget it.
Lonnie, think of someone
and invite them.
Anybody?
Yes, anybody.
Hey, look, there's some kids
from my school.
- Sarah, hi.
- Hi, Lonnie.
Come on.
This is my friend, Karen.
Hi.
She lives near me.
What school do you go to,
Ms. Dobson's?
Saint Stan's.
It's near us.
It's stuck onto a church.
Oh.
- Where's Sally?
- Sally's in France.
- Still?
- Yeah.
There's Bobby Jacobs.
I wanted to ask him to dance,
but he won't.
That guy?
I wouldn't let him
touch me if I was you.
What a stiff.
Do you wanna dance?
Who dances to this?
-Come on.
-Don't touch me.
I wanna dance, come on.
Don't you know how to dance?
Listen, I was dancing
before you were walking.
Come on, I'll show you.
Like this.
Forward, back.
-Look at that stiff.
-Oh, my God.
What are you staring at?
Don't worry about them.
Come on, you almost had it.
Hey, are you trying to make me
look like a queer, Sloan?
No.
Forget it, I don't need it.
Check you later.
That was just great,
boys and girls.
Now, get your partners, we're
going to play a cha-cha-cha,
everybody knows
how to do the cha-cha.
One, two, three.
Hey.
-Hi.
-You look like you need
something to drink
with your ice.
Yeah.
This stuff won't do anything
for you, though.
Too bad I didn't bring
a bottle, you know?
Huh?
You know, spike it up,
get some action going around
this funeral home.
Come on, let's go.
-Why?
-We're leaving now.
-What are you doing?
-Shh, just wait
till we get outside.
What's going on?
Some party.
Couldn't believe them guys.
How old was they, about eight?
And those girls, what dogs,
"Sally's in France."
Yeah, well--
Yeah, well, I showed them.
What do you mean?
Where'd you get that?
24 bucks.
All right.
I don't think that lady
in the coat check room
had such a hot time.
She was sleeping
through the whole thing.
You mean you stole that?
Yeah, I got it.
You can't do that.
Don't act like you never took
nothing before, Sloan.
It's just like
in the Five & Dime,
except a whole lot better.
It's not the same.
Stealing's stealing,
and your friends
aren't gonna be missing
a few bucks anyways.
You can't do that, not there.
What?
You can't take that money.
You just better watch
what you say to me, Sloan.
Your head's getting
pretty big these days,
and I'm getting about ready
not to like you.
What do you mean?
If you wanna keep
hanging around,
you just watch it, is all.
Just watch it.
Let's burp you, okay?
Big burp, big burp for mommy.
Watch out!
What?
You just fell out of the window.
-There.
-You're dead.
Pfft. Now you're not.
Thanks.
Why don't you go
into the living room?
I have to be in
with the baby now.
Where's that girl?
You don't have to whisper.
It's not a secret anymore.
Don't you wanna play
with her anymore?
I don't know.
Hi.
Where you been lately?
Here, around.
I thought you were sick
or something.
No, I'm not sick.
I'm sorry about the money.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
Okay?
Yeah, okay.
All right.
So you gonna come over
or what?
I want you to come over.
You wanna come over?
Okay.
Where is everyone?
Old lady Kramer
kicked off last night.
She died?
Bit the dust, but
didn't come up chewin'.
So where is everyone?
Kramer's funeral.
They couldn't wait to stick her
in the dirt.
How come you didn't go?
What do I want
at some old bat's funeral?
Where are you going,
Red Raider?
I don't know.
Just 'cause your best girl
ain't here
don't mean
there's nothing to do.
So, what do you wanna do?
I got an idea.
What?
Come on, I'll show you.
-Tell me.
-It would be a surprise.
Don't you like surprises?
Come on.
Sit down.
Sit.
You're acting like you
ain't never been here before.
We never got a chance
to talk, you and me, huh?
-Wanna drink?
-Yeah.
Okay.
How old are you?
Almost eleven three-quarters.
That's pretty old.
So, um...
got yourself a boyfriend?
No.
How come?
I don't know.
What do you mean
you don't know?
I don't know.
I guess I'm not ready.
-Look ready to me.
-What?
You know, I was ready
when I was your age.
Don't you think you're ready?
You wanna play cards?
Karen's got cards.
Strip poker?
No.
That's the only game I like.
You know Gin?
Gin?
Yeah.
Okay. We'll play your game,
but we'll play with my rules.
Okay. You've had it, Red Raider.
You're not out yet.
If you lay the card I think
you're stupid enough to lay,
you're a long goner.
I got you figured out
pretty good, Red.
Gin.
No one's beat me yet.
What do you got?
Not bad.
I almost had it.
Yeah, but almost ain't
worth shit.
So what are the special rules?
Okay.
Put your hand there.
-Why?
-Are you asking or playing?
Put your hand there.
Whoever wins
gets to hit the other guy
in the knuckles.
Ow!
Oh, come on, I didn't hurt you.
I hardly touched you.
You should see what I do
when I play with the guys.
Some of them I smashed
ain't doing much
with their hands these days.
Hey, I didn't hurt you, did I?
I'm sorry.
We're playing stickball outside.
You gonna pitch or what?
Ball?
Yeah, sure.
I'm changing my clothes.
Meet me outside.
Keep your eye
on the ball, okay?
This is right.
Now, see where it says,
"Bingo every Friday
at 7:15 p.m."?
If you swing and you hit
right over that, it's a single.
If you hit right over that sign,
it's a double.
And if you hit right over
those arches, it's a triple.
And if you right over
that cross,
right over that cross,
it's a home run.
Okay? Okay.
So hit one for me,
all right, Red?
Okay. Great.
Hey, lay off.
I wasn't talking to you.
I was talking to her.
Don't listen to him.
Nail one for me, all right, Red?
Don't do it.
It's okay, I'll play.
Good choice.
Good choice, Red.
All right. Let's go.
- Ball one.
- Yo, come on, Johnny.
Johnny, what's going on?
That's ball two.
Why don't you watch the ball,
not the pitcher?
You're pitching a walk.
Come on, Johnny.
Ball three.
Oh, Johnny, man,
you're pitching a walk.
Ball four.
Let's play
some real stickball.
What,
are you sweet on her?
Pussy-whipped pitcher.
Thank you.
So, who's coming?
Oh, I thought
I told you already.
I forgot.
The Drakes.
Mr. and Mrs. Sagers.
Remember you met them
in the country?
Aunt Linda. That's all.
You can come
if you feel like it.
No, thanks.
Mom?
Uh-huh?
How come Aunt Linda
comes alone?
Oh, I don't know.
I guess I never know
who she'll like,
so I just don't invite
anybody for her.
Isn't she married?
If she were, you'd have probably
heard about it.
You don't tell me everything,
you know.
I'll be sure to tell you
about it if it happens.
There's lots you don't tell me.
Oh?
Well, what would you like
to know?
I don't know.
Do you think she's ever...
you know...?
Ever what?
Mom!
Honey, I don't know what
you're talking about, honestly.
You know, been,
like, with a man.
Well, um,
I'm pretty sure she has.
I mean, I've never really
asked her about it,
but I'd be willing
to bet on it.
But she's not married.
Lonnie, lots of single women
go out with lots of men.
That's how they find
the right man.
Oh.
She must've had a lot
of boyfriends.
She's had her share.
When was her first one?
Oh, Linda started pretty young.
- Couldn't these guys --?
- Yeah.
Very nice.
She's moving in?
Yeah. Croner's old place.
Not bad, huh?
She's pretty old.
She's alright.
Good legs.
Not bad.
Not bad by a long shot.
Hey, Carla, let me take them.
Thanks, Johnny.
Looks like you're feeding
an army.
Just some friends.
You got lots of friends?
Everybody's got friends.
What kind of friends you got?
Same kind you have.
Probably a little older.
I ain't got no friends
around here.
Just a bunch of assholes.
Sorry.
But you know what I mean.
They're all wimps.
They'll grow up.
I like older people, anyway,
you know, adults.
They got, you know, more.
More?
Yeah, more.
Anyway, older people
like me better anyway.
Always have.
That so?
Yeah.
I guess they think
I'm mature or something.
You look pretty mature.
Yeah? Do you think?
I don't know, I think so.
Yeah, Johnny, real mature.
Yeah?
Like older people
could go for me?
Sure.
Well, what do you know?
-Well, thanks.
-Oh, I could take 'em.
Oh, no. It's okay.
Let me take them.
They're heavy.
It's a man's job.
You're a sweet kid.
You can put them on the table.
Come on,
I'm not gonna bite you.
I...
Thanks.
You're a good kid.
Go on.
Go on home.
I got some people coming.
Oh, yeah. Okay.
See you later, little man.
Hey, look,
there's Carla.
Look at the way
she's dressed.
Her pants are so tight.
Yeah, she has to
lie down and put them on.
You know her already?
Yeah,
I know all about her.
I know she's 32.
And I know she works
in a beauty parlor.
She does nails.
-Hi, honey, how are you doing?
-Hi.
-Okay.
-Oh, I like your belt. Look.
Let me see your nails.
They look good.
Nice.
See you later.
Alright.
And I know
she doesn't have any guys.
How did you know?
I'm not stupid, Sloan.
Single women
go out with lots of guys.
That's how they figure out
who's the right one.
Well, she told me she doesn't.
Yeah, but I'll bet she does.
You don't even know her.
Where did he go?
Who?
Him.
Your father?
I guess he's up
fixing something.
Fixing what?
I don't know.
He said something
about air-conditioning for 3B.
Well, that's Carla's
new apartment.
Mm-hmm.
Well, she wants
air-conditioning?
I guess so.
Well, we don't have
air-conditioning.
If she wants to pay for it,
she can have it.
Oh, fancy.
You take care of yourself.
Don't go worrying
about nobody else.
Finished already?
She ain't got the right parts.
She doesn't have
all the right parts?
Yeah.
But the one she's got
ain't too bad.
It's you.
Yeah. Who else?
You going in or out?
Out, I guess.
Okay. See you later, then.
Hi, Dad.
Hi.
What's up?
Nothing that wasn't up
a minute ago.
You finished
with these tools here?
Yeah.
I've had just about all I can
take with those tools today.
I thought I'd, um--
I thought I'd finish
fixing that pipe up on 4,
like you wanted me to.
That's good.
You're learning.
Are you gonna follow
your old man's footsteps?
Yeah. Sure.
Do me a favor.
Don't.
Oh, it's you.
Yeah, it's me.
Are you expecting somebody else?
No.
Your dad was just up here.
He's gonna put in
the air-conditioning.
It's gonna be real cool
up, because.
Yeah?
What'd you bring the tools for?
I don't know.
I just thought...
Just thought you'd come
and see how cool it is?
Yeah, exactly.
There she is.
Come on.
Jesus.
I think she's walking
to another country.
Come on.
We'll lose her.
Forget it.
Sloan, you're
really stupid sometimes.
You can't go here.
Why not?
We don't belong here.
Get it?
We're going back. Now.
Check it out.
Yo, man, check out
this mariquita, man.
Huh?
How many you want?
One, just one.
Anything else?
No, that's it.
I mean, 25 cents, please.
You're a fool.
You could have
gotten killed there.
Yeah, but I didn't.
So you found out
where she works, is that it?
Found out everything.
She's got a man.
So she's got a man,
that it?
What else do you wanna know?
I bet there's lots more to know.
Only I don't have to go
anywhere to find it out.
I got all the information,
not you.
You can't find out anything
without me.
Pretty nice...
air-conditioning and everything.
I guess she does more
than just talk with that guy.
-What?
-Look at her bed.
Bet you didn't find
anything like this
up where you went.
Here. Have one of these.
This is good.
Come on.
What?
Karen, what's the matter?
My dad's tool belt.
What's it doing here?
He was putting in
the air-conditioning.
Well, that's in the other room.
I know.
What are his tools doing--?
Oh.
Carla?
Are you here?
It's Johnny.
What are you doing here?
I thought I heard something.
I mean, I had to check
on some pipes.
Look at this.
So what?
So what's it doing here?
Well, wasn't dad putting in
the air-conditioner?
The air-conditioning
is in the other room.
Wait.
You mean, you think
him and her... up here?
I don't know.
He's been coming up here a lot.
Well, what do you know?
I never thought the old man
was up to it.
It's not funny.
What do you know?
You think it's funny?
Your own dad up here
with some slut?
She's not a slut!
Oh, she's a slut, all right.
-Oh, grow up.
-You grow up.
We better clean up.
I don't know
where she got this from.
On the hook.
What are you staring at?
I don't know about you,
but I'm getting out of here.
Don't worry.
She won't be home until 6:00.
How do you know so much
about her?
I talk to her.
Ain't I allowed to talk to her?
It was you up there,
wasn't it?
What if it was?
Tell Karen.
Why should I?
She was crying.
She'll be all right.
What do you want?
I have to talk to you.
Forget it.
I have to tell you something.
What? That my father was
up there with that slut?
No.
Get out of here.
- Wait a minute.
- Just get out of my house.
Hello? Is Karen home?
It's Lonnie.
She's not?
Oh.
Okay. Bye.
Hail Mary full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
blessed is the fruit
of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners, now
and at the hour of death. Amen.
Hail Mary full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
blessed is the fruit
of thy womb, Jesus.
Hey, hey.
Did you tell her?
No.
Then, I'm gonna tell her.
She should know.
Hold on.
I, um...
I didn't get a chance to yet.
You see,
I thought maybe you'd help me
figure out how to tell her.
Well, just say that it was you.
No, no, no.
Not here.
Come here.
Come on, Red.
I'm not gonna to bite you.
Wanna go for a ride, Red?
-No.
-Come on.
Get on.
I don't wanna do this!
Too bad.
Let me off!
Look out!
Watch out!
Pretty scary, huh?
Stop it!
I wanna get off!
No way.
Stop it!
Forget about it!
Look out!
-Let me off!
-No.
Look out!
Stop!
You keep your face
out of other people's business.
You got that?
This is nothing compared
to what I'm gonna do to you
if you tell Karen.
Do you hear me?
-Yeah.
-What?
Yeah, I hear you.
So you just keep it to yourself!
Keep what to herself?
Keep what to yourself?
It was Johnny who was up there
with Carla.
It's not your father.
You?
Yeah. Yeah, it's me.
What are you so surprised for?
I thought it was Dad.
Well, it wasn't.
Anyway, you're too busy
with your friend here
all the time
to see what's going on
in your own damn house!
Wait a minute.
Where are you going?
-It's all your fault.
-What?
You had to know everything,
and you had to know
all about her.
I tried to tell you.
You mean you knew?
You knew all along,
and you didn't even tell me?
I tried.
Just go home.
Just get out of here.
Aren't you going to go home
to your mommy?
Ain't your maid waiting
to open the door for you?
-Shut up.
-What?
I said shut up.
Yes?
It's me.
Hi, honey.
You can come in.
You want anything?
No.
Daddy and I are going to dinner,
so it's just you and Diane.
You're going out?
Yes.
Your top is undone,
you know.
Oh.
Don't you want to do it up?
Oh, I'll get to it.
I'll do it.
Can I do it?
Okay. That would be nice.
Lonnie?
What's wrong?
Tell me what's wrong.
First day
of school tomorrow, huh?
Diane's so excited,
you're gonna have a great time
getting her to go to bed.
You had a good summer, huh?
Yeah.
Oh, Lonnie.
Look.
You have
the most beautiful eyes.
Hurry up.
I'll come when I'm ready.
What are you doing?
You're not allowed.
It's not in the dress code.
Nice, huh?
I hate these uniforms.
I like them.
It's so stupid.
Colors are nice.
I'd rather be purple.
There's that girl.
So?
She's coming over here.
Hi.
First day?
Yeah.
School.
Summer was better than this
is ever gonna be.
I mean, it's not like it was--
it was different
than other summers.
Just hanging around and stuff.
It was different.
Yeah, I know.
I got to go, anyway.
Yeah.
Well, I'll see you around?
I guess.
Hey, Karen, let's go!
Hey, Sloan!
Your color...
It's good.
I mean, this fiery red
you copped for me is better.
But what you got's okay.
Yeah, I like it.