Hurry, the train.
Henry, stop this.
I'm sorry, Mr. Arthur.
Quite all right, Mrs. Nash.
Please don't be angry, Mr. Arthur.
My son is only joking.
- Good day.
- Mr. Arthur!
Stop. I'm gonna kill you.
- Can it wait? I gotta go to work.
- Work!
Someday you'll break your hands
doing that stupid work.
Then see if you'll ever play
Carnegie Hall.
I don't wanna play Carnegie Hall, Ma.
This week you don't wanna play.
I've been telling you that
since I was 7 years old.
So, what does
a 7-year-old boy know?
I gotta go.
Make sure you come back
with all your fingers.
- Hi, Dad.
- Hi, Argus.
Dad, Argus is the dog. I'm Henry.
Sorry, Henry.
Fourth down, five seconds to go.
Luckman licks his fingers.
Eyes the defense.
He sets.
Takes the snap,
hands off to Nagurski.
Bronko explodes. Knocks off
Farkas, straight-arms Todd.
Bodies are flying everywhere.
The crowd goes wild.
Left, right. Touchdown!
You're getting old, Butch.
Hop, look what I got here!
Hopper, where the hell
have you been?
Shooting down enemy aircraft.
Got an Airacobra P-39
over Pleasure Point.
The Airacobra P-39
is one of ours, Hop.
- Damn.
- Pick up 2, will you?
You better sharpen up, pal,
if you wanna be a Marine.
Hey. Anybody down there?
- Ah, Gatsby boys.
- Very lame.
Hey, sport, you wanna wait until
I got them set?
Hey, Hop, how about doubling
tomorrow night
with me and Sally at the movies?
- What's playing?
- Who cares?
Goddamn it!
What do you need me for?
You've been seeing her for months.
Sally's dad won't let her out anymore
unless she doubles.
- Why not?
- Her old man's got this idea
I been messing around with her.
Her old man's smart.
So, what do you say?
I don't know, Nicky.
I don't feel much like a movie.
Forget about the stinking movie,
will you, Hopper?
Since when do you watch
Carole Lombard?
I always watch Carole Lombard.
- Besides, I don't have anybody to take.
- Take Cindi.
Who took my...?
I like Cin...
Listen, asshole, I'm not gonna
tell you again.
- Yeah, what did you call me?
- Asshole. You heard me.
Rich bastards.
So it's all set, right?
- What?
- Me and Sally,
you and Cindi for tomorrow night.
I like Cindi.
So?
So, Nicky, when I double with you,
I don't take somebody I like.
That's just something I don't do.
All right, that's it. You son of a bitch.
Oh, boy.
Oh, shit.
Get back where you belong.
- All right. All right. All right. All right.
- Come on.
Break it up.
Break it up. I told you,
not on the lanes.
This guy tried to rivet me to the wall.
He was sleeping. He was talking
back there with his friend,
- instead of setting up the pins.
- You're full of crap.
Nicky, will you get
Hopper out of here?
Nicky, please, get Hopper out of here!
Cool him off.
All right, you, clean yourself up
in the bathroom.
- Pin boy.
- Look at my clothes.
- It's an honest living.
Okay, okay, okay, take Julie.
Take Nancy.
- Nancy?
- Why not?
Nancy's married.
All right, Nancy's out.
It doesn't matter who, it doesn't matter
what, as long as it looks like a girl.
I'll tell you what we'll do.
We'll drive out to the lake.
- You can even use the car.
- I don't know, Nicky.
All this back-seat stuff seems
kind of juvenile, you know.
Juvenile? Will you listen to this guy?
Nicky, I don't pay you
to be Hopper's shadow.
It doesn't even have to be a real date.
Just show up at her house
and con the old man.
- Boys, I need more gin.
- Take Alberta. Take...
I know what it is.
You're hot for Sally Kaiser.
- What?
- Either that or you don't think
I'm good enough for her.
Why does she go out with you?
One day at the drugstore,
we introduced ourselves over Cokes.
And I told her I would be
very honored if she...
Nicky, don't you ever think
about anything
- but hiking up some girl's dress?
- Like what?
Like... I don't know.
Like the future, son.
Hop, when you gonna wise up?
The only future we got
is Germans and Japs.
And the way I see it,
in the next six weeks,
I am gonna get everything I can.
I want my money!
What do you think, I do this for free?
Come on, sonny boy.
Hey, hey, hey. Hey.
What's going on here, Annie?
Nothing, this guy just tried
to run off without paying his tab.
I'd pay if I were you, Joe.
This is my last day on furlough.
I swear, I don't have any money.
This is not the USO.
I'll take the watch.
My grandfather gave me that watch.
I wouldn't argue with the lady, buddy.
Get out of here.
Thanks, guys.
Well, love to stay and chat,
but I gotta pay the light bill,
know what I mean?
Hey, Annie, how would you
like to go on a date
tomorrow night with Hopper?
- What happened to your eye?
- Old man's drinking again.
Oh!
I got a run in my stocking.
I don't think we're gonna
get away with this.
You and Sally share classes?
I don't think she's mentioned you.
I graduated a long time ago.
Where'd you get that eye, son?
Bowling, sir.
Sorry I'm late.
Nicky, what happened to your eye?
I'll tell you about it later in the car.
Good night.
Could I have a drink or some candies
or something?
Let's go.
Sorry.
You have such a lovely living room.
Good night.
Here you are, kids.
I thought we were going
to the movies.
Yeah, well, Hop's gotta do
some Christmas shopping.
Bye, kids.
It was great, Hop.
Do you wanna go
for a sundae, maybe?
You mean, ice cream?
Yeah.
Sorry.
When do you ship out?
Six weeks.
Well, listen, angel face,
you're welcome to stop by for
a free ride on the old merry-go-round.
Thanks, Annie.
Oh, I almost forgot.
This is for you.
Thanks, Hop, but I really can't,
I'm allergic.
One, please.
On Capitol Hill, the teenage draft bill
holds the spotlight.
Young men all over the nation
flock to the colors.
The Army and the administration say,
"We need teenage manpower now. "
And here's the response.
- Well, goodbye, I'm going.
- All right now, be sure and write to us.
Bye.
Here is a typical report
from a teenage soldier of today.
I'm 19 years old.
Before entering the service, I was
a doorman at Radio City Music Hall.
After two weeks in the service,
I was appointed corporal...
Come on.
Hi, Sally.
Hi, Hopper.
Where's Nicky?
Where'd you two go last night?
Over to the lake.
What's your dog's name?
Argus.
What's he wearing that for?
He got it for his birthday.
Come on, Argus, time to go home.
Come on. Bye.
Come on.
Goodbye.
Hey, Arnie, can we kill the angels?
God, I hate this music.
It reminds me of my Aunt Ida.
I ever tell you about my Aunt Ida?
Before my Ma died, during Christmas,
we used to have these family things.
And my Aunt Ida was always there
with her goddamn mistletoe hat.
And every time I turned around,
it was her cow lips,
her wet, puckered cow lips on my face.
It was awful.
- When did she die?
- She didn't.
Everyone else did. Practically everyone
in the whole goddamn family.
And I had this theory that it was my
Aunt Ida's kissing that was doing it.
Because they were all dropping dead
in January and February,
and she was doing all the kissing
in December.
There was a definite
cause-and-effect relationship there.
What is he, a friend of yours?
Hopper, why do you keep
looking over there?
No reason.
I saw Sally.
Oh, yeah? Where?
At the Point.
How'd it go with you two?
Okay, I guess. I think I spooked her.
- What do you mean?
- Who knows with women?
- Switch with me.
- What are you...?
- Switch places.
- Jesus, Hopper!
Hurry. There's a draft over...
- Oh, I see. Who is she?
- Who?
Screw, who is she?
- Some girl.
- Hey, Arnie, another victim.
May I help you?
Hi. Yes, what kind of pie
have you got today?
Brown pie.
All right, fine, I'll have a piece.
- And could you wrap it, please?
- You bet.
One piece of brown pie, coming up.
I'd like a piece, mister.
Just a minute, sir.
I'm waiting on the lady.
Oh, I just want one piece.
- It's on special today.
- Oh, thank you. That's very nice.
Thanks a lot. Bye-bye.
Hey, Hopper, what the hell
are you doing?
The man's out of his mind.
- Good night.
Hey.
Wait up.
Hopper, what the hell's
the matter with you?
Oh, Christ, she's a Gatsby.
She works at the goddamn
movie theater.
Her dad probably owns it.
Come on, lover boy, let's go home.
Come on.
Hey.
Customer's not going anywhere,
you know.
Listen, Henry, I know how you
and Nicky wanna get into this thing.
But you gotta understand
it's different for your mother.
This war, it just scares her.
That's why she's riding you so hard.
Now...
...when you get over there,
I want you to write.
Doesn't have to be much, just
a few lines, so she can sleep easier.
You think you can do that, son?
I bet she looks like a rose
and smells as sweet.
What's her name?
I don't even know.
P-47 Thunderbolt.
Bullet-shaped spinner.
Straight trailing.
How the hell should I know?
Oh, Christ.
Oh, Mrs. Spangler.
Religion's a little shaky.
Oh, I forgot, I have to call
Sam O'Reilly about that.
I better do it now.
Damn it, Elmer.
Someday I'm gonna take that cane
away from you.
Hi.
- Hi.
- How was the pie?
Fine.
Can I help you with something?
Oh, no, thanks, just doing
a little college prep work.
I can see.
- Hey, what's your name?
- Why?
What do you mean, why?
I don't go out with strangers.
Who said anything about going out?
Besides, if you told me your name,
we wouldn't be strangers.
I don't think so.
Hey, how'd you like the flowers?
Oh, so you're the one!
Well, at least you're harmless.
Harmless?
What the hell's that mean?
I mean, you could've been
some kind of maniac.
Well, what makes you think
I'm so harmless?
It's not supposed to be an insult.
What are you, some kind of a dolt?
Oh, first I'm harmless, now...
What the hell is this?
Oh, I take it back,
you are definitely not harmless.
Oh, isn't he a dream?
Just looking at him
makes me feel dizzy.
- What'll it be, girls?
- I'll have a grilled-cheese sandwich
- and a cherry Coke.
- Me too.
- So did you think about it?
- What?
You know, Christmas Eve.
- Oh, Gretchen.
- And?
Oh, I don't know.
Blind dates again. I hate new towns.
Oh, come on, Caddie,
it'll be good for you.
We'll have a ball, I promise.
Just one night, right?
He's shipping out
the day after Christmas.
- You'll never see him again.
- You'll be there?
- Every second.
- Do you promise?
- Yes.
- Okay.
Thanks, Caddie!
He really... He's a dream!
If he wasn't my cousin,
I'd go out with him.
He looks just like Robert Walker.
- I bet.
- Well, sort of.
Who are you going with?
I don't know. I was gonna go
with Bobby Michaels,
but he says he's sworn off women
for the duration.
Yeah, this war
is driving them all crazy.
Why not go with one of the boys
from the theater?
Too fresh. Last night,
Eddie Richards tried to drag me
behind the popcorn machine.
You're lucky you're in the booth.
Inside is hell.
Hey, what about this guy?
Henry? How do you know him?
Henry and I sort of ran into each other
at the library.
Henry Nash in the library?
I didn't even think he knew
how to read.
He's sort of cute, don't you think?
Well...
- Yeah, but I couldn't just ask him.
- Oh, come on.
- No, I couldn't ask him.
- Leave it to me. I'll do it. I'll do it.
- Okay.
- Just watch this.
Henry?
I have to apologize, I'm afraid
I was awfully rude earlier.
- Oh, that's all right.
- I didn't introduce myself.
- My name's Caddie Winger.
- Henry Nash.
Oh, it's a pleasure, Henry.
Are you working this afternoon?
Working?
Yeah, you work here, don't you?
Oh, you mean last night.
No, I was just helping out.
Oh, that was nice of you.
- I do what I can.
- Yeah.
Henry, I don't suppose
you're free on Christmas Eve?
- Christmas Eve?
- Yeah, you're probably spending it
- with your family.
- Oh, with my family, right. No.
Oh, no?
Well, what I mean is, I would be,
but my mom, that's my mother,
she's gonna be working
with the USO that night.
And Dad...
Dad's...
- Dad's going fishing.
- Fishing?
- Yeah.
- On Christmas Eve?
Yeah.
At night?
Well, yeah, it's kind of a tradition.
You know how other people
have turkey on Christmas?
We have fish.
Oh, that's great. Well, then,
you are free Christmas Eve?
Definitely.
- You wanna go out?
- Definitely.
Really? Oh, that's great.
I believe you know Gretchen.
- Hi, Henry.
- Hi.
You two will have
such a wonderful time, I know it.
It's perfect.
So anyway, we'll see you there.
- Yeah, okay, see you there.
- Okay.
Okay.
Oh, Henry, we're gonna go
roller-skating. We'll meet at 7.
- You do roller-skate, don't you?
- Sure.
Our men are the best-fed, best-paid,
best-uniformed soldiers in this war.
You look like a used-car salesman.
Where are you going
dressed like that?
I got a date.
With who?
A girl.
What are you, Mr. District Attorney?
A boy should stay home with his family
on Christmas Eve.
I'll be home all day tomorrow, Ma.
Merry Christmas.
Hey.
Oh, hi, Dad. Thanks for the flowers.
Yeah, you look just like I did
the first time I wore that suit.
- You don't think it's too big?
- You'll grow into it.
By 8:00?
There he is, I see him.
Hey, Nash.
You got your skates.
Yeah, they wouldn't let me in
unless I put them on first.
This is Michael.
- Henry Nash.
- Glad to meet you.
Michael just got his wings.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
What branch are you joining?
- Marines.
- Tough group.
I'll try not to drop anything
on you, huh?
Sorry, everybody. Hi, Henry.
These are for you.
Oh, they're beautiful.
Where'd you get them?
I just kind of picked them up.
Henry's very big on flowers.
Aren't you?
Yeah, sure.
Well, shall we?
All right.
Something wrong?
No. Go ahead.
I'm just gonna warm up.
Okay.
Hey, mister, leave me alone.
Hey.
Let go of my hand.
Let go!
That looked scary.
Only if you don't know
what you're doing.
That was great.
Thanks very much.
Does anyone feel like
taking a breather?
I wouldn't mind.
Well, Gretch, I guess
it's you and me, huh?
You damn Marines.
- You need a hand, huh?
- I do, yes.
Hey, buddy. Hey, you're not allowed
on the floor without any skates.
- No drinks either.
- Relax, I'm leaving.
Here.
Must've gotten a bad pair of skates.
Yeah.
So tell me about Michael.
What do you wanna know
about Michael?
Like...
Like, is he my boyfriend
or something?
Excuse me?
So your dad's out fishing tonight,
isn't he?
Fishing, right.
No.
No?
- I sort of lied.
- You did? Why'd you do that?
What does your dad do?
He's a gravedigger.
It's not all just digging holes,
like everybody thinks.
There's the grass and the flowers
to look after.
Trees always need cutting back.
Something about being near the ocean
makes everything grow faster.
That's what he says.
He keeps it real nice.
It's a nice place.
Why don't you
take me there sometime.
She's a Gatsby girl.
If you ask me, you're barking
up the wrong pair of gams.
Who asked?
- I'm just looking out for you!
- Right.
All right, wise guy, listen to this:
I heard the Nazis got this thing, right?
It comes right out of the ground
and goes right for it.
Blows the whole package right off.
One second, you're John Wayne,
and the next, you're Minnie Mouse.
- Nicky, there are other things.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Like what?
Like, other things.
Okay. I just hate to see you spend
the last few weeks of your manhood
- chasing something you can't catch.
- Go away.
Oh, I get it!
You want a picture for your wallet.
You want some girl who's gonna send
you flowers, poems and sweethearts...
- Shut up!
- That's it, isn't it?
- Yeah, well, what's wrong with that?
- Nothing.
But I'll tell you something.
I ain't gonna be no sap to some skirt.
Because when I finish killing Japs,
I ain't coming back here.
I want nothing to do with this place.
- Give me your hand.
- Thank you.
- Here.
- What is this place?
Danny's Tap Room.
Or what's left of it.
This is the stage.
That...
...used to be the bar.
Over in the corner used to be
a couple of nickelodeon machines.
They're gone now.
My dad used to sneak me in here.
What do you do here?
Whatever I want.
What do you think?
It's kind of spooky.
- You wanna leave?
- No.
Just feels like someone's listening.
What is this?
This is...
...the best thing about this place.
A piano.
Does it work?
- Plays up a storm.
- It couldn't.
It could. It's magic.
- Magic?
- Magic.
- Do you play?
- A little.
Play something.
Not a key sticks.
How'd you learn to play like that?
Lessons.
The day Eddie Richards tries to throw
Tommy Lester out at third base...
...hits him in the head...
...I'm doing this...
...for Mr. Arthur, my teacher.
Tommy gets a concussion...
...and I miss it.
And I've never forgiven my mother
for that.
Wish I could play like that.
Come here.
Come here, I'll teach you.
Come on, sit down.
Okay, give me your hand.
Okay, you do this.
Repeat it.
That's it?
Well, you could try my part.
What's your part?
Think I'd better go.
When do you leave?
Next month.
- Hi. Sorry, I forgot my key.
- Oh, it's all right.
- What's this?
- Alice brought you a present.
Oh, they're back.
- Did you get something?
- Yes.
She gave me some scented soap,
and they gave me a robe.
Is it pretty?
It's pretty. It's a size 44.
- It's pretty.
- Oh, Mom.
- Where is she?
- She's upstairs.
I'm gonna try it on.
Just a minute.
- Alice, this is beautiful.
- Well, I thought it would be.
You know, it annoys the hell out of me
that I can't wear that color.
I don't know what to say.
- "Merry Christmas" will do.
- Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas, Caddie.
Sit down.
I thought that your first Christmas
in a new town,
where you knew maybe three people,
wouldn't be your favorite.
Thank you, Alice.
Alice.
Hello, Caddie. Merry Christmas.
Don't you look pretty!
Merry Christmas, Mr. Donnelly.
Alice, I'm down in the pantry
with whipped cream and eggs
- all over the place. Will you hurry?
- I'm hurrying, Daddy.
How do you like those pearls, Caddie?
Beautiful.
- Please, darling.
- Yes, Daddy.
- Hey, Nash.
- Hi.
Aren't you supposed to be in school?
Sometimes I just don't make it.
How come?
I don't know. Figure, what's the point?
If you were in school, you wouldn't
have to leave so soon.
Well, a war's going on. I'm gonna have
to go sooner or later. What about you?
Oh, I got to finish up early at my
old school because we were moving.
Oh, that's good.
So I guess you got plans
for this morning.
No.
You?
No, I don't.
- Sure you know where you're going?
- Positive.
Nicky put an arrow
around here someplace.
That tree!
There's an arrow on the other side
of that tree.
- There is!
- That arrow points directly to the pond.
Good ol' Nicky.
Points straight up.
Nicky always was a fool.
Well...
We know it's not that way,
so it's gotta be that way,
that way or that way.
Or somewhere in between.
Right.
I wish Argus was here.
You found it?
Oh, that's beautiful.
How did you find this place anyway?
My father sort of gave it
to me and Nicky.
Gave it to you?
He'd make these maps,
these treasure maps,
and then me and Nicky
would follow them
and dig whatever was up
at the other end.
One time we ended up here.
He wrapped up this watch.
See there?
And he put it out there in the middle.
Me and Nicky spent
what must've been about an hour
sloshing around in the mud
on the bottom.
Crawling around.
I don't think my dad cared
whether we ever found the watch.
It was this place.
Yeah.
He sounds wonderful.
What do you say we cool off?
It's January.
It's hot.
Henry, we can come back
in the spring, when it warms up.
I won't be here when it warms up.
Come on, what do you say?
- It's hot.
Hot! I'm so hot.
I don't have my bathing suit on.
Well, when me and Nicky came here,
we never used to wear bathing suits.
All right.
You can wear your understuff
if you wanna.
Seeing as it's January and all.
Come on, it's great!
Come on!
Hurry up!
Just jump in.
It's pretty cold.
So does anybody else
know about this place?
I don't think so.
- I guess we have it to ourselves, then.
- Yeah. Guess so.
You know, it's not that bad.
I think I'm getting used to it.
Yeah, your body just has to adjust.
What made you think of coming here?
I don't know.
It's one of my favorite places.
You're shaking.
So are you.
She's a nice girl.
And money on top of it all.
You're lucky, Hop.
I think she's the one, Nicky.
You know what I mean?
Johnny Lester came in today.
His brother's dead.
Tommy?
He died on an island.
Guadel, or...
- Guod...
- Guadalcanal.
Yeah.
Funeral's tomorrow.
Johnny said we're invited. Wanna go?
- I don't think so.
- Yeah.
Me either.
You know what I want, Henry?
I want an eagle right here.
A tattoo. Yeah.
Just wait till those Japs see me and
my eagle come charging over the hill.
Just come charging over the hill.
There's a war out there
somewhere, Hop.
So they're in this submarine, right?
And the Japs are going at them
with everything they got.
Guys are drowning. Guys are on fire.
There are sharks, and they got guns.
So you know
what Tyrone Power says?
He says, "Fuck them!" Just like that.
Tyrone Power never said,
"Fuck them. "
Right. And that's when he does it.
He just... He just surfaces
in the middle of Tokyo Harbor.
Jeez!
What balls!
Maybe we should join
the submarine corps.
Pussies.
- What?
- They're pussies!
No, Tyrone Power is not a pussy.
You wouldn't know a pussy
if you saw one.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah. You know why?
You know why?
Because you drink too much.
- Me?!
- Pisses me off!
Pisses me off badly!
Because when you drink too much,
it makes your brain soft.
Let me see...
I gotta show you something.
Before I started drinking,
I could not do that!
- Why would you wanna do that?
- It gives me pleasure.
Right here!
Clear across my goddamn chest.
- A real patriot, huh?
- Damn right!
In just four short weeks,
me and my buddy here
are gonna be proud members
of the United States Marine Corps.
Lucky us.
Listen, kid,
I'm gonna do you a favor.
I'm not gonna put anything
on your chest.
That way, when you wake up
in the morning,
you still will have that wonderful
baby-pink skin.
You'll thank me, believe me.
Hey, wait a minute. This is the bird
of freedom we're talking about here.
Ain't no American that wouldn't be
proud to carry that over his heart.
You ought to cut down
on the newsreels, kid.
Hey, what is this,
you give tattoos or advice?
All right, how much do you boys got?
I...
...got $1.25.
I got 13 cents.
A dollar thirty-eight will get you
a sparrow on your elbow.
- A sparrow?
- Or how about a snake
coming out of your navel?
Now, that's real popular!
You've gotta be kidding!
He's kidding, right, Hop?
I'm talking about the high-flying red-
white-and-blue bird of freedom here!
Bird of freedom don't come cheap.
A snake coming out of my navel.
He's probably some kind of a Nazi.
Hey...
...listen.
It's the train.
Touch the rail with your shoe,
you can feel it.
Let's race it, like when we were kids.
We're drunk.
Who cares? I wanna race it.
- We'll get killed.
- No, we won't.
No, we won't.
This train's an old friend.
It would never hurt us.
Here she comes!
Come on, Hopper!
Race with me!
Race with me, Hop!
Nicky!
Hey, Nicky, where you going?
Hey, wait up, will you?
Are you all right?
She's late, Hop.
What?
Sally. She's pregnant.
What are you talking about?
Three weeks till we leave,
and she hits me with this.
She told me this afternoon.
You gotta help me, Hop.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
To get the money.
Money?
For an abortion.
An abortion? Nicky!
Didn't you use anything?
It just happened.
Just happened? Nicky, you been
seeing this girl for four months!
So?!
- So Jesus Christ, Nicky!
- "So Jesus Christ, Nicky. "
"Jesus Christ, Nicky!"
I'm paying for it, all right?!
No, she's paying for it, Nicky!
She's paying for it!
Hop.
Hop, since when did you become
such a saint, huh?
Huh, Hop?
The only difference between me
and you is you've been lucky.
That's all!
That's it, Hop!
How much?
Annie says it costs 150
for a clean one.
A hundred-fifty? Nicky, where are we
gonna get that kind of money?
Do like we did last summer,
when we needed a transmission
for the Plymouth.
We almost got killed!
Well, what other way is there?
I'll think about it. Come on.
My dear friends in Christ,
we are gathered here today to lay to
rest the soul of Thomas Alan Lester,
who gave his life
for the service of his country.
To the flag, face!
To the front, face!
Forward, hup!
To the flag, face!
Hello there, stranger.
You up early or late?
Late.
Let your mother know next time,
all right?
Okay.
You wanna talk?
Let's hurry, nurses,
we don't want to lose anyone!
More volume, Arnold!
And remember, soldiers,
if you're wounded, remain lying down
until a nurse reaches you.
If you're dead,
remain lying down.
Try and give a little comfort
to your patient.
Remember, blood doesn't bother you,
because you're professional nurses.
I think he might be dead already.
Oh, sorry.
- Where are you hurt, soldier?
- He slipped away.
Wait a minute,
I seem to be coming around.
- I'll come back when you got this.
- No, wait! Please, nurse!
I wanna show you my wound.
- R.D. Stop.
- Why?
Get on!
- What are you guys doing?
- Go to the records.
You're looking after a sick man,
so be very, very careful.
That's the idea.
You might get some bandages there
on your left.
Arnold, go to the office. Your mother
called. You gotta call her right away.
- What about my records?
- We'll watch them!
- But...
- It's an emergency, Arnold.
No "buts," man! Hop to it!
It's your mom!
Hurry! Berlin Blitz is just about to end.
Prepare for the worst shelling yet.
What the hell is going on here?
Stop that carrying on, will you?!
Just hold it!
Stop that!
That's not funny.
- It's a joke.
- It's not funny.
- It's not a funny joke?
- No.
You know, you're really
stupid sometimes.
What's that supposed to mean?
What're you doing right now?
- Bleeding.
- I can see that.
Why don't you go get yourself
cleaned up and meet me outside.
- Where are we going?
- You'll see.
- It's a hospital.
- That's right. Smart.
- Hi, Barbara.
- I'm smart.
- Yeah, you're smarter than you look.
- I'm smarter than I look?
That's good.
Good idea. You having fun?
- I'm having a real good time.
- Oh, I'm glad.
I'm glad you're having fun.
Hi!
You know who's in here?
- Sick people.
- That's right. You wanna go in?
- You bet!
- Okay.
Here we are!
All right.
Henry Nash, right here. Henry Nash.
He's my bodyguard.
All right? So don't try any funny stuff,
because I know what you're up to here.
Henry, give each person
on this side a book.
Leave one on the empty beds,
because that means they're in therapy.
Good. Hi. I'm glad you're up.
- Oh, good, you found it.
- They had it on order or something.
- What would you like?
- You got any Hammett?
- Hammett?
- Yeah. Dashiell Hammett.
- I'll check the cart.
- That's okay. Forget it.
- It'll just take a second.
- No, that's all right. Relax, forget it.
What's your name?
Henry, sir.
How old are you?
Seventeen, sir.
How old do you think I am?
I'm 22.
You call everybody who's 22 "sir"?
No, sir. I mean, no.
My name's Frank.
Guess they'll be calling you up
pretty soon, huh, Henry?
February 12th.
Go ahead, look at it.
I do. All day long.
Sometimes, you know, I can still feel it.
That's the God's truth.
Only I half-believe it's gone.
Get it?
Half.
I'll just... Give me whatever
you got there, I don't...
Thanks.
Henry.
There's a train that runs through here.
Freight.
Me and Nicky must've raced it
about a hundred times.
You get close enough, you can
feel the heat on your legs.
Gondola car's your best bet.
It's got these handles
that stick out on the sides.
Once you get your grip, it's easy.
You just pull up and let her take you.
You gotta be careful
when you jump,
because the wind will blow
you right under.
That sounds dangerous.
That's why we did it.
If you think I needed you to teach me
some kind of lesson today,
you're wrong!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I took you in there.
It's just, you made me
so mad this morning.
How come you never talk about it?
What?
The war.
- Well, what's there to talk about?
- You must think about it.
I think about it all the time.
I mean, before, it was just there, but in
the last few weeks, being around you...
...I think about things.
Like what sort of things?
Coming back.
I'm gonna be all right, you know?
Tangerine
She is all they claim
With her eyes of night
And lips as bright as flame
Tangerine
When she dances by
Seoritas stare and caballeros sigh
And I've seen
Times when Tangerine
Had the bourgeoisie
Believing she were queen
Yes, she's had them all on the run
But her heart belongs to just one
Her heart belongs to Tangerine
Nicky!
Why do I let you work here?
Because when the heat's on,
there's nobody can lay down
a set of pins faster than me.
- I'm the best you got.
- No, you're not.
Oh.
Well, then, you got me, boss.
So?
So, what?
- So you said you'd think about it.
- About what?
Come on! Sally, the money.
I am thinking about it.
Hop, we only got a couple weeks.
Shit.
Come on, get up. Get up.
Get up!
Get up, come on.
Okay, you're gonna get it.
You are going to be sorry.
You see this?
Oh! Oh, I'm sorry! Oh, I didn't...
Oh, I'm sorry. Oh, come here,
let me see.
Let me see.
Oh, I got you in the eye. Oh.
Oh, look at those shoes,
aren't they pretty? See.
Don't you like those?
I love those. Aren't they beautiful?
- How they feel?
- I like them.
- I love them.
- Of course.
They were made for you!
- How much are they?
- Oh, $25.
Twenty-five!
It's not unreasonable for such
marvelous work, don't you think?
Not unreasonable.
Well, thank you.
That's all right. You think about it.
You'll come back, I'm sure.
- Oh, thank you. Yeah.
- Well, anyway...
- I really... I love them.
- It's a pleasure.
Thanks a lot.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Henry.
What happened?
You didn't buy the shoes.
Of course not.
You can't just buy everything
you want, you know.
That's right. I can't.
I'm just kidding you, Gatsby girl.
What? But how?
I don't know.
- It's not funny.
- Well, it is, sort of.
- Well, it is sort of funny, isn't it?
- It isn't, no.
Look, did you actually ever
tell him you were rich?
- No.
- Well, then, there you go.
No skin off your nose, right?
If he wants to believe that he
is stuck on some rich girl, let him.
As far as I can see,
you've got no problem.
I don't know.
Maybe that's why he likes me.
Well, so what? I mean,
he's leaving soon anyway.
I mean, it's not like you're in love
with him or anything, right?
Uh-oh.
One thirty-five, please.
- Hi.
- Caddie.
- I thought you had to work.
- I do.
I just thought I'd drop by,
thought maybe we could talk.
- We're kind of busy. Hi, R.D.
- Hi, Hop.
- Is 1 and 2 open?
- Yeah.
You're coming to
my birthday tomorrow, right?
- Yeah.
- It's not much, just you and Nicky,
probably.
I wanna talk because...
Caddie, I gotta...
Just sit down a second, okay?
- What are you doing here?
- What am I gonna do?
Look, I've got this thing
under control, all right?
Nicky, you promised.
- You didn't have to come in here.
- What am I gonna do?
- You promised.
- Stop saying I promised you.
- Why do you have to come here?
- Don't leave me by myself.
I'm not leaving you by yourself.
You're gonna be okay.
Women.
Thank you.
What's the matter with that girl?
- Oh, nothing.
- Hopper.
I gotta go.
You look real pretty.
I'll do it.
They're too big.
What do you mean, they're too big?
You're gonna shoot pool with them,
not wrestle them.
I'm thinking about after
I shoot pool with them
and they figure out they been hustled.
And they will figure it out.
They're just a couple
stupid uniforms.
Besides, there's a fire exit
right over there.
Just in case.
Afternoon, gents.
Someone said one of you
was looking for a game.
Someone said wrong.
That's what I thought.
He must be wrong,
because I never knew any Navy boy
who had the skill to play for money.
It's all that time on ships,
does something to their balance.
There's nothing wrong
with my balance.
No, of course not.
Don't let me hold up your game.
That's a tough break.
Wanna play? I'll play you.
No, not me. I got a bad wrist.
But my friend will play.
How about it?
- Sure.
- Great.
- Hey, what's your name?
- Bill.
Glad to meet you, Bill.
I'm Bud... and that's Lou.
Now that we're all friends,
let's get down to some business.
How's 5 dollars sound?
Yeah, that sounds okay.
Eight-ball's the game.
You do know how to play
eight-ball, don't you, Bill?
I know how.
Terrific.
Eight in the corner.
That's 20 bucks you owe me, sport.
No, no, no. Now, William...
...not so fast. My boy,
he's just warming up.
How about if we make things
a little more interesting?
How about if we see
some green on the table?
Does this answer your question?
Nobody touches my money!
- Some of that money's mine.
- Not yet, it ain't.
Ten bucks a game, all right?
Oh, shit.
Nicky, let's get out of here, right now.
Would you relax?
This is perfect.
Excuse me, boys.
We've got a little contest
going on here.
And I thought you might be interested
in a little action.
What kind of action?
Well, it just so happens
that yesterday morning, I sold my car.
A dandy little 1932 Plymouth.
It's all here, 150 bucks.
- I don't have that kind of money.
- Now, William, I'm sure you don't.
But maybe your shipmates do.
How about it, guys?
You willing to back your buddy?
He is really on a roll.
- How much you got?
- Wait a minute, guys!
That's a lot of money.
What's the matter, William?
Are you losing your nerve?
- I got 40.
- I got 60.
Hundred and fifty bucks, straight pool.
First one to a hundred.
Is that okay with you, Bud,
or was it Lou?
- Call it.
- Heads.
Tails. You break.
Fourteen in the corner.
Two, corner.
Five, cross corner.
- So?
- Seven in the side.
- He's good.
- How good?
- Thirteen in the corner.
- A lot better than he was
five minutes ago.
Four in the corner.
Twelve in the corner.
Three in the side.
Rack them.
Two in the corner.
Thirteen in the side.
Four in the side.
Twelve in the corner.
Fifteen in the side.
Eight in the corner.
Three in the corner.
Rack them.
Ten in the corner.
Eight, corner.
Five in the corner.
Fifteen in the side.
Eleven in the corner.
Rack them.
One in the corner.
Twelve in the corner.
Five in the corner.
Nine in the corner.
Fourteen in the corner.
Rack them.
Six, corner.
Seven, corner.
Ten, corner.
Fourteen in the corner.
Oh, eat Martian head, you're dead!
Two more points!
What's wrong?
I don't have a shot.
Well, what are you gonna do?
Make sure he doesn't have one either.
Three in the corner.
Oh, no, he can't make that, right?
Right?
- One more.
- Seven in the side.
That's the one we want.
Well, fair is fair, boys.
We'll just be running along.
- You don't mind if we count it, do you?
- Count it.
It's not that we don't trust you.
Bad idea, boys.
There seems to be
some kind of mix-up here.
Hopper, you know
anything about this?
What are you doing?
I know for a fact that when we walked
into this establishment and...
Shit.
Duck, Hopper!
Run.
Go!
- What the hell's wrong?
- Sometimes it takes time...
If you don't get this car started,
my dad's gonna have two more
holes to dig tomorrow. Let's go!
It's about time. What the hell
happened to you two?
Never mind, just get cleaned up.
You know what trouble
your mother's gone to?
You'd think you could be on time
for your own birthday, Henry.
- What happened?
- We had a run-in
- with the U.S. Navy.
- What? Where?
Up north.
- What were you doing up north?
- Playing pool.
- Actually, it was more like hustling pool.
- Nicky!
We needed money. A lot of money.
- Knock it off.
- What?!
- I know what you're doing.
- We're leaving here in a week.
- No.
- She's our last chance.
- Shut up!
- What am I supposed to do,
leave Sally here pregnant?
You son of a bitch!
What's going on?
Damn it, Caddie, I need $150!
You got some mouth, you know that?
I told you boys to get ready.
Come on now, speed it up.
Henry, what's the matter?
Will you sit down, Caddie?
Caddie, this is very hard for me.
The way I been raised, these
people just don't ask for things.
See...
...that girl you saw last night...
...Nicky got her pregnant.
And we gotta get her an abortion.
A clean abortion costs $150.
Nicky and I don't have
that kind of money.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm not sure.
Caddie...
...can you get us the money?
It's $150, and I'll make sure
you get every bit of it back.
I'll see what I can do.
Caddie, what are you doing here?
Why do you have my necklace?
You should have asked first.
Relax. It... It's okay, really.
Do you want to try it on?
Come on.
- Oh, no. I couldn't.
- Caddie.
What is the matter with you?
L... I want to go downstairs, I think.
Why are you so nervous?
Alice, I didn't come in here to try it on.
What are you talking about?
I came because I need money,
and the necklace is the only way
I could think of.
I don't understand. Why would
you do something like that?
Caddie, are you in trouble?
Oh, Alice. Alice.
I've made such a mess of things.
There is somebody who needs
something from me,
and he thinks I'm special,
and I just wanna give it to him.
I almost did a horrible thing,
but it's only because
I don't wanna let him down.
I wonder what it would be like
to be you sometimes.
I mean...
...I look around here, and everything
seems so much easier for you.
Not so much.
I'll get you the money.
I don't want you in there.
I guess they should be starting
in a few minutes.
They say it doesn't take too long.
There's another girl coming in at 11.
Boy, 150 bucks a shot,
that's some business, huh?
You should go in there
and hold her hand, Nicky.
She doesn't want me in there.
Oh, I'm sick.
- the exact location
from which I'm speaking.
Off to my left, far away
in the distance,
I can see just that faint, red,
angry snap
of antiaircraft bursts
against a steel-blue sky.
- Nicky.
- Huh?
- Will you stop, please?
Will you stop, please?
Stop the car, please?
- What's the matter, Caddie?
- I wanna get out.
Cad, it's only a few more blocks.
Would you stop the damn car?!
- Cad. Caddie, where you going?
- Home.
- I'll walk you.
- No, I don't want you to walk me.
I know what you're thinking.
You're thinking that could've been you
in there. Well, you're wrong, Caddie.
I'd never take you to a place
like that, I'd marry you.
Did you hear what I said?
I'd marry you.
Oh, well, what makes you think
I'd marry you?
- Get back in the car.
- No.
- Get back in the goddamn car.
- Let go of my arm.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't know you were gonna
end up running into that place.
What do you want from me?
I don't want anything from you.
Hey, I'm talking to you.
It's the money, right?
You think I took advantage of you
because I asked you for that money.
Well, Caddie, we needed that money,
and you're the only rich person I know.
You are such an idiot.
I'm not rich.
- What?
- I'm not rich.
What are you talking about?
Yes, I live in that house on the hill.
Do you know why I live in that house?
Because my mother
works in that house.
My mom is a maid.
She's a maid in that house.
Goddamn you!
I tried to tell you
about a million times.
But you are so pleased
with your little girl on the hill
that I didn't wanna disappoint you.
Just leave me alone.
Leave me alone.
Hop, you coming?
Hop.
What are you doing?
This is my old man's car,
you crazy son of a bitch.
What the hell's the matter with you?
You, Nicky, you're
what's the matter with me.
You're always making your life
a mess,
and I'm always getting you out of it.
- Hey, it's over. It's all fixed.
- Shut up. Shut up.
Sally could've died tonight, Nicky.
That ever cross your mind?
But she didn't.
Jesus, you just don't get it, do you?
And then you get her mixed up in it.
I'm sick of you messing up
my life, Nicky.
I'm sick of it.
You didn't even open the door
for her, Nicky.
Girl just had an abortion,
you can't even get out of the car
and open the door for her.
Damn cold for February.
Laid a bed of these last night.
This morning, the ground
was still like rock.
I don't know what it is.
Your mom says Nicky's been by
the house three times this past week.
Well, you know your own mind.
Just seems you two could use
each other's company about now.
You know, for a time,
right after his mom died,
Nicky brought flowers here
every day.
Come after school, just sit there.
Be so tired, I'd have to carry him
home on my shoulders.
Did you know that?
Yeah, well, it was a long time ago.
Damn cold for February.
Yeah.
How you doing?
- Okay. You?
- Okay.
- Thursday's the big day, huh?
- Yeah, I guess so.
You ready?
- You bet.
- Me too.
- I went by and I saw Sally.
- Yeah?
Just to see how she was doing
and everything, you know.
- How is she?
- She's good.
That's good.
You know what she said to me
just before I left?
She said,
"Take care of yourself, Nick. "
Can you beat that?
We gotta stick together, Nicky.
We gotta stick together.
Yeah.
Why don't you try them on.
I already know they fit.
I love you, Caddie.
I love you, Henry.
Don't cry, Mom.
I'm not crying.
You come back and play for me.
Board!
- Keep your eyes peeled.
- I will, Dad.
- You too, Nicky.
- I will, sir.
Take care.
I brought something for you.
It's for your wallet.
All aboard.
Board.
You boys better be getting on.
Be safe.
- Son, your train is leaving.
- What's the matter with him?
Henry? Henry.
Your train. Your train!
Henry. Henry.
- Henry.
- Son, your train.
- Nicky.
- Henry.
- What's the matter?
- Ready, buddy?
- Ready.