[instrumental music]
[sniffs]
[music continues]
[motorcycle engine revving]
[tires screeching]
Yes!
[Thomas Newman singing
"Understanding Gravity"]
À®ä I'll always say no À®ä
À®ä That only regret is you À®ä
À®ä To be totally cold À®ä
À®ä Will you jump with me out À®ä
À®ä And when the rain falls down... À®ä
Tracey, it is fucking freezing.
À®ä So lost in the world... À®ä
- Here.
- Ah.
[female #1]
This'll warm you up.
[chuckling]
I could warm him up.
[laughing]
- Tracey!
- Oh, shit. No.
- Tracey, come on!
- Tray, come on.
[engine revving]
[female #2]
Tracey!
[engine revving]
[male #1]
Tracey! Tracey!
[screaming]
Fuckin' dork.
À®ä Understanding gravity À®ä
Are we dead?
No.
[tires screeching]
[screams]
[clanking]
[instrumental music]
- Hey, Randy!
- Hey, Mr. Johnson.
Hey, come here.
[indistinct chattering]
- Hi. How are you?
- Fine.
- Good to see you.
- Behave yourself now.
- Hey, you know who he is?
- Yes.
[male #2]
Hey, Randy.
Oh.
Hey, Mark.
You got a lane?
- Yeah.
- Good.
- Hi, Tracey.
- Hi, dad.
Hi, son.
- Ralph was just by.
- Ralph was here?
- Yeah, what'd he say?
- Looks good.
I'm gonna, uh,
meet you in the back, okay?
Alright.
Hey, Tracey, give me a quarter.
Get your own quarter.
Come on!
Asshole.
Hey, I like you too.
Hey, so listen to this.
Hey, Bennario! My face
is leaving in five minutes.
- Be on it.
- Pfft.
I'm not that drunk.
Not yet.
[Randy]
Anyway my father was talking
to chief of operations
and he says I might hear
about the job pretty soon.
- Maybe even before Christmas.
- That's great.
Yeah, it's pretty unusual for
someone to start that high up.
It's pretty unusual
for someone to have a job.
[beeps]
Hey, rich boy.
Give me a dollar.
- What's wrong?
- Come on!
[male #3]
Quit it!
Hey!
You jerk.
- What are you doing later?
- Leave me alone!
Going to bed.
[male #4]
With who?
Myself.
[chuckles]
- What good is that?
- It's good for sleeping.
Come on, stop tilting it.
How about I join you?
Pink's going straight home too.
Why don't you get
your own fucking place?
Give me the money.
Oh, shit!
Goddamnit!
[indistinct chatter]
[male #4]
It's funny, huh?
You gettin' all...
- Get out of here.
- He spilled...
Get out of here!
- Where is she?
- She's in the bathroom.
[Tracey]
David!
Yeah?
- What were you doin'?
- Nothin'.
These guys
were just being assholes.
- Rourke's the asshole.
- He is not.
Weren't you supposed to be
home by now?
- Where's mom and dad?
- I don't know.
They went out.
Leave me alone.
[indistinct chatter]
You fool. I had to pay
for this uniform.
[door closes]
What're you doing?
- Hmm.
- What're you doing?
- Stop it.
- Mm-hmm.
Please.
Stop it.
[moaning]
[indistinct chatter]
- Hey, how you doin'?
- Hey, Rand.
[door opens]
[door closes]
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
Why does something always
have to be the matter?
You never wanna do anything.
We're in the middle of a parking
lot. What do you wanna do?
Show off to your friends,
so they think you're a big man?
- What are you doing, Daniels?
- Hey.
[chuckles]
- Hey, you'll dent it!
- Oh, sorry.
[chuckles]
[chuckling]
Listen, I really am tired.
I mean, if you wanna go
with those guys...
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
Alright, um,
see you tomorrow, okay?
Okay.
Hey, wait up!
You idiots.
[engine revving]
[instrumental music]
[indistinct chatter]
- Hey.
- Oh.
- Hi.
- Late night?
- Hmm.
And?
What?
Where'd you go with those guys?
- Nowhere.
- Yeah, right.
Yeah, right.
- You could have come.
- Pfft!
- You could...
- That would have been fun, huh?
[chuckles]
- Hi, coach.
- Lookout, boys.
Lookout, lookout.
[chuckles]
Oh, God, there's Coach Barton.
- Hey.
- Hey, Coach Barton.
- Hi.
Hi, girls.
You're gonna give
our papers back today?
[Barton]
Maybe.
[Cathy]
Were you too busy last night
to grade 'em?
Oh, God, can you get
suspended for raping a teacher?
[chuckles]
Fuck you.
God, he is weird.
[Barton]
Shh! Shh! Okay, come on.
Come on, settle down.
Settle down. As soon as you get
your card, just look up here.
[indistinct chatter]
[female #3]
I need another card.
[male #5]
Back here.
[Barton]
Come on, quiet, quiet.
We gotta get this done today.
Okay, this is about Career Day...
...your ideas, goals.
One, what do you wanna be?
What do you hope
to get out of life?
Okay, come on, start writing.
Why do we gotta do this?
I already explained
to you, it's to, uh...
...get us ready
for Career Day.
Suppose we don't know
what we wanna do?
[Barton]
We're not asking for a lifetime commitment.
We just wanna know
what are your hopes.
Your fantasies,
your dreams for the future.
I know you got 'em.
Suppose we don't have any?
Then just copy off the kid
next to you, alright?
[indistinct chatter]
Good luck.
Come on, come on.
This is important.
You're only gonna be in this
playpen a couple of more months.
Tracey.
[Barton]
Alright, everybody finish
start passing the cards forward.
[bell rings]
[Barton]
Alright. Everybody hand in your cards.
[indistinct chatter]
[Barton]
Alright, now, don't leave
without handin' in these cards.
Hey, Johnny.
Don't be late for practice.
You're the coach.
[shouting]
There's still a lot of money
to be made at that mill.
Ah, you're dreaming.
Why? Just 'cause I wanna make
something out of myself?
[male #6]
Round here, there ain't
nothin' to make but it.
You're already getting that.
[male #7]
Just better be careful
you're gonna screw yourself,
you little scrub.
[male #8]
Hey, Randy Daniels screws!
He doesn't get screwed.
[male #9]
Keep it up and it's gonna fall off.
Hey, don't sweat it.
[Johnny laughing]
What're you laughing at?
Oh, nothing.
Yeah, you're just jealous.
Right.
[Johnny laughing]
Well, you're probably
not gettin' anythin'.
I never see you with anybody.
It's 'cause I'm saving
myself for you, big boy.
Alright, get out of here,
you fuckin' queer.
Hey, what ever happened
to you, Rourke?
You used to be normal.
I grew out of it.
Practice.
Hey!
Looks good.
[grunting]
[Tracey]
Ready, okay!
Let's get fired up!
[crowd]
We are fired up!
[chanting]
Let's get fired up!
[crowd]
We are fired up!
Let's get fired up!
[crowd cheering]
[Randy]
Two run left. Motion.
Twenty five dive. On two.
- Ready?
- Ready!
[all cheering]
[shouting]
Set!
[indistinct shouting]
Go!
[whistle blows]
Time! Time! Time!
Come here!
- Ready?
- Okay!
[chanting]
We have got
the number one feeling.
We are gonna do for you tonight.
[clapping]
Alright, now,
we're doing another...
- Why don't we...
- You use pro set. What?
- What did you...
- Nineteen keeper.
Their linebackers are way inside
let's run it.
- Harry.
- Yeah.
Hey, what's the inside
linebacker doing?
Alright, Rourke, you've got it.
Nineteen keeper.
Nineteen keeper, just go.
Show 'em what we're gonna do!
- Alright, let's do it.
- Go. Go. Go.
[crowd cheering]
Turn around. Alright. Win right.
Nineteen keeper on two.
- Ready?
- Ready.
[in unison]
Win! Win! Win!
[screaming]
- Alright. This'll work.
- Come on, let's go now.
This'll work. It will.
[shouting]
Set!
On!
[Randy]
Ready!
Go!
[crowd]
Go! Go! Go!
[all cheering]
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[engine revving]
[tires screeching]
[instrumental music]
[woman on loudspeaker]
Talent show tryouts
are this Wednesday
3:30 p.m. in the gymnasium.
All singers are required
to bring their own sheet music.
Pep club will meet in room 237
immediately after school.
As you all know,
The Annual Tin Can-Can
is happening this Wednesday.
And as you also know each year
we have a special lottery
just to liven up the event.
The way it works
is that five senior MVPs
of Roosevelt's
winning football team
will accompany the five
senior cheerleaders.
Couples were matched
at random, and each will enjoy
free tickets to the dance.
And the lucky couples are...
Kepner Dulcick and Karen Sybern.
- Oh, man.
- Shut up.
Gus Ulensky and Cathy Bennario.
Randy Daniels and...
...uh, Mary Pat Sykes.
Scott Metcalf and Monica Johnson.
And Johnny Rourke and Tracey Prescott.
- Did you hear that?
- Holy shit!
What the hell happened?
I fixed it myself.
You tell me.
[chuckling]
[indistinct chatter]
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[woman on TV]
Oh, I've been looking
for you everywhere.
[man on TV]
Well, they got married,
and lived happily ever after.
[woman on TV]
It's just a tiny, tiny problem, isn't it?
When the clock strikes
12:00, I'm gonna
change right back into...
Hey!
Where you going with my jacket?
Don't worry, I'm not gonna hurt it.
Such a skinny little shit.
I used to really fill out
those shoulders.
[woman on TV]
You don't seem to understand.
I gotta go.
- Come here.
- I gotta go.
Just come here!
- What?
- What is this?
You wanna go to dance
looking like an asshole?
[chuckles]
You look like a fuckin' farmer.
There. Looks like a tie.
Watch it.
- What's this for?
- You don't want it?
Give it back.
No.
I'll think of somethin'.
[woman on TV]
So that's what's been
the matter with you.
Well, I'm glad it's out, Bob
at least I know how you feel about me now.
What?
[man on TV]
I wasn't hiding anyway.
Nothin'.
...hide anything from you.
Come on, beat it.
[Johnny]
Bye.
Skinny little shit.
[woman on TV]
Jeez, dad must be
serving poor liquor.
Never seen him
behave this way before.
[Larry Graham singing "One In A Million You"]
À®ä Love had played
it's games on me À®ä
À®ä So long À®ä
À®ä I started to believe À®ä
À®ä I'd never find anyone À®ä
À®ä Doubt had tried
to convince me À®ä
À®ä To give in À®ä
À®ä Said you can't win À®ä
À®ä But one day the Sun
came shinin' through... À®ä
Here.
I already have one.
À®ä The rain had stopped À®ä
À®ä And the skies... À®ä
That's bullshit.
À®ä And oh what a revelation... À®ä
Black?
Yeah, black.
À®ä Someone was saying À®ä
À®ä I love you to me À®ä
God, I hate this shit.
À®ä One in a million... À®ä
Hey, don't expect me
to stick around here
all night long
or nothing, alright?
Do what you want.
What?
I will.
À®ä And sent to me a stroke... À®ä
You like punch?
Sure.
[laughing]
À®ä A one in a million you... À®ä
You're gonna be alright?
Leave early if you want.
I think I can ditch Mary Pat.
À®ä Arms to fill À®ä
À®ä Then I found
a piece of happiness À®ä
À®ä To call my own and life... À®ä
No, seriously, I'll be fine.
It's just for a couple of hours.
You wanna dance?
We're supposed to.
Randy, you wanna dance?
Oh, this shit.
À®ä One in a million À®ä
[crowd exclaims]
[Romeo Void singing "Never Say Never"]
Whoo!
- Let's go.
- Alright.
- Whoo!
- Ow!
À®ä If time itself
was his demeanor À®ä
À®ä There'd be no sunlight or a glimmer À®ä
À®ä Of sunlight landing
on the street À®ä
À®ä Sunsuit girls
must be discreet À®ä
À®ä Nursing their fathers
locked inside À®ä
À®ä They masqueraded
as his bride À®ä
À®ä I might like you better
if we slept together À®ä
À®ä But there's something
in your eyes that says maybe À®ä
À®ä That's never À®ä
À®ä Never say never À®ä
- Come on.
- Hey, Randy.
- Let's get out of here.
- Let go.
Right now!
Randy, let go.
Let go, nothing.
We're going.
No.
- Everybody is staring.
- So?
Hey, man, let her go.
- Hey!
[male #10]
Come on, man!
Come on, knock it off.
- Son of a bitch.
- Come on.
- What is this?
- Yeah, come on!
À®ä Slept together À®ä
À®ä I might like you better
if we slept together À®ä
À®ä But there's something in
your eyes that says maybe... À®ä
What?
À®ä Never say never À®ä
À®ä Never never never À®ä
Hey.
What do you want?
Forget it.
Hey.
What do you want?
You wanna go for a ride?
Where to?
I don't know...
...around.
Scared?
[instrumental music]
[engine revving]
What is this place?
[Johnny]
Wait up.
How come I never
noticed it before?
It's been here.
Who would put something like this here?
[Johnny]
People liked what they saw.
Take a look.
[Tracey]
Wow!
You can see everything.
Do you like what you see?
Sometimes.
Not a lot.
This place is pretty scary.
I like being scared.
It keeps me awake.
Whoo-tchoo.
So where are you planning to go?
What?
When you get out of this place.
You saw my card?
Uh-huh.
I don't know.
I'll find somewhere.
So you're just gonna pick up
and take off someday...
...all by yourself?
Yeah, why the fuck not?
I don't need anybody.
No?
No.
How about you?
How 'bout me what?
I don't, I don't
wanna go anywhere.
So you don't wanna go anywhere?
No.
Never?
[chuckles]
Hey, I wanna go home.
Bye, I'll see you at school.
Listen.
It's getting cold.
Would you take me?
Please.
Thanks for the ride.
Yeah.
- Bye.
[bell ringing]
- Seen Tracey?
- Down that way.
[indistinct chattering]
Hey, where did you go
last night?
Home.
Why weren't you
answering your phone?
I had nothing to say.
Hey, so, listen, so I was drunk,
and I get pissed off, so what?
- I did it for you.
- You did it for yourself.
What the hell's that
supposed to mean?
Forget it.
Hey, I don't wanna forget it.
What is it? That time
of the month or something?
Why do you always ask me that?
Cause you've really been
acting like a bitch lately.
I don't know what the hell
it is you want from me.
That's the problem.
Well, how am I supposed
to find out?
If I knew then
I wouldn't need you to.
- To what?
- To know what I want!
[bell ringing]
So what does this mean,
we're breaking up?
- Huh?
- You can still be friends.
[all laughing]
Rourke.
[female #4]
Okay, today, inertia.
Objects that are at rest,
tend to stay at rest.
Objects that are in motion,
tend to stay in motion.
- Hey, Johnny.
- Hey.
[male announcer]
...gonna reach in 45 minutes.
We got a problem.
We're getting a lot of pressure
from up top, Johnny.
I don't know how much
longer I can carry him.
What are you doing here, huh?
You've come for my job.
You want my job, is that it?
- Get on the bike.
- You don't know slag shit.
Never been inside
in your fuckin' life.
You'll get crushed in a second.
By the way, that was a great
game for you and Randy, Johnny.
Big star Johnny Rourke.
[laughs]
You know, your mom and I were
just saying how we miss you
coming around the house.
Yeah, well,
I've been kinda busy.
Bullshit, heh. Bullshit.
- Move your leg.
- Oh, let's go.
Take care.
No fucking way, can you do it.
You ain't nothing like me.
So my senior year,
we held the Falcons
to 61 yards, total offense.
The game's still the same now
as it was then, right?
So what the hell is the problem?
Well, here's part of it.
Our own li'l Johnny Travolta.
[laughing]
So, uh, where have
you been, Rourke?
Out signing autographs, or
just practicing a few new steps?
You want to get up,
show us a turn or two.
Come on, spread the wealth.
[all cheering]
I had something to do.
Oh, come on, don't be modest.
Let us all in on the private life
of a wild and crazy guy.
There was a problem.
Can we talk about it later?
[Barton]
No, I wanna know now.
I mean,
people are always asking me
what is Johnny Rourke
really like?
It's personal.
[Barton]
Hey that's okay,
we're old enough.
Yeah, some of us are.
[all]
Oh!
[Barton]
Come down here.
What's the matter?
You jealous?
Afraid, I'm movin' in
on your territory?
Maybe you just better go run
some laps till you cool off.
- I am cool.
- I said move it!
No, why should I?
- Why?
- Either you move it.
Or what?
Right, that's it,
you're suspended.
Get the hell outta here.
Come on, man,
you can do better than that.
I know you can.
Alright, you're off the team,
so go clean out your locker
while you still
got your teeth, Jack.
See? I knew
you had it in you.
- Good.
- Shut up!
[Barton]
Alright...
[Peggy Lee singing "Is That All There Is"]
[laughing]
À®ä Is that all there is À®ä
À®ä If that's all there is my friends À®ä
À®ä Then let's keep dancing... À®ä
Oh, must be closin' time.
What are you doing in my room?
Hey, gotta go
where the music takes me, huh?
[both laughing]
Could you please get out?
Oh, come on, don't be
such a party pooper.
Hey, come on, baby boy.
Come on, dance with me.
À®ä Twelve years old my
daddy took me to a circus... À®ä
Dad.
Oh.
À®ä And elephants À®ä
À®ä Dancing bears À®ä
À®ä And a beautiful lady in pink tights... À®ä
Cut it out!
Just take your whore
and get out of here.
Hey.
Hey, what?
Watch your tongue,
you little punk.
That's what she is, isn't she?
I told you to
keep your mouth shut!
This is my girlfriend.
Oh, yeah?
[Johnny]
Oh, well, this is great.
Let's just go, John.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
You guys think, uh, like,
you'll be getting married?
You'll probably be
getting married, right?
I'm warning you, Johnny.
Well, I'm just asking
'cause, you know...
...I'd, uh...
...uh, I'd love
to have a new mommy.
But...
...you gotta promise,
you'll do a better job
of holding onto this one.
- You bastard.
- You wouldn't.
- I'm gonna kill you. Huh?
- Don't fuckin' hit me.
- Stop it, John.
- You fuckin' wanna die?
You wanna die, you fuckin'
like you're killin' me.
[Johnny]
You're killing me,
you fuckin' bastard!
[John]
Hey, you little piece of shit!
Get the fuck out of here,
and take your bullshit with you!
You take your fuckin' bullshit out with you
you fuckin' bastard.
You're just like your mother!
I kicked her out,
now I can kick you out!
You did not kick her out.
She left!
- Bullshit!
- She left you, goddammit!
She left your goddamn loser ass,
and you know it.
- Get the fuck out of here!
- I am getting outta here.
- Mom.
- Oh, hi, honey.
I knew this old thing
was hiding someplace.
I knew where it was.
You should have just asked me.
Where're you going?
Going to Aunt Gene's.
You knew that.
Now, you sure you can't come?
I've got school tomorrow.
[Mrs. Prescott]
Can't you miss a day?
David's taking a day off
and so is your father.
I can't. I've got a game Saturday anyway.
Okay, you know best.
- How do you know?
- What?
That I know best?
Honey, it's up to you.
Not really.
I mean, you could
force me to go.
I mean, legally I'd have to obey you.
Honey, I'd never force you to do anything.
You know that.
Never had any reason to.
I've been good, haven't I?
- As a matter of...
- A good daughter?
No complaints, no problems.
You have been good.
Everything's been just great.
I've always had
a lot of friends.
I don't do drugs.
I've never had an abortion.
I've never even had the measles.
- Honey...
- Is that true?
It is true, isn't it? I've
never even had the measles.
- Well, no.
- That's incredible.
I'm perfect.
I'm fucking perfect.
Honey, calm down.
No, I don't wanna calm down.
I'm sick of calming down.
I'm sick of everything being okay.
Look, what are
you talking about?
- Don't you know?
- No. I don't.
I gotta go.
Wait a minute.
Look, it's okay, everything's fine.
I'm just kidding around.
Have a good time.
[tires screeching]
[INXS singing "Soul Mistake"]
[engine revving]
À®ä Promises are carved out of lust À®ä
À®ä With a fire in the heart À®ä
À®ä That burns without regret À®ä
À®ä I vow to play the part À®ä
À®ä In this meeting of the soul À®ä
À®ä My feelings are unknown À®ä
À®ä I learn with no regret À®ä
À®ä I'm getting what I get À®ä
À®ä Feel some pain À®ä
À®ä Though I'm miles away À®ä
À®ä And ring to let you know À®ä
À®ä Are you seeing someone À®ä
À®ä I'd better let you go À®ä
[tires screeching]
À®ä She said À®ä
À®ä This was a lesson in love À®ä
À®ä This was a love À®ä
Johnny, are you alright?
What the hell were you doing?
I didn't do anything.
No? Try almost killed me.
À®ä This soul À®ä
You've wrecked my goddamn bike.
You've wrecked it!
I did not. Where the hell'd
you come from anyway?
I didn't see you.
Will you move
that garbage can, please?
Thank you very much.
What are you doing?
À®ä Promises are carved out of lust À®ä
À®ä With a fire in the heart À®ä
Rourke, where
the hell are you going?
Get in.
It's my fucking car.
It's mine now.
[engine revving]
It's the last bus tonight.
You're gonna regret this.
À®ä This was a lesson in love À®ä
[engine revving]
À®ä She said À®ä
À®ä This was a love to end all loves À®ä
À®ä This soul À®ä
À®ä Never listens to me À®ä
What are we doing at school?
The shop. I gotta
borrow some tools.
You got a flashlight?
[dashboard opening]
[dashboard closing]
How are we gonna get in?
[instrumental music]
You know, if I don't get home soon
my mother's gonna have a real shit fit.
Your family is
away for the weekend.
[fence clanking]
How'd you know that?
I know lots of things.
Come on.
[music continues]
Johnny?
[hissing]
Jerk.
[chuckling]
Shh.
You'll wake up the rats.
Come on, it's all clear, let's go.
Wait a minute.
Why'd they close this wing down?
Town got too small
for it's britches.
I have to call Randy.
What?
I was supposed to meet him.
[Tracey]
Hi, Randy.
I'm gonna stay over
at Mary Pat's tonight.
No, you better not.
She's not feeling good.
We're just gonna hang out.
Na.
We'll probably go
super early, yeah.
I'll just see you
tomorrow, alright?
Okay.
Bye.
Listen to this.
"Rourke, John Jr.
Difficulty in dealing
with structured environment.
Onset of difficulties can be
traced to a period immediately
following mother's
abandonment of family.
Since that time there's
been an increasing evidence
of anti-social behavior.
He is potentially dangerous
and destructive."
I'd better start living
up to that potential.
[chuckling]
Johnny.
Johnny!
Geez!
Well, look at this.
Here it is.
Past, present
future, death...
Oh, shit, I love this song.
[Kim Wilde singing "Kids In America"]
À®ä Looking out a dirty old window À®ä
À®ä Down below the cars À®ä
À®ä In the city go rushing by À®ä
À®ä I sit here alone and I wonder why À®ä
À®ä Friday night and everyone's moving À®ä
À®ä I can feel the heat but it's soothing À®ä
À®ä Heading down À®ä
À®ä I search for the beat in this dirty town À®ä
À®ä Downtown the young ones are going À®ä
À®ä Downtown the young ones are growing À®ä
À®ä We're the kids in America À®ä
À®ä Whoa À®ä
À®ä Everybody live for the music-go-round À®ä
[Tracey]
Hello, baby. Hi.
Come on.
[chuckling]
Whoa!
À®ä Boy don't check on your watch À®ä
À®ä Not another glance À®ä
[glass shattering]
À®ä I'm not leaving now honey À®ä
[chuckling]
À®ä Hot shot give me no problems À®ä
À®ä Much later baby you'll
be saying never mind À®ä
- Tracey.
- Hey!
À®ä You know life is cruel À®ä
À®ä Life is never kind À®ä
À®ä Kind hearts don't make a new story À®ä
À®ä Kind hearts don't grab any glory À®ä
À®ä We're the kids in America À®ä
À®ä Whoa À®ä
À®ä Everybody live for the music-go-round À®ä
À®ä La la la la À®ä
À®ä La la la la sing À®ä
À®ä La la la la la la la la À®ä
À®ä Come closer honey that's better À®ä
À®ä Got to get a brand new experience À®ä
À®ä Feeling right À®ä
À®ä Oh don't try to stop
baby hold me tight À®ä
À®ä Outside a new day is dawning À®ä
À®ä Outside suburbia's sprawling À®ä
À®ä Everywhere À®ä
À®ä I don't want to go baby À®ä
À®ä New York to East California À®ä
À®ä There's a new wave comin' I warn ya À®ä
À®ä We're the kids in America À®ä
À®ä Whoa À®ä
À®ä Everybody lives for the music-go-round À®ä
À®ä La la la la la la la la À®ä
À®ä Sing À®ä
[music continues]
À®ä We're the kids À®ä
À®ä We're the kids in America À®ä
[water splashing]
À®ä We're the kids À®ä
À®ä We're the kids in America À®ä
[machines whirring]
[instrumental music]
[breathing heavily]
[moaning]
[thunder rumbling]
[exhaling]
[instrumental music]
[inhaling deeply]
[thunder rumbling]
[door opening]
[gasping]
[floorboards creaking]
What do you want?
I wanna come in.
No.
Look, tonight was just...
I've got something of yours.
What?
Give 'em to me.
It's kind of wet out there.
Okay, just leave 'em there.
Just leave 'em there and get out.
Uh-uh.
Alright then, give 'em to me.
Uh-huh.
You want 'em?
Yeah.
Take it.
[chuckling]
Ooh.
- You want them?
- Give 'em to me, dammit!
You want 'em?
Take 'em.
Alright, just what the hell
is it you want?
Maybe you oughta ask yourself
the same question.
[glass shattering]
[groaning]
Oh, um...
Stay right there.
[door closing]
So this is where
they made you, huh?
Here, now, put this on.
You come here.
I'm the wounded one.
[instrumental music]
Ah.
[music continues]
What?
You want me?
Huh?
Yes.
Then say it.
[sniffling]
Say "I want you."
Say it.
Um...
What?
- I want...
- Wha...
...you.
Who?
You.
You, you.
I want you.
You do?
[whispering]
Oh, God.
[moaning]
Stop, stop.
Don't, don't move.
What?
I just want to stay inside you
like this forever.
Don't move.
We could get people to bring us food.
You know, every once in a while
we could stay like this
for the rest of our lives.
[chuckling]
Okay?
Okay.
[moaning]
Oh, God! It feels so good.
You like this?
[exhaling]
It's Saint Christopher.
They took away his saint day
or some shit like that.
You know like
they fucked him over.
I want you to have it.
Here.
[laughing]
It's yours.
[breathing heavily]
[whispering]
Oh, God.
[Johnny]
What are you doing?
[moaning]
Mm-mm, do it?
[Tracey chuckling]
We came home early.
Mom had a fight with Aunt Jean.
[door closing]
Shit.
[Mrs. Prescott]
Is she up?
Oh, David, take him
to your room.
[David]
Come on.
Honey?
[Tracey]
I'm in here.
What are you doing in here?
Uh, lights went out
and I got scared.
What are you doing back so soon?
Oh.
Your Aunt Jean started it
and I didn't feel like listening.
About what?
About nothing.
Hereis the good news though.
Just feel this.
[chuckling]
Is there some way out of here?
Feel free to jump.
Oh, Christ.
Tell Tracey I gotta
meet her later, okay?
The rally's tonight!
Tell her I'll meet her there, okay?
Okay.
[dog barking]
Oh, wow.
It's got my name on it.
I thought it was a good idea
and your father agreed.
I can just go in there
and buy whatever I want?
Well, you can't go crazy
but you're going to need
a lot of things for next year.
That's great.
It's a start.
[motorcycle engine revving]
Everything's okay with you?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Not to worry, right?
Right.
Good.
[crowd cheering]
[instrumental music]
[crowd applauding]
[cheerleaders in unison]
Let's get fired up!
[crowd in unison]
We are fired up!
[cheerleaders]
Let's get fired up!
[crowd]
We are fired up!
- Let's get fired up!
- We are fired up!
[cheerleaders]
Let's get fired up!
We are fired up!
- I gotta talk to you.
- I can't.
Let's get fired up.
Well, meet me later.
I can't.
Yes, you can.
At the ledges.
I'll wait.
[cheerleaders]
Let's get fired up!
[crowd]
We are fired up!
- Let's get fired up!
- We are fired up!
[trumpets blaring]
[man on megaphone]
Hello, hello...
Roosevelt's firing up.
Now I'll just like
to take the responsibility
to thank all of you
for the tremendous support
that you've given the Raiders
all these months.
Thank you.
And also, we'd like to show
special appreciation
to our quarterback Randy Daniels
to present to the senior cheerleaders
for Roosevelt grand road.
Let's hear it for them.
Hooray!
[crowd cheering]
In first, Tracey Prescott.
Yay!
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[engine revving]
Johnny!
[tires screeching]
What the hell were you doing?
Where the hell have you been?
With Randy.
He's all upset and it's probably my fault.
Yeah?
Well, I'm pretty fuckin' upset
and it's definitely your fault.
[sighing]
Are you gonna tell him?
Yeah.
I don't know.
You are making me crazy.
[sniffling]
We gotta get out of here.
It's late.
Where can we go?
I mean, outta here.
Out of this town.
As far as we can get.
Johnny, don't be crazy.
Crazy?
You know what's crazy?
Staying here is.
Are you happy here?
Johnny.
I have to go.
Where do you have to go?
Huh? Tell me.
You're hurtin' me.
Good. Now you know
how I feel.
Let go.
No, you're gonna stay here
and you're gonna listen to me.
Where do you have to go?
Back to your fuckin' lies?
Back to playing
Miss Perfect-Little-Cheerleader
and then sneaking off at night
for the dirty work.
You're so full of shit.
Makin' believe you're so cool.
Makin' believe you don't feel anything!
Feel this! Feel what
it's like to be scared!
[gasping]
Oh, I'm sorry.
Tracey.
Tracey!
[INXS singing "To Look At You"]
À®ä What is the name to call À®ä
À®ä For a different kind of girl À®ä
À®ä Who knows the feelings À®ä
À®ä But never the words À®ä
À®ä To look at you À®ä
À®ä And never speak it's so good À®ä
À®ä For me tonight to look at you À®ä
À®ä For me tonight À®ä
À®ä What is the name to call À®ä
À®ä For a different kind of girl À®ä
À®ä Who knows the feelings
but never the words À®ä
À®ä Who do you ask À®ä
À®ä When there's no one left to turn to À®ä
À®ä You ask me À®ä
À®ä And I'll always try to hear À®ä
À®ä Past money and colors À®ä
À®ä And make believe À®ä
À®ä Good cheap values À®ä
À®ä For a thrifty clown À®ä
À®ä To look at you À®ä
À®ä And never speak is so good À®ä
À®ä For me tonight to look at you À®ä
À®ä For me tonight À®ä
À®ä What is the name to call À®ä
À®ä For a different kind of girl À®ä
À®ä Who knows the feelings
but never the words À®ä
[woman on PA]
Attention, please.
Will John Rourke report to the office?
John Rourke, to the office, please.
[engine revving]
Hiya, Johnny.
Where is he?
I want you to put this on
and come inside with me, Johnny.
Why?
Just come inside, okay?
[indistinct chatter]
[siren wailing]
[machinery rumbling]
[indistinct chatter]
John, I'm sorry.
Its alright.
[male #11]
Let us pray.
"With faith in Jesus Christ
we reverently bring the body
of our brother
to be buried in it's human imperfection.
Let us pray with confidence to God
who gives life to all things.
May we raise up this
mortal body to the perfection
and company of the saints.
May God give him
a merciful judgment
and forgive all his sins.
May Christ, the good shepherd,
lead him safely home
to be at peace with God, our father.
And may he be happy forever
with all the saints
and the presence
of the eternal king.
Our prayers are now ended.
And we bid our last farewell.
There is sadness in the parting
but it should fill us with new hope.
And one day, we shall
see our brother again.
And enjoy his love.
By God's mercy
we who leave this cemetery today in sorrow
will be reunited in the
joy of God's kingdom.
- Let us comfort one another.
- Johnny.
In the faith of Jesus Christ."
- It's okay.
- I know.
Johnny...
...it could have
happened to anyone.
[horn blaring]
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[clattering]
[lighter clicks]
[lighter clattering]
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[Randy on PA]
Tracey Prescott.
[woman on TV]
...is available
to limit our almost...
[instrumental music]
[engine roaring]
Alright, I'd like to welcome
you to Career Day.
We have with us the representatives
of Everton's main employers.
These people represent
our best hope for the future
so, let's, uh, let's give 'em
a warm welcome, okay?
[tires screeching]
[brakes squealing]
So, as you can see, it's no party.
We're not sending out invitations.
We're issuing a challenge.
We're daring you to think about your future
your country's future,
the future of freedom.
Does it scare you?
It ought to.
But if it doesn't...
...maybe, just maybe...
...you can be one of us.
The few, the proud...
...the marines.
Thank you.
Hey, Tracey.
[crowd applauding]
I-I need to talk to you.
The next guest is here
representing one
of Everton's most important employers
American Steel, as well as being
senior operations manager...
It's important.
...Mr. Daniels has the
distinction of being my father.
[crowd applauding]
- Thank you.
- Please.
[Mr. Daniels]
Thank you very much.
You okay?
Yeah.
Now, listen, Tracey.
I know I don't have any rights
over you and I would...
...I could never force you
to do anything you didn't want.
But there's something I gotta do.
I gotta go.
I don't know where.
Just somewhere different.
And I gotta go now.
'Cause
you see...
...I get real frustrated
'cause there's lot of stuff
that I feel and that I wanna say
but it just don't come out right.
So, I get real pissed off
and start smashing into
things and hurtin' 'em.
See...
...I didn't want to hurt you
I just want you.
You want?
Need.
I need you to come with me.
And do everything with me.
And then feel
everything with me.
It's just not good alone.
What the fuck
are you talking about?
You know, I'm so tired
of your fucking bullshit act.
Randy, can you just leave us
alone for a minute?
No, this has nothing to do with you.
This is between me and him.
There's nothing between me and you.
There sure as shit is.
There's you pissin' me off
and there's me not takin' it anymore.
Randy, don't.
Why the fuck not?
Who the fuck are you, huh?
I ain't gonna fight.
Randy, come on.
His father just died.
Yeah, he was so drunk,
he fell right in with the slag.
[grunting]
[Tracey]
Johnny!
[Johnny grunting]
[woman on PA]
...medical profession has today...
[grunting]
[indistinct chatter]
[yelling]
Just get him out of my sight!
Break it up!
[clamoring]
[indistinct yelling]
God damn it!
Cool off! Cool off!
[clattering]
[engine revving]
[Johnny]
Tracey!
Come on!
Are you with me or not?
Don't listen to him.
He's crazy.
Tracey, I love you.
Tracey.
[instrumental music]
- Tracey!
- Tracey.
[indistinct shouting]
David, tell mom I'll be alright!
Yeah! Alright!
Whoo!
[Bob Seger singing "Roll Me Away"]
À®ä Stood alone on a mountain top À®ä
À®ä Starin' out at the great divide À®ä
À®ä I could go east I could go west À®ä
À®ä It was all up to me to decide À®ä
À®ä Just then I saw a young hawk flyin' À®ä
À®ä And my soul began to rise À®ä
À®ä And pretty soon À®ä
À®ä My heart was singin' À®ä
À®ä Roll roll me away À®ä
À®ä Won't you roll me away tonight À®ä
À®ä I too am lost I feel double-crossed À®ä
À®ä And I'm sick of what is
wrong and what is right À®ä
À®ä We never even said a word À®ä
À®ä We just walked out
and got on that bike À®ä
À®ä And we rolled À®ä
À®ä And we rolled clean out of sight À®ä
À®ä We rolled across the high plains À®ä
À®ä Deep into the mountains À®ä
À®ä Felt so good to me À®ä
À®ä Finally feelin' free À®ä
À®ä Somewhere along a high road À®ä
À®ä The air began to turn cold À®ä
À®ä She said
she missed her home À®ä
À®ä I headed on alone À®ä
À®ä O-oh À®ä
À®ä Roll me away À®ä
[Romeo Void singing "Never Say Never"]
À®ä If time itself was his demeanor À®ä
À®ä There'd be no sunlight or a glimmer À®ä
À®ä Of sunlight landing on the street À®ä
À®ä Sunsuit girls must be discreet À®ä
À®ä Nursing their fathers locked inside À®ä
À®ä They masqueraded as his bride À®ä
À®ä I might like you better
if we slept together À®ä
À®ä But there's something
in your eyes that says maybe À®ä
À®ä That's never À®ä
À®ä Never say never À®ä
À®ä There's no easy way À®ä
À®ä To lose your sight À®ä
À®ä On the street on the stairs À®ä
À®ä Who's on your flight À®ä
À®ä Old couple walks by À®ä
À®ä As ugly as sin À®ä
À®ä But he's got her À®ä
À®ä She's got him À®ä
À®ä Never say never À®ä
À®ä Never never À®ä