We“ve got Yankee tanks coming
in from the plains.
We“ve lost most of our night vision
and have only
a few anti-tank missiles left.
Put your best men
into hunter groups armed with RPG“s.
Have your men
dig holes 100 meters apart.
Wait until the Yankees approach
to strike then attack them in force.
Yes, Colonel Bella.
I want some anti-aircraft here.
We“re working on it, sir.
This. . .this is a madhouse!
Do you want to see me?
Yes. . .yes.
Go to the sporting goods store.
From the files, obtain form 4473.
These will contain descriptions
of weapons
and lists of private ownership.
Oh, how beautiful.
What is written here?
You studied English.
Translate.
American history. . .I know this well.
Arapaho National Battlefield.
Here was a great peasant uprising
in 1908 of wild Indians.
They were crushed
by President Theodore Roosevelt
leading imperialist armies and cowboys.
The battle lasted all winter.
More than 35,000 were killed.
It was the greatest battle
of the American West.
Bravo!
Yuri, stay here.
I“ll take a photo of you.
African baboon.
Now you.
Come here, my friend.
Hurry up, you fool.
Look at me, Yuri.
Look.
Look what I“ve found.
An arrow.
And Indian arrow.
What a philosopher you are.
I did not know the Indians used steel.
Sure, you fool,
they used the melted sabers
of Federalist Cossacks.
Did these Indians work in plastic, too?
You idiot, this is bone,
polished to a high sheen.
There must be more.
Look.
Watch out!
She has a weapon.
Stop, damn it!
Quickly. . .catch him!
Stop!
Help me, comrades.
I“m dying.
God help me!
From now on all troops are forbidden
to travel outside secured areas
in any group smaller than squad size.
Yes Colonel Bella.
Then call Bratchenko.
Tell him Sector Eight is now active.
Right away, Colonel Bella.
And I want some interrogations made
starting with the Mayor.
I“m sick of his...
...pleasantries.
Consider it done.
Take gasoline.
Hey, girl, what are you doing here?
Hey, beautiful, where are you going?
Forget the broad, just get her stuff.
Where are you going?
You“re so beautiful.
What, what“s wrong with you?
Let“s get her!
It“s cut. . .it“s cut!
I“ve seen this before.
Nicaragua, San Salvador Cambodia,
Angola, and Mexico.
But these are my men!
What is a ““Wolverine““?
A small animal. . .like a badger,
but terribly ferocious.
It is also the name
of the local school sports collective.
They“re beasts, Ernesto.
You must kill every one
of them eventually.
It“s the same as Afghanistan.
They“ll never stop.
Look. . .I was always on the side
of the insurgents.
I have no experience in these matters.
But it would seem necessary
to win the support of the people.
As our opponents used
to say in Vietnam““
““Win their hearts and minds.““
And they lost, Ernesto.
Of course, General.
Things are paralyzed at the front,
Ernesto.
Morale is crucial right now.
Keep the men in the secured areas.
You“ll see how they forget
about these ““Molverines““.
Are you all right?
You were saying, comrade?
Shut up!
Help. . .
The ``Wolverines`` . . .
. . . are attacking.
Follow me. . .quickly.
Children did this?
It`s rebels.
What rebels?
They`re bandits!
Every time they shoot,
the revolution grows.
I know.
I was a partisan.
And what are you now?
Now I`m like you
a policeman.
Attention!
Be seated, comrades.
What I despise most about warfare
is the hypocrisy it often breeds.
I`ve heard euphemisms
that we are containing the enemy
that our sector
of pacification is growing.
These are the tactics of the lie.
Lies have the stench
of death and defeat.
You can only win a war by exterminating
the enemy.
Do you know who we are fighting?
We are fighting Wolverines.
Small, ferocious animals.
For them, you need a hunter.
And you know. . .I am a hunter.
From this moment on there
will be no further reprisals
against civilians.
This was stupid.
Impotence.
Comrades
If a fox stole your chickens
would you slaughter your pig
because he saw the fox?
No.
You would hunt the fox find where
it lives and destroy it!
And how do we do this?
Become a fox.
Comrade Colonel.
I would estimate
the enemy body count at. . .
12. . .
Wouldn`t you agree?
12?
I saw only one.
But they carry off their dead.
Of course, why not?
What do you think?
I can`t remember what it was to be warm
It seems a thousand years since
I was a small boy in the sun.
How did I come to this high,
desolate place where there is nothing
but loneliness?
So much is lost.
I want to look into your eyes
and forget.
It all seems so far away a warm house
where my shadow never falls your long,
black hair in my hands.
There is no more revolution
only you to come back to.
I will post my resignation.
They`re attacking the station.
Everybody to the station.
Hurry, hurry!
Subtitles stripped down to translate only,
spell-corrected, re-mixed, and re-arranged
from 2CD to 1CD -- by N3tw3rk Da3m0n