Sergeant ramsay, line 2232.
Sergeant ramsay, line 2232, please.
- They want me.
- I've got this.
Ramsay. What's the model?
7799 agricultural?
- Ramsay?
- What location?
- This is marvin. Officer thompson.
- Nice to meet you.
That's ramsay, your partner.
Your new partner. Good luck with him.
- Jack ramsay.
- Karen thompson.
- I'm on my way.
- A runaway, jack?
- Yeah. Can you order us a copter?
- Yeah.
- Come on, partner.
- Now?
If you're gonna keep up,
you gotta move.
Give me the pad.
I need a chopper for ramsay.
You'll need your gloves
and standard pro-gs.
Standard pro-gs?
- What was your last assignment?
- Traffic.
Did you like it?
Working with you is
a step up from traffic.
Maybe.
You know anything about
robotics and computers?
A little.
Basics.
I was gonna be a data programmer.
Do we need all this to...?
- Jack, your copter's on the pad.
- Great.
Let's go, partner.
Is that it?
Standard agricultural model
7799 pest controller.
Cpu is an old 8088.
- Any armament?
- Just a claw.
It's only programmed to look
for things smaller than an inch.
Could be a problem.
You may not need all that.
You may just have to throw a switch.
That's all?
Well, you never know
until you get there.
I guess you've been doing this
for a while?
Yeah, a couple of years.
It's interesting work.
Dave, how far away are we?
Should be almost there.
Let's have a look.
Right up there, jack.
What do you know?
It's a clear runaway track
in the field to the left.
You okay?
Yeah, i'm fine.
I just don't like heights.
My brother has the same problem.
Take deep breaths.
I'm fine.
Dave, can you land this sucker?
Put on your gloves.
They sure took long enough
to get here.
- What's the problem?
- That thing's running a zigzag course.
I'm not going in that field after it.
Fuel cells will blow up
in your face.
You go on and take a look.
- Have you had it serviced?
- Regular.
Isn't that what you're getting
paid for? You skedaddle in there.
Oh, there you are.
I seen that coming.
You okay? Let's get him.
World war iii!
I think they got it.
I could've done the same thing
with my.22.
We could've blown the damn thing up.
- It's all yours, fellas.
- Thanks a lot.
How long you say
you've been doing this?
I just sort of fell into it
by accident.
I kind of liked it, so i took
some night courses in robotics, apl.
All of a sudden, i just seemed to
know more about it than anybody else.
You ever wanna work
the regular force?
This is the regular force.
You mean working the streets?
I did that. I had to stop.
Because of vertigo?
I don't like heights.
I've had it all my life.
Anyway, i just decided
it wasn't a good idea...
...to work the streets
with that kind of fear.
You wouldn't run into
a situation like that very often.
- You could work the streets...
- i decided i'd rather do this.
Hey, jack, lois called.
- Leave a message?
- Nope.
- Can you call her back?
- Sure.
Lois?
I'm fine, thank you. How are you?
Whatever you wanna fix is fine.
Oh, that sounds good.
I won't be late.
Okay, bye.
- Why did jack quit the regular force?
- Why'd he quit, marvin?
What'd he tell you?
Because of vertigo,
but i don't believe him.
Well, it's true, in a way.
A few years back,
jack was chasing this guy. Bad guy.
The guy ran into a building
that was under construction.
Jack freaked out, started sweating.
Couldn't follow him.
The guy got away.
So a guy got away.
Later that night
that same guy killed six people.
A family up in ridgemont.
- But that isn't jack's fault.
- Yeah, i know.
He can't blame himself for that.
Yeah, well, he does.
It's always on his mind.
The guy that got away...
...that jack let get away.
He never wants to let anybody
get away from him again.
Is that why he's a robot expert?
I think he feels a lot safer
doing this work.
Now, why do you do
what you do?
Oh, long story.
I was gonna be a dancer...
...but i hurt my knee.
Then i was gonna be
a data programmer...
...but i didn't like sitting down.
Then i started...
runaway 2, we have a 709 alert.
- To the police academy.
Runaway 2, we have a 709 alert.
Runaway 2, runaway 2,
we have a 709 at fifth and sumter.
What's a 709?
It means people have died.
Oh, god!
- Hey, jack.
- What's up?
A model 912 cut up two people inside,
wife and her sister.
Bodies are over here. They managed
to run out before they died.
- Anything else?
- There's a 10-month-old kid inside.
- Dead?
- No. The kid's in a crib.
Maybe that's why,
but it hasn't touched the kid yet.
- We gotta save that kid, jack.
- Tell me.
What was the weapon?
Pathologist said it was probably
an ordinary kitchen knife.
We kept them for you to see.
Let's get them out of here,
or they'll be on the news.
What've you done?
Power cut, white light bath,
white sound bath.
- Floater?
- No.
- Can you prep one for me?
- Right now.
What have you got on the 912?
It's a new domestic model.
Does housework, cooks meals,
answers doors.
- Run on house current?
- Batteries.
What kind of sensors?
Sees and hears everything.
Great.
- Is it standard?
- May be modified.
Anytime you change them,
who knows how they'll behave?
The father's over there.
Electronic engineer, name of johnson.
- You got that floater yet?
- We're programming it now.
We'd like a direct feed
off your floater.
- That's impossible.
- The public has a right to know.
We got a 10-month-old baby in there.
The rest of the family's
been cut up...
...and we don't know if
the 912 will attack the child.
I'm sure you don't want
a carved-up baby on your network.
We can be the judge
of what's newsworthy.
Yeah, i know. Not tonight.
The first confirmation from
sgt. Ramsay of runaway...
...that there is a baby inside,
still alive.
Police are preparing
a floater camera...
...to enter the house to locate
the runaway 912 and the infant.
I can't see.
Lights on in the house.
Hit the house lights.
- Where's the baby?
- In the playroom, near the back.
How big's this 912, anyway?
About the size of a hatbox.
- Look.
- It dropped the knife.
Maybe the battery power's fading.
Maybe.
- You get an audio?
- Confirmed as a.357 magnum.
- The bastard's got a gun.
- Now what?
- I'm going in.
- We can send a disarm robot in.
It hit the floater, it'll hit
the disarm, and it'll hit the kid.
I want light lines out here.
No audio, no radio, no nothing.
I don't want it to know
what we're doing.
Mr. Johnson?
I'll be going in your house soon
to get your baby.
What modifications were made
to the robot?
I didn't make any modifications.
I didn't touch that thing.
Then why has it gone out of control?
Well, how should i know?
You think i should have some idea
why it's doing this?
Take it easy. I'm just asking.
Well, don't ask! I don't know!
What about the gun?
It's got a gun?
- Oh, my god, he's crazy.
- Who's crazy?
- My god, he's crazy.
No television! No pictures!
I won't be on television!
No pictures!
No television!
What was his problem?
Yeah, he was really upset.
That was very hot stuff.
Sgt. Ramsay is wearing
his electromagnetic scatter suit.
He apparently is going in.
What is your next move now?
I really can't say.
It looks as if you're going in
after the robot.
You're broadcasting on an
electromagnetic frequency...
...that the robot reads.
Let's get out of here, john.
This is exciting.
Our own john wilson...
...is accompanying sgt. Ramsay
into the house...
...for exciting live coverage
of the runaway robot.
I'm coming out with the kid.
It's all right, darling.
You okay?
Yeah, i'm fine.
Here you go. Where's the father?
He disappeared.
He disappeared?
With his own kid still in there?
After two tense hours and the
tragic death of a kbex cameraman...
... it was all over
when sgt. Ramsay...
hello?
That was great!
See, they're running it again.
You're on instant replay!
Hi, guy. Bobby, this is karen.
- You're his new partner.
- Nice to meet you, bobby.
I saw you on tv too,
but you didn't go in the house.
Wow! It was neat when
dad went in there.
I'll bet you wished you could
go in there too, huh?
It was pretty scary.
I watched the whole thing.
How come the father ran away?
Didn't he wanna see his baby safe?
We were talking about that.
It seems pretty funny to me.
I think you should...
when you hear the tone,
the time will be 10:45...
... which is exactly one hour
and 45 minutes past your bedtime.
Aw, lois!
This is a weeknight.
Tomorrow is a school day.
- I know, lois, but...
- hey, bobby.
Lois is right. To bed.
- Nice meeting you.
- You too.
- Do you like sports?
- Sure.
Bobby, bed.
- Good night, dad.
- Good night.
Good night, bobby.
He is adorable.
- How about a beer?
- Got anything diet? Soda?
I will verify that bobby brushes
his teeth. Excuse me.
So that's lois.
I thought lois was your wife.
Sometimes she thinks she is.
Or my mother.
Do you have a wife?
She died.
Sorry, i didn't know.
It was a couple of years ago.
A car crash.
But lois is a big help.
What is she, a series 10?
No, a series 12.
Series 12s are much better.
A lot of the series 10s were lemons.
My mom had a series 10 that kept
burning toast. Started fires.
- Lois is pretty reliable.
- Bobby is eating a chocolate bar.
His dinner, too, was
nutritionally inadequate.
- What did you give him?
- Hot dogs.
- You can't keep giving him hot dogs.
- It is all he would accept.
- Did he do his homework?
- Yes, he got an a in math today.
- Will your guest be staying for dinner?
- Me?
- You're welcome if you'd like.
- You are welcome if you would like.
No, thank you.
- It's no trouble.
- It is no trouble.
- Lois, i was talking to her.
- Excuse me.
- Actually, i better go.
- You sure?
Thanks for the juice.
May i show you out?
That's okay, lois.
I can find my way.
Well, see you tomorrow.
- Will i see you tomorrow?
- Lois, she was talking to me.
Excuse me, sergeant.
I'll see you tomorrow.
- Good night.
Is that someone to be put in memory?
Yes. She's my new partner.
- How should she be listed?
- As karen. Or officer thompson.
Very well.
There is a power surge
from bobby's room.
I'll handle it.
The next dinosaur giant is
brontosaurus, "thunder lizard."
Like the other two giants,
she's a peace-loving plant-eater.
She is not as heavy as
the brachiosaurus, but she does...
come on, tiger.
Lights out.
Is she still here?
No, she's gone home.
She's nice. Do you like her?
Well, sure, i like her.
She's my partner.
Does she have a husband?
I don't know.
She didn't have a ring on.
You noticed, huh?
It wouldn't kill you
to marry again.
I know, and it wouldn't kill you...
...to go to sleep.
Come on, tiger.
- Hey, dad?
- What?
Were you really scared in there?
Sure i was.
Was there blood and stuff like that?
Were you really scared?
Me? Not me.
Not even just a little?
Well, a little.
That's okay.
- But everything is fine now.
- That's right.
Everything's fine.
Good night, son.
Would lois ever go crazy
like that other robot?
No, never.
Sleep now.
Good night.
Dinner is served.
This concludes the menu for today.
Reminder: I have not received
the menu for tomorrow.
Captain mcnichol, emergency phone call.
- Son of a bitch!
- What is it?
We got a nonstandard chip here.
See that red stripe?
It's not a commercial chip.
It didn't come with the robot.
Damn sophisticated, though.
Maybe it's experimental.
- What's it do?
- Looks like hard-wired instructions.
- I'm not sure.
- So the 912 was modified.
- Definitely.
- That guy said it wasn't modified.
Maybe somebody else did it,
and he didn't know.
- We got a dense pack! Floor!
- Floor!
Assholes.
There is a high level of smoke
in the room. Please be careful.
What was that?
Monodichromate dense pack...
...the arson special.
What the hell is this all about?
I don't know.
This isn't a runaway.
This is murder.
Jack, you got a call.
You're gonna love it.
Great.
He said you were gonna love it.
Come on, this way, guys.
Careful.
You have a lot of robots here.
This is nothing. You should see
the construction project over on main.
There aren't any people working there
at all, just hundreds of robots.
No coffee breaks, no union hassles.
So what's the problem?
Stacker.
Gone nuts!
It's stacking where there's
no place to stack.
It's on the 18th floor.
Come on, i'll show you.
Have one of your people shut it off.
Our insurance doesn't cover it.
Looks pretty open.
Robots don't need doors. Come on.
How about i take this one?
Yeah, i think this one's all yours.
No problem. I worked construction
at one time.
Of course.
I'm on the 18th floor.
It's pretty windy up here.
I can see the stacker now.
We're looking for...
i found the junction box
but can't find the switch.
I got it! No problem!
I turned it off!
Jack, do you read me?
I got it!
Think it's better than it was
when people did all this work?
Sure.
But machines always break down.
I'll tell you how it is.
Nothing works right.
Relationships and people
don't work right.
People make machines,
so why should machines be perfect?
Because they're machines.
Well, that's not the way it is.
- Hi, sally.
- Hi, jack.
- How's the new car?
- It's in the shop.
You're kidding.
Did you check the door recorder?
No, not yet.
- Is it clean in here?
- Yeah, it's clean.
Hi, mary. It's sally.
I guess you're not home.
I came by to see if you wanted to
go to that ceramics class.
Call me when you get in. Bye.
Hi, dave?
I'm a little nervous
about our project and...
meet me at the office, will you?
It's important. Really.
This is acme robot repairs.
We got a call...
... that one of your 912s was not
functioning, and i'm...
it's been erased.
Yeah, but not completely.
This is acme robot repairs.
We got a call...
... that one of your 912s was not
functioning, and i'm...
i wanna know who this guy is.
Beautiful. Just beautiful.
I'm glad you're satisfied.
Satisfied?
I'm delighted. I'm ecstatic.
That's good. Good!
Where are the chips?
Be very careful with these chips,
dr. Luther. They're very dangerous.
I know.
That's why they're so valuable.
Valuable to whom?
The mafia, terrorist organizations,
foreign agents.
Anyone who'll offer me the most money.
Well, then...
...how about my money?
Harry...
...these aren't all the chips.
And where are the templates
to make more?
The rest of the chips and templates
are locked in a safe.
We'll give you the key
after johnson and i get paid.
Have you seen johnson?
No.
He didn't come in today.
It's terrible,
what happened to his family.
It's a tragedy.
Would you like me to pay now, harry?
I really would.
I thought so.
I brought the money with me.
Sentry, on rounds!
Dr. Luther?
Damned, evil son of a bitch!
- He's still in there?
- Came an hour ago.
I bet he's the only
electrical engineer there.
- What room?
- 404. fourth floor.
Coffee, black.
Keep an eye on the elevator.
Police!
Drop it, johnson!
Now!
You are the cops.
Who were you expecting?
Nobody.
You got a suitcase packed.
You got an alarm and a gun.
You got a permit for this?
Come on.
What are you gonna do?
Take you to the station
for questioning.
Sorry.
Is this about the robot?
Yeah, it's about the robot.
Come on.
- I can't go out there.
- Why not?
- I can't go!
- Sure you can.
I can't go out...!
Dispatch, this is runaway 2!
What the hell are you trying to do?
Come here.
We're the police!
He had different eyes, hm?
Is that him?
Face was narrower.
The eyes were squintier.
More like that?
Pretty close.
That's a lot like him.
That's good.
Jesus!
It's picking up diphenyl compounds
and tetrahydrocarbons.
Tetras are explosive and diphenyls
are solid propellant...
...like they use in rockets.
How big did you say
these missiles were?
About that big.
And they went around corners?
Who was this guy?
His name's johnson,
electronic engineer.
- Where did he work?
- A company called vectrocon.
Welcome to vectrocon
security systems.
A retinal identification check is
required to proceed.
Retinal identification is
now being carried out.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Retinal identification is
now confirmed.
How can we help you?
I need data files.
Data files for what person?
Employee david johnson.
One moment.
I will search the records.
That's a pretty good voice.
What is it, a 5590?
Yeah, it's a 5590 processor,
but with a z-77 phonetic rom.
Gives it that lifelike tone.
Thank you for waiting.
David "dave" johnson is 32 years old.
He has been with the company
four years.
A graduate
in electronic engineering.
He has worked on several projects:
The vectrocon security system,
the phantom missile...
... and a laser-guided
smart bomb.
For the past year, he has worked
in special projects.
Dave enjoys skiing,
biking and water sports.
- It's a standard pr bio.
- What'd you expect?
- It's no good to me.
- It's what you requested.
What do you wanna know?
This vectrocon security project.
What about that?
- That information is classified.
- Keep quiet.
- Do you wish to disconnect?
- How do i find out?
- We have a call.
- Have another unit take it.
Yeah, but our call is right here.
- On my way.
- In this building?
You wanna handle this?
It seems like we got a runaway.
All right!
Hello?
Anybody there?
Who is she?
Jackie rogers, one of
the executive secretaries.
Hello? Can anybody hear me?!
We hear you, miss rogers.
This is sergeant ramsay.
Will you guys get me out?
This damn robot won't let me pass.
He's zapped me twice.
Can you see that?
You just sit tight, miss rogers.
She's very attractive.
- Should she be in there?
- Maybe she's working late.
Let's see the runaway.
A 577 sentry?
Yeah, 577 with office-checking
routines onboard.
Got it. Insulated wheels, steel hull.
- Delivers taser shocks only?
- Standard issue.
We don't modify them.
We run them as they come.
Supposed to voice-inactivate
with a code.
Do you know the code?
Sentry. Input. Vetro.
Zip off. 891. clipper.
I've already tried that.
It isn't responding.
With these sentries,
the temperatures get too high...
...and they pop their chips
right off the motherboard.
Would you guys please do something?
All this thing can do is
deliver shocks? What level?
Sting level only.
Irritating, but it can hurt.
No bio, cardiac, nothing.
Want me to get
the insulation and padding?
- Are you sure?
- I'll knock this baby off quick.
Miss rogers, this is sergeant ramsay.
I'll be right with you.
You just sit tight.
Thank you.
I thought you got armed before
you went up against a runaway.
I think he's in love.
You just stay put, miss rogers.
This will only take a minute.
Better watch out for him.
I think i know what i'm doing.
It's set for stun, not sting level.
I noticed.
- Want the padding now?
- No.
Are you all right, sergeant?
I'm fine.
- Is this the way you usually do it?
- Sure.
What are you doing?
You didn't have to do that!
Judgment call.
It was a new jacket.
Yeah, but the sentry's ruined.
I'll have to report this.
If i find there's any irregularities...
...we'll shut down all your machinery
as hazardous for 60 days.
- Are you okay, miss rogers?
- I'm fine.
- I'll just see you to the door.
- No, it's fine.
- I insist.
- You've done enough.
It's my duty. Here you are...
...working late all by yourself.
- I just had to finish up.
- I insist.
- Let me help you.
- No, really...
- what's this?
- It's not my fault.
- He made me get them from the vault.
- Who?
Luther.
They're his chips! I don't have
anything to do with this.
He said he would kill me if
i didn't get them tonight!
He would kill me the way...
...he killed johnson and the others.
He's evil, i'm telling you!
Where's this luther now?
- A meeting.
- What meeting?
- I don't know! I'm not involved...
- where is he?!
The ritz hotel.
Ritz hotel.
The presidential suite.
Two guys with him and two girls.
They've got an evs scrambler on,
so we can't hear or see shit.
Where exactly are they?
Can't determine where without
a probe, and they'll pick that up.
- You using passives only?
- Passives only.
- All the exits and elevators covered?
- We don't have enough people.
This guy's a killer.
I'm not gonna let him get away.
Something's going on in there.
- I better go in.
- You taking responsibility?
You okay about this?
- Yeah, fine.
- You sure?
It's more interesting than traffic.
I'm gonna go in first
and when you hear me...
...you come in.
Honey, did i leave my purse out there?
Did i leave my purse out there or not?
Are you listening to me?
He's not even there.
Don't shoot, please.
Please don't shoot.
Come on, now.
Nobody move.
Just stay cool.
Everything's gonna be fine.
You said there wouldn't be trouble.
Nobody move.
Right here.
Okay, let's take it easy.
Everybody move real slow,
and we won't have any trouble.
Drop it, sucker.
I said, "drop your gun."
I'm not kidding, asshole.
Drop your gun.
Please.
Now kiss your ass goodbye!
Police! Hold it!
I'm okay. Get him.
- Where?
- The stairs!
Officer down, inside.
Call for backup.
They're on the roof!
It's all right. It's all right.
You're okay.
The coroner's office has authorized
the removal of the bodies.
- Come on.
- She's a witness, billy.
- Sergeant, may we have a word with you?
- Go away.
Later.
I want to talk to you.
Chief, any further comment?
No, there's no comment right now.
- How is it, kid?
- Fine.
Didn't even break any bones.
I'm going to the hospital.
They'll take the bullet out there.
Take it out there?
That's right, in case
she starts bleeding.
But you can't move her.
Hold on a minute.
Come here.
Take a look at that screen again.
That's not a bullet.
It's an unexploded microshell.
It can go off anytime.
- It can blow her whole arm off...
- that's right.
You gotta take it out here.
Don't move her.
- The chief wants your ass.
- I know.
Just sit tight.
It's gonna be fine.
I'm trying not to breathe.
You do that.
Look at this. Look.
Those two dead hoods?
We got a make off the prints.
Tommy aracaro, degree in
electrical engineering, cal tech.
- Great.
- And...
...luigi bandini, degree in
solid state physics, m.i.t.
These guys are high-tech shoppers.
But what are they buying?
Good question.
Now, ramsay!
Get over here, ramsay.
- Who the hell do you think you are?
- It's my operation.
It's a runaway operation?
No runaways in that room.
You screwed up good. We've got
two dead officers, understand?
Two dead cops!
Two wounded, one of them
your own partner.
We got two dead guinea punks!
And nobody knows what it's all about!
I know what it's about.
It's about this.
What is this?
It's some kind of new bullet,
like a guided missile.
It can go...
what the hell is this?!
Disarm robot.
There's an unexploded fragment.
You can't use that thing on her!
- They sent for it.
- They screw up all the time.
- We have to. It's a live shell.
- It'll screw up!
It'll blow her arm off.
- Can't you get a cvd?
- There's none available.
It's over a year old and,
they were never any good!
Jesus christ, you've got
nerve to complain!
Haven't you done enough for one day?
- I'll get the bullet out.
- You?
I'll disarm the goddamn bullet.
Get it out of here!
All right, clear out.
We've got a disarm job.
Clear out!
Can you get them to clear out?
I want tensolite shields!
I want blast pads!
I want to clear the fucking room now!
Ramsay! You're on television.
I don't give a shit.
Get that thing out of my face.
Get out. Clear it out!
Ladies, i'll give you
a statement down here.
Let's go. Get out!
Yes, i will give
the public a statement.
What's this?
Remote tv.
Of course.
Okay, guys, let's clear out.
Better get away from the door.
- How we doing, kid?
- Okay.
I heard the news.
Well, don't sweat it.
You don't have to do this.
Yeah, i know.
- You can let the robot do it.
- I wouldn't miss this for the world.
Just hold real still.
- Too tight?
- No, it's okay.
I want you to sit back
and take it real easy.
It'll hurt like a mother.
Just real easy.
Just turn your arm.
Real slow. That's it.
That's good.
Okay, whatever you do...
...don't move your arm.
I'll try and remember.
Don't you need your glasses for this?
Want me to run to the car
and get them?
Breathe it, kid.
Hold still!
Come on kid, breathe it.
That's it. Just keep breathing.
Hold still.
That's it.
Come on, kid.
Breathe it. That's it.
Easy.
- Did you get it?
- Not yet.
Can't you do anything right?
I'm doing the best i can.
This thing's gonna be okay.
Heard any jokes lately?
Come on, kid.
Hold on. Come on, hold still.
Breathe it.
I can see it.
Come on.
It's almost there.
There!
It's okay.
You didn't need to wait, jack.
I'm fine.
- I was worried about you.
- I'm fine, really.
- Hurt much?
- No. Not really.
Bet it does.
Jack, i'm fine.
Why don't we have dinner tonight?
Dinner?
Sure. I gotta go home
and change, though.
- You can go like that.
- I can't go like this.
We're going to my place.
- We should get to know each other.
- I love it.
It's a good idea for partners
to spend time together...
...away from work.
- Definitely. You're right.
We'll go over office routines...
...station procedures.
There's a lot of things
you'll need to know.
The chief isn't the easiest guy
to get along with.
I always take new partners to dinner.
Oh, you do?
Just because you're a woman
shouldn't make any difference, right?
Well, listen, i really
appreciate the gesture...
...but i want to go home.
- Why not dinner?
Just forget it.
The pasta will be al dente
in two minutes...
... 17 seconds.
Forget it, lois.
- Where's your dinner guest?
- Forget it.
She forget it?
She didn't forget it.
I'm asking you to forget it.
Very well, i will erase it
from memory.
You do that.
Bobby stayed up to say
good night to you.
Dad.
Hi, son.
I saw you on tv.
I know you didn't mean it.
- Mean what?
- What you said.
The words that you said
that you say i can't say.
- Well, you see...
- i know.
You didn't know what you were saying,
because you were worried about her.
Well, that's true.
But that's not an excuse.
- Sometimes...
- just don't let it happen again.
I'll try.
Did she come here tonight?
No, she went home.
Excuse me, sergeant.
They want you at the police station.
I gotta go.
You go to sleep.
- Good night, son.
- Yes, sir.
Good night.
Vehicle recovery on three-six.
Look at this.
The back half is solid propellant.
There's directional control.
The nose is electronic.
You've heard of a bullet that has your
name on it? This one really does.
- You can program it.
- What's its signature?
I don't know. I've tried everything.
Movement, light, shape.
- I gotta know, marvin.
- I know!
I'm doing my best, okay?
It's tricky.
Heat.
My god.
- A heat-seeking missile.
- They come at a specific person.
Sure.
Everyone's body has its own unique
heat pattern. This is yours...
...and this is mine.
Clean, simple and neat.
This is a police nightmare.
We used to worry about terrorists
getting a-bombs?
The real problem is
microelectronics stuff.
I mean, a smart bullet?
What about these chips?
Overrides all cpu instructions.
Turn any computer into a killer.
Charles luther. This the guy?
Yeah, that's him.
This is a bad guy.
Served one to three, robbery.
Arrest, murder two, no conviction.
Arrest for assault with a deadly
weapon, overturned. Mob connections.
He's a rich kid gone bad.
Why's he with johnson?
He got johnson and harry to design
the chips, killed them...
...and ran away with the stuff.
He likes to kill people.
He's killed five so far. I want him.
I'm sure you do.
But how are you going to get him?
We've got his girlfriend.
Whoop-dee-do! You think he's
interested in a piece of ass?
- She's all we've got.
- And she leads nowhere.
I want you to talk to our psychic.
Linda's in the building. I'll send
her up here to give you a reading.
- Come on, chief.
- Just do it, ramsay.
Louis...
an old name.
Lucifer.
Luther?
Is his name luther?
And you're looking for him.
He's very angry.
Where is he?
I'm not surprised you're
looking for him.
You have a karmic bond.
You were brothers in another life.
- Linda...
- your relationship is clear, like...
...pieces in the same puzzle.
You've been close many times,
and you'll get closer.
You'll definitely meet.
When and where?
He'll see to that.
After all...
...you have what he wants.
- I do?
- Of course.
- I work as an exercise instructor.
- Where?
A lot of places.
Look, i got a firm body.
My body's perfect. It's like a rock.
I can see that.
Oh, come on.
He's giving me a hard time.
- He doesn't believe me.
- I can't help.
Weiner-head!
Officer milhop, artist sketch room.
Called you back too, huh?
How are you feeling now?
Hurts, but it's okay.
- Hey, ramsay. Telephone.
- I'm not here.
What's going on?
Those illegal chips look like
they were production-etched.
Meaning what?
They were run off
a regular assembly line.
- So?
- Somewhere there's photo templates...
...to make more.
Who has the templates?
I don't know. We better find them.
He said he knows you're here.
Do you know a luther?
This is ramsay.
You're lucky to be alive.
You should've let the robot disarm it.
- So you watch tv. What's on your mind?
- I watch, i look, i listen.
I'm watching you now.
Right. What's on your mind, luther?
You're standing by the desk
punching buttons on the console...
... trying to trace this call,
which won't...
... do shit, because i'm calling
from a mobile phone.
Now you're looking around.
Now you're cupping your hand
over the receiver.
He's tapped into
the closed-circuit tv.
I can't hear what you're saying,
but i've tapped into the tvline.
That wasn't very nice, ramsay.
How'd he do that?
You're probably wondering
how i did that.
- What do you want?
- I want my girl.
I know she's there.
I want you to turn her over to me.
No way.
If you don't, i'll kill her.
And then i'll kill you.
You can't run away, ramsay.
I'll find you.
My little machines will
find you wherever you go.
- Why's he want the girl?
- Maybe she has the templates.
- Marvin, can you get me a little bug?
- Yeah, i got it for you.
You were supposed to catch him.
And how are you?
- You were supposed to catch him!
- I tried.
Well you didn't, shithead!
I feel bad about it too.
Not half as bad as i do.
You really screwed up.
He got away.
You know where that leaves me?
He's smart, you know?
He's gonna know how you found him
at the hotel room because i told.
And he's gonna be so mad...
what am i gonna do now?
- We'll take care of you.
- Sure you will.
We'll move you to a safe place.
You'll move me to a safe place?
And where is that?
There is no safe place.
Not from him.
- Sure there is.
- No, there isn't!
What does it take to get
through to you?!
He sees everything.
He knows everything here.
Do you understand
what i'm saying to you?
Why is he looking for you, jackie?
How do i know?
We better move you.
Beginning debug scan.
Scan complete. No bugs detected.
- Purse, jackie.
- Not again.
- Come on.
- I'm clean.
We'll see.
Beginning debug scan.
Bug detected.
Give me your blouse, jackie.
Nice.
Resuming scan.
Bug detected.
Give me your bra.
Resuming scan.
- Bug detected.
- Hold still.
Resuming scan.
Bug detected.
- Got a lot of bugs.
- I thought i was clean.
You're loaded.
He really wants to keep track of you.
Why is that?
- These two are clean.
- Okay, fine.
Are you crazy?
These are police cars.
- You want a four-car escort?
- Just you.
We'll take the robot driver.
You ride shotgun.
Is that gonna be enough?
Hell, no! If we're in cop cars,
they'll catch on right away.
- Oh, i doubt that.
- You doubt that?
You're acting like sir galahad.
You're gonna get us all killed.
Where's the templates?
What templates?
Let's get moving. Come on.
We hit the streets, and you,
me and dollface are dead.
Hey, jack, you need a hand?
Just don't touch the cars, rudy.
- Come on, it's me, rudy, your buddy...
- don't touch the car!
- Come on, i'm clean.
- Back off!
It's luther.
Yeah, could be.
- You reading?
- Very clear.
- Armed?
- Yeah.
- What do you think our chances are?
- I'm not worried.
Yeah, well, you should be.
Internal screens are activated.
Clear so far.
No electronic targets are shown.
Set up.
Okay. Pull back a little.
Get the lock-on ready.
Lock-on. Armed.
- Front or rear?
- Rear.
- A lock-on is tracking.
- Shit!
In progress.
- It's all yours.
- Got it.
A lock-on is targeted.
- One down.
- One coming.
- Lock-on closing.
- From the front.
200 yards.
You are crazy. You're both crazy!
A lock-on is tracking.
Conditions are serious.
Damn, how many you got?
- Five. Six.
- Bail out.
Moving in.
- What's happening?
- We're getting out.
Multiple lock-ons targeted
at less than 200 yards.
Conditions are dangerous.
Multiple lock-ons targeted
at less than 100 yards.
Come on! Jump!
Multiple lock-ons targeted
at less than 50 yards.
Multiple lock-ons are closing.
Conditions dangerous.
Take evasive action.
Lock-ons are closing.
They're still tracking!
- They're keyed on.
- Whatever it is, it moved with you.
- Jackie.
- Come on, you know i'm clean.
Six coming front and rear.
We're never gonna make it.
- Jackie!
- Lock-ons targeted at 100 yards.
All right! Just a minute.
Eighty, seventy, sixty...
... fifty, forty, thirty...
go ahead. Throw it!
Conditions...
... are hopeless.
That did it.
The templates?
Do you know how much they're worth?
Luther wants them pretty bad.
- Yeah, he does.
- And i want luther pretty bad.
What do you say we make
a public appearance?
You want sushi?
Two california rolls.
You're out of your mind to stand here.
- Why, where is he?
- He could be anywhere.
That doesn't do us much good, does it?
This is stupid!
You think he's gonna show up here?
He won't.
Let's get out of here.
- He wants these. He'll come.
- Sushi is here.
See, doesn't that look good?
You had the tekka maki.
Let me speak to her, ramsay.
Where are you?
Don't be an asshole.
I'm like you, having dinner.
You might say, a night on the town
with your partner.
Come on, come on, hurry up.
Officer thompson was nice enough
to lend me her headset.
Move a little, dear,
so he can see the gun.
Take a seat with jackie.
Come on.
- Two for dinner?
- That's right.
This way, please.
Be cool.
We don't want any shooting
in a place like this, do we?
- No.
- Good boy.
- Just don't get too nervous.
- I won't.
I beg your pardon, sir?
Nothing. This is fine.
All right, now give jackie
the templates.
Would you like something from the bar?
Nothing, thank you.
- I'll be back with the menus.
- Could you give us a few minutes?
Now send jackie over to me.
Send thompson first.
What's the matter, sergeant?
Don't you trust me?
Come on,
i haven't got all night.
It's my insurance policy.
Send thompson.
At the same time.
Go ahead, jackie.
Good bye, darling.
Sweet dreams.
Do you think i'm stupid?
What's the matter?
These aren't all of them.
Nobody does that to me.
Nobody!
So he got away.
And he stiffed the girl.
- That's right.
- That's good.
That's excellent work. What's next?
Nothing.
- Can't screw that up.
- Nothing...
...because i planted a bug on him.
- We'll pick it up anytime now.
- You hope.
What is it?
- They got a signal from the bug.
- Where?
City hospital. He must have got hurt.
Got enough people here?
They'll pick you up.
- Where is he?
- In the john.
Clear those civilians out. Let's go.
You stay here.
Where the hell did he go?
Sally!
Congratulations. You just
staked out toilet paper.
Go through the usual routines.
Maybe we'll find something.
We'd better go.
You wanna watch the door?
Sure.
Where's the chief?
Where'd you get those idiots
for the stakeout?
- It was amateur night.
- We blew it.
I'll say you did.
We should have had him.
You didn't find him, huh?
He's good.
You better look at this.
Oh, god.
It's busy.
Bobby!
Lois?
What happened?
Her voice module's broken.
See if you can patch it.
Wasn't she watching the door?
Don't try to speak, lois.
- She's lost hydraulic fluid.
- She's okay...
...if she keeps power to
her memory circuits.
Bobby.
- Bobby.
- Hit the reset.
Lois?
Bobby was on the phone when an
unpleasant man came in the back door.
What about bobby?
He forced bobby to leave with him.
- How long ago?
- My clock's disconnected.
- I do not know the amount of time.
- Did he say anything?
He left no...
let me see that.
I'm really sorry.
I am really sorry.
Dinner will not be
painted in time.
- We're not here to answer your call.
- I can't get it patched.
May i show you to the door?
I think that's it.
- Lois, do an internal diagnostic check.
- Beginning check now.
What'd you do with my son?
Listen, sucker.
Yeah, i'm listening.
If you wanna see your boy alive,
bring the other templates.
Just you alone. No tricks this time.
Where?
I'll be there.
Where we going?
- Alone.
- I'm your partner.
He'll know if you come.
I'll wait in the car.
Listen! He'll know.
I'm not taking any chances with bobby.
Where you gonna meet him?
You promise not to follow me?
I promise.
- And you won't call anybody?
- I won't.
Diagnostic check completed.
There is a malfunction.
- Please check battery connections.
- Sure.
Thank you.
- Is this it?
- Yes.
What'd you do with my son?
Listen, sucker.
Yeah, i'm listening.
If you wanna see your boy alive,
bring the other templates.
Just you alone.
- No tricks this time.
- Where?
Where?
Go down main street to...
- right to sentises
construction site.
Don't worry,
the spiders won't hurt you!
Dad? Are you coming to get me?
Better have the templates this time.
- I do.
- Drop your gun.
Now get on the elevator!
Come on, ramsay!
Let him go. Now!
Of course.
Get on the elevator.
I want to stay with you, dad.
Get on the elevator, son.
Push the down button.
Stay away from the edge!
The templates, ramsay!
After he's down.
After he's safe.
There's a little problem about that.
I can't have any witnesses.
The spiders have been programmed to
kill the first one off the elevator.
They'll let you in.
But they won't let you out.
There's nothing you can do!
Bobby!
Stop the elevator!
Push the button!
What's the matter?!
Stop the elevator!
Push the button!
They don't work!
None of them work!
You can't stop it.
I fixed the elevator.
Look on the monitor.
It's a better view.
Ever see them kill somebody?
It's really impressive.
They're loaded with acid.
Karen!
Come on, kid.
You bastard!
That's good, ramsay.
But not good enough.
Enjoy the view?
It's okay, son.
It's okay.
Thanks.
You all right?
Yeah, i'm okay.
You go to the car.
Tell lois you're all right.
You look awful.
I think i've overcome
my fear of heights.
- Hurt much?
- No, i'll get it taken care of.
How about dinner?
Dinner?
Sure.
Just because you're a woman
shouldn't make a difference, right?
Right.
Can you cook?
Try me.