We're in business.
A perfect run, Dale. The best time yet.
What did we do?
-Eighty-six a lap.
-Jesus, we hit 110.
I red-lined the last lap.
Dad, something's popped in the gear-train.
Coming down through third,
it snagged and started to shake.
Oh, no. Maybe you bound a few teeth.
We'll take it apart and look at it.
-Well, let me know as soon as you find out.
-You got it!
Did, Mr. Chase say anything yet?
No, it's too soon.
Financiers love to play cat and mouse.
Well, the Gordon Packard's
the best investment he'll ever make.
Well, we'll know soon enough.
He's coming to the house tonight.
To your party.
To my party?
Thanks a lot for telling me, Dad.
You're the hostess. Wear a dress.
Come on, Dale! Come on.
Well, what do you think?
Gorgeous.
-My daughter or the car?
-Both.
I'm not much on words, Mr. Chase.
I put my life into my company.
And you're up to your mudguards in debt.
I've bet everything I've got
on the Gordon Packard.
But you saw it perform.
It's... It's a good car.
It does fine on a nice, flat straightaway.
But what can it do in stress conditions?
Long hauls on flint beds and alkaline,
in brutal temperatures
through dust storms and sand.
That sounds like the Sahara.
It is.
The Sahara World Rally.
There are only five other cars competing,
but each one of them is a legend.
Rolls, Bentley, Saab,
Hispano-Suiza, Alfa Romeo, and Mercedes.
Look, you've got a great car, Gordon,
but before I hand you
or anyone a contract worth 60 million,
I want to see
the damn thing race straight through hell.
And win.
Hello.
Mr. Gordon, sir.
What is it, String?
The engine's clean,
but we found metal in the gear train.
-I want to tear it down.
-Metal?
The engine's fine.
It's the trans that bothers me.
Dale said it felt like a gear slip.
In that case, it's not going
to show up until I red-line it.
I'll take it for a spin on the turnpike.
Whatever it is,
it'll grind it up and blow it out.
I can do it.
Okay, now, come on. Now you promised.
No, you said that this was easy. Come on.
Now. Come on.
Ewing, what's wrong?
Miss Gordon, there's been an accident.
You were right.
It was the transmission.
The wheels locked.
I know, Dad. We'll talk in the morning.
Front left suspension is all torn up.
Dad, please don't talk.
Listen, God damn it,
this is the last time
we'll be seeing each other.
I won't listen.
Dale...
The car means everything.
My plan for the future, for you,
for the company.
We know it's the best.
But the Chase Group wants one last test.
An endurance race through desert country.
Sahara World Rally.
We can win it, Dale.
We can win.
It's just that the Sahara is one mean race.
And it was Daddy's dream,
his life.
And now, it's mine.
There's more to it than driving.
Now what's that supposed to mean?
It's just that this race
has been put together
by some very clubby gentlemen
who are awfully picky
about their membership.
They've got rules.
They won't let a woman
drive as far as the starting line.
You see, it's for men only.
So, String thought that, maybe,
since I'm here, I could drive...
Andy, just stop worrying.
Now just look at that!
Isn't that a surprise.
Welcome to Morocco, sir.
The American automobile, it is yours?
Yes. The name's Gordon, Dale Gordon.
The son, of course.
We better look after our pal.
I'm Captain Browne, British contingent.
This is Enrico Bertocelli,
our Italian competitor.
He's a terrific driver,
but he's never won a race yet.
England, you talk too much.
Welcome aboard.
He's young.
His papa beat me once.
Well, who wouldn't?
Forget it, fella.
My God, it's working.
Don't forget to use the men's room.
Where are we? What kind of a place is this?
-Who are those men?
-The Chambra tribe.
They came out of the desert
to our town to buy women.
Buy women?
The name's Gordon, Dale Gordon.
I believe you have two rooms reserved
for me and my crew.
I'm terribly sorry, monsieur, but we are full.
But I had reservations.
I am sorry, but there is nothing.
Excuse me,
but maybe I can be of some help.
I'm Eric Von Glessing.
I suppose your reservations
may have been canceled
when they learned
of your father's accident.
You knew my father?
Yes, I knew him well.
Well, I guess
we'll have to find other accommodations.
Well, as this is Al Jarida's only hotel,
I believe you have a problem.
But don't worry,
I have a large suite, plenty of room.
Concierge, please give Mr. Gordon
my suite, number 23.
Twenty-three.
Thank you very much, sir.
It's very considerate of you.
You're more than welcome.
Plus the fact,
I don't want anything to happen to you
before we start to race against each other.
Without a bloody car, Von Glessing,
you won't be racing anybody.
His car we call "le mirage."
You know, these fellows are just annoyed
that I won't allow them to see my car.
A practice, by the way, which your father
understood and respected.
You knew him well, didn't you?
I beat him once.
But it was always the best of worlds
to race against a Gordon.
So, may the best man win.
Gentlemen, welcome to Morocco.
My name is Major Douvain,
military attaché
representing the French government
in the west parts of the Sahara.
Allow me to recommend to you
that you forget your so-called Sahara rally
and just go home.
Gentlemen, the reason
for the shift in our policy is,
a tribal war is about
to break out here in the dunes.
North Africa is on the
verge of a tribal war.
How bloody marvelous!
Do you know
what a tribal war is, Mr. Browne?
Well, of course. Everybody does.
Well, then I suggest you
abandon the short route,
as only a car with wings
can cross these impossible dunes.
The long route
will take you nine to ten days.
And just remember,
the short route has only one well,
no petrol dumps, no landmarks,
only a tribal war and the Chambra.
-Amen.
Good luck.
Good luck to you, too.
Has anyone seen
Von Glessing's second car?
The kraut's probably up
to his dirty tricks again.
Too late to worry about it now.
Quite ready, old boy.
Band, stop.
Mesdames et messieurs,
your attention, s'il vous plaît.
When the cannon fires, the race...
Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Go!
-Now?
-Now!
A Fräulein he is!
You did it!
I knew we would! Now let's win the race!
Good Lord! Do you see that?
Fill her up, old chap.
What do you suggest?
The long route.
From here it will take six
or seven days on the long route.
The shortcut will save us three,
maybe four days.
That's not the point.
There's a war out there.
She could get killed.
Who's that?
The Englishman.
You want the short route,
turn left at the camels.
It's up to you, bon-bon.
You worried about getting shot at?
We've lost the Alfa.
The rest are in front of us.
Good. Then nobody
will see us take the short route.
This is so beautiful.
I wish Dad were here.
Okay, time to rest.
-What time is it?
-2:30.
Okay, but just until dawn.
All right. Andrew. Wake up, lad.
Are we there yet?
What happened?
Gypsies, honey.
Nomads of the desert. Harmless people.
They must've been shot
just before we arrived last night.
But the map said
that this was the Chambra well.
And they protect the gypsies.
Well, they didn't do much of a job.
Let's just get our water
and beat it out of here.
It's four days back to Al Jarida,
two or three to the finish line.
Let's just keep going. Fast.
Dale!
Dum-dum. That means Hamancha.
-The tribal war has started!
-Devil soldiers.
Let's get out of here.
Let's go!
Step on it!
Isn't there anything we can do?
Yeah, surrender, or surrender.
It's him!
-No!
-Wait!
Andy!
Welcome, blue-eye,
to the land of the Chambra.
No!
Run away!
Leave me alone!
Learn, blue-eye.
You are privileged
to be with the tents of my lord,
Sheik Ahmed Al Jaffar,
the lord of the sand.
I am Ibrahim Rasoul,
the warlord of the Chambra.
And you are my slave.
You should be proud to please me.
Take her to my tent and guard her.
-Is my lord, Jaffar, here?
-Yes, my lord, he is.
Then we hold a council of war.
Looks like the Hamancha are trying
to make the Chambra mad, eh?
Let's not give the Chambra a chance
to find out what we are up to.
Anyone see you?
No, but I saw the American car
over the rise,
and some Arabs were grabbing it off,
and I think they had a girl with them.
Well, that's just wonderful.
With the American out,
and us with full two days ahead,
we are sure to win.
We haven't won yet, mein lieber Herr.
Half the Sahara is still in front of us.
Get away from me!
No!
Uncle!
Enough!
Stop!
I promise you, my lord,
she will not trouble you again.
I will see to that.
Really? You tried once before
and she burned your tent.
This time if she resists me,
I will cut her throat.
And so, Uncle, for a moment of pleasure,
you would provoke the Legionnaires
to invade our sand.
No. The French will not dare to interfere.
I pray you are right.
Take her to the camp
and put her in my tent.
No! This one is mine.
You forget, Uncle, nothing in the sand
is yours unless I say it is.
She is nothing.
Here, take her to my women's tent
and guard her carefully.
This one's like the wild animal.
Come, my lord, let us ride against Beg,
this killer of gypsies.
We ride, my brothers. To the Hamancha!
Follow me!
Von Glessing, my evil friend,
you have deceived me.
I asked for a war car! What do I get?
Precisely what you ordered, Lord Beg.
Now I will be the thunder in the storm.
It is my pleasure
to serve a valiant soldier, sir.
Soon I will want more cars, 10, 20, 100.
If we can just settle the payment, sir,
then I'll be on my way.
Go now, my devils!
Kill the goat, oil the women, we celebrate!
No, my indecent friend, I cannot.
Prayers must be said,
the women pleasured,
before silver can change hands.
Come, let me drive you
to my stronghold in my new stallion.
Mustapha!
Down!
Fall back!
Go back!
Good morning, child.
Have you recovered from your ordeal?
Who are you?
I am the Sheik Ahmed Al Jaffar's
personal valet.
Let me untie you.
You're English.
Quite. One of those mad Englishmen
who cannot stay out of the noonday sun.
May I be of assistance?
You can get me out of here.
Child, in the desert,
one does not ask the rock for water.
I am a slave here,
willingly, I admit, but quite helpless.
Please, eat.
There are no poisons, no aphrodisiacs.
The food is a gift
from my lord and master, Al Jaffar.
This Jaffar's civilized?
Well, I hope that one day
Jaffar will attend
my old university, Cambridge.
That, by the way, is my name.
I was a professor there for many years.
But as to your question, it has no answer.
But I have a race to win.
Child, your friends have told me
about this silly motor car race,
but for you, it simply no longer exists.
War now rules the sand.
The Lord Rasoul owns you.
That's what he thinks.
You are his property.
And when he returns and comes to you,
it would be wise if you allowed yourself
to enjoy his advances.
-You mean to let him...
-I was thinking rather more than that, child.
If you were to be impatient for his touch,
in fact, demanding,
he might postpone your disposal.
-You can't be serious.
-But I am.
Passionate surrender
is a small price to pay
for keeping that lovely head of yours
on its shoulders.
You have shamed the name of your father.
The Chambra do not retreat.
Would you rather they died?
It is better to be eaten by lions
than to be tormented by hyenas.
The tribes of the sands will mock us now.
The torment will pass, Uncle.
Words! Words!
If you are the mallet, strike!
Hit me, shoot me,
but give me no more words.
To drive, you turn like this,
you stop the car, you go back.
You turn first. That's it.
I think, General,
you should practice your driving
for a few days first.
I regret this unfortunate delay,
my desert lion.
But I'm sure
as soon as you have the vehicle upright,
you will most assuredly rule the sand.
As for myself, I must be on my way.
Look, this race, I must win it
in order to bring you more cars, cannons,
maybe even an airplane.
This, your car.
That, mine.
Now that is... Agreed.
You may borrow my car
while I repair yours.
The armor fits both cars.
And I want him to drive me.
-Oh, no.
-Or you'll die!
Or my name is not Lord Beg.
Of course. Of course.
Come on, come on. Mustapha!
You can pay me later.
What're you doing with my friends?
If you don't let them loose, they'll die.
Only Allah determines the hour of dying.
My lord. How may I serve?
I claim the girl.
She is mine by law.
I am the law.
You shamed me once this day.
You will not do it again.
-It is done.
-No.
Only blood will see it done.
So, she makes the blood hot.
At last we have found a sweet
to your taste.
Good, very good.
You will not touch her.
Tonight is mine. I have the right.
The law says that she is mine.
Not if I take her as a wife.
You will not dare.
She is an infidel, a blue-eyed demon.
No, my lord, you must not.
Then take her now, as my gift.
But do not marry her.
-Angelo.
-Yeah?
Faster!
Tell them that we make war.
That we are unable to extend
our customary hospitality to them.
Make them go away.
They claim they have come to see Ayesha,
the blue-eyed demon.
Nonsense!
Tell them to go to the other tribes.
My lord.
Uncle!
The gypsies are the houses of the legends.
The Chambra's shade is their shade.
My lord, the blue-eye has already started
the fire of fear amongst our people.
The gypsies will make it flame.
It is the law, Uncle, and our tradition.
Give them fire, tent and water.
Has she been told of her marriage?
Or does she frighten you, also?
She will be told.
You're a handsome beauty, aren't you?
Have no fear.
Who resides in my shade
has my protection.
Protection? And what about my friends?
They also.
Then why don't you release them?
I will, in good time.
What does it mean
to be claimed by you, anyway?
Would you like to ride him?
It's like a dream.
This is the Chambra Oasis,
our secret place.
In my tribe, the young ones come here
to bathe before their weddings.
A waterfall in the middle of the desert!
It's breathtaking.
You are breathtaking.
Would they mind if I...
I want to thank you
for showing up like that yesterday.
You saved my life.
You must understand,
it was my uncle's right.
In the Sahara, a woman
with no blood relation to protect her,
belongs to the warrior who captures her.
So now I belong to you.
The water's so cool.
The car, why is it you drive it?
It was designed and built by my father.
His dream was
to win the race across the Sahara.
Your father now resides with the stars?
My father, also. Three years, now.
He was magnificent.
The storm of the Sahara.
"Resides with the stars." Beautiful words.
Like poetry.
It is the way of the desert.
Do you know that you are spoken of
around the campfires?
Really?
They say you are an evil power,
capable of possessing a man's soul.
And what do you say?
You are not evil.
Our destinies are now one.
I wish we could stay here forever.
But we risked our lives
taking this shortcut
and now we're losing all that we've gained.
You must understand
what this race means to me.
You do understand?
Go back.
Come up here.
One, two. One, two.
Roll over!
Boy.
Well now, you are the most fortunate girl.
You can say that again.
But child,
that is hardly the costume I would wear
if I was of the mind
to surrender charms such as yours.
Surrender?
You don't know, do you?
Know what?
Someone should have told you.
You are to be his bride.
It's an absolutely
extraordinarily fortunate turn of events.
The taking of a first
wife is most auspicious
so, please, hurry and change.
Everything must be perfect
when you go to him.
Don't tease me, Cambridge, please.
I'm sorry, child, I am quite serious.
But he can't, he wouldn't.
He understood, he said he did.
And he meant it. I know it.
Did he actually tell you
that you could leave?
No, but he let me believe it.
Child, he can never let you go.
It will shame him in his people's eyes.
Then he lied deliberately.
He was playing with me.
Well, I can play, too.
You tell him...
No. I'll tell him myself.
Do not approach me.
Unless you come willingly,
and only with a gift of heart.
You and your pretty words,
telling me you understood.
Well, you didn't understand anything.
Nothing!
I have to finish this race.
She is a demon,
a demon from the house of devils.
You must see that now.
Patience, Uncle.
No! She has bewitched you!
Trust me. I will make her come to me.
Oh, no, my lord, she will not come.
She is stronger than you.
She must be forced.
I'll kill you, Rasoul!
Rasoul!
Get over here in front of me
so I can see your face,
so I can spit in it.
Sand ape!
No! Just get them... Get them out of here!
No! No.
Already they are beginning to scream,
and they will not cease
until you have willingly submitted yourself
to my lord, and gone
and crawled to him to remove his shame.
The Hamancha!
Cambridge, take the children
to the west dune,
and all the women to the oasis.
Rasoul, spread the men!
Barricades! Barricades!
To the oasis! Quick! Quick! Quick!
Hurry up!
Hurry up! Now take your positions.
Jaffar, my lord, no.
Abdullah, go cover him.
The rumors are true.
They have a demon woman
to protect them.
They believe you have possessed me.
And they are right.
You cannot win against me.
As I rule the sand,
I rule you.
No.
Tonight, when the campfires are bright,
you will come to me.
Please, come to me.
Come on.
It is working.
Load up!
Britannia! Britannia, rules the waves...
Bloody hell!
-Damn fool.
-Sorry.
Here, you're gonna need this.
This is most unexpected.
I did not believe she would ever surrender.
But from the moment I looked upon you,
I have believed in the impossible.
Go on, push!
Push!
What? What?
Please let me go.
I'll do better than that, child.
I'll go with you.
We can't have you getting lost, now,
can we?
Head straight for the hills.
It's a shortcut
through the mountain to your race.
Ayesha! Ayesha!
Ayesha!
-Ayesha!
-No! No!
No! No!
-Ayesha!
-Please! No!
Ayesha!
Ayesha! Ayesha! Ayesha!
-Ayesha!
-No!
Get back! Get back!
Ayesha!
No!
No! Please! No.
Please, stop!
No!
We ride, Uncle.
Now is the moment you have waited for.
No, this is madness.
Before, you ran like a yellow dog,
today you roar like a maimed lion.
And for what? A blue-eye! A stupid girl!
Strike again, my lord.
You will not change Rasoul's mind.
They will take her to their caves,
and you cannot defeat them there.
You'll only spill good blood.
Pray, Uncle, that I do not return.
We ride!
So, at the moment, she transforms him.
Turns him into everything
you ever wanted him to be
you deny him your strength.
She has bewitched him. Made him a fool.
With your help, he would have a chance.
The blue-eyed demon
who blew my beautiful car to pieces.
Welcome.
Welcome, little demon.
Now we will see
if you are truly the devil's daughter.
Get away from me, you dirty pig!
A wildcat! And a young one.
Do you know, I collect wildcats.
Collect! You pig!
Fight me, fight me, fight me.
I love it when you fight me.
It heats the blood!
Throw her into the pit!
If she is truly a demon
she'll still be alive when I return.
Stop!
Eat them my devils!
Eat them!
Kill them!
Hurry up!
Come on, get in position. Over the hill.
In position, quickly!
Get in position. Take cover!
Rasoul, follow me!
Help!
Somebody help me!
No.
The rope!
You want me with you?
Company fire!
Jaffar!
Grab the rope!
Hurry up!
That's it!
Come on!
-I can't!
-Yes, you can!
That's good. Come on.
-No!
-Come on up!
-I'm slipping!
-You must hold on!
No!
I can't! I'm slipping. No!
Quick!
No!
Watch out!
Get out!
Slowly.
Wait, little friend, wait!
The blue-eye!
Kill Jaffar and the blue-eye!
Kill them!
-Come on!
-Look out, my lord!
Take cover!
Rasoul.
Uncle!
-I die, my lord.
-No!
All my life, I have taken orders.
From your father, and from you.
Now I would give one.
To you, my son. Will you obey?
Give it, Uncle. I will obey.
Do not follow her.
Stay with the sand.
The desert.
It is yours to take...
And to keep.
Go!
Hey! Let's get her.
Yeah!
Get in!
-Let's go.
-Go on, you'll make better time without us.
-We'll see you at the finish line, bon-bon.
-Go!
-First place. Go on!
-Go! Go!
All right!
I swear I will avenge your death.
We take the rock!
I knew she couldn't be trusted.
Takes after her father.
-You'd better jump.
-What?
I said you'd better jump,
you're dead weight.
Now!
The junction!
Hey, stop!
Blast it!
Von Glessing...
Judges! Judges!
This is my wheel.
And my wheel crossed the finish line first!
Which means I won.
I...
You done it, babe, you done it!
We saw you, kid. You were incredible!
We did it! We actually did it!
Everything's gonna be all right now,
bon-bon.
The car, the company, and you.