Phil, when did you take this one?
A couple of weeks ago.
Phil, that's impossible.
This man can't still be alive.
He's covered in tumors from head to foot.
May I take a sample?
This ground is sacred.
- We're both doctors, you know.
- Sacred ground!
No person but the Zambuli
has ever seen it before.
My God, it's true.
The healing earth exists!
The source has got to be
inside Gudjara Mountain.
Let's have a shot at it.
I have the wobblies.
Remember what Chief Haromba said?
Yes, caves are strange.
They can have weird echo effects.
But you know as well as I do, Betts,
echoes don't kill people.
Mommy!
Mom!
We'll take a sample here.
Mommy!
Janet?
The prophecy has come to pass.
On a day
when the sacred mountain cries out...
...a golden God-child
shall come from the depths of Gudjara.
And she shall grow in wisdom
and be the protector of the Zambulis...
...and all their creatures.
And she shall be called
Sheena, Queen of the Jungle.
Sleep now, little daughter.
This long day is over.
Much to learn, more to forget.
This is Shaba, the water horse.
It came to me!
Small person summons small creature.
You will grow, my daughter.
Are you all right?
A thousand, thousand moons ago...
...before She-Who-ls-Unknown
taught us peace...
...the Zambulis were great archers.
You will recall this when your time comes.
When will that be, Shaman?
I cannot say, Sheena.
But there will be great trouble
over the land.
You will know it when it comes.
- Good morning, your Highness.
- Hi, baby!
- Tell Mr. Grizzard I'm on my way up.
- Right away.
- You've got it?
- Right here.
It's confirmation of the sample
from the geo-satellite.
It's titanium all right!
Look at that, see that?
The Gudjara Mountain.
It's practically made of it!
There are billions in there for you...
And me, Prince. Right?
Burn it!
You mean it's on for tonight?
Yes!
Historically speaking,
killing a king has often brought bad luck.
Especially when he's your brother.
It's the only way.
He has this thing about the Zambulis.
Nobody steps on their turf.
- As long as he's king...
- Yeah, I know. No mining on Zambuli land.
Here's your prescription, Grizzy.
Take them after a meal.
I've added a cute touch, by the way.
You know those TV guys who are coming?
My pal, Vic Casey.
- What about him?
- Story on me for Sportsworld.
They'll be there tonight.
They'll catch my act on film.
- Sounds pretty risky.
- Not a bit!
My grief will break your heart.
- I don't like it!
- Trust me, man.
I'm the guy who kicked a 68-yard field goal
against the Denvers!
Who can stop me?
Shaman, we're not camping here?
You make camp.
This is the end of our Zambuli lands.
- From here, I walk alone.
- Please, don't go.
I must go. The city is a place of evil.
I've never visited one in my life.
But you know I must go there
to warn the king.
Are you sure he is in danger?
One is sure of nothing.
But I had the vision again last night.
I saw him lying in his own blood.
Our lands destroyed by a strange flame.
The heart torn
from our sacred mountain of Gudjara.
This cannot be.
Who would kill such a good king?
An enemy. One who takes without asking.
Embrace me now.
My heart goes with you, Shaman.
And my fear.
Keep the fear inside you.
I carry enough of my own.
I lost count. How many have I had so far?
Six or seven?
You're going down the drain, Fletch.
You're right. Twenty pounds or else.
How's this for an opening shot?
We'll start in close on the tee.
You're kidding.
The King of Tigora is gonna bend down
and hold the football for a place kick?
When it's his brother Otwani kicking
for national television, he will.
Good luck.
I know you're pals with Otwani, but he...
Holy shit!
Look, right down there by the falls!
Where are we now? What are we by?
Tigora, sir.
Near the end of Zambuli territory.
Any white folk here?
No, very black!
King Jabalani keeps even us Tigorans
out of Zambuli land.
I'll bite, what did I miss?
You're not gonna believe this, Vic.
I just saw a blonde!
A blonde what?
A blonde. A girl!
She was swinging in the trees!
You mean a blonde gorilla?
I know the difference
between a gorilla and a girl!
You know, I'm worried.
Eight thousand miles from home,
my cameraman's mind has gone to mush...
...on some whacked-out water diet!
I know what I saw.
I know you did, and I believe you.
Page 4. Any problem with the setup?
Here's your prescription, Grizzy,
take them after a meal.
My man! What's happening!
My buddy!
Bad man of the Cougars!
How are you doing?
Astonishing. Is that the normal
greeting in your country?
It's called a "high five." Try it.
I'm Vic Casey.
Welcome to Tigora, Mr. Casey.
I'm King Jabalani.
Oh, Jesus. Excuse me.
I found it tingling and delightful.
Our intended bride, Princess Zanda.
Cool!
Please follow us, Mr. Casey.
Fletch, get the bags, will you?
What's wrong? Are you lost?
I am not. Do I look lost?
You look like a Zambuli.
That is true. I am their shaman.
I have journeyed many days to Azan.
Where do I find the king?
So you want the king?
I've told you that already. Take me to him.
You're coming with us.
You would prefer the head of the table
for yourself, dear brother?
Not at all.
I have heard a strange rumor.
The cellar of the Grand Hotel
has armed guests.
Extremely strange.
You think someone's planning
a revolution?
I think it would be very wise
if you were to look into this.
Why are you here? You know it's not safe.
Mary, run to the Grand Hotel.
Tell Colonel Jorgenson I said
to keep his head down for a few hours.
Yes, Sir.
He's discovered something?
Nothing serious. Relax.
Did you hear the Zambuli shaman
has come to town?
Of course I've heard. I've had her arrested.
Are you crazy? Why?
What if Jabalani finds out?
He never will.
A Zambuli Bow.
A dead king.
And a Zambuli shaman to hang for it!
What could be neater?
You're pretty good.
You're so wrong.
I am the most wicked woman in Tigora.
Marika!
I can't believe it!
Dinner at the palace, right?
I'm supposed to have cheese today.
I bet they have breadfruit and lasagna.
Be good for you.
Excellent preventative
against seeing imaginary blondes!
I'm telling you she was not imaginary!
I know a girl when I see one!
What was she doing in the jungle?
Her junior year abroad?
We missed our floor.
Tell me again. At the airport
you saw a helicopter gunship?
No! Our story is about a guy
who kicks 60-yard field goals...
...and his brother is a king. That's it!
Center pic. Good, hold it there.
Higher up. Good.
Right, come on, Fletch, follow the pigs.
Watch the boobs
coming into the right of your frame.
Boobs? What kind of talk is that?
As in tits. Zanda, the king's sweetie.
We're for network, remember?
I see what you mean!
Boy, do I see what you mean!
Okay, follow the pigs.
- Jammed!
- Clear it, I need this shot!
A toast, dear friends.
A toast to our beloved brother,
Prince Otwani.
May his exploits with his royal foot...
...lead him to that curious American glory,
which I confess, puzzles me completely...
- Got it.
- Go.
..."Superbowl champions"!
Give me another magazine, quick!
Take this to the lab!
Start it through the soup, go on!
A Zambuli arrow!
It's a Zambuli woman.
We caught her with a bow.
No, Otwani! You are the king now.
You are quite right, Princess Zanda.
We'll leave her to the hangman.
Nairobi, Capetown...
Okay, that's got it.
I don't give a damn,
just tell me where I can rent a Learjet!
Baby, you are talking to a man in pain.
I am sitting on an Emmy
and I can't get it out!
- You know what that means?
- Sounds like he needs a laxative!
Here's the piece
where the camera jammed.
No, 86 that, it was off the action.
Look at it first.
There might be a good frame or two.
What is this?
I don't know.
Let's look at it on the viewer.
Vic, take a look at this.
Right down in there.
Well, whatever it is, it's in a tree.
Look. There's the branch.
I'll run it ahead a bit.
Now, what's that line going across there?
Looks like a scratch.
That's no scratch,
it's an arrow coming out of that tree...
...going in just the right direction
to kill the king.
And that is a steel crossbow firing it.
And that's not a Zambuli bow, for sure!
Jesus, kid, if you're right,
you just got your union card!
"Top of the news," the man says.
"Dan Rather time."
We could get killed doing this!
I'm talking about bullets through the head!
Let's just turn around and go back.
All right, Fletch, you're absolutely right.
First plane in the morning, I promise.
I want to interview that Zambuli woman
they've got locked in jail first.
Not only is he suicidal, he's crazy!
They're not going to let us
just walk up in there, you know.
I have a pass.
A what? Let me see it!
What are you waiting for?
- The battery has gone dead!
- Too bad!
We'll start with an establishing shot,
then I want to zoom in on the gate.
Back when we played "doctor,"
that's what we called a girl. A blonde!
Fletch, I apologize! Roll, roll it!
- Vic, that's jungle up ahead.
- Sure looks like it.
I'm a city boy.
I get paranoid going to zoos!
Close your eyes.
We are ready to go.
Mission: Find and kill!
It's your neck if that shaman lives to talk.
And ditto for Mr. Casey
if he's made contact and got her story.
Consider them dead.
And the girl.
I want to see her alive.
She sounds interesting.
Not to me! You will kill her on sight,
Colonel Jorgenson!
Cool it! No women's lib stuff around here,
I give the orders!
With them finished,
it's on to Gudjara full speed.
What's wrong?
Hoof prints.
Running, I think.
- How many toes has a zebra got, if any?
- He thinks he's the Last of the Mohicans!
I could sue you for kidnapping
and you're bugging me about zebra toes?
All right!
I admit we have as much chance
of finding her here as a McDonalds.
But Fletch, we both saw her.
And while there's hope...
Nice kitty, nice.
Heel.
Make that plural.
Your friends?
Do you want to die?
No.
Then go back! Tell the rest of your evil,
killing tribe not to hunt us!
You will remain here
to be sure he obeys me.
Get out!
I don't think so.
They understand you?
Of course!
Who are you?
I am Sheena.
I'm Vic Casey.
I cold-cocked that guard
when he was about to shoot you.
Remember?
You will be safe inside the circle.
Do not cross it.
Kibor, you stay here!
Hey, where are you going?
Who is that girl?
You okay?
Where are we?
Central Park. Why?
Thank God. I thought I was...
We really have to do something
about this park!
It's getting worse all the time.
Your hand, it's so cold.
The flame departs.
Don't leave me.
I must, daughter.
My time is done, as yours is beginning.
It was foretold.
Sheena will protect the Zambulis
at a time of great trouble.
She'll guard the sacred mountain...
...from the men
who would tear out its riches.
How? What can one woman do
against a man so strong...
...so evil as Otwani?
You're not alone.
I see a friend at your side.
Who? How will I know who it is?
How does one ever know?
You'll look at his eyes. You'll see.
You must go now.
Leave me in the home
Chango has made for me.
Shaman. Mother.
How soft, my daughter,
how pleasing to me.
Your tears upon me,
to extinguish the last embers.
My Sheena, my queen.
This is amazing!
It even keeps the mosquitoes out!
Now tell me. Why did you follow us?
We're storytellers, with pictures, too.
And, baby, have we got a story here!
Take me to that Zambuli woman
you busted out of jail.
The shaman? You want to see her?
Yes, you see I know she didn't kill the king.
Let me carry her own words home with me
and I can prove it to the whole world.
You must think I'm a fool.
Words are like the wind.
They cannot be carried home.
They can.
You must think I'm a fool.
Words are like the wind.
They cannot be carried home.
It bugs me, too.
Listen, why don't you just take him
to your shammie... your shaman?
She's gone far ahead.
You will have to take a long journey
with me.
I'd love to.
He sneaks back to Azan
to ship out some film we left there.
- I go with you.
- I like it!
Anybody object?
There is danger!
Come on, let's go! Get in here!
Get the film!
Shit!
Climb.
Come on, Vic Casey.
Colonel...
...somebody slipped.
Yeah, he fell right here.
Did they go on?
I'm not sure.
Find out.
That's what you're being paid for.
- I asked you, did they go on?
- I already told you. I'm not sure.
All right.
We hike back to the vehicles.
We sure handled that okay.
Fletch, you shouldn't be in Azan.
They are looking for you!
I know.
They were at the lab a half-hour ago.
- You're probably going to be next!
- What?
How many have I had now? Let's see...
...three, no, I had six, seven...
I am going insane!
What is happening?
All right, Juka, you did it, you got it!
The village where I was born
is only a few miles away.
We'll be safe there.
- Where is Vic?
- Don't ask!
Why don't you come in and wash?
You're as dirty as a wart hog!
No, I don't think so.
Water frightens you?
Well, no, not exactly.
Come in, Vic Casey, the water is cold!
It's so good for you!
Remove those strange skins you wear.
From what animal do they come?
The wild silk moth.
It roams in Bloomingdale's.
- Fur! You have fur!
- I have what?
The Zambuli men do not have fur
on their bodies. This cannot be.
Would you go back in the water, please?
Why?
Red One to Hawk One, do you copy?
Hawk One copies Red One, over.
How's it coming?
Very good. Over.
What I want to hear is, "Very soon."
We will be safe here for a while.
They would never believe
you could run over such rocks.
- Me?
- Of course. They know I can run anywhere.
Difficult on their feet.
I think we catch them now.
Wadman.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing is the matter. Tracks.
Zebra, deep.
- Must be carrying a heavy load.
- Somebody riding it, you mean?
Yeah.
- Maybe two people.
- Good.
Let's go!
Your hair smells fantastic!
What did you wash it with?
Zam Zam berries!
What else would a woman use?
Are your feet better now?
I think it's just possible
I might walk again sometime.
Sometime very soon.
Rest, Marika. Eat.
I will summon you again soon. Go ahead.
Come on, Vic Casey.
The dry season.
They cannot find anything to eat.
That big one in front, he's looking at me.
That's a cow, Vic Casey.
All the big ones are cows.
They wouldn't eat you
if you were the last thing on earth.
Sheena, where did you learn all this?
Shaman taught me.
She told me everything.
I'm sorry.
Sorry?
I sat up last night.
You talked in your sleep.
I know she's gone.
Then why do you still travel with me?
You said it was to find the shaman,
to catch her words in your box.
I did want to. That was the truth.
But since then, I've found other reasons.
Say what you mean.
It's called chemistry.
Say what you mean. Stop using words
you know I do not understand.
Do you understand that?
No.
Mouths were given us to eat with.
Why did you touch yours to mine?
There's your 10,
and I'll raise you 10 more.
Sorry, Gramps. Queens full.
You lose!
Mombassa straight beat full house.
This pile of junk?
All red color!
One jack, rest of cards all even number.
Mombassa straight!
Otwani has cut the long lines.
No calls outside Tigora.
- And the airports?
- Closed. No airplanes.
But the bastards are working awful hard
to fix the gun-chopper.
Jesus!
Vic!
These Zambulis of yours,
do they have guns?
Never! Guns are bad. Arrows!
Against machine guns?
Against armored cars?
A thousand, thousand moons ago,
they were the greatest of all warriors.
Before She-Who-ls-Unknown
brought peace to every creature.
It is told!
You make me want to cry.
For what?
Just everything.
These are good. We'll eat here.
We need strength.
Tiki saw something. Wait here.
Sheena.
Look through these.
Try them, they're magic.
Bad magic!
They've made you into a pygmy!
Try the other end.
Vic Casey, you are a giant!
Occasionally.
We'll blow it up!
All right, get some plastics
and blow the damned thing up!
Chango has stopped them.
The soldier wagons drink water.
- Gasoline. How far back?
- An hour's running.
- An hour's running for you or me?
- You.
That's way too close.
Come on, we have to get out of here.
All right, get behind the vehicles. Move!
Fletch, you are drinking
from two glasses now?
That's right,
because there's two of me to get smashed!
- Two of you?
- Yeah.
Fletch Number 1: He says,
"Go on up to Central Park, find Vic!"
Fletch Number 2:
He says, "To hell with that fool.
"Walk across the border,
get the film out and get myself an Emmy."
Cheers.
- How many have I had now?
- Fletch Number 1...
...if you want to go up into the park,
I know the greatest tracker in Tigora.
I don't.
I'd rather jump off the Brooklyn Bridge.
Where is he?
This is murder!
These thorn trees are our friends.
They will let us rest for the night in safety.
What do you mean?
The soldier wagons
must come through here.
Their round rubber feet
will be wrecked to pieces.
This forest ends soon.
We will be at the Lake of Birds.
The Zambuli lands begin there.
Across those hills is Z'Kuru,
the first Zambuli village.
My feet will be swifter
when they're back on the sacred land.
You must be kidding! Swifter?
Such beauty!
Beyond belief.
I have been here at sunset 100 times.
And it has never moved me
as it does tonight.
- Shall I tell you why?
- Please.
I am not a foolish young girl, Vic Casey.
The shaman taught me that brave tales
do not always have happy endings.
I know what guns can do.
I know that you and I may not live
to see another sunset.
- You are an enemy.
- I'm what?
The shaman taught me.
An enemy is one
who takes without asking.
I'll ask then. May I?
Yes.
Hold it!
Refuel!
What's going on here?
These men got dragged
through the thorn trees!
So bury them!
It was a tiring night.
The morale of the men is not good.
- A little killing is going to cheer them up.
- I don't understand.
We're in Zambuli territory.
Z'Kuru, next village. We hit it!
Their direct line of flight to Gudjara is here.
Z'Kuru is off to the side.
I don't care! We zap Z'Kuru!
Now, the message goes ahead
by the jungle telegraph.
Those Zambulis up in Gudjara
won't stop running till they hit Cairo!
It is good psychology.
It is good for the men.
Looks like you're going to enjoy it,
too, Jorgie.
Oh, yeah.
You will be made welcome in Z'Kuru.
The headman's locust-bean cakes,
they'll be your locust-bean cakes.
His fermented buffalo milk
will be your fermented buffalo milk.
- His week-old dried...
- Please, I'm eating!
I will speak to the men
of the time of arrows.
We will take our bows
and attack the soldier wagons!
- What was that?
- An earthquake, maybe.
The land roars at Otwani.
- No!
- Let me see!
We'll beat the bastards to Gudjara
somehow and sound a warning.
It's the only way to save their lives.
How can fire burn so hot?
How can even stone pots
be made into ashes?
Gas, probably. Gasoline.
You spoke of that before.
The water the wagons drink.
You are wrong, Vic Casey.
Warning is not the only way
to save people's lives!
What else can we do?
Stop Otwani!
Come!
Here's one with the sap dripping out.
Make flame.
Good.
You shape this with your blade.
I'll make fire grass.
- It is a good arrow.
- Yes, but it's front-heavy.
Yes, by three fingers.
They're coming!
It's the third truck from the front.
The one with the iron drums.
I see it. Get your flame ready.
Light it!
My God, you've done it!
Red One!
They're on the ridge! Go get them!
- It's circling away!
- For a better shot at us!
What do we do, Vic Casey?
The smart thing would be
to stand up and wave this.
Your cloth. It's magic?
It destroys the firebird?
No, it says we give up.
We can make it to those trees down there.
Come on, run!
Hawk One to Red One.
Red One, what's taking you so long?
We're tracking them. They're in the trees.
Marika, warn them! Get them to safety.
Go!
Wait a minute, I spot their transport!
I swear to God, I'd do it all over again.
That pleases me.
I'm sorry.
There's so much I'd like to show you.
What would you show me?
I'd show you the view
of the Trade Towers from my loft.
When you're walking down Wall Street
at night eating a sack of peanuts.
Hell, forget them!
It is easy, because there is so much
you did show me.
- Thank you, Vic Casey.
- You're thanking me?
The fire in my veins tells me I'm still alive.
I have not failed my people yet!
It's pretty amazing.
You've been on my turf all my life
and I've never met you.
How have the Zambuli ever hurt you?
Why do you chain me?
I'm your king. I can do anything I want.
- Don't even think of it!
- I'll try not to.
- What would you do with her?
- She's protector of those savages, no?
That's her story.
I would fly her over Gudjara.
I would drop her
in the great Zambuli Falls...
...with the whole tribe watching.
I like your imagination, Zanda.
You'll do it?
Sorry.
Take her away.
And bring us Mr. Casey.
You're a hard man to find, Vic, old pal.
You had it made, you asshole!
And then it got to you.
Got to me?
The cheering, the crowds.
The goddamn agents. Guys like me!
You had so much. You wanted it all.
Save that for Sunday school, Vic, old pal.
You should've stuck to your game plan.
When they put the rope around your neck,
you'll wish I had.
Around my neck?
Hey, man, it's fourth down and 99 to go.
You're behind with five seconds
left on the clock.
The ball bounces funny
in the last two minutes.
You should see some film I shot.
- I'll watch Sportsworld very closely.
- It isn't going to be on Sportsworld.
I think it'll get a better rating
at the Organization of African States.
Now, which shot is that?
Me kicking it over the palace roof?
Opens on a roast pig.
Segue into a tree, close shot, night.
Arrow zings from a catapult.
- Where are you taking me?
- Home!
We are leaving on a mission at once.
Sealed orders from King Otwani.
Now, where is this piece of film?
If you kill me, that film still goes out.
It's in Azan in safe hands.
Do you want a deal?
What do you propose?
You sign a treaty to be filed
with the United Nations...
...giving independence to the Zambulis.
It buys you the negative.
You could be bluffing.
I'd have to see it first.
That's fair.
Okay, have someone drive him to Azan.
Bring him back with the film.
All right, Blau, take him.
No tricks, old pal.
Remember, I'm holding your jungle queen.
- That cuts both ways.
- Meaning?
Meaning anything happens to her
while I'm gone, you bastard, you hang!
Lucky man.
I think he scored.
Any tips for me?
Jorgenson!
The film comes back.
Casey's ticket is one-way!
What the hell...
I see my death in your eyes.
Red One to Hawk One.
It was an accident.
Did I damage anything?
You really plan to throw me
into the Zambuli Falls.
It won't hurt a bit.
It'll be over before you know it.
My head aches.
Your firebird makes such a noise.
Fly over the village.
Bring them all out for the show.
- They're following us. Back to the falls!
- Wilco.
Bank to the left so I can push her out!
- Get us out of here!
- There's no way!
See? Even in chains we can defeat them!
Turn your minds back, my people.
Remember yourselves
a thousand, thousand moons ago!
Bring your bows!
Nice melody, huh?
Get out!
Leave!
Chief Haromba.
This is the edge of the Great Forest.
We shall wait for them here.
Now, Tiki, pass the word. Come on!
Column, halt! Stragglers!
Let's go get those bastards!
First, we secure Gudjara.
Otwani!
As long as I live,
Gudjara Mountain will not be yours!
After her!
- Straight ahead.
- She went off to the left!
- Straight ahead!
- I said, to the left!
- Chief Haromba.
- We are ready.
Hold it!
Let's get out of this damned forest!
Back up!
Attack!
Withdraw! Get them all!
Marika!
Z'Kuru!
I was only following orders.
For Z'Kuru!
Vic Casey.
Don't think about it.
How did you do?
They're all gone, dead!
Great!
- Me, too.
- No!
It's a funny thing about fatal burns...
They say there's no pain.
You're head is as clear as a bell.
I've had it, baby.
And all I can think of to say is, "Shit!"
Okay, I got the Mombassa straight,
now this Zambesi flush.
That's three red cards,
one black deuce and...
...a one-eyed jack, right?
- Jack got to be red.
Otherwise got to have
three cards under nine, add up to...
Vic!
No!
- They're killing Vic!
- No, they're not!
- They're murdering him!
- No!
Tell me more about the places
you will show me.
Where the jackals eat? Twenty-one?
I've changed my mind.
You're not seeing any of those places.
- You mean, you stay here?
- I can't.
I've got to take this earth home
to be analyzed in a lab.
Maybe even duplicate it.
It might even be a cure for cancer.
Vic Casey.
I do not understand.
They'd kill you
if they got their hands on you.
- Who would kill me?
- All of us!
You?
Hey, Vic!
Boy, are you guys hard to find! 'Morning.
We'd adore you to death.
With printed words, with moving pictures
that go through the air...
...they'd put stiff hides on your feet.
Listen, Sheena baby, just move
over a little bit so I can get you in the sun.
- Perfect...
- Let me see that a second.
It'll be really grainy when I blow it up...
What the hell are you doing?
We're talking an Emmy here! $1,000,000!
Fletch, get out of here!
A favor.
Forget the $1,000,000, huh?
I'll win it back from you
when we play poker!
If the world finds out where the healing
earth comes from, this is all gone.
You, the Zambulis,
everything you've got going here.
What are you telling me, Vic Casey?
How much I love you, Sheena.
So much it busts my heart!
My heart breaks, also.
Put out the "Don't Disturb" sign, will you?
What?
Him.
Tell him we won't be disturbed
for a few hours.
Will you return, Vic Casey?
Yes. Say it again.
I love you.
Again.
Must we waste this hour on words?