* Yee-haw!
[***]
* So many people
Got so many lines *
* They've all been tried
And it's true *
* They've all got
* So many reasons
For changing your mind *
* And there ain't
None of them new *
* But there's just
* So little distance
Between me and you *
* I think we're
Two of a kind *
* We won't do nothing
You don't want to do *
* And I won't
Tell you no lies *
* So tell me
* How do you feel
About foolin' around? **
What are you doing?
This is
my honeymoon!
You just bought yourself
a real bull.
When's
the last time
you bought
any bull semen, pal?
This is
a $100,000 bull.
* Nobody said
* It was gonna be easy
* It's only as hard
As it seems *
But... **
[HARMONIZING VOCALS]
MAN: It started, three of us:
me and Doc and Honey.
Doc and Honey got married,
but it was still
the three of us.
Honey got pregnant again.
Pretty soon,
it was just me and Doc
out there,
hacking our way
through showbiz hell.
[DOC SINGING]
* I've seen
The sweat streak *
* The pain on your face
* And you're
Caught like a clown *
* In a circus
Of strangers *
* Who do you screw
To get out of this place? *
* It's one for
* The money
* And too far
* To go
* Three fingers
* Of whiskey
* Good for
* The soul *
There you go, Doc.
My pleasure.
Thank you.
BLACKIE:
* Here you are
* The final attraction
HONEY: Get 'em
to get out of here.
That's all.
You know who I mean.
Everybody?
Yes, everybody.
Everybody out?
Everybody, out.
You heard me!
The lady said everybody out.
BLACKIE:
* Somewhere above
Everybody, out.
* Your finest performance
Out!
* Approaching perfection
* I know
What you're making *
Bye, Daddy.
* Is some kind of love
* Somewhere
* In your lifetime
What am I doing wrong?
[WHISPERING] Do it like
you did it last night.
[BACKGROUND MUSIC CONTINUES]
* So many emotions
Oh, hurry, honey!
BLACKIE: Doc's got a real
healthy imagination,
which cost him
a couple of wives
and most of our money
before leading him
to the stunning conclusion
that songwriting
was making somebody
a whole lot of bucks.
Since it obviously wasn't us,
it had to be "them,"
he immediately
quit the road forever
to be a mogul,
leaving it up to me
and the boys out here
to be the keepers the flame.
You want a statement?
I'll give you a statement.
Our relationship
is going to last forever,
maybe longer.
REPORTER: Doc,
does this mean
you're not gonna sing anymore,
you're just gonna produce?
Is Blackie
on his own?
One more time, son.
We're with you.
BLACKIE: Pick up that guitar.
* Go break a heart...
BLACKIE: Doc's ace in the hole
in this world full of wheelers
and whackos and dealers
and old obligations
and too little time
is a burning commitment
to living by his wits
without stooping to work.
Good morning, Doc.
So far, he's semi-succeeded,
thanks to innocence, audacity,
and a flat refusal
to let himself
be out-gangstered
by some fat guy in a suit.
This one fell asleep
with his beer in his hand...
You see, in the music business,
just like in real life,
it's a day-to-daily war
between the sorry
and the soulful.
No rule says
the righteous gotta win,
but I'm putting my money
on a con-man gypsy
bad-ass true-blue legendary
bandit hero,
and when it's all over,
they can say
he did it for the love,
but he was not
above the money.
Well, you know,
next party we have,
we ought to get us
a valet.
A valet with a mallet.
WOMAN: Mobile operator.
May I help you?
Hello, operator.
Get me the Ramada Inn
in El Paso, please.
MAN: Hello, Ramada Inn?
Hello. Get me Blackie Buck's
room, would you, please?
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
Yo.
Hello, Blackie. I knew
you'd still be up.
What time is it there?
How did it go?
Oh... Full house.
They got a little rowdy.
I bet you didn't have nothing
to do with that, did you?
I did the second set
with my back to the audience.
Glad you haven't lost
your sense of humor.
You need anything?
Yeah, my old singing partner.
He went on to bigger
and better things.
Bigger?
By the way, if you hear of
a girl singer, let me know.
I need one.
I'm looking for one to produce.
Matter of fact,
I got one with me here now
who sounds a little bit
like Hoyt Axton.
[SNORING]
RADIO DEEJAY: Here in the heart
of Nashville country,
it's 57 degrees
with partly cloudy skies,
clearing up this afternoon
to let the sun shine through.
The high today in Nashville
should be around 62 degrees
with overnight low
in the upper 40s.
The morning traffic
report--
Good morning, Doc.
Good morning.
What do you want
to hear?
I don't know.
How'd I do on drums?
Great.
You played your ass off
on the bass last night.
I can't
play bass.
You played bass
last night.
Is my guitar hooked up?
Sure is.
Good morning.
Sorry I'm late.
You're always sorry,
and you're always late.
* Always late
You're playing everything else
in this here supergroup.
Why don't you play
the fiddle too?
Because you play better fiddle
than I do.
Also because
I want to stack some fiddles
when we get through.
Since it's just
two of us in the group,
how about me naming the band?
All right.
The Eleven Dixie Mudcats.
Hi, Roy.
That is not
what he said.
He said you've got
to pay me $1800 a month
on an every-month basis,
not just
every now and then.
How much do I owe you?
You're back five months,
and you wrote me a check,
and it bounced.
Bounced?
The bank must've screwed up.
I sent it back to you.
It bounced again.
I'll write you
another check.
Honey, how do I know
that ain't gonna bounce?
Anita, I'm not intentionally
gonna write you a check
that will bounce.
Doc, what happens
to all your money?
Good morning.
I drove my blind brother
Tommy 2000 miles
on prayers to God
you'd listen to his song.
I'm listening.
Hit it, Tommy.
Listen to me, Doc.
I'm talking about rent money,
car payments, food, and clothes.
I don't understand
how I got behind
in your alimony.
I'll damn sure bet
you ain't behind
in Honey Carder's alimony.
She never asked for any.
Mm, Doc...
You know, I think you loved me
about 10 percent of the time,
hated me
about 10 percent of the time.
I never hated you.
I couldn't hate anybody.
Oh, yeah?
You hate Rodeo Rocky.
I've never hated
a real human being.
When are you
gonna grow up
and be a responsible
person?
I'm president
of my own publishing company,
got my own studio.
How grown up do I have to be?
You know, I think you and I
probably just got married
the wrong year and a half
of our lives,
and I'm sorry
it didn't work out.
Oh, Doc.
Why did I leave you?
I left you.
Doc, that Cajun creep
is here.
All right, Mulreaux,
send him in.
and get Hogan over here.
Well, you take the ITC,
you deduct all the interest.
You write off your fuel
and your maintenance--
I don't care about--
How much money
are you talking about?
Hogan,
you know Mulreaux.
Mulreaux,
you know Hogan.
Hey, Hogan.
How d'you do, my friend.
Chicken-fried
German food to go.
That was a long time ago.
Uh, Doc, did you
want to see me,
because I need
to see you too.
Okay, look,
write out a check
to my friend Mulreaux here
for $20,000.
Doc, I can't do that.
That's corporation
funds.
Rodeo Rocky just put the clamp
on the Cowbird Music money.
How can he do that? I'm the
president of the company.
HOGAN: You sold him
the company.
Oh, bullshit. He's just
in as an investor.
That's not what
the contract says.
You sell something
to somebody,
they own it.
You work for him.
I don't want to hear that.
How about $15,000?
That's the best damn news
I heard all day.
Here comes--
[BOTH SHOUTING]
[CHUCKLES,
WALKS AWAY]
Doc, I wouldn't
trust him
as far as we could
throw him.
I want to know how come
Anita's checks are bouncing.
Well, Rodeo Rocky
put a stop
to the Anita situation.
That son of a bitch.
Well, you sold him
the company!
Watch me
repossess it.
You'd better keep both eyes
on that son of a bitch,
because he's crazier
than you are.
Uh, Doc...
I want to talk to you.
Yeah, well,
go ahead.
Get this asshole
out of here.
He stays.
Who is he?
Purvis, Lionel Purvis.
He's the new comptroller
for Cowbird Music.
Well, you're just the prick
I want to talk to.
How come my checks
are bouncing?
You haven't been living up
your contract.
Who said?
I do.
He also turned down payment
on all those vouchers
for them invisible musicians
in that so-called superband.
Cut your
expense accounts too.
Yeah, he's gonna keep
bouncing checks to your ex-wife
until you live up
to our deal.
Some deal.
It's more like a goddamn ambush.
Hey, Doc, you live in
some kind of a western fantasy.
You ain't Doc Holliday.
You're Doc Jenkins.
I'll get you a drink.
I don't want a drink.
I want my goddamn contract back.
How much?
Hey, Doc...
Remember the old days,
when you and Blackie Buck
first came to Nashville
in that old Buick?
You both
slept in it.
How young
were we then, Doc?
Oh, how much?
Where are you gonna come up
with that kind of money?
We're talking seven figures.
Don't worry
about the goddamn money!
Now, I'm in a new business deal.
Yeah, let me guess.
He's gonna raise the Titanic.
Doc, you work for me.
You start writing
songs for me, pronto.
You don't inspire me.
I can't get in the mood.
That contract don't say shit
about mood.
You work for me, Doc,
or you got nothing!
I mean, never mind your
vouchers, your ex-wives,
your invisible
musicians.
I'll stop the $150,000 a year
I pay to keep you in golf balls.
I manage Blackie Buck,
and you can't do shit
about that.
Blackie Buck, yeah...
The way he's living,
his heart's gonna
blow up before Halloween.
You work for me, Doc!
You run Cowbird Music for me.
How could you use
his lawyer
to negotiate
your contract with him?
I mean, you should've known
he'd own you 100%.
Well, that wasn't the deal.
Well, what was the deal?
The deal was I'd put up the
talent, he'd put up the money,
we'd split 50/50.
We shook on it.
You shook hands
on it?
Doc, you didn't
sign his hand,
you signed a contract.
That's real funny.
Doc, you got cheated.
He has an exclusive
on you.
He owns you.
Do I own
this building?
Yeah, you do own
this building,
and the management
contract
with Blackie Buck,
but that's it.
* A night to remember
RADIO DEEJAY: Blackie Buck
returns to Austin.
What'd he say?
He says we're going
to Austin.
Where are we going?
We're headed
to Shreveport.
Hey!
MUSICIAN:
You deaf, or what?
Wait a minute.
This guy says we're booked
in the Austin Opry House.
That's another
Dino production.
He tried to book us
in there tonight,
but Doc turned down
the bad-paying
rat son of a bitch.
Well, it sounds like he ain't
taking no for an answer.
Yeah, well,
we don't show,
and that damned Dino
keeps the ticket money.
I'm losing my wonderful
disposition, goddamn it.
We'll get the blame.
Yeah, if we don't
show up,
Dino McLeish puts the money
in his pocket.
I'm sick and tired
of Dino McLeish.
Let's go
stomp his ass.
Hell, let's go to Austin.
RADIO: Tonight,
at the Austin Opry House...
Only the great Dino productions
could present
this fantastic country show.
In a rare Austin appearance
tonight,
Blackie Buck and the Roarers
at the Austin Opry House,
8:00 tonight.
Tickets $10 at the Opry House--
Dino, what are you
doing home?
Hold it.
I wish the vision
of how beautiful y'all are
could be painted
on the Great Wall of China.
Man, I mean that.
I love you both.
We're family, you know.
Know what that means?
Deep stuff.
So, what are you doing home?
I forgot something.
Well, I'm glad you did.
I kind of want
to go hear
Blackie Buck tonight.
We got some problems.
Blackie Buck may not show up.
Besides, Buster's too dumb
for nightlife.
Buster's got ears,
you know.
He's gonna remember
what you're saying,
grow up,
and beat the hell out of you.
Say what?
I said
you promised.
Okay. Let's go.
Come on, Buster.
So who's your opening act?
[HARMONICA PLAYING]
I'm about to make a big fool
out of myself.
There's nothing to be scared of.
Just do it like you did
in front of the mirror.
Well, looks like
your opening act
got here, anyway.
Where's
Blackie Buck?
I rented your hall,
son.
Let me worry about
if Blackie shows up.
Okay, chief.
Dino, look...
They'll
love you, babe.
I feel sick.
You're gonna chop them down
like dead limbs.
Nervous... All big stars
get nervous before a show.
Don't you know that?
I'm not a great star.
They paid money
to hear you.
They came here to see
Blackie Buck. You know it.
Yeah, but they're gonna
remember you, not him.
[WHOOPING AND CHEERING]
This little girl's shy
and nervous.
Thank you so much
for everything.
Let's give her
a great big
country greeting.
Let's hear it
for Gilda!
GILDA: * You shake my nerves
And you rattle my brain *
* Too much love
Can drive a woman insane *
* You broke my will
* Oh, what a thrill
* Goodness gracious
* Great balls of fire
* I laughed at love
'Cause I thought it was funny *
* You came along
And moved me, honey *
* I changed my mind
* This love is fine
* Goodness gracious
Great balls of fire *
* Kiss me, baby
[SHOUTS]
Tell me the truth,
Dino,
so I can get ready.
Blackie Buck
ain't really booked
here tonight, is he?
Come on.
All right,
in my office.
* You're fine
* So kind
* Got to tell the world
* That you're
Mine, mine, mine, mine *
* I chew my nails
And I twiddle my thumbs *
* I'm real nervous
But it sure is fun *
[CROWD CHEERING]
[BAND RESUMES PLAYING]
Ain't she just great?
DINO: Whoa, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah!
[BAND STOPS PLAYING]
Dear friends,
I love you so much
because I hate to be the one
to always do that...
"Hope to see you soon.
I've got the flu.
Blackie Buck."
[CROWD BOOING]
Get off
the stage!
He's in Tulsa!
[SHOUTS FROM CROWD]
[BAND STARTS PLAYING]
CROWD: We want Blackie!
We want Blackie!
Besides, I'm getting
to like you
a little more
than I want to.
Hey, make sure
she's got some money,
and make sure
she don't get back on the bus.
You got it.
[SHOUTS FROM CROWD]
Hold it! Hold it! Hold on!
You want to see Blackie Buck?
[CROWD CHEERS]
Well, I can't help
if somebody's alcoholic!
There he is!
Blackie!
Straighten up, Dino.
I'm born again.
So how about $5000?
GILDA: * All I want
Is my baby *
* And my baby
Wanting me *
* So take me
Anywhere you want me *
She's got
a nice attitude.
Hunky-dory.
* I don't want
Your sack of candy *
* Just some sweetness
Now and then *
* I got
To get myself together *
* With someone
Who wants that too *
* Maybe I can learn
To love him *
* While I'm getting over you *
[CROWD CHEERING]
No prisoners.
You're all set.
Thanks, bro.
Hey, hey, hey.
You sing real good.
Thanks for keeping
them warm for us.
I'll see you later,
all right?
Way to go,
Gilda.
They loved you out there.
You were great.
That's Blackie Buck.
[CROWD BOOING]
I've just got one more thing
to tell you ignorant assholes!
I promised you...
and I'll tell you something!
[CROWD BOOING]
Dino delivers! You like that?
Blackie Buck
and the Roarers!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[BAND BEGINS PLAYING]
Whoo!
* Hear
That holy rollin' thunder? *
* Don't it strip
Your feelings bare? *
* Smell the heartache
And the hunger *
* And the danger
In the air *
* There's a swollen moon
A-risin' *
* And salvation on the wind
* And the dark
Is full of chances *
* You bet they never
Come again *
* Let's make this
A night to remember **
* Who am I?
Where am I? *
* What am I doing here?
* Would you tell me why?
* I've been
A little too lost *
* Just a little too long
* I had a goal
* And I thought
I was gettin' there *
* It must have passed me by
* How in the wild-lovin' world
Did I go so wrong? *
WOMAN: I love you,
Blackie!
Ee-hee!
* If you don't
Like the deal *
* Then you don't
Need to buy it *
* You ought to try it from me
* 'Cause, darlin'
It sure could be sweet *
* Yes, I'm here
To impress you, girl *
* I won't deny it long
* I mean to knock you
Right off of your feet *
* If you don't
Like the deal *
* Then you don't
Need to buy it *
* You ought to try it
For me *
* 'Cause, darlin'
It sure could be sweet **
[CHEERS AND WHISTLES
FROM CROWD]
All right!
Whoa!
I, uh, I ain't got $5000.
He don't have it.
If I wanted any shit
out of you,
I'd squeeze
your head, okay?
Come on, Dino.
You're acting fidgety,
like a liar.
I've been working night and day,
man.
I took a couple of uppers.
That's true.
Put your hands out, like this.
What's...
What is that supposed to prove?
Don't shake.
This test beats
lie detectors all to hell.
Oh, man, you ain't
gonna do that, are you?
Watch me.
You flinched.
You crazy
son of a bitch.
Did he flinch?
He flinched.
So what?
What are you packing
for lunch here, Dino?
Take another $500 out of there
for Dino calling me
an alcoholic son of a bitch.
The only reason I drink
so people won't think
I'm a dope fiend.
That's five
and five.
I'm putting on-- I'm putting--
I'm putting on a big concert.
I got a spot
for you, Blackie.
This is gonna be the big one,
boy.
The word's out about you, hoss.
You don't pay your artists.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Hi.
Oh, for heaven's...
Remember me?
Young wetback
from Brownsville?
Wait a minute now.
The working girl's
favorite
and the housewife's
companion. Blackie!
Hi, you.
Hi, Honey.
You feel just like
a homecoming queen.
Where's
everybody else?
On the bus,
in the cold?
HONEY: Cooper...
Get in here!
All right!
Whoo!
Where can you get
something to eat around here?
But, Doc, I never even thought
about being a singer before.
Oh, sure...
You feel like a singer to me.
MAN: Doc, there's
a call for you.
It's Blackie.
He's in Austin.
That's really nice.
Hi, Blackie.
Dino tried to do
his tap dance again.
We negotiated.
Dino?
Where are you?
Excuse me.
Hey, wait a minute.
I want you
to talk to somebody.
Who's that?
Say hello.
Hello?
Honey?
Oh, hi, Doc.
Uh, what are you doing there?
Well, it's my house, Doc.
I'm home.
I live here.
Honey, I've been
missing you guys a lot.
I'd like to come down
and hang out with you a while.
Listen, Doc, um...
I gotta go now, okay?
You take care.
Hey, you still looking
for that girl singer?
I was just talking
to the best one in the world.
We just worked with one
there in Austin.
Man, she's clean
as an angel's drawers,
and her name's Gilda.
Well, I was thinking
about coming to Austin anyway.
Wait for me.
Hell, I'm always waiting
for you.
Y'all just make yourself
at home.
GILDA: * To go on
Throwing good love *
* After bad
* Oh
But the fools we've been *
* Ain't nothin' like
The fools we'll be *
* To keep believin' dreams
That don't come true *
* Oh, they never do
* Because, you know
It's never wise *
* To fall in love
* To make believe
* So I'll be leavin'
* If it's all the same to you
* Yes, I'll be leavin'
* 'Cause it's all
* The same to you... *
Not bad at all.
Yeah!
GILDA: Thank you.
Thank you.
I told you
you were crazy
to sign a deal
with anyone
named Rodeo Rocky.
Sounds like
some kind of ice cream,
for Christ's sake.
Why don't you
just quit?
Leave.
Let him sue you.
What's he gonna get?
My golf cart.
Well, what else?
I need that $150000
for the kids and for Honey.
Which she ain't
asked for.
Which she ain't asked for,
but nevertheless...
Do you deliberately
make it harder
just so you can
stay interested?
Get yourself
about an hour's sleep
before Shreveport.
Your voice is getting raspy.
Hell, I'm working
on that rasp.
Makes me sound
soulful.
Hey, how's she doing?
You ought to go see.
The chick is mine.
She's signed
and sealed.
I just want to say hello.
Don't you try to steal
Gilda away from me,
will you?
This is the ticket
I've been waiting for
all my life, man.
Don't burn it down.
Any deal you make
with Gilda
has got to come
through me.
You dig?
I just want
to say hello.
Uh-huh.
Hello?
MAN: Hey, Doc.
This is Doc.
Where's Gilda?
She's in there.
Look here.
It's Doc.
Great show.
I loved it.
Gilda.
Oh, thank you.
You are so good.
This is Arly.
Thanks for
coming down.
A rodeo buckle?
Yep. Calf roping.
Can I get you
something to drink?
No, thanks.
The regular?
[STAMMERS]
I don't know
what it is.
You don't look like her
or sing like her,
but there's something
about you
that reminds me
of Honey.
You're kidding.
No, I'm not.
Honey Carder was the first woman
I ever wanted to be like.
You're gonna be
a greater star
than Honey Carder
ever was.
You know that?
Right to the point,
Dino.
I've never
been wrong
about a singer yet, Doc.
Come on.
I'm gonna check
on something.
Don't let Doc talk you
out of your pants.
Oh, that's very funny.
You know,
he could be right.
What are you
talking about?
Well, not
about the pants,
about you
being a big star
some of these days.
You really could.
Honey Carder
could really sing.
Well, she still can,
God bless her.
So why'd she retire?
Well, she got tired
of traveling.
Then the kids come along...
and she just quit.
* Write it down
* What you found out
* Songwriter
* Don't let it all
* Slip away
* Speak your mind
* All the time
* Songwriter
* Someone is listening
* Today
* So write on
* Songwriter
* Write on
* Songwriter *
Okay, Dino,
I'll tell you
what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna give you
the studio time
and my time,
and I'm not gonna charge you
a producer's fee
until Gilda's album
has sold 100,000.
Not gonna
charge me a fee...
Bubba, I put this band
together myself.
I found Gilda singing
in the Pentecostal
student center.
Gilda, I'm gonna pay you five--
$5000 cash upfront.
$5000? That's impossible.
You gonna give us a million
upfront.
Dino ain't gonna do shit.
In fact, you'll probably wind up
getting screwed.
He'll get robbed.
I want to book you
all over the country,
places Dino couldn't
get into with a ticket.
I haven't
traveled much.
I feel
sort of funny.
I can also produce
a hit album for you.
Dino can't do that. No offense.
I don't know if I'm ready
to make an album.
I'll be
the judge of that.
You know the big concerts
you want to do?
Yeah,
what about it?
I'll help you
put it on.
I'll get the talent
for you,
people who wouldn't normally
talk to you on the telephone.
What if it rains?
We'll go inside.
What split
do you want?
Fifty-fifty,
after expenses.
What about the
t-shirts, posters,
art show
concessions?
Same deal,
50/50.
Man, I don't
trust you.
Gilda's worth more
than one concert.
She's a star.
I'm not a star.
Honey Carder is a star.
Pull over.
You sell vacuum cleaners?
Yeah,
they're on sale.
What kind
do you got?
All kinds.
Nice suit.
Like that.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[DOOR OPENS]
DOC: How do you do, ma'am?
My name is Jenkins.
I'm with the American Research
Institute of Technology.
I'm sure
you're familiar with us.
We own and manufacturer
the beautiful and powerful
Paradise vacuum cleaner.
However, I would like
to put your mind at ease.
This has nothing to do
with a normal purchase
of our powerful
Paradise vacuum cleaner.
Could I come in
to explain the program to you?
Oh, hold on
a minute, mister.
Now, a man who looked like you
came to my door years ago
selling vacuum cleaners.
He knocked me up.
Hmm... must have been someone
from our service department.
Excuse me.
May I come in, please?
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
Just as I thought.
This looks like a clean rug
to the normal naked eye.
People think
their babies
can crawl
on rugs like this,
but wait till you see
what happens
when I put my little
Paradise to work on it.
Oh, uh-huh.
That's what that salesman
who looked like you said,
except they sent me
a different model
than the one
I ordered.
Hi.
You feel good.
So do you.
The kids in school?
Oh, it's Saturday, Doc.
They're outside playing.
Oh.
You've been up all night,
haven't you?
You want something
to drink?
How about
some iced tea?
What, you're not
drinking whiskey?
Not for almost
a year.
Oh.
Blackie says
you're moguling again.
Blackie don't know
what he's talking about.
Well, you know
what I'm talking about.
I'm the president
of my own corporation, you know.
[CHUCKLES]
You've been
an executive
of losing
corporations
most of
your adult life, Doc.
Selling your soul
is one thing,
but your copyrights--
how could you?
It's not that simple.
Yes, it is.
It's that simple,
and it's that wrong.
Why don't you stop trying
to outdo the Fortune 500
and just be what you are?
Which is a poet.
What about
all those things...
I need some help.
Well, okay.
Are you listening to me?
What about all those dreams?
Come on here...
All that talk years ago
about following
an artistic vision, huh?
Yeah, well,
bankers don't really care a lot
about artistic vision,
and they'd just as soon
not talk to poets anyway.
Oh, the bankers.
Yeah, well, the bankers
own all the art
and the artists.
They don't think about
anything but money.
You ought to be
writing, Doc.
I am writing.
As much as you're partying?
I bet your living room
still looks like
Elvis' wedding reception.
Don't tell me you can do
any writing
with all them weirdos
and freeloaders
hanging around.
It is not possible.
I bet you haven't
picked up a guitar
and written a song in so long
you've forgotten how to.
Come here.
And, on your way by,
if you could help me
pick up the guitar...
That always was
the hardest part.
Thank you.
Would you have a seat, please?
Set down for me.
* A past that's sprinkled
* With the blues
* A few old dreams
* That I can't use
* Who'll buy my memories
* Of things that used to be?
* There were the smiles
Before the tears *
* And with the smiles
* Some better years
* Who'll buy my memories
* Of things that used to be?
* When I remember
How things were *
* My memories
All lead to her *
* I'd like to start
My life anew *
* But memories
* Just make me blue
* A cottage small
* Just built for two
* A garden wall
Of violets blue *
* Who'll buy my memories
* Of things that used to be?
* Of things that used to be? *
You showoff.
Come over here
with me.
What do you want
from me, Doc?
Well, there's not
a day goes by
that I don't miss you.
I make pretty speeches
in my head to you
all the time.
I should have thrown
my body across the door
and kept you
from leaving me.
Come home with me.
You're a hard act
to follow, Doc.
God love you
for being such a dreamer,
but you leave me out.
I love you.
But I can't live
with you.
If you ever get tired
of all the partying,
me and the girls
are here.
Come home with me,
and I'll give you
anything you want.
Will you really, Doc?
[DOOR OPENS]
GIRL: I want Coke.
GIRL #2: I want
orange juice.
I want Coke.
Coke.
Hey!
[BOTH SQUEALING]
Daddy!
How are you doing?
Well, you're
growing so much!
I got something
for you.
This one's yours.
Thank you.
Oh, it's pretty.
You're welcome.
Thank you.
How's your music, angel?
Good.
I'll get my guitar.
[***]
Hey, you're
Doc Jenkins!
Yeah.
Where to?
Eastern Airlines.
Can't you find
some way
to get back
to Austin?
We sure do
miss you, Doc.
Yeah, I've been thinking
about that.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
I'm looking for that phone.
Excuse me.
[PHONE RINGS]
Fantasy Island.
Darling...
Excuse me.
Hey, will you guys shut up?
I think this is Doc.
Doc, where are you?
I want you to go rent
a U-Haul truck,
pack all my stuff,
and drive to Austin.
Drive to Austin?
Don't tell the whole world
about it,
and call me when you get there,
at the Lakeway Ramada. Got that?
The Lakeway.
The Lakeway Ramada...
Doc, you can count on me.
Hello?
Hello, Hogan?
Doc, is that you?
Do you know
what time it is?
Yeah, I know what time it is.
Are you sure I own
the Cowbird Music building?
Yes, you own
the Cowbird Music building.
[SIREN WAILS]
HOGAN: Hello?
DOC: Hogan, we did have
insurance, didn't we?
Hey, boss, you ain't
gonna believe this.
"Fire destroyed
Cowbird Music."
What?
"Fire destroyed
Cowbird Music.
What!
"Fire destroyed
Cowbird Music.
No one was harmed
in the blaze."
Shit!
DOC:
* You're callin' us heathens
* With zero respect
For the law *
* But we're
only songwriters *
* Just writing our songs
And that's all *
* We write what we live
* And we live what we write
* Is that wrong?
* Well, if you think it is
* Mr. Music Executive
* Why don't you
Write your own song? *
* Mr. Purified Country
* Don't you know what
The whole thing's about? *
* Is your head up your ass
So far *
* That you can't pull it out?
* The world's gettin' smaller
* And everyone in it
Belongs *
* If you can't see that
* Mr. Music Executive
* Why don't you
Write your own songs? **
Hey, I want the sign up
by this afternoon,
you understand?
I want it hanging there,
and I don't want any wind
blowing it down,
or it's gonna be
real ugly if it falls down.
It's gonna be ugly
for you,
it's gonna be ugly
for me.
Hi.
Oh, hi, Doc.
Doc, this is it.
This is it.
How do you like the new sign?
It's the right
state.
Oh, no. Look.
Just leave the stuff here.
I'm going to take care
of this myself.
What I need is all
of the furniture--
That chair, just leave it there,
because I'm gonna
do Doc's office myself.
Doc, hi!
Looks great.
Where's my office at?
Oh, it's right
around here.
Uh, Doc, I'm afraid
we have
one small problem.
You got the loan?
That went through fine.
What's the matter?
No, it's about the telegram
that you got today.
Who from?
It was from Rodeo Rocky.
He says he's gonna
break your knees
and poke out
your eyes.
Well, all right
for ol' Rodeo.
This is a nice place.
Where can I hide this?
Hide what?
Doc, I seriously think
this guy's mad enough
to kill you.
What you need to do
is just give him
a couple of songs.
That's the first place
he's gonna look,
is right there.
What? Doc!
I'm really scared
of this guy.
He is crazy.
He's liable to come in here
and do anything.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
That man is a gangster.
Lone Star music.
Hi! Yeah.
Yeah, Doc's here.
Hey, Doc, it's Blackie.
Is there something weird
going on there
that I should know about?
How soon can you get out here?
What the hell
is Lone Star Music?
I'll tell you when you get here.
Playing hell with my schedule.
Blackie, I need you.
[HANGS UP PHONE]
Just relax a minute there,
darling.
Blackie...
Where are you going?
You good-looking son of a bitch.
Don't you never die.
Everything's off the truck.
I'm all finished.
No, you ain't.
Take this somewhere and hide it,
and shoot
the first son of a bitch
that touches it, okay?
And get Gilda on the phone
for me, please.
I've got her number
in my office.
I love show business.
I can't take money
for something
I didn't write.
I don't think
you should.
Actually, you should
take the credit,
I'll take
the royalties.
I can't put my name
on your song.
Strange part of it is
I can't either.
Why?
It's a business technicality.
Oh.
I don't want to get into
all this business stuff.
I just like to sing.
I think you should,
because you're
the singer,
but this is the kind
of song
that could take you
across all boundaries
and make a superstar out of you
all over the world.
Could you get me
some of those doughnuts
over there, please?
Yeah.
Is it a ballad?
One of the prettiest--
I don't do ballads.
We'll bring it up
to the kind of stuff
that you like to do...
like, uh, what
would you sing?
I don't know,
"Great Balls of Fire"?
Start it there
and bring it down
just a little bit.
What do you think?
Maybe.
[GRUMBLING]
Lone Star, my dick.
Doc isn't here right now.
I hate Texas.
You know, Doc, we would
have been great rich gentlemen--
OFFICE ASSISTANT: Ow!
[FOOTSTEPS]
All right, Doc, now
I'm going to burn you.
Get out of here!
Can I get anybody
a coffee?
Yeah. Black.
Black?
Black, Corkie.
Black.
Oh, Black. Out!
DOC: Real black.
Lose your horse?
This ain't
old "Rodeo Rocky."
This is Marvin Rapshut
from the streets
of Chicago.
And I don't let no hick like you
knock down
what I've fought my whole life
to build up!
You owe me, Doc!
You owe me
and my associates
at least six albums--
seven years
of your songwriting.
I don't care
what name
you put
on your music company.
Lone Star,
Lone Ranger...
bullshit!
That fire did nothing
but burn equipment.
I hope your associates hang you
to a light pole.
You keep messing
with me,
you're gonna end up
with nothing
but a little spot
where you're standing.
You're in deep shit!
You're a great
songwriter!
You're a genius!
What'd you write
for me? Nothing!
One song! What happened?
Something, "Tra-la-la-la!"
Something?
Nothing!
Seven goddamn years!
Prick didn't write
nothing!
[DOOR BANGS OPEN]
Hold it right there.
Put that down!
Put it down!
Easy!
Rocky, have you ever heard
of the O.K. Corral?
Don't want no violence here.
Is that the kind
of coffee you meant, Doc?
Let's be civilized.
Say hello to the president
of Lone Star Music,
Mr. Blackie Buck.
What?
[SLAPS BLACKIE]
There ain't no more
Cowbird Music,
and my and your contract
is through.
Yeah, and I'm Marie Osmond.
I'm not just talking
to one of your shit-kicking
friends, Jenkins.
Did you ever hear
of a legal injunction?
I'll have you closed down
within 60 days.
Come on.
You've been smoking
your running socks again,
haven't you?
Be serious.
You gotta help me on this.
You got to front
this company for me,
or else I ain't got
no income at all.
Jesus, Doc.
I really got a handle on it
this time.
You always had
a handle on it.
What the hell
is wrong with you?
Nothing a million dollars
won't fix.
DOC: Listen, you never even
have to come in to the company.
BLACKIE: You think that's
gonna stop that injunction?
What choice have I got?
Besides, it's already
bought us 60 days.
Come on inside.
Come here, I want
to show you something.
You're treating yourself
real good
for a bankrupt man.
This ain't my house.
This is your house.
I live in Nashville.
Rent's paid up
for six months...
Prez.
I'm not your prez.
What are you up to?
How'd you pull this off?
Well, it was a short-term loan
on a long-term lie.
It's called high finance.
It's called
bull squash.
Look out here.
I don't care what's out there.
Ta-dah!
[LAUGHING]
You asshole.
You rent me
a new backswing too?
Get in. I'll take you
for a ride.
Hey, pal, I want the president
of Lone Star Music
to work a few places
around here in Austin,
where he's already big,
and then I want him
to go out on the road
as a superstar.
Not alone,
but with an opening act,
and I'm gonna groom Gilda
for that one.
Why?
Because I got cheated,
and I want to get even.
* Losers can't believe
* In anything at all
* Hey
But never mind-- **
What's the matter?
[MUSIC STOPS PLAYING]
I can't get it right.
I can't.
I just can't get it right.
I'll come
in there.
What's wrong?
My voice cracked, and it
just didn't sound pretty.
No, it sounded great.
Let me sing harmony with you
for the bridge,
and I think
I can help you
with that phrasing part
on the bridge.
Would you run it again
from the bridge, Larry?
[MUSIC BEGINS]
* Think of all the love
We made us *
* Since you used
To be afraid of *
* Staring at
Those starry skies *
* Above our lives
* Now you're free to
* Be the best
That you can be now *
* Come here to eternity
* Love me
* Forever
[GIGGLES]
* In your love *
That was great.
All right.
Let's record it.
Okay. We'll do that.
From the top.
Hi, Blackie.
Doc wanted me
to drop this by.
What time is it?
Did I wake you up?
Not yet.
Oh. Here.
What is it?
It's Gilda's
new song, I think.
I'm sorry I bothered you.
Hey, listen, you can bother me
any time you want to.
Bye.
Bye?
How you doing, Blackie?
Hey.
Doc's feeling
a little down tonight.
Well, this'll cheer him
right up.
I need to talk
to you.
What about?
Well, I listened
to that tape
of Gilda's new song.
Oh, yeah?
What do you think?
I think she's
a shitty songwriter.
Oh, yeah?
We do need to talk.
Why are you
asking Gilda
to put her name
on your songs?
Because I can't
put my name on it.
Rodeo Rocky would get
all the money.
Why didn't you
ask me?
Because you're a songwriter.
That's the answer?
That girl's never
written anything in her life.
It's okay for people like that,
who can't write,
to say they wrote
something they didn't write.
They do that all the time,
but you're a songwriter,
and you can't say you wrote
something you didn't write
unless you really
wrote it.
Say that again.
I can't.
You're getting real strange,
Doc.
If I put my name
on one of your songs,
it would screw Rodeo Rocky,
providing you got another one
that as good
as the one you gave Gilda.
Say that again.
I can't.
You're getting
real strange, Blackie.
I'd put my name
on one of your songs,
long as it would
screw Rodeo Rocky,
as long as it was as good
as the one you gave Gilda.
Say that again.
I can't.
You're getting real strange,
Doc.
I'd put my name
on one of your songs
if it it would
screw Rodeo Rocky,
providing you got
another one
as good as the one
you gave Gilda.
You got a deal.
GILDA AND BLACKIE:
* And we can make love be
* The kind of mystery
* And, baby, you and I
* Will be making true love
* Lying soul to soul
* Inside a hideaway
* And we can make it be
The kind of mystery **
Hot damn, Doc,
I should've known
it was you
by the way
the spit squished.
How's it going?
Good, how you doing, Samuel?
Good, pretty good.
You still take payola?
You bet.
Payola ain't dead around here.
Ain't even sick.
You know, I've been pushing
old Blackie so hard,
I'm about to get a hernia.
This is Gilda's first record.
Would you play it?
Oh, yeah, we'll play it
right after this.
What's on there now?
The Geezinslaws.
You know, I've known Gilda
since the day she hit Austin,
and this is the first I ever
knew that she was a songwriter.
Says here
she wrote that one.
See? You learn something
every day.
You certainly do.
I think I like it already, Doc,
you rascal.
The more you play it,
the more you'll like it.
Well, let's play it.
Hey, talk about one
that's breaking hot.
Here you go.
Sweeping the country
like a brand-new broom,
sung and written by Gilda,
"Forever in Your Love."
Take it away, girl.
[SONG BEGINS]
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
Hello?
Turn on KVET.
GILDA ON RADIO:
* Dreamers
* Make-believe in...
All right!
Oh, my God!
* ...To last forever
Oh, God!
* Losers can't believe--
This is great!
Hey, Doc!
* Anything at all...
Thanks, Doc!
That's okay. That's why I get
90 percent, sugar.
You take the credit,
and I'll take the money.
* But don't be sorry
* Think of all the love
We made... *
I don't care
if the wheels of justice
turn slowly.
Twist them.
No, I own him.
I want him shut down.
* Now you're free to
* Be the best
That you can be now... *
You know, she writes
pretty good.
Better
than Doc Jenkins.
Oh, shit.
Rodeo Rocky
called again.
Does he have
anything new to say?
No, it's the same
message.
Yeah, I know,
if he finds me, I'm dead.
Torture first.
See you later, Doc.
Okay, Corkie.
[***]
[CROWD CHEERING]
BLACKIE AND GILDA:
* Hey
* Take it and run, child
Good morning.
Hi.
How you doing?
I'm all right.
Look here.
See right there?
Number 15,
"Forever in Your Love."
Gilda.
That's 15 in
the whole wide world.
Oh, God. Look...
Uh, you produced it,
you arranged it,
you hustled it...
All I did
was sing it.
And sang the shit
out of it too.
Now, that says
"Gilda" right there.
That don't say "Doc."
Sooner or later,
I'm gonna
cause some trouble
for you, I think.
Nah.
[***]
GILDA:
* The heavens above me
* Seem empty and green
* As dreams
* That will never come true
* The star-spangled glory
* Of love
* Fill the sky
* And my heart
* With the wonder of you
Sixth card...
"Spiritual masters
from higher realms
reveal the true nature
of God in the cosmos."
That's pretty good.
You know, I think
it was Camus who said,
"Truth is secondary
to existence."
Camus,
the jungle boy?
DINO: I was only 13 years old,
but I cried...
BAND MEMBER: Over a sheep?
What'd he say?
Something about
a damn sheep.
Nine times
out of 10, you know,
they think people
start this,
but sheep is good,
and they know it.
They'll flirt
with you.
Don't think
they won't.
Hey, Dino,
your old lady says
you ain't half
ba-a-a-a-ad.
Just remember
something:
the older the ram,
the stiffer the horn.
[***]
When I first heard Gilda sing,
I said to myself,
"Dino, this chick's a natural.
"All she needs is guidance
from you,
and a good producer."
So naturally, man,
I called Doc Jenkins.
BLACKIE: Hey.
Yeah?
Where the hell is Sam?
Don't know, boss.
Ain't seen him since
the hotel this morning.
He's probably back there
making a house call.
Where's Doc?
He's got the wheels.
I got locked out
of my room.
Could I use
your pass key,
just for a minute?
I'll bring it
right back to you.
Thank you.
[WOMAN GIGGLING, MOANING]
Dino...
Dino?
Oh, shit.
Hi.
Here you go, sweetheart.
Listen,
I can explain.
Now, Dino, she told me
that y'all had
a "plutonic" relationship.
Take a right here.
It wasn't exactly
entirely all my fault.
Stop right there.
Better me
than some asshole.
Take a swig.
Put that
right on top of your head.
Fixing to kill Sam?
Just trying to see whether
my nerves are under control.
I'm afraid you stepped in it
this time, boy.
Doc, can you talk to him,
the crazy son of a bitch?
I expect this'll be
a good lesson for you.
[SIGHS]
Fuck...
I underestimated you, Dino.
All you son o' bitches do.
BLACKIE: Anyway,
this is the song.
We're gonna do it for Dino.
[CROWD CHEERS]
* For a lady who learned
* All there is about livin'
* She sure picked
A hard way to go *
* But he loved her
* Right down to her socks
* And no further
* And her feet were
* The last ones to know *
DEEJAY: This week's number 12
is moving like a rocket:
"Forever in Your Love"
by Gilda.
Hey, we're number 12!
Gilda, we're number 12!
Did you hear that?
Congratulations, Doc!
Congratulations to you too,
Gilda.
I mean it.
I'm really happy.
I'm happy for you.
Turn it up.
Can you hear it?
How about a raise?
Number 12.
You been that high
before?
Once.
Wish them injunctions
would get here.
Yeah, we got the injunction.
When?
Last week.
Well, why the hell
didn't we serve him?
You're good
with numbers, Lionel.
What would you rather have,
100 percent of nothing,
or 100 percent
of two platinum albums?
What do you mean by that?
That song
that Gilda wrote?
Doc wrote it.
And the song that
Blackie wrote,
he wrote
that one too,
and he's writing a lot more,
and he don't think I know it.
We're gonna let that injunction
earn a little interest
before we slap him with it.
He's making us a lot of money.
A lot of money.
BLACKIE:
* Make a rule
* One by one
* With their lies
* Raisin' the danger
* Of their king
* Lord, under the gun
* No more time
* No more chances
* No more war
* Will be won
* In the end
* Only the losers
* Hold the land
* Under the gun
* Hold the truth
* Like a candle
* Let it shine
* Like the sun
* All the love
* That's left to believe in
* In a world
* World
* Under the gun
* Break a man
* Break a promise
* Break a heart
* Heart
* Break a home
* Take a long...
* Hard look at heaven
* Gone to hell
* Under the gun *
Okay, y'all go home now.
God bless you.
[BAND PLAYS INSTRUMENTALS]
It's just...
Wait. I just want you to listen
to this.
I got the auditorium
on a four-wall deal,
only had to give them
20 percent on it.
Only had to give them
20 percent on the concessions.
Doc, they could've
screwed us real bad
on that.
They're gonna
sell everything--
belt buckles, binoculars,
caps, t-shirts,
piss-warm beer,
picture programs,
popcorn, peanuts...
The whole shootin' match.
We don't have
to do nothing,
just take the money
and run.
Dino, you'd better
take a nap.
You been up
since Korea.
Yeah, that's because
I stay up 25 hours every day
keeping my eyes
on you sons o' bitches.
The way you piss away
money is phenomenal.
You promotin' that Gilda,
spendin' so goddamned
much money,
how are you gonna
break even?
Let me tell you
about Gilda.
She's number one
in the whole world.
Check that out.
Whoo!
Doc, that Cajun creep
is on the phone again.
Tell him I went to
a weaver's convention
in Itasca, Texas.
Hey, Doc, I'm gonna
tell you something.
Listen, I used
to hate you for it,
but I'm glad
you took Gilda on.
Dig it, Doc.
It's a classic.
We put all our chips
on a hysterical
neurotic drunk woman,
and she's gonna
make us rich...
Or dead.
Have you seen
where Blackie is
on the charts?
Number three!
Hey! Right behind Gilda.
[GUITAR STRUMMING]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Who is it?
GILDA: Telegram.
Shit.
[KNOCKING CONTINUES]
I'm coming.
How'd you find me?
Well, I went by
your house,
and, uh...
Ralph told me.
So...
Whatcha hiding from,
anyway?
Well, I was trying
to write some songs,
and it's not
that easy
with all the partying
going on.
Sure wish
you were into
some hard,
nasty drinking.
We could be
the same kind
of idiots tonight.
Look...
I don't--
I can't say I'm a songwriter...
I'm not a songwriter.
I just don't want to do it
anymore.
I don't want to say
I'm a songwriter.
I don't write songs.
Maybe I'm not a mogul, either.
Then it's all a game.
Come here.
Come on.
Come on...
When I was
in fifth grade,
there were always
a couple of cute guys...
a brainy guy...
a tough guy...
And then there was...
the guy that
everybody thought was...
"the guy."
There was always
the skinny little girl
in the ballerina
slippers too.
Why don't you
ever tell me
not to get drunk
on stage?
Everybody else does.
Dino does,
Arly does...
I think everybody has
to kill their own snakes.
Speaking of...
Where is Arly?
The trouble
with Arly is...
I'm in love with you.
Oh, no!
No, Doc, really.
Now, come on,
I take love serious.
I do too.
Really, Doc.
You'd better go home,
Gilda.
No. Not tonight.
You'd really better go home.
Not tonight.
No.
[PHONE RINGS]
No, don't
answer it.
Don't get it.
Don't, Doc, don't.
Hello.
Don't...
Hello?
Come on.
Oh, hi, Honey!
Honey,
you remember Gilda,
that new girl singer
I was telling you about?
Gilda, Honey says
tell you "hi."
The one that sang
so great?
Yeah, she's over here.
We're just having
a couple of drinks.
God, I wish
you was here.
I miss you a lot.
How are the kids
doing?
Straight A's!
They got straight A's
in school, Gilda.
Bye.
[DOOR CLOSES]
No, Blackie, I'm not losing it.
Why don't you come over here
and help me finish this song?
Maybe you can
screw me out of half of it
before it's over with.
And I'll explain
everything to you then.
Do you suppose
a man's got to be
a miserable son of a bitch
all the time
just to write a good song
every now and then?
That's a terrible thought.
* But from here to the end
Is what matters, my friend *
* And you're right
At the peak of your form *
You old bandit.
* Still in
* The eye of the storm *
Right on, man.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
* 'Cause from here
To the end *
* Is what matters
My friend... *
Hello.
What's up?
Man, we got to go. Gilda OD'd.
[WATER SPLASHING]
HONEY: Come on. Come on,
get up. Oh, good. Help me.
She came over here
to apologize
for trying
to seduce you,
and telling me
what a saint you are...
She passed out while
she was still talking,
she had the pill bottle
in her hand.
Oh, I'm sorry.
All right, now,
y'all go on out.
Let me get her
out of these cold clothes
so she doesn't
get pneumonia.
[GILDA WHIMPERING
AND MUMBLING]
Go on out.
It's okay, baby.
Hey, you two.
Daddy,
what's happening?
You come with me here.
[CRYING]
Gilda... Come on, honey.
Try to drink some of this.
It's hot. Be careful.
Just take
a little sip.
Okay? Is that good?
You're supposed to break
their hearts, darling.
They're not supposed
to break yours.
[SOBBING]
Gilda's gonna
be okay.
You and Blackie
go on home now.
We got a lot
to talk about,
Gilda and me.
Goodbye.
Bye, Honey.
Bye.
[LOUD MUSIC PLAYING IN HOUSE]
Can I have your attention,
please?
I hate to break up
a great party,
but it's little late,
and I'm real tired,
and I'd like to ask everybody
to knock it off
and please go home,
if you will?
Thank you very much.
[GUESTS MURMURING]
Thank you. Appreciate it.
Catch you later.
Good night, everybody.
Take care, Doc.
Thanks a lot.
Good night.
Thank you.
Happy birthday,
buddy.
Thanks, Doc.
Good night, Doc.
Good night.
Good night. See you again.
Good night, Doc.
Thanks a lot.
Bye-bye.
Bye. Thanks.
[STRUMS A SLOW TUNE]
Hi.
I just came by to tell you
that the party is over
at my house.
I asked everybody
to go home.
And, uh...
the house is empty.
Real empty.
I don't want you
to say anything.
I just wanted
to tell you that.
BLACKIE: * Thank God
You still got your feelings *
* And you're free
To be easy and warm *
* 'Cause from here
to the end *
* Is what matters, my friend
* You're right
At the peak of your form *
You old bandit.
* Still in
The eye of the storm **
Well, look who's--
Look who's here.
God, you're
looking good too.
Oh.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
How are you, Doc?
Good, good.
Well, we drove up
to Kingfisher
and got married
by Gilda's granddaddy.
Well,
congratulations!
Oh!
I think
that's fantastic.
Thank you.
There's something else
we got to tell you.
You probably
ain't gonna like it.
You'd better
tell him.
While we were in Kingfisher...
Ain't, uh...
ain't justice wonderful, Doc?
I mean, it's slow,
but it sure does work.
You are closed,
and you owe me
every dollar,
and the songs
you wrote for Blackie
you wrote for Gilda.
I guess you got me.
DOC: I know
when I'm licked.
I must be getting
old and tired.
Dropped a step somewhere.
I'm man enough to admit it
when I'm whipped,
and you always were stronger
than me,
even back in Nashville,
in the old days. Have a drink.
Humility is a quality
which becomes you, Doc.
Yeah, I've been
thinking
about slowing down
a little bit.
I think you are rapidly
approaching wisdom.
I think it's the music industry,
the concerts.
Gilda's getting so big.
I just can't handle it all.
Besides,
you deserve all that anyway.
How much?
Two million, cash.
Was the ground cold
this morning, Doc?
I mean, you want blood,
find somebody else's neck,
not mine.
I risked my life
in the Nashville fire
to saved this tape
of the Eleven Dixie Mudcats,
the supergroup.
They're all yours.
I want your management
contract
with Blackie Buck.
Mm-mm. No way.
I want my songwriter's contract
back too.
What good is that?
I'm not writing songs.
Gilda,
she's not worth that much.
She's worth more than $2 million
to a good manager like you.
I mean, you squeeze one
number-one single out of her,
and she's a star.
I mean, I hear
she's a bad drunk and a doper.
Well, why don't you
go meet her and see
if she's a bad drunk
and a doper?
Go to the concert.
If she is, we'll go back
to my old shitty contract.
But wait till you meet her
to make that decision.
Maybe I could come up
with $1 million.
Two million
is stealing from me.
You always been
pretty good at that.
One million, one million,
and you throw in Blackie.
Well, you got me in a trap.
I'm gonna take the million
for Gilda and the rest,
but I'm keeping Blackie.
All right, bring her backstage,
tomorrow night, 8:00.
You bring me
the money,
just like
I like it--
all cash.
Yeah.
Put it in water.
It may explode.
BLACKIE: * We used to talk
About the rock 'n' roll *
* Made it matter
Not to sell your soul *
* Like a banner
That we held so high *
* We weren't afraid to fall
* Instead we rolled into
The wanted sign *
* That put heaven
In between the lines *
* That kept us rockin'
Till the break of day *
* Or any break at all
* We used to take 'em
* By the day and the night
* Try to steal 'em
Without a soul in sight *
There you go.
Hey, man,
that's the wrong pass.
They changed it.
What do you mean,
they changed it?
I'm "they"--
I'm Dino McLeish.
I'm your boss, son.
Rodeo Rocky's
my boss, asshole.
Oh, Rocky.
Listen, I've got
this tape...
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
Now who's the asshole?
* We could do no wrong
* We'll never be
The same again *
* But the show goes on *
[BAND PLAYS INSTRUMENTAL]
[***]
Thank you!
What do you say, Rocky?
How are you doing?
What are you
gonna do with it
if you get it, Doc?
I'm gonna sit
up on a mountaintop somewhere.
You are a hick, Doc,
really a hick,
but I've got
a warm spot
in my heart
for you.
I mean, we've
known each other
for a long time.
Yeah, you always
were sentimental,
when you had your hand
in my pocket.
* See the light
* We had to leave behind
It is five after 8.
Where is Gilda?
She'll be here.
Let me hold that for you.
Must be getting a little heavy,
huh, Rocky?
Oh, there she is. Right there.
Come on over.
I'll introduce you.
Oh, thank you.
Hi there.
How're you doing,
Gilda?
This
is Rodeo Rocky.
This is Gilda.
Arly, how are you?
I've heard a lot about you...
but you seem to be a nice man
anyhow.
Well, I'm am a nice man...
You have
a positive sort of aura.
I do?
[SNIFFING]
You ain't been
drinking?
No.
I don't drink anymore.
You don't drink?
Hi. I'm Arly.
This is Arly.
Yeah.
Well, it was lovely
meeting you,
Mr. Rocky.
Call me Rodeo.
Rodeo.
Yeah.
ARLY: Would you
excuse us, please?
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Come on, darling.
Excuse me.
Well, what do you
think?
She's sweet, Doc.
She's sweet,
and my gut feeling
is she's honest.
Right.
Sweet, honest girl.
All right, you stick around,
because the best is yet to come.
My own lawyer
looked at this one.
You got my songwriter's
contract there?
Thank you very much.
You got the money?
Yeah, give him the money.
Give me the money. Thank you.
You know something, Doc?
What's that?
I think I got myself
a new star.
You just might.
Big one.
Real big.
See you
in Waco.
We got him.
So that's the white hat, huh?
What are you doing up there,
deer hunting?
Something like that.
Well, good luck.
You're taking off,
aren't you, hoss?
Yeah.
And you finally
got him.
We got him.
We did it.
Well, I love you, Doc.
I love you too.
God bless you.
We'll have to have
lunch sometime.
Let's do that.
Hey, Doc, here's that tape
that you wanted.
Bye, Corkie.
See you later.
Thanks for
the warning.
Hi, Blackie.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
And now,
ladies and gentlemen,
the hottest act
in country music,
Gilda!
[CROWD ROARS]
Thank you...
Thank you.
We didn't know
whether to tell you this,
but our good friend,
Doc Jenkins, said we should.
Arly and I got married
a couple of days ago.
[WILD CHEERING]
Well, I think
that's real nice, boss,
don't you?
We have found something
stronger than everything.
Something more satisfying
than anything.
And as a result of this,
we have decided
we won't be performing
any more country
or rock 'n' roll.
We have joined
the Pentecostal church...
And we will be doing
only gospel music from now on.
Doc says
those disappointed
can get your money back
at the box office.
[THUD]
Sing along with us
in joy and celebration.
* There's a church
In the valley *
* By the wildwood
* No lovelier spot
In the dale *
* No place is so dear
* To my childhood
I'm making a collection
for Rodeo Rocky.
Here's my authorization
right here.
Just give me half.
Go on, now. Keep going.
Come on. Get on the floor.
Get on the floor.
Hey, Rocky Shit Detail Man,
what are you listening to?
I'm listening
to Chopin, asshole.
Well, listen to that,
asshole.
Too much bass?
Tell Rocky I wrote it
just for him.
* Come, come, come, come
* Come to the church
In the wildwood *
* Oh, come to the church
In the vale *
[GILDA'S SONG CONTINUES]
How much did you get?
I did pretty good.
You got robbed.
There's a lot of that
going on.
How many tickets
did you sell?
Seven thousand
two hundred.
Building holds five.
Well, shit, bubba, airlines
do that all the time.
Boss?
What happened to him?
I don't know.
He just blacked out.
This will make him
feel better:
a song Doc Jenkins
wrote for him.
DOC: * Write it down
* What you found out
* Songwriter
* Don't let it all
* Slip away
* Speak your mind
* All the time
* Songwriter
* Someone is listening
* Today
* So write on
* Songwriter
* Write on
[***]
* So write on
* Songwriter
* Write on
* Songwriter *