[person whistling]
[whistling continues]
[birds warbling]
[boy] I love to ﬂy.
It's just you're alone.
You have peace and quiet.
Nothing around you but clear blue sky.
No one to hassle you.
No one to tell you
where to go or what to do.
The only bad pad about flying
is having to come back down
to the fucking world.
[ship horn blowing]
[chattering]
[pop music playing from passing car]
Spare some change, ma'am, so me
and my father can get something to eat?
-No, I don't, son.
-All right.
Why not say you're my father, man?
-[man] No.
-All right, then get lost.
I gotta make some money.
[Dewayne]
Living downtown, a typical day was
I'd get up at 12:00,
um, take a shower, get something to eat.
Then 3:00, I was on my robbing streak.
Start robbing people until 6:00, 7:00.
Spare some change, sir?
Then I'd go get my drugs, get my food.
Get my — Whoever
l was gonna sleep with for that night.
What's up, what's up?
-[girl] Not much.
-Spare some change?
-[girl] Hell no.
-Let me get a kiss.
-Oh, well. Life's hard.
Party until 12:00.
Then everybody would turn in and stuff
[blues guitar:
"Teddy Bears' Picnic" playing]
[chattering]
[rock music blaring on boom box]
♪ Burning down the house ♪
♪ Now, if you go down to the woods today
You're in-a for a big-a surprise ♪
♪ It's lovely down in the woods today
You'd better go in disguise… ♪
-[screaming, laughing]
-[man continues singing song]
Oh, that I have.
But I don't want to give it up.
-Give it up!
-No!
♪ Every teddy bear who's been good
Is sure of a treat today ♪
[singer imitates Popeye's laugh]
♪ There's lots of marvelous things to eat
And wonderful games to play ♪
♪ Beneath the trees where nobody sees ♪
♪ They'll laugh and shout in their BVDs ♪
♪ 'Cause that's the way
The teddy bears have their picnic ♪
Look at that bleached blonde.
["Teddy Bears' Picnic" continues playing]
[no audible dialogue]
[man slurring] Look, dogs.
What? Dogs?
Does she live on a farm, or what?
Fifteen dogs?
[both laugh]
♪ Now, if you go down to the woods today
You better not go alone ♪
♪ Drop me down in the wash today… ♪
-[no audible dialogue]
-[tires screeching]
♪ For every bear that ever there was
Will gather there for certain because ♪
♪ Today's the day
The teddy bears have their picnic ♪
♪ It's picnic time for teddy bears ♪
♪ Well, the teddy bears are having
A lovely time today ♪
♪ Watch them, catch them unawares ♪
♪ And see them frolic
In their market underwear ♪
♪ See them gaily gad about
They love to laugh and shout ♪
♪ They never have any cares ♪
♪ At six o'clock
Their mommies and daddies ♪
♪ Will take them home to bed ♪
♪ Well, because they're tired
And wired little teddy bears ♪
[vocalizing]
-[song ends]
-[crowd clapping, cheering]
Sir, you wouldn't be able
to spare a little bit of change?
-No.
-Not at all, huh?
You know you're a fucking dick?
[boy] I wasn't even thinking
about running away or nothing,
you know, but, uh, my dad once told me,
if I ever got caught selling pot,
never come home 'cause he'd kill me.
So when it all came down,
I just said, "Oh, well."
[Dewayne] I never miss my mom and dad.
They're just part of my past now,
the way I look at it.
-Rat, you going with her?
-What? Where?
-You going with her?
-Who, her? This is my old lady here.
-Why?
-Where you be living at?
[Rat] I be living at the ♪ Y-M-C-A ♪
[Rat] There's this old abandoned hotel,
and we took all the furniture
we could find in all the different rooms
and put it all in this one room.
And we'd just carry water up
in these gallon jugs
'cause it didn't have
no water or electricity
And we'd just shower down at this place
called the Compass on Washington Avenue
for 50 cents
and do our laundry in the laundromat
and whatever it took.
You know, it was pretty easy, actually.
Smash, bang, crash 'em up.
And then me and Jack
just started hanging out together.
I would never have even thought
about catching the train, except for Jack.
He showed me the ways of the trains —
how they run, where they go.
And Jack taught us you can tell
the main track because it sits highest.
They got, like, a gravel mound,
and it will sit higher
than all the rest of the track.
And then you just look north,
and that's toward the north yard.
Then you just count
three tracks over to your right.
And, you know, we'd just
jump on a train and be on our way.
[bell clanging]
[Tiny] I want to be really rich
and live on a farm
with a bunch of horses,
which is my main best animal,
and have three yachts or more
and diamonds and jewels
and all that stuff
[woman] So you don't have
any symptoms fight now?
I don't think so.
[woman] But you do have some concern
that you might have
a sexually transmitted disease?
Mm-hmm. Nothing serious.
It might just be trichomoniasis again.
I don't know.
[woman] Uh-huh. You ever have one before?
-Mm-hmm.
-[woman] What did you have?
I've had chlamydia,
trichomoniasis and gonorrhea.
[woman] That's quite a bit.
[Tiny] I think it is very strange
that older men like little girls,
'cause they're perverts is what they is.
I mean, I like the money,
but I don't like them.
[woman] You've been sexually active
since the time that you were treated?
-What do you mean by that?
-[woman] Oh, good question.
Have you had sex with anyone
since you were treated in Portland?
-No, just dates.
-And —
The first date I turned
was about two Thursdays ago.
Then I turned another one on a Friday.
Some dates are — are nice,
and some of them,
the young ones, are really cute,
but I don't want to be interested in them.
Except for the money, that's it.
Man, killer "doob-wah."
[Rat] When we'd get, uh,
real low on money,
I'd take Mike's .45,
because I'd sold my .38,
and I'd go roll a queer.
[holding breath]
Tastes like Colombian to me.
Ain't that bud that's going around,
that's for sure.
Oh, no way.
You gotta buy that stuff in grams.
I think it went out.
-[Jack] What did?
-Oh, I guess not.
You know Alan and that guy
he was running around with?
He had us walking around Mount Vernon
for two days
looking for this queer
that turned him on to all this procaine.
You know, we was gonna go
and live in his house for a day,
and when he went to bed
we was gonna tie him up,
you know, take all his money
he had in his wall safe,
all his procaine and all his marijuana
and stuff he had.
We walked around Mount Vernon
for two days looking for this guy.
-Yeah, he was telling me about that.
-I finally told Alan and his friend,
I told him, "Fuck off, man."
Me and Mike got on the freeway
and hitchhiked up there to Bellingham.
That's when you had all them fucking keys
and the cops was asking you —
Yeah!
What happened
to that Burlington Northern key?
My mom's got all my keys.
Just a little bit?
Spare some change?
-You know I can't spare no change.
-Come on, man. I'm poor.
Excuse me, sir.
Can you spare a little bit of change?
[Tiny] I used to
at least bring in $300, $400.
For a blowjob, it would be 30 on up.
And for a lay,
it would be, like, 40 on up.
Most of these veterinarian has
would charge more than,
you know, us little kids do.
Isn't it after every two weeks
you can get pregnant?
After your period, every two weeks?
[woman] You can get pregnant
anytime during your cycle.
A person can even get pregnant
when she's having her period.
It's not as likely.
Okay, because I pulled a date
and didn't use a rubber,
'cause he said he didn't use them, so...
[woman] How often do you
usually have your periods?
[Tiny] Every four weeks.
[woman] Mm-hmm. They come pretty regular?
[Tiny] Well, I just started in August.
-[woman] Just in August?
-[Tiny] August 17th.
[woman]
So you'd only had the one in August?
[Tiny] And the one in September.
[mutters]
[woman]
Uh-huh. Okay, so you've barely begun.
-Did you ever have periods before then?
-[Tiny] Uh-uh.
-[woman] You're how old?
-[Tiny] Fourteen.
[woman] And how would you feel
about being pregnant?
-I want a baby.
-[woman] You do?
But not by no trick, though.
[woman] But if you're pregnant right now,
then it would be a pregnancy by a trick.
And what's your feeling
about being pregnant, if you are,
if a trick is the father?
Well, I'm not getting an abortion.
-[woman] You might?
-No, I won't.
[woman] Oh, you would not get an abortion?
I don't believe in it.
[woman] And tell me about that.
Why don't —
What's your feeling about abortion?
Because it's like
you're murdering somebody.
Murd — I can't pronounce the word.
But it's, like, it's a little baby
inside you, and you're just killing it.
And that's not fair to the baby.
I mean, it's not the baby's fault.
You know what I mean?
[woman] So that would not be
a choice for you?
Mm-mmm.
[woman chuckles]
So, you want to put your feet up?
Let's slide these things out a little bit.
Oh, man.
This one's stuck.
-Okay. Slide your bottom all the way down.
-[Tiny] My blanket's falling.
A little bit farther
until you can feel me.
Okay, that's good. Just like that.
[Tiny] I mean, I used to turn dates
lots and lots of times.
Just about every day I'd be pulling dates,
day and night, day and night.
And then it's just, like,
I got busted five times,
so I don't pull dates that I don't know.
[buskers playing upbeat music]
♪ If you want joy, you must jump for it ♪
♪ If you want joy ♪
♪ You must jump for it ♪
♪ The joy of the Lord is… ♪
Everybody say I did something
when I wasn't nowhere the fuck around.
-That's what she just got through saying.
-Nobody else called the police.
He sold me a gun, and it didn't work.
I gave it to this other dude to shoot
and it blew up in his hands.
Hey, you wanna buy a knife off of me?
I got two buck knives and a pig sticker.
Homeboy handed it to me.
I seen the bullets in it.
I said, "Thanks for the gun."
He said, "You ain't taking my gun."
I said, "How come I ain't?"
[laughing]
♪ If you want joy, you must jump for it ♪
[chattering, laughing]
My mom, before she went on vacation,
about 4:00 in the morning —
they left Friday —
she comes down and she wakes me up.
She goes, "We're leaving now."
And I go, "Yeah, yeah."
It's 4:00 in the morning.
"Yeah, bye." You know?
And she goes, "I know that
you're a prostitute and everything
and I know what you're doing
and I know you've got money."
And I jumped up.
I'm like, "Did you look in my purse?"
And she goes, "No."
And I go, "Mom, I am not. Just leave."
She goes, "Fine. Thanks a lot.
I'll remember this.
All week, I'm going to be thinking about
how much you love me and everything."
I don't care. She doesn't care about me.
She never did. She doesn't.
[laughs] Oh, well.
My mama cares about me a lot.
Where is she? Where's she live?
She went to Eastern Washington,
I think, for the weekend.
That isn't even really my mom.
I was adopted.
I don't even know who my real parents are.
I don't know if they're
dead or alive or what.
I'm gonna find out, though, when I'm 18.
I can go through the court system
and find out.
But... I don't know.
Sometimes it seems like a waste of time.
If they didn't care enough to keep me,
why should I care enough
to find out who they are?
Well, you know, they could be rich,
though, right now.
You know what I'm saying?
Could be rich. Real rich.
-Yeah.
-But yet, they could be bums.
[Tiny] My real dad, I've never known.
He could be a guy that's really rich,
driving a Mercedes, you know.
Or he could he
one of these bums on the street.
I don't know. I really want to meet him.
For all I know, you know, he could be
one of these dates rolling around.
I could have dated him, for all I know.
-[music playing, loud]
-What?
["Electric Avenue" playing on boom box]
Sarah, come here.
Where's that one dude with the gun?
Oh, he's in jail. He got busted.
I'm gonna spare some change here.
I love sparing change, man.
-All right, let's go.
-[Rat] You hit the people on that side.
-l'll hit them on this side.
-[Dewayne] All right.
Ma'am, you wouldn't be willing
to spare a little change?
Excuse me, sir. Could you spare
some change so me and my brother
-can get something to eat?
-[man] Where's your brother?
[Dewayne] Right there. He's spare-changing
too, so we can get some food.
-That's for you.
-[Rat] How you doing?
And this is for your brother.
-Thank you very much.
-Thank you, sir.
[Dewayne] Rat, his panhandling technique
is a little on the rusty side.
He's gotta take lessons from me.
But me and him can make some good money.
We did once or twice.
-[Rat laughs]
-All right.
[Rat] Your mom is where?
[Dewayne] I don't know.
San Diego some where. My dad's in jail.
-Life's a bitch, ain't it?
-Are you originally here from Seattle?
-Nope.
-Where you from?
Port Orchard. Well, Washington, yeah.
Been in New York once. I left.
l hitchhiked there,
was there for an hour and left.
[Rat] Shit.
-Redmond.
-What jail is your dad in?
King County, going up
to Walla Walla State Penitentiary
for burglary and attempted arson.
[Rat scoffs]
So where you been living, before
you lived in that — wherever you live at?
-[Rat] Oh, in that hotel?
-Yeah.
Is it seriously deserted?
How long you been living there?
[Rat] Shit, since a month
after I got here to Seattle.
-Where are you from originally?
-[Rat] California.
-What part?
-[Rat] Sacramento.
I went through there one time.
It was bunk.
[Rat] I don't like Sacramento. I lived
right on the outside of Sacramento.
I went there and some faggot was trying
to pick me up, but I robbed him for $150.
-[Rat] Really?
-Yep.
-[Rat] Take his car too?
-Hell no. I hitchhike.
I love hitchhiking.
Not in Seattle, though,
'cause the only ones that'll pick you up
is hippies, stoners, or fine girls.
-I like the fine girls to pick me up.
-[laughs]
I just started doing this stuff.
I never even thought of whoring
before I got down here and then —
-You know Tracy?
-Uh-huh.
She used to live with me
when she was a homegirl.
because her parents kicked her out.
Then she disappeared.
She went downtown with Lorna.
-You know Lorna?
-Mm-hmm.
Lorna came back up and said,
you know, "Tracy's a ho now."
So then I got really worried about her.
I go, "I gotta get her.
I can't let her do that stuff."
'Cause I always heard bad things
about, like, white slavery,
that she's gonna get beat up.
That's what scared me. So I thought,
"I gotta come down here and get her out,
whether I gotta kidnap her or what."
I come down here, I see her,
she goes, "It's great!"
So I'm just going, "What?
I heard you don't like it here,
that you're getting beat up
and raped and everything."
"No, I'm — I'm making so much money,
and it's so easy.
The money comes so easy.
It's great. You oughta do it."
Then I go, "How much money do you make?"
And she started naming off,
and I just thought,
-"Wow! I think I'd better."
-[Tiny laughs]
[clears throat]
Hi, Dan.
This is Kimberly again.
Yeah. [chuckles]
So have you decided?
Do you want a date tonight?
Juan always be lettin' them broads
wear his coats and shit.
That bitch ain't gonna listen
to him for long.
She only break $30 wops.
Floyd hit me so goddamn hard, man,
when I woke up, man, it was dark.
I had to ask people around me
what had happened.
[no audible dialogue]
He goes, "If anybody beats up on you,
and I come and save you,
that means you gotta work for me."
I hope he doesn't get somebody
to beat me up so I gotta work for him.
What is you talkin' 'bout?
I don't do nothing for free. I'm a pimp.
He'll kill you. Okay? He'll ass-fuck you,
fuck you in the ear, anything.
-But I'm serious. Don't be with Patrice.
-Who?
I don't know about all that, but I know
you're making a serious mistake.
I'm gonna go out to those high schools
and get me some fresh ones.
He shoots up. He's a drug ﬁend.
Well, what do you want to do?
Who do you want to be with?
I don't know. I'm confused.
I don't know who's the right person.
I just don't know.
Oh, I know they know I'm fine.
See you later... baby!
Look, I'll tell you the truth, okay?
And this is the honest truth.
With me you'll be safer,
happier... and richer.
Hey, come here! Hey!
Michelle!
Girlfriend!
[Tiny] He raped me last year
when I first came downtown.
He raped you? He raped me too.
He took my money too.
Up in the hotel. Came up there,
told me he was gonna rob some dude.
Oh, man. And he —
He took a fucking coat hanger
and heated it up on the gas heater,
said he was gonna beat me
if I didn't take off my clothes.
-I said, "I ain't taking off my clothes."
-We're scaring her.
-ls that what you want?
-We don't mean to scare you.
-Good. Scare her. Tell her the truth.
-We're just telling you the truth.
She's running from me.
Look at her run from me.
You get beat up, and some
of these girls end up getting killed.
What, you think I'm a bad guy? Is that
why you wanna do something like that?
No!
-Huh?
-[Michelle] No.
Why — Wh-Why —
Why would you even think I'd —
What would give you the audacity
to even think of me like that?
People get killed down here.
They go to jail down here.
Everything happens down here,
and none of it's good.
I haven't seen nobody get killed.
I saw a guy get the shit
get kicked out of him by three niggers
over in front of TJ's this morning
and get hauled off in the ambulance.
He got the shit kicked out of him
because he pulled
a big old steak knife out on him.
You missed that one here,
but that was just this morning.
So, who cares? I don't really care.
Whatever happens happens.
-[radio: announcer chattering]
-[car horn honking]
[radios pop music playing]
[horn honks]
[grunting]
[girl] I should pass the word around.
You're a snitch.
-Chris, just leave me alone.
-What you gonna do about it?
Huh?
I'm gonna quit.
[Chris] Snitch!
Sorry, but I ain't no tramp,
and I ain't a fucking snitch either!
-Come over here and say it to my face!
-l'm getting pissed.
Um, no, don't take a message.
Um, did he say what time
he'd be back or anything?
Okay, well, thanks anyways.
Bye.
[coin drops in phone]
There's nothing happening!
[girl] He's cute!
I ain't trying to get
in nobody's business.
I want you to call your man
and tell your man I want to beat you up,
but I want to talk to him first
to let him know what's going on.
'Cause he's streetwise
like a motherfucker.
If you're gonna be downtown,
you're gonna be cool,
you better learn the ways of the streets
before you start hanging down there
and doing shit like you're doing.
We got five suspects caught,
and he was one of 'em.
[police radio chatter]
[group] ♪ And he shall come ♪
♪ Knock, and the door ♪
♪ Shall be opened unto you ♪
[chattering, arguing]
You stupid —
[horns honking]
-[shouting, grunting]
-[man] What the hell...
[siren wailing]
[siren continues wailing, fades]
[ship horn blowing]
[Rat] Up. Come on now, Jack. Let's go.
[Jack muttering]
[Rat] Me and Jack are real good friends.
He'II treat you right.
He won't rip you off
You know, when your back is turned,
he ain't gonna stab you.
[Rat] Shit! What is all this shit?
[Jack] I don't know, come on.
[Rat] You want a jacket? A leatherjacket?
[Jack] No, it's full of grape jelly, man.
[laughs]
[loud banging]
[Rat] What the hell's all the poundin'?
-[Jack] Well, this is a —
-[both] Chinese dumpster!
[Jack laughs]
[Rat] When you get regular dumpsters —
we call 'em regs —
you go there every night.
You check all these dumpsters,
all these different places,
and you can tell, because they're regs,
what's been there last week
and what was put in there that night.
'Cause a lot of people say,
"Well, shit, that shit could be a week old
and you can't even tell."
But you can because it's your reg.
You know, it's your regular dumpster
-Look at this.
-Oh, I think I hit the jackpot.
Jesus Christ!
This little boy is a love bird.
-[Tiny chuckles]
-[Dewayne] Young, dumb, and full of cum.
Ugh! You fool!
[Dewayne] Oh! Is he gonna kick his ass?
He's gonna kick his ass.
They both are! [laughing]
-I told her I'd give her even bus fare.
-Really?
I don't want to see her get beat up.
She's too young.
-What are you?
-l'm 15.
You ain't even 15. Don't tell me that.
-You ain't 15.
-Fuckin' next year —
-Bullshit!
-Sixth of June, dear!
Bullshit. You're talking shit.
-How come you can't say it to my face?
-I don't know what she's talkin' about.
-You ain't 15.
-You ready?
-Look at me.
-You ain't 15.
-You ready?
-That's good.
She ain't 15.
She gonna get you in trouble.
[Lulu] I've talked kids into going home.
They say 13'll get you 20!
I help a lot of people out.
Thirteen — Thirteen years old!
I ain't gotta prove myself
to show that I'm a girl.
I've thought about not being a lesbian,
but then every guy I've ever been with
screwed me over anyway.
-[chattering]
-I get along with straight people too.
It's just most of them think
because I'm gay,
l'm trying to pick up
on their girlfriends.
To tell you the truth, I gotta
like somebody a lot to even kiss 'em,
to tell you the truth.
See, I'm my own type of person. I am.
I protect a lot of people.
This bum was trying to feel on
a friend of mine's chest.
I literally walked up to him, made him
come back and apologize to the girl.
Because she is not public property.
I could understand if it was
a telephone pole or something.
He could touch it then.
It's just the way I am. I've been
like that since I've been down here.
'Cause nobody did nothing for me.
So I made him come back and apologize
and sent him on his way.
I just told him, "Go on, man,
get out of here." He left.
[man on radio] Which means Washington
weather should improve somewhat tonight.
"Improve" if you don't like the rain,
because the rain's gonna get worse.
Temperatures
will remain moderate statewide…
[woman] She has grown up quite a bit
since she is been on these streets.
She's 14 going on 21.
[man on radio] GE's new
high-tech electronic dish washer…
Extra pickles too, Mom, please.
[Tiny's mother] Put extra pickle on that.
[Tiny's mother] Oh, when l was drinking,
Erin and I used to get
in some bad arguments.
See, I could see it in her mind,
she's thinking, "Oh, no, not again."
You know I don't like mustard or ketchup.
It's gross.
Mmm! Thank you, Mom.
[Tiny's mother]
I don't know why I started drinking.
I think just 'cause of boredom
half the time.
I don't know.
Too much juice! [laughs]
-Come on. Two more bites.
-One more.
-Uh-uh.
-I don't like the bread.
[radio announcer continues talking]
[Tiny's mother]
See, I've had Erin all my life.
I've had to bring her up myself and then —
and then one day, I suddenly get married.
And I think she likes Tom, but she just
doesn't want to admit it. [laughs]
Feel like I'm pregnant.
[yawns] Oh, goodness.
-Don't you have no whipping cream?
-No.
My fear is that someday I'm going to get
a phone call or a knock on my door
and it's — she is not gonna
be there anymore.
-[in high-pitched voice] Hi, babies! Hi!
-[dogs yipping]
[Tiny] We started living at Larry's
a couple months ago
because my mom and my dad
had got kicked out of their apartment,
and Larry offered them a place to stay.
-Ow. Shit.
-Erin.
[Tiny] Naturally, you call somebody
who marries your mother a dad.
-Don't fall.
-I won't.
-[dog barking]
-[Tiny] Sometimes he's an asshole.
-But he's in the treatment center.
-[Tiny, high-pitched voice] Puppas!
He's gotta stay there for two months.
[Tiny's mother] Oh, for crying out loud.
-Damn dog.
-[dog whines]
Quit pissing on the floor now.
Look at this mess.
Open the other door.
[Tiny's mother]
Oh, for crying out... Damn that dog.
[dog whining]
Should've left her out.
What happened to this house? I cleaned it.
Oh. I'm gonna spray
some deodorant around here.
My book.
Spray some Right Guard.
[Tiny's mother laughs] Right Guard.
Well, you wanted the dog, Erin.
I didn't want her.
[sighs]
I need more makeup, Mom.
[Tiny's mother] Well...
-I wanted Cloudy Blue.
-Yeah.
Then I wanted Meadow Violets.
-Then Cl — Uh...
[Tiny's mother] She's always wanting this
and wanting that.
Now, when you're a waitress,
you just don't make that much.
I want these three frosts — Blue Flame,
Flash of Blue, and Country Lavender.
[Tiny's mother] One day she come home,
told me she's made $200.
I about fell off my chair.
And here, I wanted The Best of Bronze.
That costs too much.
Look at the price on that.
-Two for $4.99.
-Oh, two. Oh.
When Erin first told me about this,
she thought I would be really angry
with her and hate her, but I don't.
You gonna need some money for the weekend?
[Tiny] Yeah.
[Tiny's mother] It's just a phase
she is going through right now.
I can't stop her from doing this
'cause she's just gonna do it anyways.
How much money can I get? [sniffs]
-[Tiny's mother] Why?
-Just wondering.
[Tiny's mother]
So you can spend it foolishly?
Whatever. [sighs]
-Can I get 20?
-[Tiny's mother] No.
-[Tiny] Ten? Fifteen.
-No.
-Ten?
-Maybe.
You're gonna be gone the whole weekend.
-No.
-[Tiny] I'm not gonna spend it on no dope.
[Tiny's mother] She's very bullheaded.
She kinda resented me getting married.
She and Tom, just —
He tries to correct her.
-[sighs]
-[Tiny's mother] What?
I was gonna say, you think
I'd be getting that makeup
by the end of this month or next month?
Uh, probably about the 17th.
-[Tiny] The 17th?
-Of October, yeah.
Isn't that the day you got married?
Oh, yeah! How about that?
[scoffs]
[Tiny] He beats up on my mom.
He broke her leg before.
I betcha Dad's gonna
start bitching at you, probably.
No. About what?
Probably wondering
if you was sleeping with Larry or not.
Oh, Erin!
-l'm not saying you did.
-For heaven's sakes.
But that's what he's gonna
start bitching at you about.
[Tiny] He doesn't work.
He depends on my mom a lot,
which is not right.
I think a man should support the woman.
He says, "She doesn't have the money"
and all this other shit.
And I say, "It's because of you.
Because you spend her money on beer,
and she doesn't have time for me."
Now my mom's in a mess
she can't get out of
I feel really sorry for her.
[Tiny] Be a year.
Year has gone by fast, huh?
Huh?
Mom?
-[Tiny's mother] Yes.
-[glass sets on table]
-Don't bug me...
-[Tiny murmurs]
...when I'm drinking.
[Rat] When I first ran away
and came here to Seattle,
l was tired of being the middle man
between my mom and my dad is divorce.
I told my mom when I called her
about two weeks after I got here,
you know, I was in trouble with the law,
and she understood it, you know.
She said, "All right,
I'll see you when you're 18."
And I said, "All right."
And then about a month later
I called her again and I said,
"Hey, Mom, how's it going?"
And she said, "Oh, it's awful. l'm broke.
He is trying to drain me,
flying to make my life miserable."
And she stated crying a lot
and asking me to come home,
and I just said, "Mom, I gotta go,"
and I hung up on her.
Sir, you wouldn't have a dime, would you?
I need to finish my laundry.
And then l never called her again.
l never wrote her a letter or nothing.
I need to finish my laundry.
I need one more dime.
-Here you go, son.
-Thanks a lot.
Have a good day.
Fuck it, you know.
Let her think what she wants —
I'm dead, whatever she wants to think.
But I don't want to listen to her cry.
Making me feel bad.
That building at 1420 Second Avenue,
by the grace of God,
will be the new shelter
that will sleep 200 men and 15 women
and two families.
And all we ask from you is one dollar.
We don't ask
for tens, twenties, and hundreds.
But you let God move on you
and you give one dollar,
and God will bless you.
For 14 years,
I believed that God was dead!
But I do not believe that anymore.
Billy Graham convicted me
when he pointed his finger right at me
and said, "God wants you to serve him!"
When you leave here, what you gonna do?
You gonna go home.
-Right, brother?
-Sure am.
Yeah, you're gonna go home,
and you're gonna go into your big house,
and get in your big bed,
and sleep with your big wife,
and all that there, brother.
I'm gonna go to my house and I'm gonna
pack food for tomorrow's food bank.
-Okay, what religion are you?
-l'm Pentecostal.
-You're Pentecostal?
-Full Gospel.
That's what I was raised as,
a Pentecostal.
But I don't believe that shit.
You want to know how they're working us?
This is how they working us.
Remember once a year in school
when they'd tell you,
"Bring your canned goods
and give 'em to us?"
That's what they're doing.
They say, "Bring your canned goods
and give 'em to us."
Then they turn around
and give 'em back to you.
-[laughter]
-Then they say, "We're doin' somethin'.
We're doing something for y'all.
Give us some money."
That's how they working us, man.
I could stand here and say, "Yes, Lord.
Thank you, Jesus. Give me a dollar."
-You know? I can do that.
-Well, you could.
Yeah, right, I could,
and probably get a dollar.
-It's your privilege.
-But see, man, all this is nothing.
But I'm not standing here for me.
You would be standing there for you.
-Who you standing here for?
-l'm standing there for you.
-You standing here for me?
-[preacher] That's right.
-Ain't that nothin'!
-'Cause you might be hungry this winter.
You ain't gave me a dime.
We're wise out here, man. Streetwise.
Because the whole situation is,
everybody scamming. You're scamming.
You and I gonna have to talk about this.
Maybe you can wise me up a little bit.
-Yeah, 'cause you need a lot of wising...
-[laughter]
...if you think you're going to get rich
standing out here.
What gives you the audacity to think
that we gonna come off our street life
into your program, right?
-I don't want you in my program.
-Ah, just a second ago you said —
All I want to do is just bring you in
and give you a good night's sleep.
[Patrice] I can wake up in the morning,
go downstairs, eat some Cap'n Crunch?
-Cookies and coffee, whatever we got.
-And I can leave and come back again?
-Then you can leave again.
-Can I bring my girlfriend?
No. If you do, she'll have to stay
in a different place.
-No, brother. It don't work like that.
-Yeah, it works that way.
-No, but I like you, brother.
-I like you too.
-What's your name?
-Tom Robinson.
Let me have a card. Can I have a card?
[both] ♪ My mama done told me
You better shop around ♪
[Jack] ♪ My mama told me ♪
[Rat] There's many different scams.
There's eat and run.
That's where you go into a restaurant.
You know, you order something.
Usually, they'll set you right
by the cash register if you look young
and like you don't have no money
so they can see you.
But right by the cash register
is right by the door,
so that works out even better.
There's also dumpster diving.
You call Shakey's Pizza.
You can do it right out in front
of the restaurant at a pay phone.
They got a pay phone out front.
You call 'em up, you order
these Hawaiian-style pizzas
with Canadian bacon, you know.
Yes, I'd like a large pepperoni pizza
with pineapple on it.
They ask your name and your number
and you give it to 'em.
Uh, regular crust. Richard.
345-9762.
Yes, it is.
All righty. Bye-bye.
You hang up,
they call you right back, you know.
You say, "Yeah, I ordered
this, this, and this,"
they say "All right," and you hang up.
[phone rings]
Yes, this is Richard.
Yes, I did.
Uh, thin crust
with, uh, pepperoni and pineapple.
All righty. Bye-bye.
And then about an hour, you know,
nobody comes to claim the pizzas,
and they set 'em out
in the dumpster in the boxes.
And you go over there, you know,
you got six or seven free pizzas.
It's easy to survive without pulling
tricks or dates on the streets.
[chattering]
You get two hits out of every pack, man.
Five dollars a hit.
[laughter]
I sell it all the time, man.
It sells like pancakes. Hell yeah.
Me and Junior made
over a hundred and something bucks
selling nothing but bunk at a concert.
Then we went and bought some good cocaine
and... [imitates explosion]
[laughs]
[man] Oh, you guys be trippin', man!
[Rat] You never really
see James around that much.
He's always off gone somewhere, you know.
No tellin' what he's doing.
I doubt if he's turning tricks, though.
The first one you do, the last two we do.
But you make sure that we do them, okay?
It's your responsibility to make sure
you walk out of here alive.
All right.
Okay, hold a fist for me.
There we go.
[speakers: pop music playing]
[Rat] You gotta be over 18 to sell blood,
so the kids on the streets can't sell it,
so they can't make money that way.
But if you get a fake ID and you look 18,
you can go there and sell blood.
I asked Steve.
He gives me big old leftovers like this.
-Big plateful that's this high and shit.
-Ugh! Leftovers.
I could give you a big old foot
full of something right now.
No, leftovers from the same night.
You know, like lasagna and shit.
49th and Kenyon.
He was telling me that your friends —
No, my friends.
I said, "Remember that address for me."
-Oh, okay.
-[Rat] Hey, back off, Jackson. I gotta —
[Tiny] Donna!
-Back off.
-Give me your money, boy.
-Give me my money.
-[Rat] Give you your money?
[Dewayne] Yeah, give me — It's gonna be
my money when I take it from you.
-[Tiny] Donna!
-[Rat] How much money you think I took?
[Dewayne] Whatever you got
in your pocket's mine.
[Rat] Uh, let me see.
[Dewayne] Crap!
-[Rat] What was that?
-[Dewayne] We just playing.
If you're a goddamn woman,
why don't you act like one?
-Fuck you. Fuck you.
-Don't you know how?
-Don't you know how to act like a woman?
-I am a woman! Yeah!
Well, then act like one!
I don't have to act like
all these bitches down here, hell no!
I'm not talking about acting like a bitch!
Talking about acting like a woman, Lulu!
-You don't do that!
-Fuck you! You ain't my man!
You don't tell me shit!
I wouldn't be your man
even if you liked men!
You can't tell me shit!
You can't tell me nothing!
Bitch, I'm telling you
all kinds of things!
Fuck you, punk!
Yeah, punk!
-Bitch!
-Punk!
-Ho!
-Tramp!
-Get your KC,
the one with the burning
goddamn gonorrhea!
[Lulu]
I ain't putting on a dress for nobody.
I haven't done it since I was 16.
I've had my nose broke five times.
[Lulu chattering, faint]
And I've had both sets of my eye bones
on top and bottom broke.
[Lulu] Kiss my motherfuckin' ass!
I've had my jaw cracked three times.
He ain't got nothin' on me!
What the fuck is it to you?
I'll tell people
they can beat the shit out of me,
but they're not getting me
away from down here.
Calvin and Erica been down here?
Erica was, yeah.
'Cause I hear — This girl told me
that they're after my ass.
So I gotta keep it cool.
Man, I wouldn't even worry about 'em.
A lot of people after my ass 'cause
I'm not working anymore, so I don't know.
Well, be with me
and you wouldn't have to work.
-[laughs] No.
-I'm serious.
No. [laughs]
No motherfucker's gonna fuck with you.
No, I'm just not gonna
come down here anymore.
-I just felt coming down here today.
-Let me get your phone number then,
so I can call you, so we can
go out for pizza or something.
I don't have a phone right now.
Well, let me give you my number
and you call me.
-Okay, whatever.
-Anybody got a pen?
Don't got no pen. Anybody got a pen?
-Say, anybody got a pen?
-[singing, faint]
Nobody got a pen.
Fuck.
There's a pen. Thank you, sir.
Anybody got a piece of paper now?
Whoa!
[man] Well, you gained
about three inches in height
since we saw you
almost a year and a half ago.
You haven't gained much weight.
You're about the same weight as you were.
I eat all the time,
but I don't gain no weight or nothing.
Think there's a worm
inside me or something.
-You think you got worms, huh?
-I don't know.
-I want to get it checked out.
-Sure.
Can you sort of straighten up?
Do you spend a lot of time on the streets?
[Dewayne] Yup.
-What do you do down there?
-Panhandle. Just hang around.
-Hug all the girls and stuff.
-Mmm.
-You got a lot of girlfriends?
-Yup.
Mmm.
Let's see those tonsils
and see how they look now.
-Ah!
-That's good. That's good. Take it easy.
When did you have tonsillitis last?
Um, let's see.
When I was locked up in Echo Glen.
That was maybe two months ago.
-Did you go to school last year?
-Nope.
For two years, I haven't been to school.
So you haven't been to school
since you were 12, huh?
No. I'm 16.
-You're 16 now?
-Yep.
-Does it hurt when I do this?
-Nope. It feels good.
Feels good, huh?
What do you think
you'd like to do someday?
I don't know.
-Anything interest you at all?
-Nope.
You got lots of big glands in your neck.
You got chronically infected tonsils,
which certainly don't help
your growth and your nutrition any.
I might join the navy
if the world lasts that long.
Reagan's sending all them marines
shooting everybody.
All them marines gettin' shootin',
cuttin' out Russia,
and Russia's probably gonna
bomb us or something.
-Yeah, right there.
-That hurts, huh?
-Yeah.
-That hurt bad or just a little?
-Just a little.
-Just a little, huh?
Oh! Right there hurts. Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I had a blade like that
until I got busted.
It was that black one right there.
You ain't got 50 cents?
Not today. I got a job.
-You want a job?
-Nah.
Why don't you just walk up to some guy
and ask him for 50 cents to catch the bus?
-'Cause I ain't got a face like yours.
-Oh, it'll work.
He's the worst one on Pike Street.
He's the worst one out of them all.
He'll be your buddy
when you're face to face,
but as soon as you turn around,
you got a knife in your back.
It ain't worth it.
[boy] You learn how to fight,
one way or another, or you disappear.
I know how to fight,
but I like disappearing.
My mother and father got a divorce
when l was about a year old.
My mother decided
I should go to a foster home.
About five years ago, my father says,
"I want you to come over."
So, I spent six months with my father.
Six months were up,
nobody could find my mother.
A year went up,
My father got tired of me and my sister.
He told me to leave.
I left.
Hi. Is Mom there?
Hi. How ya doing?
Nothin'. Just called
to tell you I'm okay and shit.
Where am I? None of your business.
You don't even know.
No, call me a prostitute.
Come on, I dare you to.
No, that's not what I'm doing,
but that's what you called me
last time I was gone.
Yes, you did.
I called to tell you I'm okay,
to see how you were doing,
and now I'm gonna hang up saying I'm okay.
And I hope you have fun
with your stupid-ass husband. Bye.
Ooh, she pisses me off. [chuckles]
[boy] Shellie, she's a real sweet girl.
The streets is nothing
for a girl that young.
I mean, 14 years old and on the streets?
I've taken care of her a little
here and there, made sure she is eatin'.
She's like a little sister.
I like women for the simple reason
they're sweet,
they're caring, they need care.
[boy] With somebody
that cares and loves me.
In return I'll give them
everything I've got.
[Shellie] One thing I don't do
is fall in love in two or three days.
-I've made many mistakes.
-You've never lived on the streets.
I've made many mistakes —
I have so lived on the streets before.
Not like this. Not like I have.
I don't want to live
on the streets like you have.
I'm not going to either, man.
Are you gonna help me dye my hair?
-Hell no. I can't dye hair, man.
-I'Il do it myself then.
I'll do it myself then.
I don't know how I'm gonna do it,
but I'm gonna do it myself then.
Why do you want your hair dyed?
To change?
Not actually to change.
To get away from everything.
That ain't gonna get you away
from jack shit, honey.
It will, considering
I'm gonna dye my hair.
[Shellie] My mom's got seven kids.
She's 32.
I can't have you living out on the street.
So? I can't have me living here.
[sighs] I'm trying to get
some input from you, Shellie,
anything but sarcasm.
[Shellie] That's all I get around here.
-That's all I ever hear from Larry.
-That's his way of dealing with people.
Right.
-[toddler chattering]
-He makes me sick.
From when I was little
and he was a pervert and shit.
When every time I remembered that,
every time I remember what he did to me,
when he took advantage of me and shit —
[mother]
I didn't know. You wouldn't tell me.
I didn't know it
until you started asking me!
-But you wouldn't tell me then.
-[Shellie] I told you that he did.
When you asked me
if he did a certain thing, I said, "Yeah."
And then when you went and told him,
ever since then he's hated me.
Yeah, but he didn't do it anymore.
So? I still hate him
for doing it to begin with.
[toddlers babbling]
[Shellie] My wishes would be
to have a small family that was happy.
Just my older brother and my real dad
and me and my mom.
Nobody else.
Shadow asked me,
if he found a place for me to stay,
a permanent place, would I stay there?
And I said, "Yeah, probably."
He says, "Well, Patti and Munchkin
said you can stay with them.
They need the money for rent."
[Shadow] I grew up with Munchkin.
For a long time, I ran around with him.
And Patti, I met her down here
about three years ago
beating the heck out of some old dude
'cause he said something wrong to her.
Patti and Munchkin are very —
They — They were, in my eyes,
made for each other.
[video game playing
"Toccata and Fugue in D Minor"]
They argue.
But doesn't all love affairs argue?
-[electronic video game noises]
-Get him, hon.
[Shadow] They're together,
and that's the way it is.
Patti and Munchkin are a team.
That's the way they work the best.
A street couple
that are struggling to survive.
[railroad bell clanging]
[Rat] Every person,
no matter how big or tough they are,
should always have a partner.
You never want to go
on the streets alone. It's a mistake.
Whoo! [laughing]
It's just you'll get lonely,
you'll get upset, you'll get beat up.
Because you never can tell if someone's
gonna come up from the front of you
and start to get your attention,
and then this other dude
is gonna walk up behind you
and bust your fucking head.
Partners are always better.
[chattering]
[Shadow] "Immediately after mixing,
squeeze preference.
Mix all mixture
until thoroughly saturating hair.
Loosely pile hair on top of head.
Leaves your hair silky,
shiny and free of tangles."
Okay. Goddamn glove.
[Shadow]
Well, I consider myself a playboy.
A boyfriend is,
you're obligated to one girl.
Apply on top of head lightly.
I considered myself dependent
upon a couple of girls supporting me.
But as far as being a pimp, no.
I never pushed them out onto the street.
You can't be a boyfriend
and have three girlfriends,
but you can be a playboy.
A playboy is what I consider myself
[Star Wars playing on TV]
[man] Standby alert.
Death Star approaching.
Estimated time to firing range:
15 minutes.
[orchestral soundtrack score playing]
Let me see, Shadow.
See?
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Hi, little boys. Want some candy?
[both laughing]
Goddamn.
I can just see what
you're giving those little boys.
[both laugh]
I'm gonna get a tattoo right there
to cover this mess up.
-Why?
Because that looks sick. Hold on.
That right there
is what I'm gonna have done.
-Really?
-Looks hungry, don't he?
[Shadow] You ever heard of D&D —
Dungeons and Dragons?
-[Munchkin] Yeah. I've played it before.
-[Shadow] You have? Far out.
Guess how much this is gonna cost me
to have it done in a tattoo right here?
-How much?
-Fifty.
Me and Patti want to get dragons
on each side of our arms.
I want to get just this dragon.
It's one of my characters.
-[Tiny] ♪ All night long ♪
-[Shadow] He's my character.
[barking]
[Tiny] Shut up.
Son of a fucking bitch.
[Shellie]
Shit, I don't know what's my problem.
[electronic video game noises]
But now she's married again.
That's why I'm not at home.
'Cause I can't stand my stepdad.
Nobody can stand their stepdads.
Some people get along fine with them.
My first —
Too much smoke. My first stepdad was okay.
I got an idea that — It's fantastic.
We'll make some money and then you can —
We'll put it in,
uh, Lee & Sons Thrift Shop.
We're gonna open up our own store,
like that thrift store I had.
Mm-hmm.
Now as soon as I'm out a little while
I want you to come with me,
'cause I've already talked to some people
about a building in maybe Redmond.
Look around out there. See if there's
any good thrift shops out there.
-All right.
-I was supposed to get out this Friday.
But I won't because I've got to wait
for the damn parole board.
If it'd just been that burglary
it'd been all right,
but it was that stupid arson thing,
so the board wants to talk to me.
And like he said and everybody says,
you know, I've done 30 years.
What the hell good is it gonna do
to make me do a couple more years?
I've only got three years left on my max.
-Are you in a cell by yourself?
-No, l-l'm in the — I'm in the mean tank.
That's A-5. That's the mean tank.
That's for guys who've done time
and everything before.
-For a felony and stuff?
-Yeah.
-Is a bunch of The Jokers in there?
-Two of 'em are, yeah.
-Is one Stubbs?
-Yeah.
-Tell him I say hi.
-Yeah, yeah.
What's this? You're gonna have
to take your tonsils out?
They say it's always infected and stuff,
so I don't know.
They think that's why
I'm so small and stuff.
Well, you know, that's funny.
I was that way too.
-Were you small like this and stuff?
-Yep, yep.
So it could just be...
And then they took them out,
and about a year after that,
I got almost as big as I am now.
'Cause I eat all the time and stuff,
and I don't gain no weight.
Wait, after — So, you think it's just —
What do you call it?
-Tonsils and adenoids.
-Yeah, but —
-Heditary — Hereditary.
-Yeah, yeah.
All right. Yeah, how much are you smoking?
Oh, I'm cuttin' down
to maybe four cigarettes a day.
Four or five.
All right. Well, that's good.
You know, don't smoke too much
'cause that's bad too.
[Dewayne] All right, hold on.
Still messing with that weed?
-Huh?
-Still messing with that weed?
A little.
-How about anything else?
-Nope.
-Let me see your arms.
-My arms? Why?
Undo your sleeve.
No, I haven't been doing none of that.
Here, I'll even show you. Here.
See? Hold on.
-See? Nothing.
-Okay.
-What you messing with?
-Huh?
-Nothing.
You're a smart kid.
You're a good-looking kid.
You've got intelligence.
You've got my brain.
[laughs] But you're like me.
You're a con man, Dewayne.
What do you wanna be,
a little punk on the street?
Huh? Eh? You wanna be a little punk?
A little smart-ass little punk.
That's all you think you are.
You're gonna wind up just like I am.
Look at me when I talk at you. Look at me.
Pay attention to me.
That's the dang trouble.
You haven't paid any attention to me.
There's a guy in our tank, 24 years old.
They just gave him four life sentences.
Twenty-four years old.
It won't be too damn many more years
that they'll be doing that to you.
They're not gonna slap your little hand
and send you up to Echo Glen
or some damn place.
Is that what you want? Huh?
No.
Yeah, you say it now
'cause you're sitting here talking to me.
Get your hands out of your mouth.
Let me see your fingers.
Still biting your damn nails too,
ain't you?
-Yep
-Huh?
-Yep.
-When you gonna stop doing that?
Huh? When you gonna stop doing that?
You're out there,
tough guy on the street, man.
Big-time, tough little punk
is all you are.
Can't even quit biting your fingernails.
You're too goddamn little
to be tough, kid.
I'm — I'm serious.
I love you very, very much, even though
I get mad at you and want to kill you.
I love you. You're — You're all I've got.
And unfortunately, I'm all you've got.
I'm gonna make it up to you. Eh?
For all the stuff that we didn't do.
You know? [sniffles] Eh?
I know I have to talk rough
to you sometimes, Dewayne,
but you know that I love you
a whole big, big bunch.
If I get out this time, if I get out,
I'll keep you straight
and you keep me straight.
-Is that a deal?
-Mm-hmm.
-Huh?
Just remember, you and I is all we've got.
And together,
hey, there ain't nobody can whip us.
Ain't nobody can do anything to us.
[Lee] I love you.
[Dewayne] All right, bye.
[woman] Look at you. All beat up
and cut up and scarred up and drugged up.
I haven't seen you in two months.
You didn't even call me.
I can't get over that.
After I sent for you all the way
from California, down there stranded.
And you didn't even thank me.
You ought to thank me now.
-Thank you, Mom.
-[chuckling]
Call her up. You can call her up.
Nikita and them calls me,
and Todd calls me.
-[woman] Do you love your mother?
-Yes.
When you gonna show me?
-[woman chuckles]
-Hmm?
-[Patrice murmurs]
-When you gonna make me proud?
So that's what you should do.
You should stop and see Mom.
You know what I mean?
'Cause she is the only one
got a guide map to your life.
Because you can't go nowhere
unless you ask your mother
advices and things, you know that?
He don't want no advice right now.
He thinks he's doin' it.
-That's why he's getting knocked around.
-You think you're doin' it?
I love you, Patrice.
You wanna go eat something?
I'm not gonna just give you my money now.
If you wanna go eat something,
I'll feed you.
-I'm not hungry, Ma.
-Yes, you are.
What did you eat today?
Um... some cookies and, um...
-Junk food?
-And some juice.
You want something hot in your stomach.
That's what you need.
Well, if I give you some of my money,
what you gonna do with it?
Save it.
-Oh, yeah. How you gonna save it out here?
-[all chuckling]
You'll just tell me anything
just to shut me up, huh?
I'm tellin' you. He gonna save it.
-You got some money, Mama?
-Mmm, a little change.
If I think you're buying
a pack of cigarettes,
next time I see you
I won't give you a dollar.
-Okay.
-[woman] Or some weed.
-Yeah, you better not.
-[woman] Mm-hmm.
You know, that's hard-work money.
I worked for that money.
-You spend it wisely. Okay?
-Okay.
And when you get straight,
you know where your house is.
-Okay.
And the only way
you can really get straight,
you have to stay in touch with Mom,
because you can't straighten yourself.
[Lulu] I have seven brothers and sisters.
I lost one seven months ago
from, uh, cirrhosis of the liver.
She was 26.
l loved her a lot.
It made me sort of loony
for about a month, month and a half
People thought I was going crazy.
l wasn't going crazy.
I just couldn't handle it.
[Lulu, onlookers shouting]
[shouting continues]
Fuck that!
[Lulu] I just got out of jail
not even a month ago.
I ain't getting in no trouble, punk!
I bet you, guaranteed,
I got a bruise on my arm,
and I'm pressing charges on your ass.
Punk!
'Cause I hate you
and I'm gonna get you for that.
-Hey, you want him?
-[Lulu] I'm not a him. I'm a her.
-Can you please calm down?
-I'm pressing charges.
-I want you to know that.
-Fine, you do that.
-Are you a sergeant?
-I'm asking you to please calm down.
I'm calm.
Now will you please leave?
Because we have quite a crowd here.
[Lulu] You're a punk!
Punk!
[Lulu continues shouting]
I don't give a fuck! [continues shouting]
[needle whirring]
[Shadow] Giving blood, there's pain.
Falling in love, there's pain.
All you feel is the first initial needle.
The rest is lingering pain
from when the needle is pulled out.
That burns.
-[man] That's the worst part of it.
-Yeah, I know.
-Well, how do you like it?
-That's nice.
Honey...
come and help me figure this out.
Now hold this.
-Right here.
-[Munchkin] What, there?
-Right there.
-[Patti scoffs]
-[laughs]
-Bring your head back up here.
Shit burns your eyes, I'm telling you.
You're not supposed
to have your eyes open.
-Yeah, you poked me in my eye now.
-Stop being a jerk.
Thanks. You just wiped it
right across my fucking eye.
God, man.
Why don't you do
your own fucking perm, then?
[man] I probably have
about a hundred kids on my caseload
Of course, Patti is Patti.
She's an individualist,
and she'll go along with you
if you're doing what she wants,
but she isn't gonna do a damn thing
that she doesn't want to do.
I knocked on the door,
and I was just worried about you.
I don't care how worried
you're getting about me.
All I gotta say is, you don't got
no right walking into my house.
But this morning, we've got the —
You know, we've got job therapy.
We know that,
but, Jerry, you gotta understand
that you can't just be
walking into my house.
You might get shot, as far as you know.
I took the chance you wouldn't shoot me.
And then I did, I banged on the door—
Well, the next time,
you're getting shot, okay?
Okay.
So that means the rent's due today, right?
-No.
-And if you're gonna stay here —
-Not from what Bob says.
-It is.
I give Bob $20 and I told him
I'd give him the rest Friday.
This is the deal. If you're gonna stay
here, you've gotta go out to job therapy.
[Patti] You can't tell me what to do.
We've been together,
working together on this.
-Me and you ain't been together.
-We have.
We've been working together, Patti.
And I'm concerned about you, you know.
I don't want you guys
to have to hit the bricks again.
I don't want you to have
to get back into some crap
that you shouldn't be involved in
to pay your rent.
You've got a chance
to make it a good way, okay?
Now, this guy has got some ideas
that can help you get a job.
That's a better life for you
than having to be hustling on the streets
or be down there pushing —
-Who says we're hustling on the streets?
-How else you gonna make your money?
[Rat] Most of the kids on the streets,
that's how they survive.
They feel like if they don't do the dates,
that they're gonna be broke,
they're gonna have to dumpster dive,
they're gonna have to beg for money,
and that's gonna make them feel,
because they're girls,
like, "Oh, I'm no good.
l'm dirty, l'm rotten, I'm a scum.
I'm living in this rathole, you know.
No water, no electricity no nothing.
I'm begging for money."
I guess they feel
that's worse than pulling dates.
I don't know what their problem is.
Munchkin's the one that wants us out there
ho-ing and shit. I don't want to do it.
The only reason why I'm out there
is because, like I said, Patti —
Patti's out there
and she has to have somebody with her.
-But you wanna make him go to you —
-Hi.
[man] How you doing?
-[Shellie] I'm okay, how are you?
-Oh, hi.
And when I moved in with them, I said,
"Patti, I don't wanna be
ho-ing or anything."
She said, "You won't be.
Munchkin's not gonna pimp you or nothing."
[Tiny] Do you turn dates now?
[Shellie] Hell yeah. With her.
Me and Patti do.
I try to tell Patti I don't want to,
and she'll start bitching at me,
saying that I just missed a $100 date.
Every time I fuck up,
she says it was a $100 date.
[Tiny] When you do make money,
do you give it to Munchkin?
-I give it to Patti.
-[Tiny] All of it?
And Patti gives it to Munchkin.
[Tiny] And you haven't
got nothing out of it, huh?
Uh-uh.
Me and Patti are both mad fight now,
because Munchkin's sending us out here.
He is sending both of us out here
to fucking get him a suit.
All he wants is
a whole bunch of clothes and shit.
Get this. Patti hasn't pulled
any dates today at all.
-[Tiny] And you have?
-I did two.
Forty bucks each.
[Shellie] No, you don't know
what I'm doing, man.
-I don't like the shit that you think.
-Neither do I.
[Shellie] Doesn't make me happy.
That's why I walked by
without even talking to you.
For the simple reason that that's
what I thought you were doing.
[Shellie] But I ain't.
I don't do that kind of shit. I told you.
-Then what you doing just sittin' there?
-[Shellie] I'm talking!
All he does is fuckin' shoot
the shit up his damn arm, man.
Well, I told her, I said,
"Hey, I can't handle this.
I'm gonna take off and shit."
Last night, she says,
"You ain't going nowhere."
And I said, "Yes, I am."
This morning she was
talking all this shit about
now she was gonna sock me
if I even tried to go up there and stuff
I mean, I was just tripping out.
How the hell can these people
just think they own me and shit?
Nobody does.
You end up with the wrong people
down here, it's just —
You wanna know who set me up
with the wrong people?
-Who?
-A person by the name of Shadow.
Huh.
[both laugh]
You changed too.
When I first ran into you,
you were real sweet.
-I still am. I still am.
-Oh, yeah, uh-huh.
When you ended up at George's,
you were a real pain in the ass.
Now you're even worse.
I was a real pain in the ass
because you fucking bullshitted me.
-You don't bullshit with me!
-But I keep wanting to. I don't know why.
-Probably because I like you.
-[laughs]
-Drop that cigarette.
-It's not done.
Now it's done.
♪ America ♪
♪ God shed his life on y'all ♪
[laughing]
[Rat] I like a lot of the girls
on the street.
Tiny, I like her especially
She's a sweet girl.
[laughs]
You're a surprise.
Wanna go swimming?
[laughs] You think I'm crazy or something?
Right. Let's just jump in.
All right.
How about a back ﬂip?
[Tiny] The reason why I think Rat is cute,
and the reason why I love him so much,
is because he's got pretty eyes.
I think they're brown or blue.
One or the other.
[dog barking]
[Rat] I gotta go back to school someday.
'Cause I need a diploma
so I can get into the air force.
But right now,
the open road, USA, is for me.
[laughs] Check you out.
[Rat] I didn't talk to her much
about her being a prostitute.
She hadn't done it that often
from what she told me.
-[dog yelps]
-[chuckling]
Now where's my kiss, honey-bunch?
[Tiny] Not with braces.
[chattering]
Okay, Dewayne, right in here.
There we go.
I'm the smallest guy in the unit.
Are you? Yeah, for a while I thought
maybe you'd be in the other unit.
Junior boys? Nah, 'cause of my age.
-So when will I be released?
-Okay, now here's the deal.
Um, I got a phone call
from Kim yesterday, and I wasn't in.
Then I phoned Kim this morning
'cause I need to talk to her
before you get out of here.
They won't tell us nothing
unless we are his parents
or got a piece of paper that says
I'm his legal guardian, and I'm not.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
I am not his legal guardian.
No, I don't understand.
I'm temporary guardian.
No — Fuck that pig.
So all I can do is just keep trying.
And as soon as I get ahold of her,
I've given permission for her
to come down and get you.
The court worker signed the papers
so she can get you out of here.
What do you want me to do? I'll do it!
I'll go down there and waste some time
and not find out where the fuck he's at.
[man] Just shut up, man.
[Jerry] Kim, with that new baby,
she doesn't need any of these problems.
You're in a really
touchy situation anyway, right?
You're living with an 18-year-old who used
to be real active on the streets herself.
-Kim's 20.
-Is she 20 now? Okay.
[Jerry]
Legally, she is not a foster parent.
-Well, then give me his phone number!
-[man] Go look in the phone book.
-Under "Jerry Esterly"?
-[man] No, under juvenile parole services.
They're closed, Steve. It's 5-fucking-15
in the fucking afternoon!
I think it's really good.
You guys are working out like a family.
And I think
it's a good arrangement for you.
But I don't want you getting busted
and messing that up. Okay?
Right now,
you're charged with selling pot.
So as far as you
staying away from downtown,
I don't care whether you
stay away from downtown or not.
You've got a lot of friends down there.
I think that you have to use
your own judgment on that.
-Yep
-Okay?
Uh, you know the things
you'd better not be doing downtown.
-Yeah.
-The police, everybody knows you there.
-Okay?
If you're dealing dope,
they're gonna bust you again.
And if you get busted again,
then you're not gonna get out of here
until after your hearing.
[Rat] She'll start talking about,
"Oh, I wanna have a kid,"
and all this shit.
She just wants to get too serious
at too young of an age.
Aah!
She's only 14 years old,
and she makes it sound like
she is ready to get married.
-Well, then don't leave.
-[sighs] I got to.
No, you don't.
Yeah, I gotta get Mike
out of juvenile hall.
Why?
'Cause I can't have
my best friend locked up.
Gotta go break him out.
[laughs] Check you out.
I'm serious. I'm gonna go break him out.
Then we're gonna go to Florida.
And what if you get caught?
Oh, well. I'll still be with him. [laughs]
They'll throw me in jail
right along with him.
[Rat] Women are a pain in the ass
on the road.
[dog barks]
Come here.
I can't stand watching you and that dog.
Shit.
Puppas! [kisses]
[Rat clears throat]
[Tiny chattering in singsong]
-Throw that thing out the window.
-Uh-uh.
-Ugly.
-[dog whining]
Aw, man. Shit.
[dog whining]
He'll be with you soon.
Then we're gonna leave you alone.
We're not even going
to talk to you no more.
[Rat] I don't want you guys
to be mad at me.
-Who's gonna be mad?
-[Tiny] Fuck you, Diane.
I wouldn't want you to.
[Tiny] I wouldn't want him to
with you either.
Somebody's watching.
[laughs]
She's going to kidnap me tonight
and take me home.
-Bullshit.
-Yeah, she is.
-You gettin' a new family.
-[Tiny] Bullshit.
-Go ahead and go with her.
-Why do you say that?
Because if you want to, go ahead.
Doesn't matter to me.
-Aha, I found it.
-[yawns] Oh, you did.
[Tiny] We got in a fight.
She was drunk that night.
-Mama, go away.
-[laughs]
[Tiny] She was slapping on me
and l was slapping back on her
'cause she hit me and l hit her back.
The masterpiece.
[Tiny] The next day, she felt really bad.
[Tiny's mother]
Finally, one day, I woke up and said,
"I'm an alcoholic.
I'd better do something about it."
-[Tiny] You coming?
-Yeah, I'm a-coming, I'm a-coming.
-Goodbye, Mama.
-Goodbye, honey. I love you.
-I love you too.
-l'll be back.
[laughs]
[engine starts]
[Tiny] No fucking walls or anything.
You got one little stair into the bedroom.
And you can look over to see
there's a whole room in the front.
Then it has a bathroom, right?
It has fucking see-through curtains.
Jumped out the car and went "Pow!"
What's your name?
Did somebody hurt you?
What did they do to you?
Hey, really, I won't hurt you.
See? I'm not...
-Looks like her jaw is broke.
-Her jaw is broken?
She's been banging her head on the wall.
Her eyes are rolling.
-[man] What has she been taking?
-[Lulu] I don't know.
-Open your eyes.
-Her tongue was sticking out.
Come on now. We're here to help you.
I want to look at your eyes for a second.
[Lulu] Think somebody assaulted her,
to tell you the truth.
-[man] Does anybody know her here?
-[woman] She take any medications?
[woman] You have
a half an hour for visiting.
[Tiny] A half hour?
-You're stupid!
-I am not. It wasn't my fault.
Well, if you wouldn't have been
in that next room,
hanging your fucking head
out the window, yelling,
"Hey, guys, I'm over here! Look!
What you doing?"
[laughs] I didn't say that!
Sitting there halfway out the window,
talking to 'em.
Can't ever keep
your fucking head in, can you?
Like Brian says,
"You can take the ho off the street,
but you can't take the street off the ho."
[chuckles]
[laughs]
Oh, well. I guess it don't matter to me.
I didn't get arrested.
You're lucky. You're real lucky.
[Rat] Just gotta stay one step ahead.
-You left me there!
-That's right. I sure did.
[Tiny] It wasn't my fault.
You didn't say,
"Hey, Rat, where are you going?
Hey, Rat, take me with you."
I would've never got caught.
I wouldn't be in here till Monday.
[Rat] I'll be gone by Monday.
I don't want you to leave.
Why can't you leave till next Sunday?
'Cause I got places to go
and things to do.
Wait till next Sunday. Come on.
This is the last time you guys
get to see me. Or you.
[Rat] Oh, well.
You missed a good fight there tonight.
Lulu kicked this one whore's ass.
She said, "You bitch," and she fucking
smacked her right in the face.
You know, she didn't smack her.
She punched her.
Broad fell down, jumped up and just
took off running all the way up to Pike —
[Tiny] Who was this girl?
She's sort of tall.
She's real skinny, like you.
And she's got real dark,
shod hair, black hair.
I'd show her to you,
but you ain't getting out till Monday,
and I'm leaving Sunday.
-Why?
Why do you have to leave
a day before I get out?
Why? Because Monday, Mike gets out.
Gonna break him out Monday.
Thump! Take their cuff keys.
Open the door, take Mike's cuffs off,
and off to Alaska we go. That simple.
Maybe we'll stop through here
and pick you up.
-[Tiny] Maybe?
-Doubt it.
I doubt it, but maybe.
Oh, well. So long.
[whispering] Tiny.
Hey, Tiny.
-What's the matter?
-[sniffling]
-Nothing.
Then why you crying?
If nothing's the matter,
why are you crying?
You should have figured it out by now.
Well, I gotta go.
[softly] Go, then.
[Rat] Hmm?
Don't I at least get a hug goodbye?
[Tiny sobs]
[Tiny sniffling]
-[door closes]
-[sniffles]
[seagulls squawking]
[ship horn blowing]
[railroad bell clanging]
[Jerry] I-I found out in the morning
that, uh, there'd been a suicide.
Uh, I didn't know who it was,
and l didn't think of Dewayne,
even though I knew
he was in that institution.
Dewayne, um, hung himself
The one thing that Dewayne
wanted was — was a family.
And he wanted to grow up
as, uh, what he saw as just a regular kid.
I think that he sort of had that dream of,
uh, a mother and a father
and a house in the county,
and maybe a horse or a bicycle to ride on.
He just wanted what
every kid has a right to have, I think.
At the funeral home, there was his father.
There were guards, prison guards,
because of his dad's status.
Three other people.
Uh, all three who worked with Dewayne
in one way or another
as part of the social service agencies.
And that was it.
So it was pretty much
as his life has been.
It was a pretty lonely,
pretty skimpy affair.
[minister] Lord, in our lives,
we are often confused,
and we often ask, "Why?"
But it is times like these
when our "Why?" becomes our strongest cry.
[Dewayne] Get a girlfriend,
have a house or a car or something.
Have a little money in the bank,
get a job.
That's what I expect out of life.
Not much.
[Lee] I love you.
And I'm sorry.
But I'll see you.
[Jerry] It's my understanding
Dewayne will be cremated
and his ashes spread out on Puget Sound.
Dewayne was a — a street kid.
Dewayne drifted all his life.
And, uh, it — it seemed better for me
than putting him in a hole in the ground
in a box where he's gotta be there.
Um, he's free.
He's never been that way before.
[blues guitar:
"Teddy Bears' Picnic" playing]
♪ Now, if you go down to the woods today
You better not go alone ♪
♪ It's lovely down in the woods today
It's safer to stay at home ♪
♪ For every bear that ever there was
Will gather there for certain ♪
♪ Because today's the day
The teddy bears have their picnic ♪
♪ Picnic time for teddy bears ♪
♪ Little teddy bears are having
A lovely time today ♪
♪ Watch them, catch them unawares ♪
♪ And see them frolic
In their market underwear ♪
♪ See them gaily gad about
They love to laugh and shout ♪
♪ They never have any cares ♪
♪ At six o'clock
Their mommies and daddies ♪
♪ Will take them home to bed ♪
♪ Well, because they're tired
And wired little teddy bears ♪
[vocalizing]
[song ends]
[dog whines]
[ballad playing]
♪ Oh, take care of all of my children ♪
♪ Don't let 'em wander and roam ♪
♪ For I don't know
when I'm comin' back home ♪
♪ You can put all of my possessions here ♪
♪ In Jesus' name ♪
♪ Nail a sign on the door ♪
♪ Bright and early Sunday morning
With my walkin' cane ♪
♪ I'm goin' up to see my Lord ♪
♪ Oh, keep them together at the sundown ♪
♪ Safe from the devil's hand ♪
♪ You gotta make them a pillow ♪
♪ On the hard ground ♪
♪ I'll be goin' up to Beulah Land ♪
♪ You can put all of my possessions here ♪
♪ In Jesus' name ♪
♪ And nail a sign on the door ♪
♪ Bright and early Sunday morning ♪
♪ With my walkin' cane ♪
♪ I'm goin' up to see my Lord ♪
♪ Oh, remember you never trust the devil ♪
♪ Stay clear of Lucifer's hand ♪
♪ Oh, and don't let 'em wander ♪
♪ In the meadow ♪
♪ Or you'll wind up in the fryin' pan ♪
♪ You can put all of my possessions here ♪
♪ In Jesus' name ♪
♪ Nail a sign on the door ♪
♪ Bright and early Sunday morning ♪
♪ With my walkin' cane ♪
♪ I'm goin' up to see my Lord ♪
♪ Put all of my possessions here ♪
♪ In Jesus' name ♪
♪ And nail a sign on the door ♪
♪ Bright and early Sunday morning ♪
♪ With my walkin' cane ♪
♪ I'm goin' up ♪
♪ To see my Lord ♪