[ People Chattering ]
HELLO TO YOU.
I HOPE YOU'RE FINE.
[ Woman ]
NOW, LET'S TRY SOMETHING
DIFFERENT: A CHALLENGE.
WHO KNOWS
THE ELECTRON WAVE FUNCTIONS...
FOR KRYPTONIAN
CONVALENT BONDING ?
SORRY.
LEYA ?
THE CUBE ROOT
OF THE WAVELENGTH
OVER THE NATURAL LOG...
OF THE INTEGRAL
OF THE SPEED OF LIGHT--
I THINK SQUARED.
WELL, MAYBE THAT WAS
A BIT TOO EASY.
GREETINGS.
GREETINGS, OLD FRIEND.
YOU LOOK WONDERFUL.
HELLO, KARA.
HELLO TO YOU.
OH, IT IS BEAUTIFUL.
WHAT'S THAT GOING
TO BE, ZALTAR ?
I THINK... A TREE.
A TREE.
WHAT IS A TREE ?
A LOVELY THING
WHICH GROWS ON EARTH.
EARTH ?  YOU MEAN
WHERE MY COUSIN WENT ?
AND TO WHERE ONE DAY SOON
PERHAPS I MIGHT VENTURE
AS WELL.
I DON'T BELIEVE YOU.
HOW ?
IN THAT.
THROUGH THERE.
THE BINARY CHUTE ?
BUT YOU COULD NEVER
SURVIVE THE PRESSURE.  IT--
THAT I CAN,
ZIP ZAP, AND I'M GONE.
BUT YOU'D NEVER
LEAVE US, ZALTAR.
YOU'D NEVER LEAVE ARGO CITY.
INDEED I MIGHT, KARA.
TOO MUCH OF A GOOD THING HERE.
PERHAPS I'LL TRY
SATURN INSTEAD.
- YES, I THINK I MIGHT.
- SATURN IS--
IS THAT FURTHER AWAY
THAN EARTH ?
SILLY QUESTION.  DID YOU
NOT STUDY SIX-DIMENSIONAL
GEOMETRY AT SCHOOL ?
DO THEY NOT TEACH YOU
ANYTHING ANYMORE ?
WELL, OF COURSE THEY DO.
UH, I KNOW THE EQUATIONS.
UH--
I JUST CAN'T SEE THEM
IN MY HEAD.
MOST GREAT ARTISTS
FIND MATHEMATICS
TROUBLESOME, KARA.
ONLY USE YOUR IMAGINATION.
MM-HMM.
SATURN AND EARTH
ARE IN OUTER SPACE,
BUT WE-- WE ARE
IN INNER SPACE.
OUR CITY HAS
TWO GREAT POWER SOURCES.
THIS IS ONE OF THEM.
LOOK.
AN OMEGAHEDRON.
THE GUARDIANS
LET YOU HAVE IT ?
NOT EXACTLY.
I BORROWED IT.
YOU STOLE IT.
OH, ZALTAR,
THEY'RE GOING TO--
NO.  BORROWED IT,
FOR THE AFTERNOON.
FOR INSPIRATION.
INSPIRATION.
BUT I THINK THAT I SHALL
NEVER SEE THE BRANCHES
OF A LIVING TREE.
WHY ?  AN OMEGAHEDRON
CAN CREATE LIFE, CAN'T IT ?
IT CAN'T, CHILD.  IT CAN'T.
JUST THE ILLUSION OF LIFE.
IT'S A FANCY SHADOW
OF THE REAL THING,
WHICH IS THE MOST
WE CAN HOPE FOR
ON THIS LONELY OLD ROCK.
[ Woman ]
KARA !
I'M HERE, MOTHER,
I--
[ Whirring ]
KARA, I'VE BEEN LOOKING
FOR YOU FOR AGES.
OH, I'M SORRY, MOTHER.
ZALTAR.
ALURA, JOIN US.
WE'RE JUST
INVENTING MIRACLES.
PUT YOUR FINGERS HERE,
KARA, AND PRESS HARD.
GOOD.  NOW, TRY IT.
LET YOUR
IMAGINATION EXPLODE AND
GIVE IT A TRY.  GO ON.
ZALTAR, MY HUSBAND TELLS ME
YOU TALK OF LEAVING
ARGO CITY.
FOR WHERE ?
PARTS UNKNOWN.
IT IS, ALAS, A FACT.
YOU AND ZOR-EL HAVE A LIFE HERE.
YOU HAVE EACH OTHER,
AND YOU HAVE KARA.
BUT, ZALTAR,
YOU FOUNDED THIS CITY.
IT'S YOURS.
AS FAR AS THE EYE CAN SEE,
RIGHT TO THE VEIL,
SMACK, AND THEN WHAT ?
WHAT IS BEYOND ?
ALURA, I CANNOT CONTAIN
MYSELF TO ARGO CITY ONLY.
MY HEAD IS BOILING WITH IDEAS.
MY IMAGINATION IS TOO VAST.
IT'S UNCONTROLLABLE.
IF YOU WANT MY OPINION, ZALTAR,
YOU'RE STARTING TO REPEAT
YOURSELF...
WITH ALL THIS
AIRY, GLITTERY STUFF.
EXACTLY.  THAT'S WHY
I'M GOING TO VENUS.
VENUS ?  WHEN ?
TOMORROW.
OR THE NEXT DAY,
AT THE LATEST.
ZALTAR, HAVE YOU
THOUGHT ABOUT THIS ?
IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE TO ME.
I HAVE THOUGHT INTENSELY.
MY MIND IS MADE UP.
- KARA, THE POWER SOURCE !
- [ Screams ]
ZALTAR !  SAVE ME !
PLEASE, HELP !
- NO !
- KARA !
ZALTAR !  HELP !  NO !
- [ Alura ]
KARA, ARE YOU ALL RIGHT ?
- [ Man ]  CALM DOWN, EVERYBODY.
IT'S ALL OVER.
YOU'RE HERE WITH US.
YOU TOOK THE OMEGAHEDRON.
THAT'S NOT CORRECT.
I LOST THE OMEGAHEDRON.
OH, NO, FATHER.
I DID.
NO MATTER WHO.
WITHOUT IT,
THIS CITY CAN'T SURVIVE
MORE THAN A FEW DAYS.
OUR LIGHTS WILL GROW DIM,
AND THE VERY AIR
WE BREATHE SO THIN.
I KNOW.
SO I SHALL FIND IT.
I SHALL GO RIGHT
TO THE END OF INNER SPACE
AND I SHALL RETURN IT.
IMPOSSIBLE.  HOW ?
NO ONE CAN LEAVE ARGO CITY,
AND YOU KNOW IT.
THIS IS OUR UNIVERSE, AND
YOU'VE DESTROYED IT WITH
A GAME, A CHILDISH GAME.
I THINK
IT CAN BE DONE.
THROUGH THERE.
THE BINARY CHUTE,
IN THE TRAVELLER.
[ Man ]
LIKE A COWARD.
CHOOSE INSTANT DESTRUCTION WHILE
THE REST OF US ARE DOOMED TO
STAY HERE IN OUR BELOVED CITY...
AND SLOWLY PERISH.
KARA !
KARA, NO !
NO !
YOU LUNATIC !
SHE'LL BE KILLED.
OH, NO, SHE WON'T.
SHE WILL BE SAFE.
THROUGH THE BINARY.
THROUGH THE WARP.
- INTO ANOTHER REGISTER.
- ANOTHER WHAT ?
GRAVITATIONAL RADIATION.
A PATHWAY FROM
INNER SPACE TO OUTER SPACE.
THEN SHE'LL NEVER
BE THE SAME, EVER.
AT LEAST
SHE'LL BE ALIVE.
AND MY FATE IS SEALED.
I'VE LOST THE OMEGAHEDRON.
I MUST BE SENT
TO THE PHANTOM ZONE.
YOUR SUFFERING
WILL BE SHORT.
MINE... FOREVER.
[ Beeping ]
[ Explosion ]
SOME MORE CHAMPAGNE,
MY DEAR SELENA ?
WHAT ARE YOU
THINKING ABOUT ?
[ Sighs ]
SUCH A PRETTY WORLD.
I CAN'T WAIT
UNTIL IT'S ALL MINE.
THE ONLY WAY
YOU CAN RULE THE WORLD IS
TO BECOME INVISIBLE, MY PUMPKIN.
INVISIBLE ?
YOU'D ALMOST KNOW HOW
TO MAKE ME INVISIBLE.
OH, I DO KNOW.
TAKE FIVE BLACK BEANS
AND THE HEAD OF A DEAD MAN.
PLACE ONE BEAN IN HIS MOUTH,
TWO BEANS IN HIS EYES.
THEN--
NIGEL, ENOUGH.
BUT IT WORKS.
THEN YOU CAN GET ANYWHERE,
DO ANYTHING.
NIGEL, HOW LONG
HAVE WE BEEN TOGETHER ?
OOH.  MONTHS, DARLING.
THEN WHY DOES IT SEEM
LIKE YEARS ?
BECAUSE YOU'RE SO IMPATIENT.
YOU WANT EVERYTHING YESTERDAY.
IT TAKES A LIFETIME
TO DISCOVER THE SECRETS
OF BLACK MAGIC...
FROM THE ANCIENT
GRIMOIRES.
MORE CHAMPAGNE,
MY SWEETNESS ?
DON'T CALL ME...
"YOUR SWEETNESS."
I AM NOT SWEET.
I AM SELENA.
AND I AM A BITTER,
BITTER PILL TO SWALLOW.
- [ Whooshing ]
- HOLY... COW.
I WONDER--
IMMORTALITY
BE UPON THIS ONE.
SHE IS A SHARER OF
THE SUN'S EVERLASTING LIFE.
THERE WILL NOW
BE NO DANGER OF DEATH.
THIS WORLD
WILL KEEP HER FOREVER.
WHAT IS IT ?
WHAT'S GOING ON ?
I'VE JUST
OUTGROWN YOU, NIGEL.
THESE THINGS HAPPEN.
YOU CAN'T TREAT ME
LIKE THIS, SELENA.
WITHOUT ME,
YOU'D STILL BE READING
TEA LEAVES AT LAKE TAHOE.
[ Whirring ]
[ Radio Squeals ]
???? [ Rockabilly
On Radio ]
YOU CAN'T RUN OUT
ON ME, SELENA.
I'VE GOT THE KEYS,
SWEETHEART.
THE PRESIDENT CONFIRMED REPORTS
THAT SUPERMAN HAS EMBARKED ON A
SPECIAL PEACE-SEEKING MISSION...
TO A GALAXY SCIENTISTS ESTIMATE
MAY BE SEVERAL HUNDRED TRILLION
LIGHT-YEARS FROM OUR OWN.
OH !
[ Gasps, Laughs ]
WHOO-WHOO !
[ Whinnying ]
[ Man On Radio ]
NOW HERE'S THE WEATHER
FOR THE GENERAL CHICAGO AREA.
INCREASING CLOUDINESS
WITH THE POSSIBILITY
OF SHOWERS.
BREEZY BUT WARM
WITH A HIGH OF 62.
BIANCA !  I'M HOME.
BIANCA !
WHAT ?
SHOW YOUR FACE.
I HAVE A SURPRISE FOR YOU.
THEY TURNED OFF
THE HOT WATER AGAIN.
I'M REALLY GONNA HAVE
TO KILL SOMEBODY
DOWN AT THE D.W.P.
I FIGURED THE ONLY WAY THAT
WE'RE GONNA PAY OUR BILLS
NEXT MONTH IN THIS DUMP...
IS TO JUST GO AHEAD
AND START OUR OWN COVEN.
NO LONGER NECESSARY.
I WAS READING IN THIS BOOK,
THE WITCHES GUIDE
TO HEAVEN AND HELL.
IF YOU START YOUR OWN COVEN,
ALL YOU DO IS CHARGE FIVE BUCKS
A HEAD, MINIMAL ADMISSION.
CHICKEN FEED.
THAT'S BETTER
THAN GOOSE EGG.
WHAT'S IN THE COFFER
OF SHADOW THERE ?
WHERE'S LITTLE NIGEL ?
NIGEL, MY DEAR BIANCA,
IS HISTORY.
OH, YEAH ?  HOW SO ?
THE WATER DEPARTMENT IS HISTORY.
THE CAR PAYMENTS ARE HISTORY.
THE MORTGAGE PAYMENTS
ARE HISTORY.
HOW ARE
THE PROPERTY TAXES ?
HISTORY.
THE WORLD IS AT LAST
MY OYSTER.
IF I CAN FIGURE
THIS THING OUT--
WOULD YOU MIND LETTING
BIANCA IN ON THIS UNEXPECTED
BIT OF GOOD LUCK ?
OR WHATEVER IT IS ?
BA-AD LUCK.
I HAVE BEEN CHOSEN.
THE POWERS OF DARKNESS...
I THINK MAY, AT LONG LAST...
HAVE COME TO THEIR SENSES.
YOU WANNA HEAR
SOME BAD LUCK ?
THE PHONE COMPANY SAYS...
UNLESS WE PAY THIS BILL TODAY,
THEY'RE TURNING THE PHONE OFF !
SHUT UP, SHUT UP.
WATCH.
LEARN SOMETHING
FOR A CHANGE.
[ Sizzling ]
[ Bianca ]
OH, MY GOD.
ARE YOU DOING THAT ?
[ Sizzling Continues ]
IT'S A TRICK, RIGHT ?
IT'S A TRICK.
I THINK IT'S DONE.
SELENA, I THINK IT'S DONE.
[ Moaning ]
[ Whispering ]
OH, MY GOD.
IT'S GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE PRACTICE.
[ Beeping ]
[ Vehicle Approaching ]
[ Horn Honking ]
NOW, THIS I LIKE.
- HELLO.
- "HELLO," SHE SAYS.
WELL, HELLO TO YOU,
HONEY BUN.
HELLO.
I WAS WONDERING
IF YOU COULD TELL ME
WHERE I AM.
WHAT DO THEY CALL
THIS PLACE, EDDY ?
LOVERS LANE, ISN'T IT ?
YOU GOT IT IN ONE,
BILLY BOY.
LOVERS LANE.
OH, NO, YOU SEE,
WHAT I MEANT WAS--
WELL, THOSE
LIGHTS OVER THERE.
WHAT ARE THEY CALLED ?
CHECK OUT THE VIEW
FROM BACK HERE,
EDUARDO.
OH !
STOP THAT !
- HEY.
- YOU'RE SUPERMAN'S
BEST FRIEND, HUH ?
NO.  HIS COUSIN.
I'VE COME HERE TO SEARCH
FOR THE OMEGAHEDRON.
IT'S A POWER SOURCE
VITAL TO ARGO CITY.
- THAT'S WHERE I LIVE.
- NO KIDDING.
EDDY AND ME HERE,
WE'RE ON A SECRET
MISSION ALSO.
WE'RE OUT LOOKING
FOR A GOOD TIME.
AND YOU JUST WON
THE BRASS RING, BABY.
[ Groaning ]
- OH, SHE WORKS OUT, HUH ?
- WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS ?
IT'S JUST THE WAY WE ARE.
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE
DONE THAT, BABY.
COME ON.
[ Gasps ]
OH, I SEE.
YOU REALLY WANNA PLAY GAMES,
EH, SWEETHEART ?
COME ON.  COME ON.
[ Groans ]
HUH ?
EDDY.
I THINK MAYBE WE SHOULD...
KIND OF KEEP THIS
TO OURSELVES.
WHAT DO YOU THINK ?
???? [ Pop ]
FREDDIE, YOU LITTLE
DEVIL, HOW ARE YOU ?
FRESH AMMUNITION,
EVERYBODY !
[ Guests Chattering ]
[ Man ]
WHO SAID THAT ?
IT'S TRADITION.
[ Laughing ]
TRY TELLING YOUR WIFE.
I NEED ANOTHER.
WHERE IS IT ?
WHERE'S THE LITTLE
MYSTERY BALL ?
LET ME HAVE A PEEK.
MAYBE I CAN SHED
SOME LIGHT.
I HATE LIGHT.
IS IT ELECTRICAL ?
IS IT HOT TO THE TOUCH ?
WHERE IS IT ?
SAFE AND SOUND.
GO MIX.
LEAVE ME TO MY THOUGHTS.
GO MIX ?
WITH THESE PEOPLE ?
YOU MUST BE MAD.  WHO ARE THEY ?
WRINKLY LITTLE WRETCHES.
THESE ARE
MY FOOT SOLDIERS, NIGEL.
MY ARMY OF THE NIGHT.
I'M CONSIDERING
NOTHING LESS
THAN WORLD DOMINATION.
WORLD DOMINATION ?
SO YOU START BY LETTING BIANCA
GET ON THE PHONE...
TO THE LOCAL
PSYCHICAL RESEARCH SOCIETY
AND SAY,
"HELLO, GOT ANYONE OVER THERE
WANTS TO JOIN A COVEN ?"
THERE ARE TIME-HONORED WAYS
OF DOING THIS, HONEYBUNCH.
CENTURIES-OLD RULES
TO FOLLOW.
I HAVE A SECRET, SELENA.
HOW EXCITING FOR YOU, NIGEL.
BEST WRITE IT DOWN
BEFORE YOU FORGET IT.
AFTER YOU LEFT ME IN THE LURCH,
I SAW SOMETHING THAT SHOULD
WORRY YOU GREATLY...
IF YOU'RE SERIOUS
ABOUT TAKING OVER
THIS PLANET.
MY SECRET WAS BLUE AND RED,
AND IT KNEW HOW TO FLY.
I'VE A SECRET, TOO, NIGEL.
I HAVE THE POWER.
NOW, GET THAT
THROUGH YOUR HEAD.
SELENA IS THROUGH WORRYING.
THE SHOE IS ON THE OTHER FOOT
AND IT'S THEIR TURN TO WORRY,
ALL THOSE WHO MOCKED ME
WHEN MY CHIPS WERE DOWN.
OH, I BET THEY'RE
IN FOR IT NOW, EH ?
COUNT ON IT.
I HAVE IN MY TIME SEEN
A GREAT NUMBER OF THINGS...
EVEN MORE IMPRESSIVE THAN
A HUMAN CIGARETTE LIGHTER,
DEAR LADY.
TO WIT.
WHAT IS THAT ?
OVERREACHING AMBITION.
TAKE HEED.
TOUCHED A LITTLE NERVE,
DIDN'T I ?
HELLO.
THE RED TOAD THAT LURKS
IN THE BRIARS AND BRAMBLES
IS FULL OF SORCERIES.
THERE'S A LITTLE BONE
ON THE LEFT SIDE.
A LITTLE BONE ?
A LITTLE BONE
WHICH IF BOUND TO A MAN
STIRS UP THE GREATEST LUST.
- I WANNA BE RICH AND FAMOUS.
- THEN STICK WITH ME.
I WAS PUT ON THIS EARTH
TO THRILL MILLIONS.
MMM.
THIS IS SCRUMPTIOUS.
WHY DON'T WE
GO SOMEWHERE ELSE
AND DANCE CHEEK TO CHEEK ?
[ Screaming ]
STOP IT, SELENA !
THAT'S NOT FAIR !
PICK ON ME !
[ Moaning ]
OH !
THANKS.
HEY, NO SWEAT.
WHAT HAPPENED ?
OH, NOTHING MUCH.
GET OUT OF MY HOUSE,
NIGEL,
AND DON'T COME
SLITHERING BACK.
LISTEN, SELENA,
I'M THE ONLY ONE WHO CAN
SAVE YOU FROM YOURSELF.
YOUNEEDME.
LIKE AN ESKIMO NEEDS
A LAWNMOWER, KIDDO.
I'M WARNING YOU, SELENA.
DON'T BE SO SHORTSIGHTED.
OKAY, FOLKS.
THE SHOW'S OVER !
LET'S PARTY.
???? [ Pop Resumes ]
[ Chattering ]
FREDDIE, DARLING,
THANK YOU FOR COMING.
GOODBYE !
GOOD PARTY.
THANK YOU.
LOVELY TO SEE YOU.
BYE !
[ Sighs ]
FOUR PEOPLE SIGNED UP.
WE GOT 20 BUCKS,
CASH ON THE BARRELHEAD.
FOURPEOPLE ?
THEY LOVED THE FOOD.
THEY WERE REAL IMPRESSED
WITH THAT SPINNING TOP NUMBER
YOU DID ON THAT GIRL.
BUT WHEN NIGEL WALKED OUT
THE WAY HE DID,
I GOTTA SAY IT HURT US.
THEY THOUGHT HE WAS
GIVING YOU A WARNING
TO SLOW DOWN.
[ Chuckling ]
ROME WASN'T BUILT IN A DAY.
A WARNING ?
A WARNING, THEY SAY ?
NOBODY GETS
A WARNING ANYMORE.
GOOD MORNING.
[ Girl ]
HAVE YOU GOT IT, LUCY ?
IT MUST BE NEAR THAT OAK TREE.
FOUND IT, GUYS !
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
IN THERE ?
YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO FIND THE BALL.
[ Girls Shouting ]
COME ON !
DON'T TAKE ALL DAY.
YOU'RE HOLDING UP THE GAME.
HEY, IT'S
YOUR TURN TO BAT.
LET'S GO !  LET'S GO !
- OKAY, OKAY,
LET'S PLAY BALL.
- ALL RIGHT, BATTER.
[ Cheering ]
HOW'S IT GOING ?
I COULDN'T MAKE IT.  I HAD
TO FINISH MY ENGLISH LIT.
[ Girl ]
HEY, TOSS THE BALL BACK,
WILL YOU ?
- LOOK AT THAT.  OOH-WEE !
- THANK YOU.
COME ON !
MAKE IT TWO IN A ROW !
PLAY BALL.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN ?
WITH THE PRINCIPAL.
DANVERS IS DOING
HIS USUAL NUMBER.
GEEZ, ANOTHER BARFY NEW STUDENT.
THEY'RE REALLY SCRAPING THE
BOTTOM OF THE BARREL THESE DAYS.
HANG IN THERE,
DANVERS.
DON'T LET 'EM
GET TO YOU.
THIRTY DAYS.
SEMESTER'S JUST STARTED.
YOU'LL BE--
HELLO.  I--
DIDN'T KNOCK.
DON'T WE TEACH YOU
MANNERS AROUND HERE ?
DON'T WE TRY TO IMPRESS
ON ALL OUR YOUNG LADIES...
THAT ANIMALS
IN THE JUNGLE NEVER KNOCK,
BUT MIDVALE GIRLS ALWAYS DO ?
WHERE ARE YOU GOING ?
COME BACK HERE.
[ Knocking ]
- COME IN.
- I FORGOT.
I'M JUST NOT USED TO--
WAIT A MINUTE.
WAIT JUST ONE SECOND.
I HAVE NEVER BEFORE IN MY LIFE
LAID EYES ON YOU,
HAVE I, YOUNG LADY ?
NO, SIR.  I'M NEW HERE.
WELL, OBVIOUSLY YOU'RE NEW HERE
IF I'VE NEVER LAID EYES ON YOU.
JUST WHO ON EARTH
ARE YOU ?
UM--
[ Clears Throat ]
ON EARTH, I'M LEE.
LINDA LEE.
WHERE'S YOUR LETTER
OF RECOMMENDATION ?
LETTER ?
I MUST TALK TO YOU,
PRINCIPAL.
I AM BUSY NOW.
SO ARE THEY.  THEM.
ALL THE LITTLE MONSTERS
YOU ADMIT TO THE PLACE.
THEY HAVE NAILED
MY DESK DRAWERS SHUT.
NEVER IN ALL MY YEARS
AS A SCHOOLTEACHER--
COME, DANVERS.
I WILL NOT BE PROVOKED.
I WILL NOT LET HIM GET TO ME
THIS SEMESTER.
I'LL BE STRONG.
BE STRONG.
BE LIKE A ROCK.
NOW, WHAT DID YOU SAY
YOUR NAME WAS ?
OH, YES, YES.
LINDA LEE, HUH ?
YES, MY COUSIN
PROBABLY WROTE YOU.
UM, MAYBE YOU GOT HIS LETTER
UNDER "K" FOR "KENT"
IN YOUR FILES.
KENT ?  KENT ?
IT DOESN'T RING ANY BELLS.
DOESN'T EVEN RING A--
WELL, HERE IT IS,
BIG AS LIFE.
"MY DEAR MR. DANVERS,
I'M WRITING ON BEHALF
OF A VERY SPECIAL YOUNG LADY"--
AN ORPHAN ?  WELL, DON'T EXPECT
TO BE TREATED ANY DIFFERENTLY
ON THAT ACCOUNT, MISS LEE.
- OH, NO, SIR, I WON'T.
- ONE WAY OR ANOTHER,
WE'RE ALL ALONE ON THIS
MISERABLE LITTLE PLANET.
YES, SIR, I KNOW.
SINCE YOUR SCHOOL RECORDS
WERE OBVIOUSLY LOST IN THE MAIL,
YOU'LL HAVE TO START
AT THE BOTTOM.
IT'S ONLY FAIR TO
THE OTHER GIRLS.  YOU'LL
HAVE ENGLISH, LATIN, MATH,
BIOLOGY, COMPUTING...
AND CHEMISTRY.
ALL AT ONCE ?
IDLE HANDS ARE
THE DEVIL'S PLAYGROUND.
THIS WAY.
???? [ Music Playing ]
[ Girls Chatting ]
MAN ON THE FLOOR !
[ Girls Screaming ]
???? [ Stops ]
[ Knocking At Door ]
OPEN UP, LANE.
I KNOW YOU'RE IN THERE.
I'M NOT DECENT,
MR. DANVERS, SIR.
AND YOU NEVER
WILL BE EITHER,
YOU LITTLE LIAR.
COME ON.  COME ON IN.
I HAVEN'T GOT ALL YEAR.
NO.  I'M SUPPOSED
TO HAVE A SINGLE
THIS TERM.
WE DON'T ALWAYS GET
WHAT WE WANT, MISS LANE.
DISAPPOINTMENTS
THICKEN OUR SKINS.
WHO WANTS THICK SKIN ?
[ Clears Throat ]
I'M LINDA LEE.
HI.
OH.  HI.
- I'M LUCY LANE.
- LUCY LEE, THIS IS LINDA LANE.
NO, IT ISN'T.
SHE'S LINDA LEE, AND I'M--
LUCY LANE.
- YOU TWO KNOW EACH OTHER ?
- NO, WE JUST MET.
- WHEN ?
- JUST NOW.
THOUGH WE'VE KNOWN
EACH OTHER FOR YEARS,
HAVEN'T WE, LINDA ?
- OH, GEE, I DON'T THINK--
- OF COURSE.  THEDAILY PLANET.
OF COURSE.
LINDA'S COUSIN WORKS THERE
AND YOUR SISTER--
WHAT'S HER NAME ?
THE ONE THAT'S ALWAYS
CALLING ME AND BOTHERING ME.
LOIS.
AH, YES,
THAT'S THE ONE.
ANYWAY, UH, SHOW OUR
NEW MISS LEE AROUND,
MISS LANE.
BY THE WAY, SHE'S AN ORPHAN.
BUT DON'T LET HER PLAY
ON YOUR SYMPATHIES, HMM ?
- SO WHO'S YOUR COUSIN ?
- CLARK KENT.
YOU'RE KIDDING ME.
CLARK KENT'S YOUR COUSIN ?
YOU'RE PUTTING ME ON.
- DO YOU KNOW HIM ?
- DO I KNOW HIM ?
DOES MY SISTER KNOW HIM ?
NOW, THAT'S THE BIG QUESTION.
OH, I SEE.  I GUESS IF THEY WORK
AT THE SAME NEWSPAPER,
THEY MUST KNOW EACH OTHER.
- WELL--
- IS THIS WHERE I'LL SLEEP ?
WELL, THIS IS YOUR BED,
BUT WE DON'T SLEEP
AROUND HERE.
NONSTOP EXCITEMENT
IN THIS DORM.
ALL THE REAL DEMENTOES
ARE SENT HERE.
SO, WHEN'S THE REST
OF YOUR STUFF ARRIVING ?
I DON'T HAVE ANY OTHER STUFF.
WHAT, IT'S ALL
IN THAT LITTLE BAG ?
OH, WELL, YOU SEE,
I HAVE THE MEANS TO BUY MORE.
IT'S JUST--
WELL, I JUST HAVEN'T
HAD THE CHANCE SINCE--
- DO YOU KNOW HIM ?
- SUPERMAN ?  SURE.
MY SISTER'S GOT
SOMETHING GOING
WITH THE BIG GUY.
HEY, YOU CAN BORROW
ANY OF MY CLOTHES
ANY TIME YOU WANT.
JUST DIG IN
AND HELP YOURSELF.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE VERY KIND.
HE'S A REAL CHARACTER.
A REAL HUNK.
I'LL INTRODUCE YOU
TO HIM SOMEDAY
IF WE WIND UP GETTING ALONG.
WELL, YOU HAVEN'T HAD
A CHANCE SINCE, WHAT ?
DID YOU HAVE A FIRE
AT YOUR HOUSE OR SOMETHING ?
FIRE ?
WELL, YOU KNOW.
HOW YOUR PARENTS GOT KILLED.
- I'D RATHER NOT TALK ABOUT IT.
- OH, SURE.
I'M SORRY.
ME AND MY MOTOR MOUTH.
NOW, THEN,
FOCUS YOUR TINY MINDS...
ON THE KIND OF PROBLEM
THAT USED TO TAKE WEEKS
OF THOUGHT BEFORE THE COMPUTER.
EVEN NOW IT CAN TAKE
A LONG TIME WITHOUT
CERTAIN ALGORITHMS...
WHICH, IF YOU BEHAVE
FOR TWO SECONDS,
I MIGHT REVEAL TO YOU.
LOVE.  HATE.
LOVE.
THE CARDS HAVE DECIDED.
PEOPLE WILL DO ANYTHING
FOR LOVE.
THEY'LL JUMP
OFF CLIFFS FOR LOVE.
THEY'LL DROWN THEMSELVES
LIKE LEMMINGS.
SO...
I'LL MAKE EVERYBODY
LOVE ME.
OH, NO CHANCE.
YOU'RE AN AWFUL PERSON,
HONEY, REMEMBER ?  FORGET IT.
USE YOUR IMAGINATION, PINHEAD.
THAT'S WHAT MAGIC IS ALL ABOUT.
- WHY ARE WE NOT MOVING ?
- OOH, BECAUSE I'M IN LOVE.
COME HERE,
YOU BEAUTIFUL THING.
HE'S CUTE.
HEY, WHAT'S GOING ON ?
[ Nigel ]
HERE'S AN EXERCISE IN BIG
NUMBERS I WANT YOU TO TRY.
[ Selena ]
IT'S TRYING
TO TELL ME SOMETHING.
WELL, WHAT ?
THAT WE'RE NEAR DANGER ?
I DON'T KNOW.
HOW DO I KNOW ?
- I KNOW.
- WELL, TELL ME.
MY PRINCE HAS COME.
[ Bianca ]
OH, NO.
I SAW HIM FIRST, SELENA.
THAT'S NOT FAIR.
I COPIED HIS NUMBER FIRST.
WELL DONE.
NOW, LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
[ Beeping ]
YOU'LL BE GIVEN THE AVERAGE
SIZE OF A CHINESE FAMILY,
AVERAGE AGE OF DEATH,
AVERAGE AGE OF MARRIAGE,
AVERAGE AGE OF PREGNANCY.
USE THIS EQUATION
TO COMPUTE THE POPULATION
OF CHINA IN THE YEAR 2040.
LINDA, ARE YOU WITH US ?
[ Scattered Laughter ]
UM--
YES, SIR, I AM.
OH, ARE YOU ?
WHERE, MIGHT I ASK ?
WELL, HERE, SIR,
ON EARTH.
[ Girls Laughing ]
HOW FORTUNATE
FOR THE REST OF US.
MAY I PRESUME THAT WHILST
YOU WERE STARING AT THE WALL
AND NOT AT YOUR TERMINAL...
LIKE YOUR OTHER
LITTLE FRIENDS HERE,
YOU WERE HARD AT WORK
SOLVING THIS LITTLE
EQUATION ?
OH, YES, SIR, I WAS.
I MEAN, I WAS--
EXCELLENT.
THE ANSWER, PLEASE.
PAY ATTENTION, CLASS.
MISS LEE IS ABOUT
TO ENLIGHTEN US.
5,271,009,010.
[ Girls Laughing ]
[ Bell Ringing ]
COME ON.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE
BEFORE HE MAKES YOU STAY.
COME ON.  HURRY.
- MISS LEE ?
- OH, SHIT.
- YES, SIR ?
- HAVE YOU BEEN GOING
THROUGH MY PAPERS ?
- OF COURSE NOT, SIR.
- THEN HOW DO YOU KNOW
THE CORRECT ANSWER ?
HOW ?
I GUESS I JUST--
IT'S THIS CRAZY WEATHER
WE'VE BEEN HAVING, SIR.
ALL THE STORMS.
SHOCK WAVES,
ELECTROMAGNETISM.
IT MAKES PEOPLE SMARTER
THAN THEY ARE FOR A SECOND.
WE GOTTA GO, SIR.
OH, BOY.  THANKS.
HOW DID YOU KNOW
THE ANSWER ?
I DON'T KNOW.
SIX-DIMENSIONAL GEOMETRY.
I NEVER COULD DO IT BEFORE.
YEAH.  WELL, YOU WANT
SOME FRIENDLY ADVICE ?
DON'T GO SHOWING IT OFF,
'CAUSE NOBODY'S
GONNA LIKE YOU.
I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
[ All Shouting,
Cheering ]
HEY, LUCY,
WHERE'S YOUR ROOMIE ?
OUT TO LUNCH ?
NO, SHE HEARD YOU WERE GONNA
BE HERE, MYRA, AND SHE GOT
SICK TO HER STOMACH.
HEY, LINDA, WAIT A MINUTE.
COME ON.  STAY.
YEAH, AREN'T WE
GOOD ENOUGH FOR YOU ?
CAN I HAVE MY BOOKS
BACK, PLEASE, MYRA ?
[ Chattering Stops ]
SAY "PLEASE."
- I JUST DID.
- SAY IT AGAIN.
PLEASE, CAN I HAVE
MY BOOKS BACK ?
[ Books Clatter ]
GOD, WHAT A WIMP.
GEOGRAPHY ?
YOU'RE NOT TAKING
GEOGRAPHY, ARE YOU, LINDA ?
"MIDVALE AND ITS POINTS
OF INTEREST ?"
GOOD.  SHORT BOOK.
[ Laughing ]
I'M JUST TRYING TO LEARN
A LITTLE BIT ABOUT--
MORE IN THE--
IN THE PLACE THAT I--
I LIVE.
[ Chattering Resumes ]
I HAVE TO GO STUDY.
"OH, I HAVE TO GO STUDY.
I'M NOT BORING ENOUGH YET."
- SHUT UP, MYRA.
- MAKE ME.
- BUG OFF.
- [ Chattering Continues ]
ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT !
[ Chattering Stops ]
NOW, WHO'S GONNA
CLEAN UP THIS MESS ?
NOT ME.
[ Girl ]  WHY DIDN'T ANYBODY
TELL US SHE WAS COMING ?  GOD.
WE DIDN'T CARE.
[ Shouting ]
[ Groans ]
[ Whistle Blows ]
NICE GOING.
DO YOU KNOW
SHE TRIPPED YOU ON PURPOSE ?
ABSOLUTELY.  SHE'S ROTTEN.
- [ Whistle Blows ]
- WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME LEFT.
[ Blows Whistle ]
YOU TAKE IT, MY.
HEY, MYRA,
SEE IF YOU CAN
PUT LANE OUT FOR GOOD.
ARE YOU GUYS
ALL RIGHT ?
OH, MY GOD.
WHAT HAPPENED ?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT ?
MYRA, HOW DID SHE DO THAT ?
IT JUST HIT HER SHOULDER.
LISTEN, YOU BETTER KEEP
AN EYE OUT FOR MYRA NOW.
SHE'S OUT TO GET YOU.
ME ?  WHY ?
BECAUSE SHE HATES ANYBODY
WHO'S NOT AFRAID OF HER.
HEY, YOU GUYS,
DID YOU SEE THAT CUTE GUY
ON THE SOFTBALL FIELD ?
OH, YES.
WITH THE BLACK HAIR
AND THE BIG MUSCLES.
HE WAS SOMETHING ELSE.
DID YOU TALK TO HIM ?
NO, BUT I'M GONNA.
HE'S WORKING ON THE TREES.
HE COULD BE AROUND FOR A WHILE.
ARE THEY IN ?
YES.
[ Hearing Voices ]
OH, BOY, I'M REALLY
GONNA ENJOY THIS.
I CAN'T WAIT
TO HEAR THEM SCREAM.
BUT, MYRA, WHY DON'T
YOU SHUT OFF THE HOT
AND GIVE THEM AN ICE BATH ?
ARE YOU KIDDING ?
THAT'S NOWHERESVILLE.
IF YOU SHUT OFF THE COLD,
YOU MIGHT SCALD THEM.
SO THEY LOSE A LITTLE SKIN.
SERVES THEM RIGHT.
I WANT TO SEE THEM SUFFER.
[ Screaming ]
[ Girls Yelling ]
I'M WET !
- [ Girls Laughing ]
- MYRA, DON'T LEAVE ME.
- I HATE YOU !
- YOU NEVER LOOKED BETTER !
WE'LL GET YOU ALL !
[ Girls Cheering ]
- WHAT DO YOU THINK ?
- IT LOOKS THE SAME TO ME.
IT'S KIND OF DULL.
ALL YOU NEED
IS A COUPLE OF STREAKS
AND YOUR EARS PIERCED.
I CAN DO IT FOR YOU
FREE OF CHARGE.
- MY EARS WHAT ?
- PIERCED.
I TAKE A NEEDLE,
AND THEN I HEAT IT UP,
AND THEN I DAB IT
WITH SOME ALCOHOL AND, ZAP,
ALL THE GUYS GO CRAZY.
BECAUSE I HAVE HOLES
IN MY EARS ?
WHAT, ARE YOU PUTTING ME ON ?
SOMETIMES I CAN'T
FIGURE YOU OUT, LINDA.
SO WHERE ARE YOU GOING
THIS WEEKEND ?
NOWHERE.
NOWHERE ?  WELL,
YOU CAN'T STAY AROUND HERE.
THIS PLACE IS DEPRESSING.
I MEAN, LIKE THE TOMBS.
WHY ?
WHAT, WERE YOU BORN YESTERDAY ?
THIS IS A THREE-DAY WEEKEND.
A THREE-DAY WEEKEND.
SO, LISTEN, WHY DON'T
YOU COME HOME WITH ME ?
I ONLY LIVE ABOUT FIVE MILES
FROM HERE, AND I GOT THIS GUY
COMING UP FROM METROPOLIS.
I THINK HE KNOWS
YOUR COUSIN CLARK.
HIS NAME'S
JIMMY OLSEN.
I THINK
HE'S REAL STUCK ON ME.
ANYWAYS, I COULD ASK HIM
TO BRING A FRIEND ALONG.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING ?
OH, NOTHING.
NOTHING.  NO, I THINK
I'M GONNA STAY HERE
AND STUDY,
GET THINGS ORGANIZED.
[ Girl ]
DON'T FORGET
TO CALL ME SATURDAY.
JUST A SECOND.
HEY, LINDA,
I'LL SEE YOU LATER
IN MIDVALE THEN, OKAY ?
ALL RIGHT, I'LL TRY.  I PROMISE.
YOU BETTER.
IT'S GONNA BE FUN.
BYE.
BYE.  HAVE A GOOD TIME.
TAKE A SPIDER...
OFF HIS WEB...
AND SHUT HIM UP INSIDE...
TWO SHELLS OF A NUT.
NOW, BOIL THE NUT IN OIL,
INTO WHICH HAS BEEN ADDED
SOME OF THE WEB.
WITH A SILVER SPOON,
PUT TWO DROPS OF THE OIL...
INTO SOME WATER.
RIGHT.
HE WHO DRINKS THE WATER...
SHALL BE IN LOVE
WITH THE FIRST PERSON HE SEES,
SO LONG AS THE SPIDER
IS SHUT UP IN THE NUTSHELL...
[ Train Whistle ]
OR ONE DAY GOES BY,
WHICHEVER COMES FIRST.
BIG DEAL.  ONE DAY.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST USE,
YOU KNOW--
I'M SAVING IT
FOR BIGGER THINGS.
HIYA, FOLKS.
YOU'RE LISTENING TO BIG SAM,
THE COUNTRY-AND-WESTERN VOICE
OF THE CHICAGO AREA.
NOW TO START OFF THE HOUR,
SOMETHING MELLOW.
[ Door Buzzing ]
BIANCA, GET THE DOOR !
[ Buzzing Continues ]
BIANCA !
YOU RANG ?  HEY, YOU !
I SAID, YOU RANG ?
OH, YEAH.  HOW YOU DOING ?
UH, I'M LOOKING
FOR SOME PERSON
CALLED MRS. SEL-ENA.
- MADAME SELENA.
- AH.
AND YOU FOUND HER,
LUCKY BOY. ENTREZ.
YOU MUST BE VERY POPULAR
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
I ALWAYS SEE
YOUR TRUCK PARKED AROUND.
OH-- OH, YEAH.
I GET A LOT
OF REPEAT BUSINESS.
PEOPLE LIKE MY WORK.
YES.
I'M SURE THEY DO.
WET YOUR WHISTLE ?
HUH ?
OH, YEAH, YEAH.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
I DON'T MIND IF I DO.
SO, UH,
WHERE'S THE LAWN ?
IT DROPPED DEAD.
WHERE AT EXACTLY ?
OUT BACK ?
I THOUGHT WE MIGHT GET
TO KNOW EACH OTHER
A LITTLE MORE...
BEFORE WE DIG IN
AND TALK REAL TURKEY.
[ Clears Throat ]
WELL, UM, SEE, I'M KIND OF
A PRIVATE PERSON, YOU KNOW.
I DO MY WORK.
I GO HOME.
TO YOUR WIFE ?
NO.  AT THE PRESENT
MOMENT IN TIME,
I'M CURRENTLY ENJOYING
A SINGLE STATUS
IN MY PERSONAL LIFE.
CHEERS.
BOTTOMS UP, HUH ?
BOTTOMS UP.
[ Clears Throat ]
I, UH--
I NOTICED YOU GOT
A PRETTY ALKALINE-LOOKING
SOIL OUT THERE.
WHAT I WANT
ARE SOME HOUSEPLANTS...
INSIDE HERE.
SOMETHING THAT GOES WELL
WITH THE HOUSE.
THIS IS A HOUSE ?
OF COURSE
IT'S A HOUSE.
THERE'S THE BEDROOM
OVER THERE.
I THINK IT'S
GETTING DARK IN HERE.
YOU KNOW,
WHAT KIND OF PLANTS...
ARE GONNA WANNA
GROW IN THIS DUMP ?
- I DON'T KNOW.
- SHADE PLANTS ?
- HMM.
- TO US.
YEAH, I'LL, UH--
I'LL DRINK TO THAT.
MM.  YOU PROBABLY
KILLED HIM, YOU KNOW.
SLEEP WELL.
AND WHEN YOU WAKE,
DROWN IN MY EYES...
AND BE ALL MINE.
[ Door Buzzes ]
I'LL GET IT.
[ Buzzing ]
OH, HELLO, NIGEL.
IT'S YOU.
NICE SUIT.
- SUBTLE.
- I WANT TO SEE SELENA.
SHE'S INDISPOSED
AT THE MOMENT.
WHOEVER IT IS,
WE DON'T WANT ANY.
IT'S NIGEL,
AND HE'S NOT GOING AWAY
UNTIL HE TALKS TO YOU.
WHAT THE DEVIL
DO YOU WANT ?
I WANT
TO MAKE A VERY SERIOUS PROPOSAL.
- IN THAT OUTFIT ?
- THIS IS A LEISURE SUIT.
I'VE GOT THREE DAYS OFF
FROM THOSE LITTLE BEASTS
AT MIDVALE...
AND I INTEND
TO LET MY HAIR DOWN.
LET'S TALK.
TOGETHER WE COULD REALLY
RATTLE SOME CAGES.
KNOW WHAT I MEAN ?
I'M LISTENING.
MAKE IT SNAPPY.
[ Groaning ]
[ Bell Ringing,
Woman Screaming ]
[ Ghoulish Screaming,
Laughter ]
THAT BALL WILL NOT OPERATE
AT ITS FULLEST...
UNTIL YOU INTERNALIZE
YOUR POWERS, SELENA.
SOME MOSAIC INVOCATIONS.
SOME WHAT ?
COME AGAIN ?
EXACTLY.
THAT'S MY POINT.
YOU GIRLS ARE RANK AMATEURS
PLAYING WITH FIRE.
BECAUSE WE OWN
THE MATCHES.
I, OF ALL PEOPLE, KNOW
A HUSTLE WHEN I HEAR ONE.
GOOD-BYE, NIGEL.
IT WAS NICE TALKING
TO YOU, NIGEL.
NO, IT WASN'T.
- I HATE TO SEEM PUSHY,
MY FAIREST OF THE FAIR, BUT--
- A WORD OF ADVICE, NIGEL.
IF I HAD YOUR SKIN PROBLEMS,
I'D STOP BOTHERING PEOPLE,
PUT A BAG OVER MY HEAD
AND GO LIVE UNDER A BRIDGE.
- OUCH !
- [ Bianca Laughs ]
THERE'S NOTHING WRONG
WITH MY SKIN.
YOU KNOW, SOME PEOPLE.
WHERE IS HE ?
[ Groaning ]
WHOEVER HE SEES FIRST, HE'LL
LOVE WITH ALL HIS HEART.
WHAT, FOR A DAY, TOPS, RIGHT ?
HE WAS TOO YOUNG
FOR YOU ANYWAY, YOU KNOW.
NO, I DO NOT KNOW.
WHERE IS HE ?
HEY, I KNOW THAT GUY.
OH, THE CABLE'S OUT.
WHAT CABLE ?
THIS IS A MIRROR.
SO HOW COME
WE COULD EVER
SEE HIM IN IT ?
THAT WAS MAGIC, DAMN IT.
THE POWER.
OH.  SO MAKE IT
HAPPEN AGAIN, YOU KNOW.
I... CAN'T MAKE IT
HAPPEN AGAIN.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
I DID IT THE FIRST TIME.
OH.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD
LET THAT THING OUT
OF ITS BOX, YOU KNOW.
MAYBE IT'S MORE POWERFUL
IF YOU LET IT OUT OF ITS BOX.
THE BOX.
WHERE IS IT ?
THE BOX ?
IT'S UNDERNEATH THE RUG
WHERE YOU LEFT IT.
GO AHEAD.
IT'S STUCK.
[ Grunting ]
THIS IS NOT MY DAY.
IT'S STUCK ?
HOW COULD IT BE STUCK ?
IT'S GROWING.
HOW COULD IT
BE GROWING ?
IT'S MADE OUT OF LEAD.
OH, TOO BAD
THERE'S NO SOUND.
HOW COME
THERE'S NO SOUND ?
[ Horn Honking ]
GET OFF THE ROAD,
TURKEY !
HEY, DUMMY,
YOU WANNA DIE ?
WHAT ARE YOU SMOKING,
STUPID ?
YOU WANNA KILL YOURSELF ?
[ Woman ]
ANYWAY, SHE SAW A LAWYER,
AND NOW SHE'S GONNA FILE.
I TOLD HER TO TAKE HIM
FOR EVERY CENT,
CLEAN HIM OUT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
B.L.T.,
HOLD THE MAYO.
HERE YOU GO,
EVERYBODY.
WHO WANTS ONION RINGS ?
YEAH, HERE.
THANKS.
SOME FRENCH FRIES.
THE FRENCH FRIES
ARE MINE.
CHICKEN FOR MYSELF.
THANK YOU.
[ Girl ]
SIDE ORDER TOMATOES.
THANKS FOR INVITING ME, LUCY.
I'M GLAD YOU
COULD COME, JIMMY.
[ Girl ]  YOU WANT A ROOT BEER ?
YEAH, THANKS.
OH, THERE'S LINDA.
- HEY, LINDA !  HI !
- OH, HELLO.
THAT'S CLARK KENT'S COUSIN ?
WHO'S CLARK KENT ?
[ Girl ]
IS THAT LINDA ?
GUESS WHAT.
WHAT ?
THERE'S THIS ALL-NIGHT
PARTY TONIGHT AT EDDIE'S.
HE'S THE GUY WITH THE TATTOO.
HIS FOLKS ARE OUT OF TOWN.
AND THE GUY WITH THE BOW TIE ?
THAT'S JIMMY.
SO YOU WANNA COME ?
OH, I DON'T KNOW.  I'M NOT
SIGNED OUT FOR AN OVERNIGHT.
SO WHAT ?
GO BACK, SIGN IN
AND CLIMB OUT THE WINDOW.
MRS. MURPHY'S DRUNK
AS A SKUNK BY NOW.
TOTALLY ON ANOTHER PLANET.
OH, I DON'T KNOW.
IT JUST DOESN'T SEEM RIGHT.
BUT THAT'S WHY
IT'LL BE FUN.  OKAY ?
OKAY.
[ Tires Screeching,
Horn Honking ]
GET OFF THE ROAD, BUDDY !
HEY, STUPID !
- HEY, YOU, SPACE CADET,
GET OUT OF THE STREET !
- HEY, IDIOT !
WHAT IS WRONG WITH HIM ?
I DON'T KNOW.
HE'S PROBABLY ON DRUGS.
AND HE'S
GONNA GET CREAMED
IF HE'S NOT TOO CAREFUL.
HI.  JIMMY OLSEN,
PHOTOGRAPHER.
OH, I'M KARA.
WHO ?
OH, I'M... CONCERNED.
WELL, THAT IF WE DON'T
DO SOMETHING--
YOU GO OUT THERE AND TRY
TO HELP A GUY LIKE THAT...
AND HE'S PROBABLY GOT
A GUN OR A KNIFE.
IT'S NOT TOO SAFE.
HEY, I'M STARVING.
LET'S EAT.
COME ON, LINDA.
POWER OF SHADOW,
BRING HIM...
TO ME !
[ Engine Starts ]
WHOA.
WHOA !
LOOK AT THAT.
WATCH IT, BUDDY.
HEY, TURKEY,
GET OUT OF THERE.
LOOK OUT !  WATCH OUT !
IT'S COMING THIS WAY !
IT'S GONNA GET HIM !
WATCH OUT !
THERE'S NO DRIVER !
[ Screams ]
- [ Man ]
MY CAR.
- OHH !
[ People Shouting ]
[ Sighs ]
YOU'VE NEVER SEEN
A TATTOO BEFORE, LINDA ?
LOOK !
WHAT'S THAT ?
[ Boy ]
I DON'T KNOW, BUT THERE'S
SOMEBODY HANGING OUT OF IT.
OH, MY GOD.
IT'S A RUNAWAY.
SOMEBODY'S
GOTTA DO SOMETHING !
LUCY, BE CAREFUL !
WHAT'S GOING ON ?
LUCY !
WAIT !
[ Jimmy ]
GET THE KIDS
OFF THE STREET !
OKAY, EVERYONE, LOOK HAPPY.
THIS WAY.  THAT'S IT.  GREAT.
[ Screaming ]
HEY, WHAT THE HELL'S
GOING ON ?
[ Woman ]
GET OFF THE STREET !
[ Groans ]
[ Woman Screams ]
[ Woman ]
SOMEBODY GET AN AMBULANCE.
OH, EXCUSE ME.
I'M IN A RUSH.
I KNOW THE FEELING.
[ People Shouting,
Chattering ]
ARE YOU OKAY ?
[ Man ]
IT'S GASOLINE !
HEY, LOOK AT THAT !
A STORM DRAGON ?
A SUPER GIRL.
OH, MY GOD.
- [ Grunts ]
- DON'T.
DON'T LOOK AT HER.
YOU'RE GONNA BE ALL RIGHT.
THERE'S NO BROKEN BONES.
I LOVE YOU.
WHAT DID HE SAY ?
- LOOKED LIKE
"I LOVE YOU" TO ME.
- NO !  NO !
YOU LOVE ME ?
[ Gasps ]
WITH ALL MY HEART FOREVER.
A BIRD OF FREE
AND CARELESS WING WAS I
THROUGH MANY A SMILING SPRING.
THE COLD REPULSE,
THE LOOK ASKANCE, THE LIGHTNING
OF LOVE'S ANGRY GLANCE.  STAY.
LET ME BEHOLD YOU.
I-- I HAVE TO GO.
LIKE MELTING WAX
OR WITHERING FLOWER,
I FEEL MY PASSION...
AND THY POWER.
OH, I-- I HAVE TO GO.
[ Man ]
WE'VE GOT EVERYTHING
UNDER CONTROL.
LUCY ?
JUST GO ON
BACK TO YOUR HOMES.
- LUCY.
- OH !
OH, THANK GOD.
YOU ALL RIGHT ?
I THINK SO.
I HIT MY HEAD.
NIGEL MUST KNOW HER.
SHE MUST BE ONE
OF HIS STUDENTS.
- HE MUST'VE PUT HER UP TO IT.
- NO.  I DON'T THINK THAT
AT ALL.
OH, SHE JUST HAPPENED
TO BE IN THE WRONG PLACE
AT THE WRONG TIME, RIGHT ?
MATERIALIZING
IN A BULLDOZER, HUH ?
SHE'S A WIMPY LITTLE THING.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHY YOU
CARE WHAT SHE DOES ANYWAY.
BECAUSE NOBODY
GETS IN MY WAY.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST LEAVE
THIS POOR KID ALONE AND WORRY
ABOUT THE OTHER ONE THAT FLIES ?
I WORRY ABOUT EVERYTHING.
IT'S MY JOB.  STAND BACK.
AH, COME ON NOW.
SHE'S JUST A TEENAGER.
WHAT GOOD IS A SWORD
IF IT'S NOT UNLEASHED ?
BUT SHE'S A TOTAL ZERO.
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW
HER NAME.
THE NAMING OF NAMES
IS NOT NECESSARY.
I'LL JUST CONCENTRATE
ON HER FACE,
AND MY SHADOW
WILL DO THE REST.
YOUR WHAT ?
POWER OF SHADOW,
TAKE SHAPE.
LOOK LIKE
A VICIOUS DARK STAR.
SEEK OUT THAT
WRETCHED YOUNG CREATURE...
AND DESTROY HER
WHEREVER SHE...
ARE.
OH, GOD, THAT'S AWFUL.
THAT'S NEVER GONNA WORK.
[ High-pitched Warbling ]
[ Yells, Gasps ]
[ Roaring ]
OH, MY GOD !
OH, I'M SCARED.
[ Screams ]
OH, MY GOD !
I'M SCARED !
NEXT TIME...
REMIND ME
TO DO THIS OUTSIDE.
[ Thunder Crashes ]
LEAVE THIS PLACE
AND DO NO HARM.
[ Gasps ]
THERE SHE IS AGAIN.
WHAT'D SHE SAY ?
NO, THIS
IS NOT POSSIBLE.
THIS IS NOT RIGHT.
WHERE'S THE WIMP ?
[ Thud ]
[ Groans ]
HE CAN TAKE CARE OF HER.
SEE ?  WHAT'D I TELL YOU ?
SHE QUIT, RIGHT ?
WRONG.
[ Roaring ]
EVERY TIME !
SEND A MAN
TO DO A WOMAN'S JOB,
AND THAT'S WHAT YOU GET.
DAMN HER EYES.
WHO IS SHE ?
- ARE YOU ASKING ME ?
- I'M TELLING YOU-- FIND OUT.
WELL, SURE, BUT, YOU KNOW,
I THINK I RECOGNIZE
THE COSTUME.
[ TV: Man ]
IT WASN'T HIS FAULT ?
THEN WHOSE FAULT WAS IT ?
[ TV Continues ]
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN ?
OUTSIDE, I--
LOOK AT YA.
LOOK AT THOSE CLOTHES.
I'LL GO CHANGE.
I'M SORRY.
AND YOU'LL PUT ON
YOUR PROPER SCHOOL UNIFORM...
AND GET OUT OF
THAT RIDICULOUS COSTUME.
YES, MA'AM.
AND COVER YOUR LEGS !
DON'T YOU
"YES, MA'AM" ME.
NO, MA'AM.
I THINK YOU'RE
BLOWING THIS THING
OUT OF PROPORTION.
NO, THIS BOX
IS DEFINITELY
GETTING BIGGER...
AND UGLIER.
ALL I'M SAYING IS,
YOU CAN'T GO NUTS
OVER A LANDSCAPE GUY...
AND A TEENAGER
IN A BLUE SUIT.
SHE FLIES.
[ Sighs ]
CAN YOU GET THAT
THROUGH YOUR THICK SKULL
AND INTO YOUR TINY BRAIN ?
THE GIRL CAN FLY.
OKAY, NOW,
LET'S GET SERIOUS.
COME TO MAMA.
OHH !  OHH !
OH !  WHOA !
[ High-pitched Warbling ]
[ Warbling Continues ]
[ Warbling Quickens ]
[ Warbling
Lowers In Pitch ]
[ Warbling Fades ]
[ Warbling
Intensifies ]
SELENA, CUT IT OUT !
I'M NOT DOING IT !
[ Warbling Continues ]
[ Warbling Fades ]
[ Warbling Resumes,
Volume Increases ]
I THINK WE'RE VENTURING WHERE,
YOU KNOW, FOOLS RUSH IN
AND ANGELS FEAR TO TREAD.
I'M NO ANGEL.
[ Warbling Continues ]
IT'S THE WIMP AGAIN.
- ANDSHE'STRESPASSING.
- [ Lid Clunking ]
FIRST THE SCHOOL,
NOW HERE.
YOU KNOW, THIS THING REACTS
WHENEVERSHE'SAROUND.
AND WHENEVER SHE SHOWS UP,
THAT GIRL THAT FLIES--
MM.
THAT "SUPER GIRL"--
ISN'T FAR BEHIND.
MAYBE THEY'RE BEST FRIENDS.
[ Footfall ]
- HELLO.
- OH, NO.  NOT NOW.
'TIS ONLY BUT ME,
MY LOVE.
PLEASE.
YOU'LL LET EVERYONE KNOW.
WHAT, THAT I LOVE YOU ?
I'D SHOUT IT
FROM THE HIGHEST HILL !
SHH !
PLEASE DON'T.
I KNOW YOU THINK ME THE FOOL,
BUT AT LEAST
TELL ME YOUR NAME.
LINDA.
LINDA LEE.
LOVELY LINDA LEE.
THESE ROSES
PALE BESIDE THEE.
OH.  WELL, THANK YOU,
BUT I'M--
AND SWEET CHOCOLATES
FOR MY SWEET LINDA.
MMM.
[ Sniffs ]
[ Grunting ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING ?
PLEASE ?
OH, NO, I--
WELL, ALL RIGHT,
BUT JUST FOR A MINUTE.
YOU HATE ME, DON'T YOU ?
HATE YOU ?
I DON'T EVEN KNOW YOU.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
YOUR NAME.
ETHAN.
SAY MY NAME ALOUD BUT ONCE,
AND I SHALL DIE
THE HAPPY FOOL.
LOOK, ETHAN--
[ Gasps ]
ETHAN.
HER SOFT CARESS DID AT ONCE
RENEW THE BEATING
OF HIS BROKEN HEART.
ARE YOU CRAZY ?
MARRY ME ?
MARRY YOU ?
I--
DON'T SAY IT.
DON'T, PLEASE.
I KNOW.
WHAT ?
WE'RE FROM DIFFERENT WORLDS.
YOU MEAN YOU KNOW
WHERE I'M--
JUST GIVE ME
A CHANCE, LINDA.
LOVE MAKES EVERYTHING
POSSIBLE.
A POOR, UNEDUCATED GARDENER
CAN INDEED WORSHIP
A RICH DEBUTANTE...
AND MAKE HER HAPPY,
IF SHE'D JUST--
OH, ETHAN.
I'M NOT RICH.
WELL, THEN
I'LL SUPPORT US BOTH.
YOU'RE NUTS.
YOU KNOW THAT ?
YOU'RE SO SWEET,
BUT YOU'RE OUT OF YOUR MIND.
OVER YOU.
WHAT A TOUCHING
SCENE.
ROUND AND ROUND THEY GO,
AND WHERE THEY STOP--
BOY, YOU'RE REALLY GETTIN'
THE HANG OF THIS.
[ Groaning ]
WHERE IS SHE ?
[ Both Gasp ]
JEEZ !
WHO ARE YOU ?
I AM SELENA,
DIODENES OF CATANIA,
PRIESTESS OF SEKHNET.
I AM THE ULTIMATE SIREN
OF ENDOR.
AND YOU, LITTLE LADY,
ARE TRESPASSING
ON PRIVATE PROPERTY.
SHE MEANS HIM.
I AM KARA OF ARGO CITY,
DAUGHTER OF ALURA
AND ZOR-EL,
AND I DON'T SCARE EASILY.
NO ?
[ Supergirl ]
NO.
TRY...
THIS.
[ Grunts ]
OH.  OHHH.
WHOA !  WHOA.
THIS LADY'S IMPROVING
BY LEAPS AND BOUNDS,
I GOTTA TELL YA.
[ Panting ]
[ Gasps ]
HEY--  HEY, WHAT--
WH-WHOA !
[ Grunts ]
[ Gasps ]
YOU OKAY ?
NO.
YOU WANT A HACKSAW
OR SOMETHIN' ?
[ Chanting
In Unknown Language ]
[ Gasps ]
NOW I AM REALLY UPSET.
WHAT'S GOING ON ?
WHOA !
PUT ME DOWN !
WHERE AM I ?
YOU'RE SAFE.
SAFE ?
WHERE'S LINDA ?
PUT ME DOWN--
[ Grunts ]
WHERE'S MY LINDA ?
TAKE IT EASY.
[ Whooshing ]
ETHAN !
VERY CLEVER.
THAT OUGHTA KEEP HER OUT OF
YOUR HAIR FOR A FEW HOURS.
CLEVER ?
A CHEAP TRICK.
POWER OF SHADOW,
BRING HIM TO ME.
BRING HIM...
TO ME !
OHH !
DIDN'T WORK, HUH ?
MAYBE THEY'RE TOO FAR AWAY.
I CAN MAKE THE SKY
RAIN COCONUTS
WITH PINPOINT ACCURACY,
BUT I STILL CAN'T
CONTROL MEN'S MINDS.
NOT WITH HER AROUND.
SO MAYBE--
[ Sighs ]
NOW, DON'T GO THROUGH THE ROOF,
BUT MAYBE WE OUGHTA BACK DOWN...
AND GIVE OLD YOU-KNOW-WHO
A CALL.
YOU KNOW WHO ?
- SPIT IT OUT.
- NIGEL.
I SHALL PRETEND
YOU DIDN'T SAY THAT.
BUT I DID.
ALL I'M THINKING,
AND FORGIVE ME FOR THINKING
OUT OF TURN HERE,
IS THAT
HE'S BEEN AROUND.
HE KNOWS THINGS
WE DON'T.
PLUS, THE WAY YOU WRAP HIM
AROUND YOUR LITTLE FINGER,
I'M ALWAYS AMAZED.
[ Dial Tone ]
YOU MUST THINK ME
A BABE IN THE WOODS.
NOT AT ALL.
SCRATCH MY BACK,
AND I'LL SCRATCH YOURS.
WHAT'S IN IT FOR ME ?
ME.
AHA.
THINK OF THE COMBINATION,
NIGEL.
THE TWO OF US.
ONE MORE TIME, PLEASE.
MY DEAR NIGEL, THE WAY
TO A WOMAN'S HEART...
IS THROUGH THE ELIMINATION
OF HER RIVALS.
MURDER ?
ARE YOU PROPOSING THAT--
CERTAINLY NOT.
LEAVE THAT TO ME.
YOU DELIVER THE GOODS--
HER.
HER ?  HOW ?
BY GETTING ME...
HIM.
- SHE'LL FOLLOW.
- WELL, I DON'T.
- FOLLOW ANY OF THIS, I MEAN.
- PUT THAT DOWN.
NIGEL,
I WANT ONE THING--
TIME TO MASTER
MY NEW TOY.
[ Nigel ]
SO WE CAN RULE
THE WORLD ?
WE--
ANDSHE,
I HAVE BECOME CONVINCED,
POSES SOME VAGUE YET
POTENT AND UNDENIABLE THREAT.
SHE'S AUTHENTIC, THEN ?
THE SUIT IS NOT A JOKE.
IT'S NOT RENTED.
- THE CAPE FLAPS FOR REAL.
- WE HAVE EVERY REASON
TO BELIEVE IT'S LEGITIMATE.
AND YOU WANT HIM HERE ?
JOHNNY APPLESEED
IN YOUR LIVING ROOM ?
YES.
IN THE FLESH.
SO SHE'LL FOLLOW ?
NO OTHER REASON ?
NONE.
YOU'RE SURE OF THAT ?
WHOOPS, I'M SORRY.
THE LITTLE SPIDER GOT OUT.
WHAT ?
WHERE AM I ?
WHO ARE YOU ?
KARA.
KARA ?
WHAT HAPPENED ?
YOU GOT HIT ON THE HEAD
BY A COCONUT.
HUH ?
WHAT'S WITH
THE HALLOWEEN COSTUME ?
THIS IS NOT A COSTUME.
THESE ARE MY CLOTHES.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN ?
- LOOK, I-- I HAVE TO GO NOW.
I WILL COME BACK FOR YOU.
I'VE JUST GOT TO GET BACK
TO THE AMUSEMENT PARK.
AMUSEMENT PARK.
LINDA !
I GOTTA FIND LINDA.
SHE WAS IN TROUBLE.
OH, LINDA'S ALL RIGHT.
SHE CAN TAKE CARE OF HERSELF.
NO, NO, SHE CAN'T.
SOMETHING'S WRONG.
SHE'S IN BIG TROUBLE,
AND I LOVE HER--
I LOVE HER.
YEAH, I DO LOVE HER.
I HAVE TO GO, ETHAN.
GOOD-BYE.
YEAH, SO DO I.
HEY !
I TOLD YOU,
LINDA CAN TAKE CARE OF HERSELF.
YOU JUST FLEW OVER MY HEAD.
I SAW YOU DO THAT.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF EVERYTHING.
I SAID,
YOU JUST FLEW OVER MY HEAD.
TRUE OR FALSE ?
TRUE.
LIKE SUPERMAN.
HE'S MY COUSIN.
[ Snickers ]
HE'S YOUR COUSIN ?
YES.  I SHOULDN'T BE
TELLING YOU THIS, THOUGH.
WAIT, YOU CAN LEAP TALL
BUILDINGS IN A SINGLE BOUND,
LOOK RIGHT THROUGH THINGS ?
YES.
BEND STEEL BARS ?
WHOA !
OH, SELENA.
I HAVE TO GO.
SELENA HAS THE OMEGAHEDRON.
PLEASE TAKE ME WITH YOU.
I HAVE TO FIND LINDA.
WELL, NIGEL.
ARE WE IN BUSINESS ?
I'M THINKING ABOUT IT.
HE PROBABLY
CAN'T EVEN DO IT.
OH, INDEED I CAN,
BUT I NEED THE LITTLE
MYSTERY BALL.
NO WAY.
NO BALL, NO TRICK.
OKAY.
BUT I KEEP HOLD OF IT.
[ Bianca Gasps ]
- WHAT IS IT ?
- THE BURUNDI WAND.
PURE,
UNADULTERATED EVIL.
READY ?
BUT HOW CAN YOU LOVE HER ?
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW HER.
OH, YEAH, I DO.
AND IF SHE'S IN TROUBLE,
THEN I GOT NO BUSINESS
STANDING HERE
TALKING WITH YOU,
EVEN IF YOU ARE
WHAT YOU SAY YOU ARE.
LINDA IS NOT IN TROUBLE.
LOOK, DON'T MAKE ME
GET ROUGH, OKAY ?
YOU WOULDN'T
STAND A CHANCE.
PLEASE TRUST ME.
LINDA IS ALL RIGHT.
HOW DO YOU KNOW ?
I JUST...
KNOW.
LINDA !
[ Bianca Gasps ]
OH, MY GOD !
HOW DID YOU DO THAT ?
ETHAN.
ETHAN !
NIGEL,
YOU ARE WONDERFUL.
PURE GENIUS.
YOU DESERVE...
ME.
AND SOMETHING ELSE.
NOW LET'S GET OUT
OF THIS DUMP.
[ Zap ]
[ Man ]
DID YOU SEE THIS THING ?
LOOK AT THIS !
WHAT'S THE MATTER ?
YOU CATCHIN' FLIES ?
LUCY, LOOK.
[ Man ]
ONE MINUTE NOTHIN',
THE NEXT MINUTE THIS.
WHAT IS IT ?
[ Man ]
DO YOU SEE WHAT I SEE ?
IT'S A MOUNTAIN, LUCY,
ISN'T IT ?
TELL ME I'M NOT
SEEIN' THINGS.
HOW DID IT GET THERE, JIMMY ?
I DON'T KNOW.
IT JUST APPEARED.
HOW CAN A MOUNTAIN JUST APPEAR ?
[ Lucy ]
HEY, THERE'S SOMETHING
ON THE TOP.
[ Jimmy ]
LOOKS LIKE A CASTLE.
[ Lucy ]
LOOKS MORE LIKE A FORTRESS.
ETHAN ?
ETHAN.
[ Chains Rattling ]
ETHAN !
ENJOY YOUR PRISON,
SUPERGIRL,
FOREVER AND EVER.
NO, ETHAN !
DON'T DO IT !
ETHAN !
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
[ Grunts, Groans ]
WHERE AM I ?
[ Echoing ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Man ]  YOU CAN'T ARREST ME
WITHOUT A WARRANT !
I'M GONNA CALL MY LAWYER !
SLOW DOWN.
[ Girl ]
WE WANT SELENA OUT !
SMILE, LUNKHEAD.
YOU'RE NOT A GARDENER ANYMORE.
YOU'RE PRINCE ETHAN NOW.
HOW MUCH LONGER ARE
THE TELEPHONE LINES
GOING TO BE CLOSED ?
MY WIFE'S VERY SICK
IN THE HOSPITAL IN METROPOLIS.
I'VE GOT TO GET THROUGH !
[ Man ]
WHEN ARE YOU GOING
TO REOPEN THE AIRPORT ?
ARE WE GONNA STAND UP TO HER
OR NOT ?
[ Crowd ]  YES !
- SELENA MUST GO !
- WHO'S THIS LITTLE TWIRPETTE ?
SOMEONE WHO BELIEVES IN FREEDOM.
LUCY, IT'S NOT A GOOD TIME
TO EXPRESS YOURSELF.
I DON'T KNOW WHO
YOU THINK YOU ARE OR WHAT
EVIL FORCE YOU REPRESENT,
BUT IF YOU THINK YOU CAN
JUST GET RID OF ANYBODY
WHO STANDS UP TO YOU,
JUST MAKE THEM DISAPPEAR
LIKE MY FRIEND LINDA--
- WHO ?
- LINDA, MY ROOMMATE.
SHE DISAPPEARED
THE DAY THAT MOUNTAIN SHOWED UP.
[ Together ]
THE WIMP.
SEIZE THEM !
[ Shouting, Screaming ]
[ Jimmy ]
LEAVE HER ALONE !
[ Selena ]
DRIVE OFF.
LEAVE HER ALONE !
NOBODY MESSES AROUND
WITH JIMMY OLSEN !
LET GO OF ME !
I'M WITH THE PRESS !
[ Gasps ]
ZALTAR !
SQUIRT ?
ZALTAR ?
SQUIRT.
ZALTAR, IT'S ME.
IT'S-- IT'S KARA.
I KNOW.
SQUIRT.
[ Spits ]
WHAT IS THAT ?
WHERE ARE WE ?
HERE.
BUT WHERE ?
NOWHERE.
THE PHANTOM ZONE ?
IT'S LONELY HERE,
MY KARA.
SO SAD.
SO LONG AGO.
NO, ZALTAR, ONLY DAYS.
AND ONLY DAYS LEFT.
ZALTAR, WE HAVE
TO GET BACK TO EARTH.
WE HAVE TO GET THE OMEGAHEDRON
AND GET IT BACK TO ARGO CITY.
I'VE BEEN HERE FOREVER,
AND I SHALL STAY HERE
FOREVER.
ZALTAR, THE PERSON
WHO HAS THE POWER SOURCE,
SHE TRICKED ME.
SHE SENT ME HERE
AND I HAVE TO--
STAY HERE FOREVER TOO.
SHE SOUNDS FORMIDABLE,
SOMEONE TO BE RECKONED WITH.
SHE'S A SORCERESS,
A WICKED AND DESP--
MORE POWERFUL
THAN THE GUARDIANS,
IS SHE ?
BUT THE GUARDIANS
ARE GOOD.
ZALTAR IS BAD.
WORSE THAN
THIS WICKED SORCERESS.
SELF-PITY.
YOU ALWAYS TAUGHT ME
TO HAVE PRIDE, ZALTAR.
PRIDE--
SHOULD A MAN WHOSE
FOOLISH AMBITIONS...
DESTROY ALL THE HE LOVES
HAVE PRIDE ?
IF YOU THINK THAT,
THEN I AM A FOOL WHO
HAS TAUGHT YOU NOTHING.
[ Bianca ]
I GUESS OUR NEXT MOVE IS
TO TAKE OVER THE WORLD, HUH ?
I'M READY
WHEN YOU ARE, HONEY.
FIRST THINGS FIRST.
ETHAN.
YES, MY DARLING ?
DON'T CALL ME
YOUR "DARLING."
YOU DESPISE ME.
BRING ME
THE COFFER OF SHADOW.
YES, MY DARLING.
I THINK
WE NEED SOMETHING...
THERE.
[ Gasps ]
OH, JIMMY.
OH, TERRIFIC.
THE OLD DANGLING-IN-A-CAGE
ROUTINE.
PATHETIC, SELENA.
- WHO IS THAT GUY ?
- HE'S MY MATH TEACHER, I THINK.
I WOULD HAVE THOUGHT
A CEILING FAN, MYSELF.
BUT IT'S YOUR HOUSE.
WHAT ARE THEY FOR ?
INSURANCE.
BUT YOU CAN'T JUST GIVE UP.
YOU FOUNDED A WHOLE CITY.
I DID, AND THEN I DOOMED IT
TO DESTRUCTION.
THAT WAS AN ERROR,
A TRAGIC ONE.
WHEN YOU'RE MY AGE
AND YOU MAKE AS MANY
TRAGIC ERRORS AS I DO,
IT IS A DIFFERENT TUNE
THAT YOU WILL SING.
I WILL NOT.
I WILL NEVER GIVE UP.
I WILL NEVER SPEND MY ENTIRE
LIFE IN A PLACE LIKE THIS.
I WOULD DIE FIRST.
STRONG WORDS.
THERE ARE WORSE THINGS
THAN DYING, AND I DESERVE
EVERY ONE OF THEM.
WHAT IS THIS ?
A HORSE, I THINK.
ON EARTH...
I THINK IT'S CALLED
A HORSE.
AND YOU MADE THIS HERE ?
MMM.
THEN YOU HAVEN'T GIVEN UP.
DON'T BE RIDICULOUS.
EARTH, ZALTAR.  A TREE, A HORSE.
YOU KEEP MAKING THINGS
FROM EARTH.
THE PLACE INTRIGUES ME.
THEN LET'S GO THERE.
CERTAINLY.
WHEN IS THE NEXT TRAIN ?
WHAT IS A TRAIN ?
[ Laughing ]
WHAT'S SO FUNNY ?
DON'T LAUGH AT ME, ZALTAR.
I'M ONLY LAUGHING AT MYSELF.
FOR YOU I WEEP.
IS THIS TRAIN
A WAY OUT OF HERE ?
THERE IS NO WAY
OUT OF HERE.
THAT IS THE POINT
OF THE PHANTOM ZONE.
MY NEIGHBORS KNOW--
THE CRIMINALS, THE CORRUPT,
THE EVIL.
THEY'RE HERE,
OVER THE HILL THERE,
WITH NO WAY OUT.
BUT...
THERE'S ALWAYS A WAY OUT.
IF THERE'S A WAY IN,
THERE'S A WAY OUT.
THERE IS A WAY.
- BUT IT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
- WHY ?
NO, IT WOULDN'T WORK.
YOU'D BE SWEPT
INTO A SINGULARITY
IF IT DIDN'T WORK.
FORGET I MENTIONED IT.
HAVE A SQUIRT INSTEAD.
I COULD DO IT.
THEN, PLEASE,
AT LEAST TEACH ME HOW.
THERE'S NOTHING TO TEACH.
YOU CAN'T, AS THEY SAY,
PRACTICE.
AT THE RIFT
YOU GET ONE CHANCE ONLY.
- THE RIFT ?
- SURE YOU WON'T HAVE A SQUIRT ?
ONCE YOU GET USED TO IT,
I THINK IT'S DELICIOUS.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
YOU ARE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
THERE IS ENOUGH
DOOM AND GLOOM
IN THE AIR ALREADY,
AND IT IS BETTER
TO ACCEPT DEFEAT...
THAN TO TAKE A CHANCE
AND TRY LIKE FOOLS
TO REDEEM OURSELVES...
AND SAVE OUR CITY
AND ALL THOSE
WE LOVE THERE,
PLUS ALL THE PEOPLE ON EARTH
THIS WICKED SORCERESS IS GOING
TO MAKE SUFFER BECAUSE OF US.
CHEERS.
WE COULD DIE TRYING.
BUT WE WON'T.
COME ON.
[ Wind Howling ]
TOMORROW.
THURSDAY.
FRIDAY.
JUST LIKE HERE,
WE GO FOR THE COPS FIRST,
RIGHT ?
AND THE ARMY.
BY SATURDAY
WE HAVE THE CONTINENTAL
UNITED STATES,
MEXICO, CANADA.
-WISH WE'D KEPT OUR MOUTHS SHUT.
-I'M NOT AFRAID TO DIE.
I'M PROUD OF US.
LUCY, THERE'S SOMETHING
I'VE ALWAYS WANTED
TO SAY TO YOU.
GUESS I'D BETTER
SAY IT NOW.
UM, I'VE BEEN
IN LOVE WITH YOU F--
FOR MANY YEARS.
- [ Chuckles ]
YOU HAVE ?
- MM-HMM.
[ Sighs ]  REMEMBER WHEN
YOU USED TO VISIT YOUR SISTER
IN THE NEWSROOM ?
YOU USED TO PUT
YOUR FINGERPRINTS
ON MY LENS.
REMEMBER ?
I WAS TRYING DESPERATELY
TO GET YOU ATTENTION.
- REALLY ?
- UH-HUH.
[ Chuckles ]
YOU MEAN, WE COULD HAVE--
WE COULD HAVE BEEN--
YOU KNOW WHAT--
ALL THIS TIME ?
- YOU BETCHA.
- [ Laughs ]
- WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME ?
- YOU WERE SUPPOSED TO GUESS.
[ Wind Howling ]
AAH !
CAREFUL !
KARA !  KARA !
MY CHILD !
WHERE IS IT, ZALTAR ?
WHERE'S THE RIFT ?
WHERE IS IT ?
EVERYWHERE.
AND NOWHERE.
WE DON'T FIND THE RIFT,
WE MAKE IT.
ZALTAR, NOW OF ALL TIMES,
NO DOUBLE-TALK, I BEG YOU.
DOUBLE-TALK ?
OUR LIFE IS TOO SHORT
TO SQUANDER IT
ON DOUBLE-TALK.
LOOK:
THE PHANTOM ZONE.
GET UP.
[ Wind Continues Howling ]
[ High-pitched Squealing ]
[ Gasps ]
OH, MY GOD, SELENA,
IT'S THE BOX !
HUSH IT UP !
NO.
WHAT THE BOX WANTS,
THE BOX GETS.
[ Loud Crash ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Wind Howling ]
WHAT IS IT ?
FASCINATING.
[ Ethan Laughs ]
I DON'T KNOW.
IS THIS IT ?
IS THIS THE WAY OUT ?
NOT YET !
THIS IS THE QUANTUM VORTEX !
WE MUST RISK
OUR DESTRUCTION IN IT !
TO MOVE MOUNTAINS,
YOU MUST MAKE
SACRIFICES !
ZALTAR, I'M SCARED !
ACCEPT YOUR FEARS.
CONFRONT
YOUR DEMONS.
FIND YOUR DESTINY
IN THE MAELSTROM !
ZALTAR, I CAN'T !
I CAN'T !
YOU...
CAN !
[ Groans ]
[ Grunts ]
TWO SPECKS.
LOOK !
WHAT DO I DO ?
HOW DO YOU MURDER SOMEONE
IN THE PHANTOM ZONE ?
SHE'S WITH SOME OLD GUY,
IT LOOKS LIKE.
MOVE, HUH ?
COME ON !
CALM DOWN, OKAY ?
AH !
THIS IS WHAT I WANT !
THE SAELIAN FIREBALLS.
PAGE 321,
CHAPTER SIX.
AAAH !
WHAT WAS THAT ?
WATCH OUT !
AAAAH !
OHHH !
[ Groans ]
OH !
[ Grunting ]
[ Groaning ]
"RAINMAKING."
NO !
"HOW TO SEPARATE
HUSBAND AND WIFE."
NO, NOT NOW, NOT NOW !
WELL, YOU'D BETTER
FIND SOMETHING FAST,
LIKE AN ATOM BOMB.
I FOUND IT.
"SUMMONING...
THE DEMON STORM."
WE... GO...
HIGHER, GIRL, HIGHER !
COME WITH ME !
IAMWITH YOU !
ON, GIRL !
I AM WITH YOU.
ZALTAR !
[ High-pitched
Squealing ]
OH, THANK GOD !
YOU'VE HAD YOUR FUN, SELENA.
THE GAME IS FINISHED.
HARDLY.
ONE FALSE STEP,
BLUEBIRD,
AND EVEN IF YOU DON'T,
YOUR FRIENDS WILL GET THE POINT.
HEY, NO !
[ Sizzling ]
I DON'T LIKE THIS.
DON'T WORRY, LUCY.
DON'T WORRY.
I WOULDN'T,
IF I WERE YOU.
WELL, YOU'RE NOT ME.
[ All Screaming ]
QUICK, GET OUT OF THE WAY !
INTO THE ALCOVE OVER THERE !
COME ON, OUT !
[ Lucy ]
HURRY !
THE OMEGAHEDRON, SELENA.
I WANT IT.
WELL, THEN, SUPERGIRL,
YOU SHALL HAVE IT.
[ Zap ]
[ High-pitched
Squealing ]
AAAH !
[ Gasps ]
SUPERGIRL !
ABOVE YOU !
LOOK OUT !
[ Gasps ]
AAAH !
I THINK I'LL BE GOING.
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME.
AAAAH !
THAT'S WHAT I SAID.
I'M STAYING, I'M STAYING !
YOU HAVE NO FRIENDS,
SELENA.
YOU TREAT EVERYONE
AS IF THEY WERE PUT
ON THIS EARTH TO SERVE YOU.
MORE OR LESS,
I THINK THEY WERE.
YOU INCLUDED.
POWER OF SHADOW,
APPEAR !
[ Growling ]
[ Creature Roaring ]
POWER OF SHADOW,
DESTROY HER !
[ Continues Roaring ]
[ Supergirl Groaning ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming, Groaning ]
OH !
[ Screaming,
Groaning Continue ]
I...
CAN'T.
I CAN'T !
[ Zaltar's Voice ]
YOU CAN !
ON, GIRL !
YES !
[ Squealing Stops ]
CONFRONT HER WITH IT !
IT'S THE ONLY WAY !
[ Gasping ]
[ Roaring ]
[ Screaming ]
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO !
[ Continues Roaring ]
[ Continues Screaming ]
[ Bianca Screaming ]
OH.
I HAVE TO GO.
I HAVE TO RETURN THIS
TO WHERE IT BELONGS.
I MUST ASK YOU ALL
SOMETHING.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, SUPERGIRL.
WE NEVER SAW YOU.
WE NEVER EVEN HEARD OF YOU.
THANK YOU.
ETHAN, LINDA, SHE--
SHE HAD TO LEAVE IN A HURRY,
BUT SHE--
YOU DON'T HAVE TO SAY A WORD.
I KNOW.
I'LL EXPLAIN
ABOUT LINDA.
THANK YOU, ETHAN.
TAKE CARE OF YOURSELF,
KIDDO.
[ Crowd Gasping,
Screaming ]
WHEW !  WOW !
THAT WAS SOME KISS.
WOW !
BETTER GET A SHOT
OF WHERE THAT MOUNTAIN
USED TO BE.
OH, JIMMY.
CAN'T YOU STOP THINKING
OF YOUR CAREER FOR A SECOND ?
HAVEN'T WE WASTED
ENOUGH TIME ?
NIGEL !
I'M SO GLAD TO SEE YOU.
I'VE BEEN TRYING
TO FIND YOU.
I WANTED TO KNOW MORE
ABOUT THE LITTLE BONE
IN THE RIGHT SIDE OF A FROG.
UH, IT'S A TOAD, MY DEAR.
A RED TOAD.
AND THAT LITTLE BONE
IS IN THE LEFT HAND SIDE.
GOOD-BYE, LINDA.
HMM.
[ Crowd Chattering ]
HI !  TAKE CARE.
YOU GUYS TAKE IT EASY,
OKAY ?
GOOD LUCK !
BYE.
SEE YOU SOON.
[ Jimmy ]
TAKE IT EASY !
CLOSED-CAPTIONED BY
CAPTIONS, INC.  LOS ANGELES