All right, all right. Get back now.
Get back. Get over there.
All right, hold on, you little animals.
I'm coming now.
It's cold out there, ain't it?
All right, come on.
Get through those doors.
Oh, come on. Move it. Move it.
Come on, get off it. Hey!
Danny, check this out, man.
Piece of cake.
- ... either one of these schools...
- Sit down.
...you can go to...
- Mr. Rubell!
- What happened?
- We've got another one.
Stab wound.
- Who stabbed you?
- I don't know.
Of course.
Call an ambulance.
I don't want no ambulance.
It's not for you,
it's for the insurance company.
Send an ambulance
to JFK, please.
Oh, would you call
the nurse, please.
- Mr. Rubell. - Just a moment.
I'll be right with you.
Oh, Ms. Hammond,
what can I do for you today?
- Do you know that kid
is bleeding? - Yes, I do.
- Well. This is for you, Mr. Rubell.
- What's that?
It's a notice informing you we'll
be holding depositions here.
If your teachers can't remember
to bring their records with them,
we'll come to the records.
- We want to start tomorrow.
- Fine.
Is that student bleeding?
- Yes. We're taking care of it.
- Good. Good.
Oh, Principal Horn,
this is Lisa Hammond
of Kemel, Keating and Hess,
attorneys at law.
How do you do?
Her firm is handling
the Calvin case.
- What?
- John Calvin. Suing the school.
Oh, yes.
Well, Ms. Hammond,
I think you'll find that we're
trying to cooperate fully
with you in this matter.
Mr. Horn, our client
is suing the school
because he graduated
but he can't read or write.
I should think all of us would be
cooperating to help clear this up.
Mr. Rubell?
- Mr. Rubell!
- Yes.
We have at least 10% of our
teachers absent again today,
and we're having
trouble finding subs.
Scrape the bottom of the barrel
if you have to, Grace, please.
- Mr. Rubell, I'm going to need...
- Is Jurel in yet?
On a Monday?
Hello?
Mr. Jurel, Mrs. Wensel from Kennedy.
Are we coming in today?
Or are we taking another of our
famous three-day weekends?
No.
What time is it?
It is 7:45, We are already
10 minutes late, Mr, Jurel,
Well?
Well, what?
Are you going to
teach today?
Yeah,
I'll be in very soon.
Oh, why, thank you,
Mr, Jurel,
It's so nice of you to
take into consideration
the trouble you cause
other people by your...
I thought you said you
were an airline pilot?
I am.
Didn't I just hear that lady say
something about teaching?
Yeah, well, I gotta go teach
a class on cabin pressure.
Oh.
You know, oxygen masks.
Things like that.
Do you want some coffee?
- Sure. You want some help?
- No. No.
Coffee's brown, right?
How do you like it?
Black or burned?
Look, I'm really running late here.
Maybe I'd better skip the coffee.
Yeah, that'd be my move.
Yeah.
- Call me sometime.
- Yeah. Sure.
Mr. Rubell, I have a list
of the teachers
- that I would like to meet with tomorrow.
- Must have the time down.
- It's important that we start... - Lee,
would you do this for me, pal, please.
None of you seems to take
this lawsuit very seriously.
And you, Ms. Hammond,
take things too seriously.
That was your problem when
you were a student here.
- And it's your problem now.
- And you were a rotten English teacher.
I know.
Do you know that kid's bleeding?
You should report that.
- Well? - Well, not to me.
I'm here to give a lecture.
How thrilling.
Auditorium across the hall.
You are always hogging
that machine.
Of course.
Every day. Day in and day out
you are on that machine.
I have been trying to use
that machine for three weeks,
and every time I try,
you're here.
Well, today is my day.
I want to use that machine.
I need that machine.
That machine needs me.
- I fail to see any reason for your...
- Oh, you fail to see?
You fail to see?
Can you see this?
You son of a bitch!
- Oh, my God.
- Today is my day! My day!
- Ms. Bloom, in control.
- My day.
- You control yourself. This is a school.
- My day. My day.
Grace, hold up.
- Ms. Bloom! Ms. Bloom!
- My day! My day!
Please control yourself.
This is a school. Ms. Bloom!
- Ms. Bloom, please, control yourself.
- Put her on the floor.
Ms. Bloom, stop it.
- Nurse!
- Come on, now. Nurse, help, help.
Ms. Bloom, calm down.
Who is that?
School psychologist.
Must apologize for the heat.
This hallway is the warmest part
of the whole building.
Most of the tenants just
leave their doors open,
so you can get the heat.
We're a real friendly building here,
you know.
Are you sure he's safe? I mean,
he isn't dangerous or anything, is he?
No. I assure you, there will be
no problems with Mr. Gower.
He's completely harmless.
He merely has a few problems
with reality, that's all.
Oh, this place would be just
marvelous for Herbert.
It's only four blocks
from the hospital.
Yeah, well,
the apartment's upstairs.
- Yes?
- Hello, Mr. Stuart Van Ark?
Yes.
Mr. Van Ark, this is Mrs. Wensel
from Kennedy High.
We want you to come in and substitute
one of our history classes,
It may be for several days,
Can you make it?
Yes.
She poured ink, ink,
all over Ditto.
Oh, God, I'd have given anything
to have been there to see that.
Can you just imagine his face?
I tell you, Alex, it's never dull
around here on Mondays.
- Oh, you ought to...
- Excuse me?
Could you tell me where
I might find room 127?
Yup. Just go back, go down the steps,
turn right and it's right around the corner.
- Thank you very much.
- Yeah.
Well, back to the trenches.
My God, it's a stampede.
Where are you going?
I thought you didn't like school!
Move it!
Now!
Hey, Timmy, if you're not running
for President, sit down.
All right, will you?
All right.
If you're not here, speak up.
All right, boys and girls!
Ladies and gentlemen.
Today we're gonna delve
into the fascinating world
of radiator repair.
Oh, we're supposed to be learning
about social studies, not radiators.
Learning is limitless, Tim.
Hold it down, please.
Hold it down.
Paller?
- Paller?
- Here!
Look, just raise your hand.
That's all I need.
Please, can you keep it down?
Please!
Frame? Please. Not those pants.
Not again. All right.
Hold it down. Please, please.
Hold it down.
Henson? Henson?
How are you, Henson?
- Pretty good.
- Good to see you.
- Alvado?
- Alvedo!
What?
Yesterday you said
it was Alvado.
No, I didn't, Mr. Rosenberg.
Yes, you did. And the day
before it was Alverus.
No, I didn't!
You're trying to get me
into trouble, man.
What's so funny?
I don't find anything funny.
Aren't you going to
take attendance?
Attendance?
Oh, yes.
Sarah, I asked for a wrench,
not a screwdriver.
Oh, I don't know.
- Which is it?
- It's by your right hand.
Your other right hand.
Thank you.
No calculators, Ms. Mason.
A "B" becomes a "C,"
remember, with a calculator.
What is this, summer camp?
Please, please.
Everybody has their own paper.
Come on, Danny, you forgot
to carry over...
All right, everybody.
Stay put.
Please!
Please let me go!
Somebody, please!
Somebody!
Alex!
Get him off me!
He's crazy. He's crazy!
Dues are not being
paid here, people.
Let's try and bring those
delinquent ones up to date,
or we're gonna have
to take action.
A union cannot be run on
just good intentions alone.
We need cold hard cash.
I want you to know that as your
union rep, I'm on top of this.
They want us here at 7:35.
We're gonna hold fir
until we get 7:38.
Now, these are our three minutes
and we will get it.
And if we were a
private school
then we wouldn't have to depend
on a bond issue for our salary.
How do you spell tardiness?
L - a - t - e.
Now, about this
court-case thing.
Well, all I know is that now they're
gonna take depositions here.
So, we have to change
our strategy on that point.
What strategy?
Remember,
whatever they don't find out
can't hurt us.
- Did anybody really vote
for this guy? - I know.
Alex, please,
I wanna hear this.
I don't care what anybody
else says about this,
we're gonna stick together
with the union.
I get the feeling I
interrupted something.
Just Malloy,
addressing the Reichstag.
Oh, say, Alex. Remember this student
you once had about 10 or 12 years ago?
- Her name is Lisa Hammond.
- Lisa Hammond?
Oh, yeah. Bright kid.
Great ass.
Yes.
Well, nothing's changed.
Really?
She's here?
Yeah.
But get this, she's working for the law
firm that's handling the Calvin case.
She's taking depositions here.
Starting tomorrow.
In fact, she's taking your deposition
in two and a half weeks.
I knew we should
have flunked her.
You know what
you're gonna say?
You're not gonna betray old JFK,
are you?
Oh, come on, for Christ's sake, Roger.
That'd be like shitting on the Peace Corps.
You haven't lived till you see them
try to serve me with a subpoena.
- Oh, here.
- What's this?
Well, I tell you, Alex. You heard about
Ditto and Theresa Bloom, right?
- Yeah, which version?
- Yeah.
With our psychologist on temporary
leave and no money to replace her,
I gotta have somebody to take over
the counseling chores.
Me? Why me?
- Because you're sensitive.
- Oh, that's bullshit.
- You're compassionate.
- Bullshit, Roger.
- You're caring.
- Bullshit.
You've got a free period.
Well, so does everybody
else in here.
And the teachers in
the next period
are gonna have a free period too,
for Christ's sake.
And they'll be drafted too.
Alex, we have a lot of misunderstood
youth in this place.
Now, everybody's got to pitch in.
Starting with you.
- How many kids is this?
- One.
- One?
- Name's Eddie Pilikian.
He and his parents
are gonna be
at the counseling office
in about 10 minutes.
- All right.
- Now, I know you'll do well.
- One kid?
- Yeah.
All right.
Sit. Right there.
Right there.
Oh, Mr. Rubell!
Superintendent Burke is in the
conference room with Principal Horn.
Great.
I mean, just what the hell
are you guys running here,
a goddamn zoo?
I'm in the middle of a
fund-raising breakfast
and I'm informed that
your school psychologist
has flipped out in the middle
of your goddamn office.
And then I get here and I find
out there has been a stabbing.
And if that's not enough,
one of your kids
tries to eat one of your
goddamn teachers.
Mr. Rubell, what the
hell do you call that?
Monday.
Look, Dr. Burke, whatever happens here,
I'm taking care of it.
Are you also taking care
of the lawsuit here, too?
You do know we're
being sued, don't you?
- Yes, I do.
- Oh, you do? Good for you!
- Dr. Burke, I don't think you really...
- I know. I know.
I...
I understand your problem, all right?
But you sure as hell
better understand mine!
I am fighting for our
survival out there.
We cannot let the things that happened
here today circulate around the city.
We have got to
control the publicity.
Or else this community
is gonna lose faith in us
and we won't get the new
bond issue passed
and that means no money.
No money means no school.
Do I make myself clear?
Absolutely.
All right, I've asked Alan Lewis,
our attorney, to be here
to help us on this matter.
First of all, I wanna know who
is on our team,
and I wanna know who is
going to rock the boat.
And most importantly,
we all have to agree on what's to
be said at these depositions.
Well, very well.
What would you like me to do?
Well, I have taken the liberty
of having your secretary pull the file
of the remaining teachers involved.
I would like to go over them.
All right. The first one
is Kenneth Stiles.
No. Stiles has no problem.
School line all the way.
Then of course there's Principal
Horn and myself.
Yes, of course. What's that one?
Alex Jurel, social studies.
Yeah, Alex.
I don't see any problem there.
Oh, really?
"1969, started free school.
"Strong advocate of students' rights.
"Reading program canceled in 1974
due to lack of funds.
"Excellent leadership qualities. "
This sounds like trouble to me.
No. No, that was
over 10 years ago.
Alex and I did all those things
when we started. Now look at me.
No, Alex is all right now.
Why, hell, if they hold a deposition on
a Monday, he might not even show up.
Mr. and Mrs. Pilikian.
Alex Jurel.
No, I'm Jeffrey Propes,
Mrs. Pilikian's attorney.
Oh, really?
Oh, what did he do this time?
No, I'm here in regards to
Mrs. Pilikian's recent divorce.
Oh, okay. I see.
Eddie, would you wait outside.
Mr. Jurel, Mrs. Pilikian has just
been through a very trying...
Excuse me, one minute.
Well, as you can see here
in regards to custody,
Mrs. Pilikian enjoys full rights...
Mr. Pilikian will of course
be allowed to see Eddie
under certain conditions and
with Mrs. Pilikian's approval.
Excuse me, one minute.
Why are you telling me this?
Because we want
to make it clear
that Eddie's father is not to
see him during school hours
nor is he to attempt to pick
Eddie up from school.
Mrs. Pilikian, I'm sorry you have problems,
but we're here to talk about Eddie.
He's been kicked out
of his third class.
He reads at a sixth-grade level
and he's majoring in detention.
Now, don't you think that's just
a little bit more important?
It's very important to Mrs. Pilikian
that we first settle this custody problem.
Now, she hasn't been able to function
in full capacity since the divorce.
I think we've
said our piece.
Mrs. Pilikian, don't you care
about your son's education?
Isn't that your job, Mr. Jurel?
Eddie.
Come on in here.
Eddie, in.
Sit down.
- Read that.
- Do what?
Just open it up anyplace
and just start reading.
Out loud.
- I don't like this magazine.
- What kind of magazine do you like?
Come on, just lay off.
I don't need this.
What you need, Eddie, is another
remedial reading class again.
You're not fooling anybody.
Hey, I passed that class.
You can't make me take it again.
I read fine. So don't you worry
about it, okay? Just lay off.
All right.
But you just got kicked out
of your social studies class.
So, I'll give you a choice,
you can take my class or
you can take study hall.
I'll take a study hall.
Yeah, my class. Third period.
I'll see you there tomorrow.
That's all.
Now, don't blow on me.
I can make it.
No, I can't.
Are we here?
- We're here.
- See, I told you I could make it.
What do you want?
Hey!
What was that?
What do you want?
I'll have a Grasshopper.
- No, make it a Pink Lady.
- All right.
And put in it some fruit
and Tabasco sauce.
And some of those
little sesame seeds.
Oh and don't forget
the umbrella.
Hold the umbrella,
open it up and put in the drink.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Too much vermouth.
I sense tension here.
What's the matter, Alex?
Oh, it's getting to me, Rog.
It's supposed to,
that's why it costs so much.
No, not the booze.
The school.
The bullshit.
Of course, the bullshit.
Hey, I know.
Let's go be...
Let's be cowboys.
- Yeah, yeah. Cowboys!
- Yeah...
- Oh, no, no, no.
- What?
- I'm afraid of horses.
- You pussy.
I'm afraid of them too.
I'm just getting tired
of the whole damn thing.
Like that Pilikian thing.
You knew that lawyer was gonna be
with that mother, you knew that.
Oh, come on. Is that what's
been bothering you?
Pilikian? Oh, forget about Pilikian.
Pilikian is a lost cause.
Oh, yeah.
It's getting too easy to forget.
There's too many Pilikians
in that school.
Hey, hey, we do good.
Lots of them learn.
Lots of those kids learn.
They learn good.
We are not the bad guys.
We do good with what we've got.
- What we got sucks.
- You know it.
So, what are you gonna do?
Quit.
Just quit.
Hey, now listen to me.
You've been a teacher for 14 years.
- Fifteen.
- That's what I said.
- Oh. - And you're a
fucking great teacher.
- Was! I was a fucking great teacher.
- No, no, no. Listen to me.
Without us, there's nothing.
Nothing.
We're the last stand
of civilization.
If we fail, anarchy.
"Anarchy. "
- Or worse...
- "Worse. "
- A baby boom.
- "A baby boom. "
What do you think those little monsters
would be doing if they weren't in school?
I don't know.
- Fucking, fucking like fucking
little rabbits. - Fucking?
We've got to stop them.
- You mean, I'm a contraceptive?
- Yes, and one of the best.
I'm an old fucking rubber.
I'm going to bed.
You wanna stay over?
No, no, no. I can drive.
- Fasten your seat belt.
- Absolutely.
Mr. Jurel!
Mr. Jurel,
I would like a word with you.
Well, make it a quiet one, Gracie.
I've had a hard day.
School hasn't even started yet.
All right, what do you want?
You cannot put Eddie Pilikian,
a lower-level student,
into your third-period social-studies class,
an upper-level class.
Sure, I can, Gracie.
I've got tenure.
It's not school policy
and if you would read the curriculum
circulars you would know that.
But then you never read the
curriculum circulars, do you?
Mr. Jurel, at least have the decency
to fill out the proper paperwork.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
Alex, you seen this yet?
Looks great. I've been meaning
to get one of those myself, Carl.
Mr. Jurel!
Shit!
Hi.
Lisa Hammond.
Okay.
Holy shit, lady.
God damn it.
- Mr. Jurel.
- Lisa, are you nuts?
This is the boys' bathroom.
Yeah, I know. Well, I've always
wondered what one looked like.
- No big deal.
- I'm taking a leak.
I wanted to talk to you.
Well, call me on the phone,
for Christ's sake.
This is the boys' bathroom.
Oh, come on, Mr. Jurel,
I have two brothers, for crying out loud.
Well, I don't.
Do you mind?
- Here, dry your hands.
- Thank you.
Oh, fuck!
Hi.
That was cute, real cute.
It really is good to
see you, Mr. Jurel.
Considering how much you've seen,
why don't you call me Alex?
God, the room seems
so different.
I guess nothing's the
way you remember it.
You're mad, aren't you?
You really take your job seriously,
don't you?
That's what you taught me.
- So, what do you think?
- About what?
- The Calvin case.
- I try to stay out of political things.
I have a hard enough
time just teaching.
"Political"?
Alex, this case is about teaching.
It could mean a great deal to education.
I mean, a boy goes all the way
through a school system
and gets passing grades and a diploma
and still can't read or write.
This boy was one of your students and
he can't even fill out a job application.
Don't you think there's
something wrong with that?
You were one of my students
and you can fill out
a whole subpoena.
You know,
I had a terrible crush on you.
Who didn't?
Listen, I'm really sorry about what I did.
Let me make it up to you.
Let me buy you dinner.
- Dinner?
- Yeah.
What do you say?
Talk about old times and all that.
Okay.
Where?
How about my place, 7:30?
- Does your bathroom
have a lock? - Two.
Good.
Okay.
See you tonight.
Love the shirt.
Great ass.
Hold it.
Let me see your pass.
- Okay.
- Thanks.
- You wanted to see me, Mr. Troy?
- Yeah, come on in.
Present here are Lisa Hammond,
counsel for the plaintiff,
Alan Lewis, counsel
for the defendant
and Eugene Horn, principal of
John F. Kennedy High School.
Have you ever given a
deposition before, Mr. Horn?
No.
Well, it's very simple. I'm just
going to ask you some questions
and you're under oath, so I'd like for you
to answer them as fully as you can.
- Okay.
- Good.
Did you have a student here
at JFK named John Calvin?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
Ms. Hammond, there are 2300
students here at Kennedy every year.
I don't know all of them.
- Wouldn't your records
show enrollment? - Yes.
Okay,
where are your records?
I don't know.
Fuck you!
Move it! Coming through!
Move it! Move it!
Move it!
Look out.
What the hell is going on here?
No problem. There's no problem.
He just slipped, okay? He's fine.
- I'm fine. Fine.
- He's fine. No problem.
- Hey, you okay? All right.
- I'm fine.
- Come on, let's go.
Fucking Paller.
- Fucking Paller.
- Oh, excuse me.
I didn't do shit to him.
- Eddie, you got to get me a piece.
- A piece of what?
That's very funny, Eddie.
Very funny.
Next time I see that asshole I want
to have something on my side.
No, forget it, okay?
You let me handle Paller, all right?
Okay.
- Thanks, Eddie. Thanks.
- Forget it. Forget it, will you?
Okay. Thanks.
Okay, I'm taking off.
You want to come?
Sure, yeah.
Sure.
- Hey, wait...
- Shit!
What're we gonna do now?
Hey, trust me.
Come here.
- Come on, will you.
- Okay. All right.
Can you believe this shit?
If John Calvin was a student here at JFK,
would his name appear on these records?
Yes, it should.
Good. Now, who's in
charge of the records?
I don't know.
Nice touch.
What touch?
I really don't know.
That's the fire alarm.
Move it out, quickly.
To the right! To the right!
Hey! Hey, you two! Come here.
I want to talk to you. Hey!
You're in big trouble.
- Get in. Come on!
- No.
We can't do this, Eddie.
Haven't I taken care of things
since third grade?
Have we got balls or what?
This is fucking great.
Give me five.
So, that's how I passed
the bar exam.
So, whatever happened to Mrs. Jurel?
I wanted to be a teacher
and she wanted something more
than my teacher salary could provide.
Food, clothing, shelter.
So there hasn't been
anybody else?
No, not really.
What about you?
Oh, hundreds.
I'm a lawyer after all.
So, you haven't told
me what you think.
Oh, the meal was great.
No, I'm not talking
about the dinner.
I know the dinner was great.
I got an "A" in home ec.
- I'm talking about the case.
- What case?
Oh, that's how we're
gonna play it?
I'm serious. I really want
to know what you think.
Why is it so important what
I think about your case?
Because the other teachers
will follow what you do.
You're one of the leaders
of that school.
Boy, Lisa, you've been
gone a long time.
Yeah, I guess I have,
because JFK is nothing
like I remember it.
- Maybe you have a selective memory.
- Oh, come on.
In the two days that I've been
there I've seen a stabbing,
a teacher attack another teacher,
a student bite a teacher,
a fire alarm that looked
like Hiroshima.
It's not a school anymore,
it's a loony bin.
- Oh, Lord, here comes another subpoena.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- What?
- That crack.
What's the matter? You afraid I might
do more for education than you?
Education? Are you nuts?
Lisa, your lawsuit isn't
about education.
It's about money.
Nobody really cares if
that kid didn't learn.
They just wanna make
some major bucks.
Oh, great.
Just what we need.
Words of wisdom from a guy
who hides out in bathrooms.
You know, Lisa, there's nothing worse
than a female lawyer with a cause.
Except a male teacher
without one.
Is it so hard for you to admit
that something's wrong there?
Oh, hell, Lisa.
Come on!
Do you think you're telling
me something here?
I've been there day in and
day out for 15 years.
Don't even think you can try.
Listen.
I counseled a kid named Eddie Pilikian
the other day and it was a waste of time.
I can't reach this kid.
The parents and the system,
they've so fucked up this kid
that I don't know.
I don't think I'm ever gonna
be able to reach him.
Yes, you will.
You'll reach him.
You'll make a difference.
You did with me.
Look, it's not right for a lawyer
to be discussing a case
with someone she's gonna be
deposing in two weeks, is it?
No. But I didn't ask you
here as an attorney.
Why did you?
I think I better
check the dessert.
What do you mean, what am
I gonna say at my deposition?
I'm gonna say the same
as everyone else.
Oh, Carl, just forget it.
Easy for you to say.
You forget it!
I'm telling you that Reese
kid has gotta go!
He's trying to drive
me crazy.
First he attacks me,
now he's trying to drive me nuts.
- I want him out!
- Will you calm down?
Yeah, Alex,
I had Eddie Pilikian.
The kid had about
a sixth-grade reading level.
He couldn't do the work.
I didn't know what
to do with him.
How about teaching
him to read better?
Mr. Van Ark,
I am a social studies teacher.
It is not my job to
teach reading.
But you are a teacher.
Some people should have more
experience before they speak.
So, what are you gonna say
at your deposition, Ray?
What is this?
An inquisition?
- Carl, be reasonable.
- "Reasonable"?
Now, what do you want
me to do with him?
- I told you!
- I cannot expel him!
Why not?
Because the courts will not allow us
to violate that poor child's rights.
What about my rights?
And a juvenile hall will just
send him right back here.
Nobody would want us to let
that kid loose on society.
Then put him in his class.
Oh, it's fine with me.
- I'll handle him.
- You'd bore him to death.
What's that supposed
to mean?
What do you think
it means, Ditto?
Your class is boring.
Your students don't learn a thing.
If it weren't for tenure,
you'd be selling vacuum cleaners.
Have I left anything out?
I don't have to take
that from you.
I have received three consecutive teaching
awards for the most orderly class.
Three consecutive
teaching awards
for the most orderly class.
And what do you think
about that, mister?
Gee, Ditto,
your shit don't stink.
And how was your date last night
with Ms. Hammond, Alex?
Reese, where the
hell is my desk?
Reese,
where the hell is my desk?
Reese!
All right.
Let's talk about the responsibility
a school has to its community.
Aren't we going over
our homework questions?
We'll do that later.
Let's talk about this first.
Does a school have a responsibility
to its community?
Babysitter.
All right, babysitter.
That's right. Yeah.
Anything else?
You were supposed to
be here yesterday.
Mrs. Wensel says I ain't even
supposed to be in this class.
Yo, me neither.
No one knows where you're
supposed to be at, Terry.
It's all right. I'll take care of it.
Take a seat.
So, what other responsibilities
does a school have to its community?
Where did you leave off?
Pickett's Charge.
"Four score and
seven years ago,
"our fathers brought forth
on this continent
"a new nation,
"conceived in liberty
"and dedicated to
the proposition
"that all men are created equal. "
All right, all right.
Forget community.
Let's just talk about you.
Let's talk about us.
You in school,
what does school do for you?
- Nothing!
- Nothing?
It gives you a diploma
so you can get a job.
Then it does something.
School is just a place where
teachers make money.
Yeah, sure.
I got a yacht in the Caribbean.
All right?
Lot of money.
- Does school round out
your knowledge? - No.
Why?
They teach you all this junk
like who was Hiawatha.
I don't care who she was.
They never teach you what
you want to know, right?
Hiawatha was a man, Tim.
You see what I mean?
Who cares?
I think we know what's better for us
more than the teachers do, you know.
- Right.
Tell them about it, Diane.
I think school does
a good job.
Oh, shit.
It makes us better people
if we learn this.
Mr. Pilikian, was that
just a large breakfast?
Or do you disagree
with this man?
Well?
Come on.
This place is a joke.
What do you mean,
it's a joke?
You're being sued by some kid
'cause you didn't teach him nothing.
What're you gonna say when
they ask you about that?
All right. Fine.
Mr. Pilikian has just given us
another assignment.
Say what?
Oh, man!
No, wait a minute.
You tell me. Tell me what's
wrong with this school.
You tell me what I should say.
So, what? We gotta write
another paper now?
No, you don't gotta
write another paper.
Just communicate your ideas.
I don't care how you do it.
You can write a paper if want or take
a photograph. Do it any way you want.
Sing a song.
Communicate.
Hold it.
How do we know if we do this
we're not gonna get in trouble?
You don't.
But I'll guarantee it.
No getting us for
what we say?
No reprisals.
Yeah, no reprisals.
All right.
One more, one more.
All right, you ready?
Okay. Great going.
Okay. And...
Boring!
Boring.
Teacher's lounge.
That's the girls' bathroom.
Eddie.
- All right.
- Eddie.
Way to go, Eddie.
No reprisals, right?
- Mrs. Wensel?
- Yes.
Dan Hall, Independent
Insurance Company.
I'm here about the accident
involving the driver's ed car.
- Sounds good.
- Oh.
We seem to have
misplaced it.
What?
How can you misplace a one-ton
piece of equipment?
Are you kidding?
At this place?
What's up?
This.
- Not too bad.
- Not too bad?
The kid rips off a camera
and takes these pictures
and all you can say is,
"Not too bad. "
The morning paper is
running these tomorrow.
I've been on the phone
with Dr. Burke all morning.
- Do you want to know
how mad she is? - No.
He claims you okayed this.
Did you?
Yes.
You can go.
Where the hell are
your brains?
You know how much embarrassment
this is gonna cause us?
Oh, come on, Roger.
It's not like that kid was chewing
bubble gum or something.
Look, this is the first time
I've gotten to this kid.
Maybe I can make him
give a shit about himself.
That's a hell of a lot more important
than a silly thing like this!
That's not your job!
So don't pull some of that
Mr. Chips crap with me!
Your job is to get them through this
school and keep them out of trouble.
That's it!
Well, maybe I should
reexamine my job.
Maybe you should!
I don't know what's
happening to you, Alex.
But if you got a personal problem,
you work it out at home, not here.
This goes on your
permanent record.
Does that mean I have to
stay after school, too?
Did you forget to tell
me about the paper?
Okay, Pilikian.
You miss my class one more time
I'll let them have your butt.
Deal?
It's a deal.
So, this is your idea
of a gourmet dinner, eh?
Well, you haven't lived until
you taste one of my tacos.
One taste and you're gonna agree,
I should've taught home ec
instead of Mrs. Badie.
Move your buns.
Wasn't Mrs. Badie...
Cut.
Wasn't Mrs. Badie having
an affair with Ditto?
Why, does that turn you on?
Compared to what?
To this.
Sure beats the
hell out of Ditto.
I had my...
My little talk with Ditto today.
Guy's still a jerk.
Why? Did he fall asleep while
you were asking questions?
We both fell asleep
during his answers.
It's really ticking me off.
I mean, I just don't understand.
I...
- Are you listening to me?
- No.
Cut.
I mean, I can understand Horn
and Rubell ducking my questions,
but I'm trying to
help the teachers
and all I'm getting is a lot of
"I don't knows" and "I can't remember. "
Wish I knew what
the hell was going on.
Lisa, are you gonna talk about this
all night, because I'm getting turned on.
You just don't understand
the frustration, Alex.
You wanna bet?
You don't get out much,
do you?
Lisa, can't you for one night just forget
about the case, the school and everything?
For one night?
All right.
I'm sorry.
You're right.
We'll...
We'll just have a nice dinner and
relax and I won't say another word.
Great.
It's just, I can't understand
the teachers.
I mean, I'm trying to change
an inept system
and that can
only help them.
Lisa, who do you think
makes up this system?
The people do.
And they don't wanna be
scapegoats for that system.
- I'm not on a witch hunt.
- Yes, you are.
What is that supposed
to mean?
Everybody wants
to change it.
They all have ideas, but nobody
wants to pay the price.
Now, you're asking some teachers
to stick their necks out
and they know they're
gonna get chopped.
You'll end up closing the school,
not changing it.
You're not gonna tell
the truth, are you?
It won't change anything.
Oh, Lisa, look.
I remember a lot from your class,
Mr. Jurel.
About how you were supposed to
fight for what you believed in
no matter what it cost.
Was that all a lie?
Were you just having fun
with a bunch of kids?
What about Eddie Pilikian?
Doesn't he mean anything
or was that just self pity?
I needed you, Alex.
I was counting on you.
And what about you, Lisa?
I haven't seen you
since I don't know when.
All of a sudden we're going
out and having dinner.
Is that part of this fight?
- Is that what you think?
- What're you getting out of this?
Your name in the paper?
Just by being here I am
eopardizing my career,
but I couldn't stay away.
And now I can't even
remember why.
I don't know how to
make you believe me.
I don't know if I even really care,
but I'll tell you this.
I'm gonna ask
the questions
and you're gonna have to
give me the answers.
I know what's going
on in that school
and I'm gonna change it
with or without you.
What the hell do you know, Lisa?
You're not a teacher,
you're a lawyer.
You can't see what's
going on in there.
You and those others, you come in the
school and you waltz down those hallways
and you think you can tell us
what's happening there?
Well, that's bullshit!
You can't see what's
happening there
because you're hiding behind
your memories and your ideals.
You use them like shields.
When you can drop
your shields
and walk down those halls naked
and really see what's happening
then talk to me and
I'll believe you.
Bye.
Hey!
Not bad.
Where did you
get this car?
What do you think?
A little paint, a little glue.
Where did you
get this car?
- Where did you get it?
- It's Rosenberg's.
What, are you fucking crazy?
What...
What's your problem?
You, you stupid asshole,
you don't go ripping a teacher's car.
What, you want to go
back to juvie again?
- Get the hell off of me!
- No, you can't do this.
You're gonna get caught.
Now, just take it back.
No way. I took this. It's mine.
No, no. Take it back.
Get rid of it, all right?
- Oh, I see. I see.
- Get rid of it.
Only the great Pilikian can steal a car,
anybody else does it, they're stupid.
- I'm not stupid!
- No, no, Danny, you don't understand.
Rosenberg is gonna have
the cops all over the place.
Just take it back,
all right?
No! Fuck you! You're so worried about it,
you fucking take it back.
Fuck you!
Oh, shit!
- Why do we have to read this book?
- Because I said to.
It's a good book. I just reread
it myself last summer.
You read in the summer?
What is the name of this river?
Potomac!
The Delaware!
Delaware!
Row!
What we're talking about here, literally,
is the future of the school.
They're gonna try to prove that John
Calvin was knowingly promoted
when in fact he
should've failed.
Now as two of
his teachers
you're going to be asked
questions pertaining to that.
Mr. Rosenberg,
your deposition is tomorrow.
Mr. Jurel, yours is in four days.
Carl, give it a rest, will you?
Now, I feel confident
that we have effectively stalled
their access to the school records.
However...
it would be most beneficial if neither
of you had any personal records.
Don't you wanna
know if it's true?
Beg your pardon?
I said, "Don't you wanna
know if it's true?"
Isn't that the best
place to start?
Not necessarily.
Alex, just stick to the discussion,
please.
- Well, I am.
- No, no, no.
I don't think the question here
is whether or not we're guilty.
No.
Innocence is irrelevant.
Oh, you mean we're guilty?
Let's not say that, okay?
Even if you're kidding.
Let's just agree
not to say that.
Oh, I see. I see.
Guilt isn't irrelevant.
I asked you not
to say that.
Look, Mr. Jurel,
all we're trying to do here is to help
you better prepare your answers.
We're not conducting some
great search for the truth.
Oh.
Yes, now, let's stick to the discussion.
Carl, quit pacing, will you?
I'll pace if I want to, damn it!
God!
This place is unbelievable.
- I want my car back!
- What is he talking about?
Now, calm down.
Just calm down, Carl.
Calm down? Calm down?
That's what you said when I got bit.
That's what you said
when they stole my desk.
I got a big flash for you, Roger.
It didn't work then and it won't work now.
Calm, Carl.
And you people
are beautiful.
All of you just sitting here,
telling us how to lie.
- Don't say that!
- Come on, come on!
That's what all of you people
are doing, aren't you?
- Telling us how to lie!
- Mr. Rubell.
I will not tolerate this
breakdown of teamwork.
Teamwork?
Teamwork, my ass!
I'll tell you what you can do
with your teamwork!
- Carl... Carl.
- Mr. Rubell...
- I got a lot to say. A lot to say!
- Don't say that!
You will sit down and you
will do what you are told
and that is all there is to it.
I will not sit down!
I'm not a child!
You can't talk...
I'm not in kindergarten!
- Mr. Rubell!
- What?
I'm sorry, Grace,
what is it?
There is something
wrong with Mr. Stiles.
Who?
Ditto.
Move out now!
Let's go!
Move out!
Let them through!
- Come on, let's go.
- Let them through.
Come on!
Move, move, move!
- What the hell is this place?
- He's inside.
Down this way.
Let him through, now.
Let him through,
let him through.
- This guy's dead.
- Really?
How can you tell?
Hi, Eddie.
Hey, Diane, what's up?
I need some help.
Do your parents know?
You can't tell them,
Mr. Jurel, please.
Eddie told me I could
trust you, you know.
Look, Diane...
- They should be told.
- No, Mr. Jurel.
My God, they'd kill me.
My father would throw me out.
My whole life would be over.
Please.
Which teacher is the father?
No, never mind.
I don't wanna know that.
What do you want to do?
Get an abortion.
Well, there are other options.
You could...
You could have the baby
and put it up for adoption.
Will you take me, Mr. Jurel?
I can't.
Please.
I'll take you.
Are you sure you're okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Listen,
can I bum a cigarette?
- Diane, look, I don't think...
- Mr. Jurel,
I just had an abortion.
I think I'm old enough to smoke.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Diane,
you gotta try to
forget about it.
You know what
really gets to me?
What really gets
to me is that
it just doesn't bother me,
you know?
It doesn't bother me.
Why?
So?
You gotta be kidding me.
You know how many people
have been looking for this car?
You took it?
Hey, I never said that.
I'm just showing
you something.
- Why? - Well, I figure this
makes us even now.
What?
Well, you did something for me,
I'm doing something for you. We're even.
That's important to you?
I don't owe people nothin'.
Hey, Eddie,
how about keeping the car
and taking the reading class?
Hey, we're even, man.
Oh, come on, Eddie,
knock off the dumb-talk crap.
You wanna act stupid in class,
that's fine by me, if that's your act.
But we both know
you're not stupid.
So give me a break.
You're getting a chance here, Eddie,
take it.
Sure beats the hell
out of stealing cars.
Take the class.
Who you doing this for, me or you,
all this?
Does it matter?
All right, I'll take the class.
You can keep the car.
Well, what the hell am I supposed
to do with it?
Just drive it up to
the principal's office?
You're a teacher, man,
you'll think of something.
Smart.
You okay, Carl?
Fine, fine,
don't worry about me.
Okay, Mr. Rosenberg,
you just follow my lead today.
- I think everything will be...
- I know. I know. I know.
You've gone over it a million times.
I know it by heart.
I'll be okay. Don't worry about it.
I'll do the right thing. I will.
- Okay, good man.
- Okay. Let's do it.
Was John Calvin a
student of yours?
Absolutely.
Did John Calvin pass the
required course in your class?
I don't think Mr. Rosenberg could
answer that question as put.
It's rather vague.
Okay, did John Calvin receive
a passing grade in your class?
Yes.
Did he deserve it?
I don't think Mr. Rosenberg
can answer that question
until he fully understands
what the question means.
Did John Calvin complete
the work required
to enable him to receive a
passing grade in your class?
- Once again...
- Oh, shut the hell up!
Just shut the hell up!
John Calvin didn't deserve
any grade in my class,
because he rarely, if ever,
bothered to show up.
I had nothing to
base my grade on.
Then why did
you pass him?
Because it's policy.
I'm sure we can clear
this whole thing up.
- It's like he's retarded.
- Yes, I know.
I demand to know why
you are flunking my son.
What?
How can you flunk him when
he's already passed the class?
Wait a minute, Mrs. Pilikian,
now, I'm not flunking your son.
The problem here is your getting Eddie
to take over the reading class
that he's already taken.
He's already passed.
- Who's Jurel?
- I am.
He's not supposed to be here. You know that.
I told you I can handle this.
- He's my son, too.
- Wait a minute.
- What's going on here?
- Are you trying to flunk my boy?
Mr. Rubell said that he doesn't have
to take the reading class again.
Well, wait a minute, if he doesn't have
to take the course again, why...
You're not supposed to be here.
He is not supposed to be here.
- He needs that class.
- I asked you a question, Jurel.
Alex, he's already
passed the class.
- Look, I've got a...
- Will you just shut up.
Hey, why don't you all just
shut up for a minute, all right?
You don't talk to me like that.
Fuck off.
- Come on, come on, come on.
- He's my kid, Jurel, I'll handle him.
You're doing a hell
of a job, pal.
If you screw around with
my kid again, I'll be back.
That's not gonna solve anything.
Now, please.
Let go.
Mr. Pilikian, please.
Please.
What are we gonna do?
You heard him. Drop it.
- He can't read.
- He can read enough.
Enough? What the hell's
that supposed to mean?
God damn it, Alex, what the hell
do you want me to do?
I am not wasting what little time
and money I've got on one kid.
For every Eddie Pilikian, there are 50,
100 kids who learn here and learn well.
Now, we're not here to
worry about one kid.
We're here to get as many of these kids
through the system with what we've got.
Now, that's reality,
and you know it.
- You can't see it, Roger, can you?
- See what?
This is the same thing
we're being sued about.
Don't talk to me about being sued, Alex.
I don't wanna hear that.
This is the reason Lisa Hammond's
down the hall taking depositions.
- We're not teaching these kids.
- I can't hear you, Alex.
- I can't hear you.
- We're doing it again!
- I can't hear you!
- One second.
- Violators...
All these names, numbers don't match up.
They're not even close.
But I wasn't the
only one there.
Superintendent Burke, please.
Anything wrong?
Rosenberg fucked us.
What?
He told everything.
How could you let
that happen?
There wasn't anything I could do
about it, Roger.
Oh, God damn it!
You can't even
control Rosenberg?
You know,
this puts it in your boy's lap.
If Jurel confirms this
in his deposition,
we're sunk.
Donna, hold on.
Donna, this is Roger.
We've gotta dump Jurel.
Hey, Mr. Jurel,
aren't we gonna do nothin'?
How could you
be so stupid?
Would you tell me how you
could be so goddamn stupid?
As if we don't have
enough problems.
We're in the middle
of a lawsuit, buddy.
- Three girls.
- Oh, hey.
Three of our own students.
Why don't you go to some other school
and get their girls pregnant?
Do you know what this is
gonna do to this school?
Do you know how
it's gonna look?
Teamwork, Troy,
does not mean going out
and starting your
own team.
- What?
- Mr. Rubell?
What?
What is this?
It's a search warrant for lockers
50 through 400, inclusive.
Oh, no, you gotta be
kidding me. When?
Right now.
Did you know your
cop is flunking?
I'm trying to talk to them,
but they won't take it seriously.
That's why it's very important
that everyone be
at that meeting.
Oh, my God.
- Something wrong?
- What?
No, no, no, nothing's wrong.
There's cops out there
searching lockers again.
Get back there.
Fuck you!
330, whose is this?
It's his.
You wanna explain this?
Busted!
Hey, you,
get away from the locker.
Get away from the locker.
Hold it.
Hey, you.
Gun!
Drop the gun.
Drop the gun!
No!
Drop it!
So, why did you
divide your force?
Why? To prevent escape.
That the Indians would escape
was my greatest fear.
Excuse me, is your name
Herbert Gower?
Yes!
Okay.
You mean,
you're not Stuart Van Ark?
Certainly not.
You're an outpatient at
Riverdale Mental Hospital?
At times.
Get him out of here.
- Oh, no.
- Hey, you can't take him.
Sit down!
Don't you know who I am?
Sure, you're General Custer.
I am a teacher,
and you will treat
me as such.
Mr. Jurel.
Mr. Van Ark.
Gower.
Mr. Gower.
Where you been?
Just around.
You okay?
So, you gonna come back?
Not to this place. No way.
Then what are you
doing here, Eddie?
I heard about Danny.
Why'd they kill him?
He wouldn't have used the gun.
Nobody knew that, Eddie.
Yeah, well, I did.
I knew Danny, man.
He was just scared.
He was always scared here.
He wouldn't have
used the gun.
He just wanted to make sure
nobody got to him, that's all.
It's not your fault.
No, it is my fault,
'cause I should have been here.
He was my friend.
I know that.
But he's dead.
I'm sorry about it.
But, Eddie, he's dead,
you're not.
Now, you still got a chance.
You got a chance, the one he didn't have.
Now, don't lose it.
There's still time.
What, time for what?
We both have a lot to do.
I'm gonna do my part.
Do yours.
Come back.
You gonna stay,
or you gonna go?
You wanted to see me,
Mr. Sloan?
Yeah, I thought you might
want to know that
we've reached a
settlement with JFK.
The school district has agreed
to pay the Calvins $150,000
with a non-admission of guilt.
Well, what's the matter, Hammond?
You look like I just shot your dog.
You can't be serious.
This isn't just a routine
contract negotiation,
this is a school.
We have the chance
to do what's right.
You know the only thing that's right
is what the client wants.
They want to settle,
we settle.
We're a business. Like anybody else,
we make a profit,
hopefully more than most.
So, we just check the profit and
loss column to see what's right?
Don't get involved, settle the case,
collect our check
because we're just a business?
Well, what do we tell all those children
who have to attend that school
and others like them
that aren't gonna learn?
Sorry kids,
maybe next time.
We lose if we
settle this case,
because we're helping to turn out
a whole generation of illiterates.
We're not talking about business here,
damn it. We're talking about the future.
We're talking about reality, Hammond,
and sometimes it's a pain in the ass.
Leave what's right to God
and the Supreme Court.
That's what they
get paid for.
Good night, Hammond.
No, no, no, wait a minute, now,
listen to me, really, really.
This kid has beaten up everybody
in the neighborhood,
and I wanted him bad.
All right!
So, Mr. Jurel, what's going on?
You getting married or something?
Ms. Warren,
one does not require a special
occasion to show a little style,
a little class in one's
personal appearance.
Oh, of course, excuse me.
Besides, today's my deposition.
Yeah, and she's good-looking.
I don't know the names,
but if you do see him,
have him go directly
to the gym. Okay?
Mr. Rubell.
- All waiting down in the gym.
- All right, good.
Grace, would you find Principal
Horn and have him join us?
Okay, Malloy,
you've got your deal.
Now, is the union gonna
stand in our way?
He's all yours.
I hate making deals,
but I sure as hell don't want anybody
around who could hurt us the next time.
Yeah.
What about the gym teacher?
He's cooperating.
We're putting him in another school.
- Rosenberg?
- I'm having him come in today.
Mr. Jurel?
Mr. Jurel, you're wanted
in the gymnasium.
What for?
I'm sure I don't know.
Ah, Mr. Jurel,
won't you join us, please?
- What's going on?
- Please be seated, Mr. Jurel.
Mr. Jurel,
how happy are you here,
at John F. Kennedy?
What is this all about?
We feel, that is,
all of the board members
present and myself,
that it would be best
if you
were to tender
your resignation.
- Why?
- Because,
Mr. Jurel,
nobody here wants to go through
the pain of firing you.
You can't fire me,
I've got tenure.
Hey, I just heard they're
gonna fire Jurel.
What?
Where'd you hear that?
The office. Old lady Wensel
was talking about it.
Mr. Jurel, you know a student
named Diane Warren?
Isn't it true you took Diane Warren,
a 16-year-old student,
to the free clinic to
have an abortion?
The abortion was performed
without parental consent.
- Roger?
- I'm waiting for your answer.
Roger.
Now, come on, Roger.
Talk to me.
Do you think that this is proper
conduct for a teacher?
Well, it's a hell of a lot better conduct
than the teacher that got her pregnant.
And what was
his name?
You son of a bitch.
I just figured what
this is all about.
You know, this isn't about a
16-year-old girl that got pregnant.
Oh, hell no, that's the last thing
that this would be about.
We're afraid of what
old Alex is gonna say
at his deposition today.
Well, I'll tell you what
I'm gonna say.
Wouldn't you like to hear that,
Rog, old buddy?
Forget it, Alex.
The case has been
settled already.
There's not gonn
be a deposition.
It's over.
Your resignation, Mr. Jurel.
Oh, for Christ's sake, Burke,
what do you think,
that's gonna stop me?
A disgruntled former employee,
who was fired, connected with
sexual misconduct.
Now,
who would listen to you?
Who's gonna listen to you?
Take the deal, Alex.
- Take it.
- Roger.
Sign the paper and
then go home.
Tomorrow, go out and look
for another job. Do it, Alex.
Or you'll never work as a teacher
for the rest of your life.
I promise you that.
Oh, Roger.
Well.
Larry. Hey, Larry.
Come on, Larry.
Help me out.
I mean, is three minutes all
we got left to fight for?
Larry?
You son of a bitch.
Son of a bitch.
I hope it's worth it.
Alex.
You were right all along.
The case wasn't about education,
it was about money.
They settled.
- It's over. - Your news
bulletin's a little late.
What are you doing?
What does it look like I'm doing?
I'm packing.
I quit.
- You can't.
- Oh, yes, I can.
Why?
Some schoolteacher knocked up
a 16-year-old girl,
and I took her to
get an abortion.
Now, if I don't resign,
they're gonna nail my ass to the wall.
They're bluffing, Alex.
They'd never risk the publicity.
Didn't you hear what
I said before?
The school system settled the case.
They paid them off.
The school was more afraid
of publicity than of losing.
Fight 'em, Alex.
You still can't see it, can you?
Nobody cares!
I'm out.
I'm through fighting.
I can't make a difference.
Yes, you can!
So, you gonna stay,
or you gonna go?
No!
No, damn it!
Don't you walk away, Alex!
Don't you turn your back on this
just because you're scared!
So, everybody loses,
is that it, Alex?
Just because you're the one
who's afraid to face reality?
You're the one who's afraid
to drop your shields,
because if you did you know you'd have
to take the risk of staying and fighting.
You're the one who's afraid
to walk naked down the hall.
Well, I'm not.
You're scared, Alex.
There's a whole room full of kids
in there, and they care!
And there's a hell of a lot more
where they come from.
They need you,
and you need them,
but you just pretend it isn't real
so you have an excuse to walk away.
For Christ's sake,
put your clothes on, Lisa.
Well, I'm not afraid
to face reality.
I'm not afraid to walk
naked down the hall.
- Lisa. Lisa!
- Alex, come on.
- Come on, Alex.
- Lisa!
Lisa!
Damn it, baby, please get dressed,
or I'm gonna call the cops.
- Get out of here! Get out of here!
- That's it, I'm calling the cops.
Central, this is hall D calling.
Get the cops up here, right away.
Lisa,
you are crazy.
You are absolutely crazy.
And you are a teacher.
Alex Jurel, the teacher.
Don't let them destroy that.
Oh, God.
Oh, Lisa, jeez.
Come on.
Are you gonna stay,
or you gonna go?
Take Lisa out of here, okay?
All right,
I can handle that.
I just think I was a little hasty, maybe.
What do you think?
I don't wanna go to another school.
I love this school.
Alex, look at this.
They're making me resign, Alex.
What the hell are you...
He signed that.
They can't make
you resign, Carl.
- What?
- Nobody is resigning.
No?
Hey, my car!
Hey, that's my car.
That's my car.
What happened to my car?
- I'm not gonna resign, Roger.
- You're finished. You're out.
Oh, hell, Burke,
I'm gonna tell you something.
I haven't even started.
Now, listen,
if you try and fire me,
I'm gonna be suing you.
What's that gonna solve, Alex?
I don't know, Roger,
but let's try it and find out.
The damn school wasn't built
for us, Roger.
It wasn't built for your unions, your
lawyers, and all your other institutions.
It was built for the kids.
They're not here for us.
We're here for them.
That's what it's about.
Kids.
Alex, half of them aren't even
coming back after the alarm.
But half will.
I think they're worth it.
Jurel, you're crazy,
you know that?
What can I say?
I'm a teacher.
All right, Jurel!
You're the man, Jurel!
Don't let them push you around,
Mr. Jurel.
Forget to tell me about
the fire alarm?
You're a teacher.
Subtitle:
sync. fix: titler