[Birds Twittering]
[Clucking]
[Ringing]
[Boy Grunts]
ARNOLD, TURN IT OFF.
[Ticking]
- YOU DEAF? GET UP.
- IT'S NIGHT.
GO BACK TO SLEEP.
[Rooster Crows]
COME ON. GET UP. IT'S 6:15.
GO AWAY, ARNOLD.
[Chuckles]
GOT YOU NOW.
[Grunts]
YOU GOT THINGS MIXED UP, BOY.
LOOK, SEE THAT LIGHT OUT THERE?
WE JUST GOT INTO BED,
ALL RIGHT?
WE'RE GOING TO BED EARLY
BECAUSE WE GOTTA GET UP EARLY.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST
LIE HERE NOW AND WATCH.
YOU'LL SEE HOW IT GETS DARKER
AND DARKER AND DARKER.
[Laughs]
[Dog Barks]
NO, ACE. GO AWAY. ACE, GO AWAY.
[Crowing Continues]
GOD, YOU SMELL, DOG.
ARNOLD, YOU LITTLE--
GET THE DOG OUTTA HERE.
COME ON, ACE. GET OFF.
I'M UP. ARNOLD--
[Laughs]
[Crowing Continues]
WHOO, IT'S COLD OUT.
COME HERE, ACE. COME ON.
HEY, ARNOLD, WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA DO WITH THE GUN, HUH?
SHOOT A DUCK. OH, YOU'RE GONNA
SHOOT A DUCK, ARE YOU?
HERE, GIVE ME THAT GUN
BEFORE YOU SHOOT SOMEBODY.
HERE. TAKE THE PAIL.
YOU CAN PICK SOME PEAS ON THE WAY.
THANKS.
[Barks]
WHY DO WE HAVE TO GET UP SO EARLY
JUST TO PICK PEAS?
WELL, ARNOLD, IF YOU DON'T PICK THE PEAS
BEFORE THE SUN RISES, THEY JUST WILT.
SO? I DON'T EVEN LIKE PEAS.
NEITHER DO I.
THEN WHY DO WE HAVE TO PICK 'EM?
IT'S PRETTY SIMPLE. IF WE DON'T PICK
THE PEAS, DAD IS GONNA KICK OUR BUTT.
OH. OKAY.
WE'RE NOT GONNA SHOOT ANY DUCKS
WITH ACE ALONG, ARE WE?
HE'LL SCARE 'EM AWAY.
YOU'RE RIGHT. HERE, ACE.
ACE, GET OUTTA HERE.
ACE, GO HOME.
GO HOME, ACE. GO AHEAD.
GO HOME.
[Barks]
NOW YOU REALLY GOTTA BE QUIET,
'CAUSE THESE DUCKS WILL HEAR YOU.
I KNOW. A MILE OFF.
THEY'RE AROUND HERE.
[Sniffs]
I MEAN, NO NOISE AT ALL.
[Duck Quacking]
[Exhales]
COME ALONG.
[Whispering, Indistinct]
[Pail Rattles]
SHH.
ARNOLD, YOU'RE HELPLESS.
[Gunshot]
- [No Audible Dialogue]
- [Wind Whistling]
[Insects Buzzing]
[Pea Pod Drops In Pail]
YOU BOYS FILL THE PAIL? I HEARD YOU
SHOOTING. DID YOU GET A DUCK?
- EUGENE'S DEAD.
- YOU CALL THAT A JOKE?
[Woman]
WHERE'S EUGENE?
[Man]
TELL HIM TO
COME IN RIGHT NOW. OKAY?
[Pan Clatters On Stove]
WHERE'S EUGENE?
IN THE PASTURE.
[Woman] EUGENE.
[Barking]
[Meows]
[Girl Crying]
[Cow Lowing]
[Crying Continues]
[Siren Wailing]
[Wailing Continues]
[Chattering On Police Radio]
GOT A DEAD BOY HERE, I'M AFRAID.
[Chatter Continues]
[Crying]
[Sobbing]
[Sobbing Continues]
[Duck Quacks]
[Man] ARNOLD?
I KNOW YOU'RE UP THERE.
COME ON OUT. I WANNA
ASK YOU A FEW QUESTIONS.
ARNOLD?
TELL US.
EUGENE WAS SNEAKING DOWN
AHEAD OF ME.
THERE WAS FOUR DUCKS.
HE SAID, "KEEP DOWN."
ALL RIGHT. THEN WHAT?
THE GUN GOT CAUGHT ON THE WIRE.
I WAS CLIMBING THROUGH AFTER HIM.
HOW COME YOU DIDN'T RUN HOME?
HMM?
[Horse Whinnies]
- YOU ANSWER?
- NO.
WELL, ANSWER.
[Bell Tolling]
[Woman Crying]
GRANDPA, CAN I GO HOME WITH YOU?
I DIDN'T HEAR YOU.
WHAT'D YOU SAY?
CAN I GO WITH YOU?
YOU THINKIN' ABOUT MOVIN' OUT,
ARE YOU?
NO. ONE NIGHT?
WHAT ABOUT YOUR WORK?
AIN'T YOU GOT CHORES TO DO?
NORA CAN DO 'EM ONE NIGHT.
YOU FIGURE THEY DON'T
WANT YOU AROUND, DON'T YOU?
KIND OF. HOW OLD ARE YOU?
TWELVE.
WELL, SON, AT 12 YEARS OLD, YOU
MAY NOT KNOW ALL THE ANSWERS.
BUT I DON'T SEE WHERE ONE NIGHT'LL HURT.
SURE. WHY NOT?
[Chattering]
[Woman]
OKAY. I'LL SEE YOU.
[Chattering Continues]
[Tolling Continues]
FROM THE 19th CHAPTER
OF JOB, THE 25th VERSE.
"FOR I KNOW THAT MY REDEEMER LIVETH...
"AND THAT HE SHALL STAND AT
THE LATTER DAY UPON THE EARTH.
"AND THOUGH AFTER MY SKIN,
WORMS DESTROY THIS BODY,
"YET IN MY FLESH SHALL I SEE GOD...
WHOM I SHALL SEE FOR MYSELF
AND WITH MINE OWN EYES BEHOLD."
AND FROM THE NEW TESTAMENT, I--
[Sighs]
"IN MY FATHER'S HOUSE,
ARE MANY MANSIONS.
"I GO NOW TO PREPARE A PLACE FOR YOU.
"IF IT WERE NOT SO
I WOULD'VE TOLD YOU SO.
"AS IT WAS IN THE BEGINNING,
SO IT SHALL BE IN THE END...
WORLD WITHOUT END."
AMEN. [Man]
YEAH, THAT'S TOO BAD.
[Man #2] YEAH, WE'LL--
WE'LL GET THROUGH IT.
[Man #3] MUST'VE FORGOT MY TOBACCO.
[Man #4] WELL, I CAN'T HELP YOU OUT.
I DON'T SMOKE ANYMORE.
[Man #5] JOE, I'M AWFUL SORRY.
[Woman] DORIS AND ME WERE BEST FRIENDS
ALL THROUGH SCHOOL.
CALLED US THE TWINS.
[Laughs] LONG TIME AGO.
[Woman #2] YEAH.
[Sniffling]
SHE LOST HER HUSBAND LAST YEAR.
YEAH. WHEN HE WAS NO BIGGER
THAN A BABY,
I REMEMBER HIM COMING UP
TO ME AT HARVEST TIME.
- YOU REMEMBER, ANDY?
- YEAH.
WE'S NO MORE THAN
KIDS OURSELVES THAT YEAR.
BUT WE WAS DOIN' A MAN'S WORK.
THAT'S RIGHT.
HERE COME EUGENE.
AH, HERE COME EUGENE.
RIGHT ACROSS THAT FIELD.
[Laughing] HE WAS FALLIN' IN
THEM RUTS LIKE THEY WAS CANYONS.
YEAH. [Laughs]
HE WAS GONNA DO A MAN'S WORK.
YEAH. HE COULDN'T SAY
MORE THAN TWO OR THREE WORDS,
BUT HE WAS DAMN SURE
GONNA JOIN IN THE HARVESTIN'.
YEAH. LEAST HE
GOT TO LIVE 17 YEARS.
I HAD A SON DIED AT NINE.
[Man] YEAH. ISAAC.
I REMEMBER ISAAC.
HE'D HAVE BEEN 20--
23.
- ONE TIME OL' EUGENE WHIPPED ME
WRESTLING. HE WAS GOOD.
- [Woman] HE SURE WAS STRONG.
YEAH, HE WAS, WASN'T HE?
I REMEMBER ONE TIME
HE GOT MAD AT ME,
AND AT THE TIME,
HELL, I WAS, UH, ALMOST
TWICE AS TALL AS HIM.
DIDN'T MATTER TO HIM, BOY. UP THEY GO,
BOY. HE WANTS TO FIGHT. [Chuckles]
HE DIDN'T CARE. HE WAS TOUGH.
[Woman] HE WAS A GOOD BOY.
[Man] SURE WAS.
[Woman] USED TO WEAR EACH OTHER'S CLOTHES.
[Woman #2]
I WAS THINKIN' THAT, UM, MAYBE--
[Man] YOU BOYS GET SOME OF
AUNT LOVE'S PIE IN THERE?
YOU DON'T GIVE A HOOT, THAT IT?
[Woman]
CLINTON MIGHT WANT TO COME OVER.
[Woman #2] SURE.
- BUT THEY WON'T FORGET.
- [Man #2]
THAT'S STRANGE.
[Woman] THEY WON'T FORGET.
[Man #2] I DON'T UNDERSTAND IT.
[Engine Starts]
NOT A TEAR.
YOU'D THINK TEARS WAS GOLD
AND HE WAS A MISER.
[Clock Ticking]
[Wind Whistling]
MOTHER. MOTHER?
ARNOLD?
GO BACK TO BED.
WH-- ARNOLD.
HE CAME DOWN.
SURE HE CAME DOWN.
HE'S-HE'S ALONE UP THERE.
HE'S SCARED.
NO. SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
NO. NO. NO.
YOU LET HIM ALONE.
NOW, MAYBE WHEN HE'S ALONE,
MAYBE HE'LL KNOW WHAT HE DID.
WELL, WHAT IF HE KNOWS ALREADY?
HE KNEW.
HE KNEW. NO. NO.
BELIEVE ME, HE DON'T KNOW.
[Thunder Rumbles In Distance]
[Chattering On Police Radio]
SIT DOWN.
NO. I'LL STAND OVER HERE.
SIT DOWN, SON.
HELLO, ANDY.
HOW YOU DOING, MAC?
WHAT'D YOU SAY YOUR NAME IS?
ARNOLD.
JUST THAT?
ARNOLD HILLERMAN.
NOBODY CAN GET ALONG ON JUST ONE NAME.
WHAT WERE YOU DOING
WITH A .22, ARNOLD?
IT'S MINE.
OKAY. WHAT WERE YOU GONNA SHOOT?
SOME DUCKS.
IT'S OUT OF SEASON.
YES, SIR.
YOU AND YOUR BROTHER
THE BEST OF FRIENDS?
I GOT A BEST FRIEND.
HE'S SOMEBODY ELSE.
- WERE THEY GOOD FRIENDS?
- YEAH, THEY WERE.
DID THEY QUARREL
A LOT?
NO MORE THAN WHAT'S TO BE EXPECTED.
I MEAN, NOT EVEN THAT. IT SEEMED TO ME
ARNOLD CARED A LOT FOR EUGENE.
[Mac]
DID YOU?
YES, SIR.
YOU MAD AT HIM?
NO, SIR.
SOMETHING HE SAID MADE YOU MAD.
WELL, HOW'D YOU COME TO SHOOT HIM?
HE WAS CRAWLING THROUGH THE FENCE.
YES?
THE GUN GOT CAUGHT.
IT SEEMS THE HAMMER MUST'VE CAUGHT.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW, THAT'S WHAT HAPPENED.
BUT WHAT I WANNA KNOW
IS THIS.
WHY DIDN'T YOU GO BACK TO THE HOUSE
AND TELL YOUR PARENTS?
THE SUN WAS GONNA COME UP.
WHAT'S THAT GOT TO DO WITH IT?
GOTTA PICK PEAS
BEFORE THE SUN COMES UP.
[Chattering On Police Radio]
[Meows]
[Lowing]
YOU KNOW, IN MY LIFE, I NEVER COULD
FIGURE OUT ANYTHING I COULD POSTPONE.
AND WHAT A GUY POSTPONES
FIGURIN' OUT ARE THE BIG THINGS.
LIKE SOMEBODY DYIN'.
YOU HUNGRY?
YEAH.
WANT AN APPLE?
SURE.
SOMEBODY DYIN' CLOSE TO YOU
LIKE, UH, WELL,
SOMEBODY SO CLOSE, YOU--
YOU BEGIN TO THINK MAYBE SHE WAS YOU.
[Water Running]
AND THE DROUGHTS--
[Chuckles]
NOT ONE GODDAMN LITTLE DROP
OF WATER COMES DOWN.
TO WHERE YOU FIGURE HE'S MAD AT YOU UP THERE,
AND YOU KNOW YOU NEVER DONE NOTHIN' THAT BAD,
I MEAN, THAT HE SHOULD CAUSE EVERY
LITTLE GREEN SPROUT TO SHRIVEL UP AND DIE.
[Dog Barking In Distance]
AND THEN THE SNOWS COME.
DEEP SNOW. BLIZZARDS.
YOU KNOW, MY KID BROTHER LOST HIS WAY
BETWEEN THE HOUSE AND THE BARN.
IT WAS ONLY 200 YARDS.
AND HE FROZE TO DEATH.
AND IT WAS SEVERAL DAYS
BEFORE THEY FOUND HIS BODY.
THAT'S WHEN I WAS A BOY IN NEBRASKA.
[Sighs]
IT'S TRUE WHAT THEY SAY, YOU KNOW.
ONLY THE GOOD DIE YOUNG.
¶ BABY, YOU'RE SO YOUNG ¶
LOOK IT OVER,
TELL ME WHAT YOU THINK.
I-I THINK EVERYBODY
MAKES MONEY HERE, BUT, UH--
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO DO? SIGN THIS?
I WANT YOU TO SIGN IT.
WELL, I'VE GOTTA READ IT FIRST.
READ IT, THEN SIGN IT.
CAN I GET YOU GUYS SOME MORE COFFEE?
'NIGHT, JOANNE.
SWEETHEART, JUST A SMILE.
YEAH. MAKE THAT TWO SMILES.
YOU WANT SOME COFFEE?
YOU GUYS,
I'M TRYING TO CLOSE.
YOU WANT SOME COFFEE OR NOT?
NO. THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
NO.
¶ 'CAUSE, BABY,
YOU'RE SO YOUNG ¶
¶ AND YOU'D BE SO MUCH FUN ¶
GIVE THE MAN A SMILE, JOSH.
HE WANTS A SMILE
WITH HIS COFFEE.
¶ SMILE A WHILE
LA-DA-DA-DA-DEE
DA-DA-DA-DA-DA ¶
HALF-ASSED
WHEELER-DEALERS.
[Both Laugh]
¶ I WISH THAT
I COULD BE THE ONE ¶
¶ [Singing]
¶ 'CAUSE YOU'RE SO YOUNG ¶
AMALIE, I ALREADY
CLOSED OUT. WHY DON'T YOU
LOCK UP, HONEY, OKAY?
OKAY. YOU GOING HOME?
I'M GOING HOME.
YOU SURE YOU'RE
GOING HOME, JOSH?
WHAT'S IT TO YOU?
UH-HUH. I BET YOU ARE.
¶ BUT, BABY, YOU'RE SO YOUNG ¶
YOU AIN'T GOIN' FISHING.
[Josh Laughs]
YOU THROUGH, ANDY?
¶ I WISH THAT
I COULD BE THE ONE ¶
¶ 'CAUSE, BABY, YOU'RE SO--
YOU'RE SO YOUNG ¶
¶ BABY, YOU'RE SO YOUNG ¶
YOU KNOW,
WE ALL LOVED EUGENE.
BUT WE ALL GOTTA LEARN
TO GET OVER IT.
¶ SO YOUNG ¶
I KNOW.
THEY KEEP TELLING ME THAT.
I MEAN, YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO KIND OF LEARN
TO SMILE ALL OVER AGAIN.
HIDE YOUR FEELINGS
IN FRONT OF STRANGERS.
[Sighs]
CLOWNS ANYWAY.
¶ BUT, BABY, YOU'RE SO YOUNG ¶
YOU ACT LIKE 12 DAYS
IS 12 YEARS.
¶ I WISH THAT
I COULD BE THE ONE ¶
MM.
DAYS ARE YEARS
AND YEARS ARE DAYS
WHEN IT COMES TO SORROW.
AIN'T NO SUCH THING
AS TIME.
[Tsks]
IT'S THE WAY IT IS.
¶ I WISH THAT
I COULD BE THE ONE ¶
COME ON.
I'LL DRIVE YOU HOME.
¶ BABY, YOU'RE SO YOUNG ¶
¶ AND YOU'D BEEN SO MUCH FUN ¶
¶ I WISH THAT
I COULD BE THE ONE ¶
[Amalie] ANDY, YOU SAID
YOU'D TAKE ME HOME.
I WILL. I WILL.
JUST THAT I THOUGHT MAYBE
WE COULD TALK BETTER HERE.
I MEAN, UH, THERE'S NOBODY
AT YOUR HOUSE THAT
YOU CAN TALK TO.
[Sighs]
AND THERE'S SURE AS HELL
NOBODY AT MY HOUSE...
THAT WANTS TO TALK TO ME,
I TELL YOU THAT-- [Scoffs]
YOU KNOW, HE TOLD ME
ONE TIME HE WANTED TO
BE A--
WHAT'D HE CALL THAT?
REMEMBER THOSE PEOPLE
IN HIGH SCHOOL,
THOSE TEACHERS THAT
TAUGHT YOU ABOUT
THE INSIDE OF A FROG...
OR, SAY, UH,
THE LIFE OF AN EAGLE.
BIOLOGIST.
YEAH. BIO-BIOLOGIST.
THAT'S IT. YEAH.
[Chuckles]
HE TOLD ME THAT TOO.
YEAH. THAT'S WHAT
HE WANTED TO BE.
THAT'S WHAT
HE WANTED TO DO.
[Chuckles]
WELL, I ENCOURAGED HIM.
I SAID, UH, YOU KNOW,
IF THERE'S ANY WAY I CAN,
I'LL PUT YOU THROUGH SCHOOL--
THROUGH COLLEGE--
IF I CAN AFFORD IT.
I WOULD HAVE.
YOU SEE,
I NEVER THOUGHT OF EUGENE
AS JUST MY NEPHEW.
I ALWAYS FELT
HE'S MORE LIKE
MY KID BROTHER--
THE ONE I NEVER HAD
BUT ALWAYS WANTED.
SEE, I MEAN,
WE-WE WERE REAL CLOSE.
REAL CLOSE.
I WAS THE FIRST ONE
THAT TOOK HIM HUNTIN'.
YOU WERE?
MM-HMM.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT.
YEAH.
FIRST-FIRST TIME.
BOY, IT'S SURE--
[Tsks]
CLEAR AS DAY WHY HE WAS
IN LOVE WITH YOU,
TELL YOU THAT.
YOU'RE ABOUT
THE PRETTIEST GIRL
I'VE SEEN IN A LONG TIME.
'ROUND HERE.
I THINK.
I KNOW. I SHOULDN'T BE
TALKING LIKE THAT
AND EVERYTHING.
[Tsks] WHEW.
SURE GETS COMPLICATED,
DON'T IT?
SURE DOES
GET COMPLICATED.
ANDY, TAKE ME HOME.
I WILL.
I'LL TAKE YOU HOME.
SAID I'D TAKE YOU HOME.
I WILL TAKE YOU HOME.
IN A MINUTE.
[Exhales]
[Whispering]
BASTARD.
[Dog Barking In Distance]
DAMN.
[Sewing Machine Whirring]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING UP?
LORD. CAN'T SLEEP?
YOU OKAY?
YOU BOTH OKAY?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
[Sighs]
YOU ALL RIGHT?
- WHERE YOU BEEN, ANDY?
- I TOLD YOU I WAS
GOING OUT WITH TEDDY.
YOU'RE LYING TO ME.
I'M NOT LYING TO YOU,
AND I DON'T LIKE
TO BE TOLD I'M LYING.
NOBODY'S LYING TO YOU.
AH, LU,
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
HUH?
HEY. JUST RELAX.
JUST RELAX.
IT'S GONNA BE OKAY.
EVERYTHING'S OKAY.
YOU'RE DOING IT TO ME
AGAIN, AREN'T YOU, ANDY?
DOING WHAT?
YOU KNOW WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
NOBODY'S DOING ANYTHING.
I'M NOT DOING ANYTHING.
I DON'T BELIEVE YOU.
LOOK, YOU'RE JUST HAVING
SOME KIND OF CHEMICAL REACTION.
YOU KNOW, LIKE THE DOCTOR
WAS TELLING YOU ABOUT.
YOU KNOW?
[Crying]
THAT'S ALL. HEY, COME HERE.
JUST DON'T TOUCH ME.
JUST LEAVE ME ALONE.
I WANNA TALK TO YOU.
WAIT A MINUTE. WAIT A MINUTE.
I DON'T WANNA TALK TO YOU.
COME ON. YOU LOOK
REAL PRETTY, YOU KNOW?
[Sniffling]
OH, ANDY, STOP.
STOP IT! WHO IS IT THIS TIME?
WHO IS WHAT?
IT'S NOBODY. IT'S YOUR
MOTHER'S AUNT HARRIET.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
I DON'T WANNA KNOW ANYWAY.
IT DOESN'T MATTER. I DON'T WANNA KNOW.
COME ON.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
IT'S OKAY. NOW, COME ON.
JUST LEAVE-- I CAN'T EVEN LOOK AT
YOUR FACE. ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT.
I'LL MAKE IT EASY FOR YOU,
'CAUSE I'M GONNA GO TO BED.
YOU WANNA STAY UP ALL NIGHT,
THAT'S YOUR PROBLEM.
JUST MAKIN' YOURSELF SICK, LU.
THAT'S ALL YOU'RE DOIN'.
JUST MAKIN' YOURSELF SICK.
YOU WANNA DO THAT, THAT'S--
THAT'S WHAT YOU CAN DO.
[Exhales]
[Birds Twittering]
[Rooster Crows]
NORA, YOU GONNA KEEP
THAT PITCHER FOR YOURSELF?
PASS THAT PITCHER TO ARNOLD.
[Door Closes]
[Screen Door Bangs]
WHO DO YOU THINK YOU ARE?
I DON'T KNOW, MAMA. WHAT DID I DO?
I WANT YOU TO TALK TO HIM,
NOT TO THE AIR. AND YOU TALK KIND.
YOU CAN'T DO IT,
AND YOU WANT ME TO DO IT?
THAT NIGHT, I WOULDN'T LET HIM
TELL ME HOW BAD HE FELT.
NOW HE CAN'T.
HE'S SO FAR AWAY.
WHAT'S A KIND WORD?
- [Horse Whinnies]
- [Ruth]
HERE, CHICK, CHICK, CHICK.
HERE, CHICK, CHICK, CHICK,
CHICK, CHICK, CHICK, CHICK.
HERE, CHICK, CHICK, CHICK.
HERE, CHICK, CHICK,
CHICK, CHICK.
HERE, CHICK. HERE, CHICK, CHICK,
RUTH, I WANNA TALK TO YOU.
IT'S ABOUT ANDY.
WELL, HE'S DOING IT TO ME AGAIN.
[Groans]
YEAH. I KNOW HE'S DOING IT
AGAIN, AND I WANNA KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE GONNA DO ABOUT IT.
LU, I DON'T KNOW
IF THERE'S ANYTHING I CAN DO.
WELL, SOMEBODY'S GOTTA
DO SOMETHING, BECAUSE
HE'S NOT LISTENING TO ME.
[Sighs]
I JUST CAN'T--
I CAN'T GET INTO YOUR--
YOUR LIFE LIKE THAT.
WELL, WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
I'M PREGNANT. I'M GOING TO
HAVE A BABY, AND MY WHOLE
MARRIAGE IS FALLING APART.
WELL, I-I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT--
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY.
[Sighs]
WELL, DAMN IT, RUTH.
HE'S YOUR BROTHER.
HE'S YOUR BABY BROTHER,
SO WHATEVER HE DOES
IS ALL RIGHT WITH YOU, RIGHT?
I NEVER FELT THAT WAY ABOUT ANDY.
[Scoffs]
I NEVER SAID THAT.
OH, YOU DON'T HAVE TO SAY IT.
NOBODY HAS TO SAY IT. I ALWAYS KNEW
WHAT YOU WERE THINKING ABOUT ME.
THAT HE WAS SO GODDAMN CLASSY, WHAT WAS
HE DOING WITH SOMEONE LIKE ME, RIGHT?
HANDSOME ANDY. GOT HIMSELF A LITTLE WOMAN
THAT LOOKS LIKE A PLUCKED CHICKEN.
CAN'T EVEN KEEP A BABY
ALIVE INSIDE OF HER, RIGHT?
NOBODY HAS TO SAY ANYTHING.
I ALWAYS KNEW WHAT YOU WERE THINKING.
NOW YOU'RE TALKING NONSENSE, LU.
[Huffs]
YOU'RE THE SMARTEST LADY AROUND, AND YOU
TALK NONSENSE. DON'T MAKE FUN OF ME, RUTH.
I'M NOT MAKING FUN OF YOU, LU. [Scoffs]
YOU THINK I DON'T KNOW WHAT GOES ON?
I KNOW EVERYTHING.
I KNEW ABOUT THAT OTHER WOMAN.
BUT SHE WAS OLDER THAN ME, AND SHE ALREADY
HAD A HUSBAND. AFTER A WHILE, THEY MOVED AWAY.
BUT THIS TIME IT'S DIFFERENT.
THIS TIME IS DIFFERENT.
- YOU KNOW WHO IT IS THIS TIME?
- MAYBE IT'S NOBODY.
MAYBE YOU'RE JUST MAKING IT UP
OR IMAGINING IT.
[Laughs] JESUS. THAT'S WHAT HE SAID.
THAT'S RIGHT. I'M CRAZY.
JOE, YOU WANNA KNOW
WHO IT IS? DO YOU WANNA KNOW?
JOE? JOE. IT'S AMALIE.
YEAH. IT'S EUGENE'S GIRL.
IT'S AMALIE.
AMALIE WOULDN'T DO THAT. EVERYBODY KNOWS
HOW HE'S HANGING AROUND HER SINCE EUGENE DIED.
EVERYBODY KNOWS ABOUT IT.
IT'S AMALIE.
YEAH. IT'S EUGENE'S GIRL.
YOU COME BACK HERE, LU.
REMEMBER EUGENE? REMEMBER?
LU, YOU STOP THAT! LU!
HEY. COME HERE.
[Sobbing]
GET INSIDE. COME ON. YOU'RE GETTING
HYSTERICAL, WOMAN. NOW GET IN THE HOUSE.
GO ON IN.
NORA, GET HER SOME WHISKEY.
COME ON.
[Screen Door Bangs]
SIT DOWN OVER THERE, LU.
NOW, WHERE'S ANDY AT?
HE'S AT SULLIVAN'S
HELPING HIM WITH HIS HARVESTIN'.
HE'LL SUP-SUPPER THERE.
HERE.
WENT AND HID HIMSELF IN THE BARN.
I WANNA STAY HERE TONIGHT.
WHEN HE COMES HOME,
I DON'T WANNA BE THERE.
[Sniffs]
ALL RIGHT.
[Grunts]
- I THINK I'M GONNA LOSE THIS ONE TOO.
- WHAT MAKES YOU SAY THAT?
LAST NIGHT, I HAD THESE PAINS.
I DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT THEM, BUT I GOT THEM NOW.
[Crying]
I'M SO AFRAID.
LU, YOU GO LAY DOWN.
OH, I THINK I'LL BE FINE.
[Exhales] I'LL BE FINE.
[Laughs]
I EXAGGERATE, YOU KNOW.
[Sniffles]
THAT'S WHAT I DO.
HEY, GRANDPA.
HI, DARLIN'.
HOW ARE YOU?
FINE.
"GRANDPA," SHE SAYS.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT ME, DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHO YOU'RE REALLY LOOKING AT?
YEAH.
WHO?
YOU'RE YOU.
I'M LOOKING AT MY GRANDPA.
YOUR NAME'S GEORGE JANSEN, YOU GOT
BLUE EYES AND YOU'RE-- HOW OLD ARE YOU?
WELL, I'VE SEEN 60 SNOWS.
WELL, THAT'S WHO I'M TALKING TO.
[Chuckles]
SWEET JESUS.
YOU HEAR THAT?
YOU KNOW YOUR SISTER HERE, SHE'S GONNA
GROW UP TO BE SOME KIND OF WELFARE WORKER.
MAYBE WORK IN THE COURTHOUSE WHERE
THEY KNOW  YOU BY YOUR NAME AND NUMBER.
SHE SAYS I'M GEORGE JANSEN.
I'M 60 YEARS OLD.
WHO'S THAT?
YOU GOT ANY IDEA WHO THAT IS?
ARNOLD.
ARNOLD HILLERMAN.
[Chuckles]
YOU SEE WHAT I MEAN?
YOU COULD WORK IN
THE COURTHOUSE NOW IF YOU WANTED.
GO GET THE FISH
OUT OF THE TRUCK, SON.
HIYA.
HEY.
HOW ARE YOU? OKAY?
OH, I'M ALL RIGHT.
WHAT YOU MAKING?
WELL, I GOT THIS PILLOW HERE.
I BEEN WORKING ON IT FOR A WHILE.
WHERE'S JOE? HE'S OVER AT CORBETT'S.
THEY HAVE SOME PROBLEM.
OH, YEAH?
YEAH.
LU'S HERE,
SLEEPING IN THE GUEST ROOM.
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH HER OWN BED?
YOU KNOW.
YOUNG ANDREW, WHERE'S HE?
HE'S OVER AT SULLIVAN'S.
THEY'RE HARVESTIN'.
HE'LL BE COMIN' HERE, YOU KNOW.
MAYBE KICKIN' THE DOOR DOWN, ACTIN' LIKE
SOME CRAZY KID QUICK AS HE FINDS HER GONE.
WILL YOU STAY TONIGHT?
YOU CAN SLEEP UP IN ARNOLD'S ROOM.
BE A NICE CHANGE.
I BROUGHT YOU SOME TROUT, AND I'LL
CLEAN 'EM IF YOU'LL COOK 'EM.
[Chuckles] WE'LL HAVE A GOOD SUPPER,
AND I'LL STAY.
ALL RIGHT.
¶ [Nora Humming]
SHE SINGS
HERSELF ASLEEP.
[Chuckles]
I GUESS SHE MAKES DAMN SURE SHE'S ASLEEP
BEFORE SHE STOPS, HUH?
MM-HMM.
I THINK THAT SHE OUGHTA PUT THIS BED
OUT IN THE SHED. [Breathing Heavily]
OR MAYBE YOU CAN
COME OVER AND STAY WITH ME.
HELP ME OFF
WITH THESE BOOTS, WILL YOU?
YEAH, YOU BETTER
COME STAY OVER AT MY PLACE.
MIGHT BE ALL RIGHT, THOUGH,
IF I SPEND THE NIGHT IN IT.
THEN IT'D BE MINE.
YEAH.
FROM NOW ON, LET'S JUST
FIGURE THIS IS MY BED. OKAY?
MM-HMM.
WELL, GET YOUR CLOTHES OFF.
¶ [Humming Continues]
[Pounding On Door]
[Pounding Continues]
LU! LU!
WHERE IS SHE? SHE'S SPENDIN' THE NIGHT.
SHE'S NOT FEELIN' TOO WELL.
THE HELL WITH THAT. I'LL TALK TO HER
IN THE MORNIN', MAKE SURE SHE GOES BACK.
SHE NEEDS A CHANGE,JUST LIKE YOU.
I'LL GIVE HER A CHANGE.
LUCILLE? LU? LU?
WHERE YOU HIDIN'?
[Ruth] ANDY.
LUCILLE, YOU UP THERE?
COME ON DOWN, BABY. COME ON DOWN, HON--
- DAMN. WHO ELSE IS UP THERE?
- [Exhales]
LOOKS LIKE A FULL HOUSE.
WHAT YOU DOIN' HERE, PAPA?
I'M TRYIN' TO GET SOME SLEEP.
I JUST BROUGHT BY SOME TROUT.
HMM.
LOOK LIKE A KANGAROO COURT
IF I EVER SAW ONE.
DANGED IF I AIN'T HANGED ALREADY.
LU. LU!
COME ON OUT, BABY.
COME ON OUT, HONEY.
COME ON.
COME ON, RUTH.
[Ruth] MAYBE SHE JUST
WENT ON BACK HOME.
[Andy] NAH, SHE DIDN'T GO BACK HOME.
THAT AIN'T HER STYLE.
SHE'S GOTTA PULL SOME KIND OF DIPSY-DOODLE
SHIT LIKE THIS, TRY TO SCARE US.
[Ruth] SHE DON'T WANNA SCARE ANYBODY. LU!
[Andy] LUCILLE!
LU! COME ON, BABY.
COME ON HOME.
WE'LL FIND HER.
SHE'LL BE IN HERE.
SOME KITTENS AROUND HERE, AND THAT'LL BE
WHERE SHE'LL BE. [Lu Groans]
[Lu Gasping]
UH-OH.
[Grunts]
UH-OH-OH-OH.
[Groans]
THERE, MY GIRL.
IT'S COMING.
GRANDADDY, IT'S COMING.
IT'S COMING. WELL, THEN, DON'T YOU THINK
YOU OUGHTA BE BACK IN YOUR BED?
[Groans] IT'S COMING WAY BEFORE
IT OUGHT TO.
[Breathing Heavily]
JUST LIKE THE OTHER ONE.
- [Groans]
- I DON'T KNOW WHY
THEY DO THAT.
YOU HANG ON.
OKAY. [Whimpers]
WE'LL GET SOME HELP.
WHAT'S GOIN' ON HERE?
SHE ALL RIGHT?
[Groans] IT HURTS.
I KNOW.
IS SHE IN HERE?
[Grunts]
LU? LU, YOU ALL RIGHT, HONEY?
YOU ALL RIGHT?
[George] PUT YOUR HAND HERE.
CAN YOU GET UP ON YOUR FEET?
[Lu] YEAH.
[Andy] COME ON, BABY.
COME ON NOW.
[George] HELP HER UP THERE.
[Lu] OKAY.
ALL RIGHT?
YEAH.
[Whimpers] SHE CAN'T MAKE IT.
TAKE A HOLD OF MY NECK.
THAT'S A GIRL.
[Groans]
[Ruth] IT'S ALL RIGHT.
WELL, SHE MIGHT FEEL DIFFERENT
TOMORROW, BUT--
MM.
I DON'T KNOW IF SHE WILL THIS TIME.
[Sighs] I REALLY BLEW IT,
DIDN'T I?
DAMN.
YEAH. YOU KNOW, SOMETIMES I THINK
SHE MARRIED ME JUST TO BE FOOLED.
SHE THOUGHT I WAS THE BEST THING
SINCE POPCORN.
BOY, I SURE FOOLED HER,
DIDN'T I?
I SURE FOOLED HER.
I TOLD HER-- I TOLD HER
I WASN'T NO GOOD.
YOU EVER THINK THAT...
MAYBE YOU FOOL YOURSELF?
HMM.
YEAH. I THOUGHT ABOUT THAT ONE
A LONG TIME AGO.
[Exhales]
I THINK I FOOLED MYSELF
ABOUT--
JUST ABOUT EVERYBODY I'VE KNOWN--
MAN, WOMAN, CHILD.
I SAY TO MYSELF,
"I KNOW THAT PERSON BETTER
THAN HE KNOWS HIMSELF."
OF COURSE, I'M WRONG
ABOUT NINE-TENTHS OF THE TIME.
ABOUT ARNOLD TOO.
ARNOLD?
[Exhales]
WELL,
I THINK I'M GONNA
LEAVE YOU, SISTER.
YOU GOT A HOUSE FULL
OF CRAZY PEOPLE HERE.
I'M ABOUT TO MAKE IT ONE LESS.
[Kisses]
BE SEEIN' YOU.
[Screen Door Bangs]
[Andy] JOE. BE SEEIN' YOU.
[George]
IT AIN'T YOUR DOIN', KID.
IT'S THEIR OWN DOIN'.
IF ANDY HAD A-CHOSE MONEY, HE'D A-HAD
EVERYBODY'S LAST DOLLAR.
OR IF HE'D A-GOT INTO REAL ESTATE,
HE'D A-GATHERED UP ALL THE LAND,
AND YOU'D HAD TO PAY A GODDAMNED
TOLL TO GET ACROSS IT.
HE JUST CHOSE WRONG. THAT'S ALL.
THAT BOY CHOSE WOMEN.
AND IF YOU WANNA KNOW,
I CHOSE 'EM MYSELF.
BUT I'LL TELL YOU SOMETHING--
ONE, MAYBE TWO.
THREE AT THE MOST.
IT WAS ENOUGH FOR ME.
AND NOT AT THE SAME TIME.
IT AIN'T YOUR DOIN'. YOU HEAR ME?
I HEAR.
WELL, THEN SAY SOMETHIN'.
[Exhales] I GUESS YOU DID.
I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW
THAT I NEVER FELT LIKE--
LIKE YOU SAID,
THAT YOU WEREN'T
GOOD ENOUGH FOR HIM.
I ALWAYS FELT
HE WAS LUCKY TO GET YOU.
EVEN IF MY CHILDREN DON'T GET BORN?
WELL,
IT SHOULD NEVER BE THAT WAY--
CHILDREN DIE BEFORE THEIR PARENTS.
IT SHOULD BE THE PARENTS
THAT GO FIRST.
[Lu] WELL, I'LL GO DOWN TO RENO,
GET MY OLD JOB BACK.
I GOT A LOT OF FRIENDS IN RENO.
YEAH?
YEAH, I DO.
LOT OF FRIENDS.
YOU KNOW, WHEN ANDY MET ME DOWN THERE,
I WAS JUST A CHANGE GIRL.
MAYBE--
MAYBE IF HE EVER COMES DOWN THERE
AGAIN, MAYBE I'LL BE A DEALER.
I GOT A GIRLFRIEND WHO'S A DEALER
THERE NOW-- BLACKJACK DEALER.
I THINK YOU BETTER
TAKE IT EASY FOR A WHILE.
OH, YEAH, I'LL DO THAT.
I'LL DO THAT. I'LL DO THAT
AT MY FOLKS'.
- [Vehicle Approaching]
- HERE IT COMES.
YEAH.
[Exhales]
I SURE HATE TO SEE YOU GO, LU.
I'LL--
I'LL KEEP IN TOUCH.
OKAY.
[Joe] LU'S NOT A SPUNKY WOMAN.
SHE ACTS LIKE ONE,
BUT SHE'S GOT NO REAL LIFE IN HER--
ONLY TO HIT ARNOLD.
[No Audible Dialogue]
SHE'S THE KIND THAT JUST,
YOU KNOW, LEAVES.
[Ruth] SOMETIMES I WISH I COULD JUST...
WANDER AWAY.
I DON'T MEAN
GO BUY A TICKET,
GET ON A BUS.
I JUST MEAN WANDER AWAY.
I WOULDN'T KNOW MY NAME
OR WHERE I CAME FROM.
IT'LL BE ALL RIGHT TO DO
WHEN I'M AN OLD LADY.
THAT'S WHAT MY MOTHER DID.
ONE DAY, SHE JUST...
WANDERED AWAY.
SHE HAD ON A SOILED DRESS.
SHE'D BEEN TRYIN'
TO FEED A PUNY HEN.
WHEN THEY BROUGHT HER BACK, SHE STILL HAD
SOME CORN FOR THE CHICKEN IN HER HAND.
SHE DIDN'T RECOGNIZE US.
[Footfalls Approaching]
[Door Closes]
CAN'T BE NOBODY BUT ARNOLD.
IT'S ME.
SEEMS TO ME LIKE YOU CAME A LONG WAY
JUST TO HIT THE SACK.
FIGURED YOU WERE ASLEEP.
[Chuckles] NO.
SEE, WHEN I'M SUPPOSED TO BE ASLEEP,
I USUALLY AIN'T.
SOMETIMES I GET UP IN THE NIGHT
AND HAVE ME A LITTLE BITE TO EAT.
YOU WANT ONE?
OKAY.
A MAN CAN LIVE A LONG TIME
IN THE WOODS, CAN'T HE?
LONG AS HE WANTS.
THAT LONG?
[Chuckling]
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, "THAT LONG"?
USUALLY, A GUY GETS OFF IN THERE AND
HE WANTS TO COME RIGHT BACK OUT.
COULD I LIVE IN THE MOUNTAINS
BY MYSELF?
GET YOURSELF A GUN, YOU CAN.
MM, FISHIN' GEAR,
FRYIN' PAN, BEDDING.
YOU UNDERSTAND, I'M NOT TRYIN'
TO GET RID OF YOU.
BUT YOU ASKED ME,
SO I'M TELLING YOU WHAT YOU NEED.
YOU NEED A SHARP KNIFE.
A FELLA CAN GET ALONG ALMOST ANYWHERE
ON A LOT LESS THAN HE THINKS,
IN TOWN OR ANYWHERE.
SHRIVEL UP SOMETIMES THOUGH.
ESPECIALLY YOUR COCK.
SOMETIMES IT'LL FALL RIGHT OFF.
I FIGURED YOU'D LEND ME A SHOTGUN.
OH, YOU DID?
WELL, IF YOU AIN'T COMIN' BACK,
THEN IT WOULDN'T BE A LOAN.
I THINK WHAT YOU'RE ASKIN' IS,
WILL I GIVE YOU A SHOTGUN?
YOU'VE GOT A FEW.
YEAH.
BUT I'VE HAD THEM GUNS
A LONG TIME.
AND IF I GAVE ONE AWAY,
I WOULDN'T SEE IT NO MORE.
AND I WOULDN'T SEE
THE FELLA I GIVE IT TO EITHER.
NOW, IT MIGHT BE I CAN GET ALONG
WITHOUT ONE OF MY SHOTGUNS,
BUT I DON'T WANNA LOSE A GRANDSON.
I WOULDN'T HAVE NONE LEFT.
SAY, DID YOU EVER THINK
OF BECOMIN' A MILLIONAIRE?
NO. IF I WAS YOU,
I'D GIVE THAT SOME THOUGHT.
[Screen Door Bangs]
- WHERE'S ARNOLD?
- NOT WITH ME.
WELL, WHERE IS HE?
I BET YOU HE'S GONE TO GRANDPA'S.
NORA, WHY DON'T YOU CALL?
ALL RIGHT.
IF HE'S GONE TO MY FATHER'S, YOU WANNA GO GET HIM?
[Nora] GRANDPA?
I THINK WE OUGHTA LET HIM DO WHAT
HE FEELS LIKE DOIN' FOR THE TIME BEING.
WHAT ELSE WOULD HE FEEL LIKE DOING
EXCEPT GETTIN' THE HELL OUT?
[Nora] IS ARNOLD OVER THERE?
WHO TALKS TO HIM LIKE HE CAN HEAR?
SHOULD SOMEONE COME GET HIM?
WHO LOOKS AT HIM LIKE HE CAN SEE?
NOT YOU, NOT NORA.
NOT ME.
BYE.
HE'S OVER THERE.
HE SAYS NO ONE SHOULD GO AND GET HIM.
WELL, LET HIM STAY THERE FOREVER.
SHALL WE DO THAT?
[Thunder Rumbling In Distance]
[Door Opens, Closes]
OLD PEA VINE'S ABOUT DUE.
YOU WANT A LITTLE COLT?
GONNA BE REAL PRETTY,
I BET.
WHERE'S ARNOLD?
ARNOLD? IS HE WITH YOUR FATHER?
I HEARD HE WAS.
YEAH, UH-HUH.
THE TWO OF 'EM LIVIN' LIKE A COUPLE
OF OLD CODGERS.
ARNOLD'S THE OLDER ONE.
HE'S GOIN' ON 90. HMM.
I WANNA GO.
YOU WANNA GO?
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO SAY,
"ANDY, I WANNA LIVE WITH YOU
THE REST OF MY LIFE."
NOT "I WANNA GO."
I WANNA GO.
YOU JUST GOT IT WRONG,
RIGHT?
BUT YOU WERE SURE SAYIN'
THE RIGHT THINGS LAST NIGHT.
I'LL TELL YOU THAT.
[Horse Whinnies]
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?
YOU NEVER LET ME SORROW.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
I LET YOU DO ANYTHING YOU WANT.
YOU NEVER LET ME SORROW FOR EUGENE.
YES, I DID.
I SURE DID.
YOU WERE SORROWING SO MUCH,
YOU NEEDED COMFORTIN'.
- SO DID I.
- NO.
YOU NEVER LET ME.
YEAH, RIGHT. IT'S ME.
IT'S ALWAYS ME. JOIN THE CLUB.
WHAT DO YOU THINK YOU CAN DO, JUST WALTZ
OUT OF HERE CLEAN LIKE A SPOON?
YOU JUST BROKE UP
MY MARRIAGE, HOTSHOT.
WHY DO YOU PUT ALL THE BLAME ON ME?
THAT'S WHERE IT LIES, AIN'T IT?
YOU JUST GOT A NEED.
THAT'S ALL, JUST A STRONG NEED.
NOTHIN' TO BE ASHAMED ABOUT.
[Whimpering, Crying]
ANDY, I JUST WANNA GO HOME. PLEASE.
I JUST WANNA WALK HOME.
[Exhales]
WELL, COME ON.
[Sniffles]
I'LL DRIVE YOU.
[Exhales]
[Thunder Rumbling]
SINCE I BROUGHT THE VENISON,
YOU DON'T MIND ME SITTIN' DOWN HERE
WITH THE FAMILY?
[Scoffs]
WHAT FAMILY?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
YOU STILL GOT FAMILY.
JUST... ONE MISSIN'.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,ONE?
EUGENE.
YOU KNOW WHOSE CHAIR
YOU'RE SITTIN' IN?
WELL, I DIDN'T KNOW ALL THE CHAIRS
HAD NAMES ON 'EM,
BUT, UH-- [Clears Throat]
WHOSE IS IT, ARNOLD'S?
THAT'S RIGHT.
IF YOU HADN'T HAD ARNOLD, IT'D BE EUGENE'S
CHAIR, AND EUGENE'D BE SITTIN' HERE.
AND YOU'D HAVE A CHAIR FOR COMPANY,
AND THERE WOULDN'T BE
NO BAD FEELIN'S.
YEAH, AND IF LU HADN'T LEFT YOU,
YOU'D BE SITTIN' AT YOUR OWN TABLE...
ON YOUR OWN CHAIR.
UH-HUH. IF THE RABBIT HADN'T STOPPED,
THE DOG WOULDN'T A-CAUGHT HIM.
IT JUST SEEMS TO ME ALL THE TROUBLE
STARTED WITH ARNOLD,
SO I DON'T KNOW WHY YOU MAKE IT SOUND
LIKE IT ALL STARTED WITH ME.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE IT STARTED.
WELL, IF IT DIDN'T START WITH ARNOLD,
THEN WHY DON'T JOE GO GET HIM
AND BRING HIM BACK HERE...
SO HE CAN BE SITTIN' HERE
INSTEAD OF ME?
YOU KNOW, I BEEN THINKIN'
ABOUT LITTLE OL' ARNOLD.
MAYBE HE AIN'T
SUCH A MEAN SON OF A BITCH
LIKE THE SHERIFF SAID HE WAS.
MAYBE HE'S JUST LIKE A WOMAN--
CAN'T BEAR TO ADMIT WHAT THEY DO TO YOU.
THEY JUST LOOK AT YOU LIKE,
"WHO, ME? WHAT'D I DO?"
THAT'S ENOUGH. OUT.
WHAT?
OUT OF MY HOUSE.
I HARDLY EVEN STARTED.
FINE. OUT OF MY HOUSE. OUT OF MY HOUSE.
ALL RIGHT. OKAY.
I'VE HARDLY EVEN BEGUN.
GET OUT OF MY HOUSE.
OUT.
DON'T BE TAKIN' OFF ON ME.
OKAY, JOE. YOU OUGHT TO GO GET ARNOLD,
BRING HIM BACK HERE.
OUT. YOU ACT LIKE I'M THE ONE THAT
TURNED YOU ALL AGAINST HIM.
I DIDN'T DO NOTHIN'.
DAMN. YOU OUGHT TO GO, JOE.
[Clears Throat]
BRING YOUR BOY BACK,
LET ME OFF THE HOOK.
GET OUT OF MY HOUSE.
GET OUT. OUT!
ALL RIGHT. OKAY.
I CAN TAKE A HINT.
GET OUTTA HERE.
I AIN'T STUPID, YOU KNOW.
DAMN.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU FOR THE SWELL DINNER!
I SURE DID LIKE THE DESSERT TOO.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH!
¶ I'M CALLIN' UP TO TELL YOU
THAT I LOVE YOU ¶
THAT I CARE ¶
- [Dogs Barking]
- ¶ AFTER ALL IS SAID AND DONE
YOU KNOW I'M THE ONLY ONE ¶
YOU GO GET ARNOLD.
YOU THINK THE HARD THINGS ARE...
JUST THE WORK YOU DO,
AND IF YOU
TAKE CARE OF THE WORK--
BUT THERE'S SOME HARDER
THINGS TO DO THAN WORK,
LIKE TRYIN' TO FEEL
WHAT YOUR SON IS FEELIN'.
YOU'D JUST RATHER NOT
SEE HIM AROUND.
WELL, I DON'T THINK YOU KNOW.
YOU'RE THE ONE THAT TALKS ABOUT WANDERING OFF.
WHY DON'T YOU GO AHEAD
AND JUST DO THAT?
LU RUNS OFF, HOPS ON A BUS, AND-AND--
AND  YOU TALK ABOUT WANDERING AWAY...
TO LOOK FOR YOUR MIND
LIKE YOU LOST THE DAMN THING.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT GOES ON IN ME
ABOUT ARNOLD.
YOU THINK I DON'T FEEL LOVE ANYMORE?
WELL, YOU DON'T KNOW.
YOU DON'T KNOW. [Slaps Counter]
CARROTS.
[Crying] AND, NORA, PLEASE DON'T
CRY AT THE DINNER TABLE.
DON'T CRY [Sniffling]
OKAY.
[Whimpering]
[Crying]
ARNOLD? ARNOLD?
ARNOLD.
HEY, ARNOLD.
I'VE BEEN CALLIN' YOU.
I DON'T HAVE THE MEASLES.
I GOT A CLEAN BILL OF HEALTH.
A WHAT?
I SAID, "A CLEAN BILL OF HEALTH."
NOBODY SAYS THAT ANYMORE.
MY DAD USED TO SAY THAT.
[Sighs] NOW, WHERE'S--
WHERE'S GEORGE AT?
HE WENT TO TOWN.
HOW COME YOU DIDN'T?
I DIDN'T FEEL LIKE IT.
WHAT, ARE YOU A HERMIT THESE DAYS?
- WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO WHEN SCHOOL STARTS?
- GO TO SCHOOL.
WELL, I COME TO BRING YOU HOME.
I DON'T BOTHER HI-HIM.
HE LIKES TO HAVE ME.
I'M NOT SAYIN' YOU BOTHER HIM.
I'M SAYIN' YOUR MOTHER WANTS YOU HOME, ARNOLD.
I'LL GO TO SCHOOL FROM HERE.
NOW GO GET YOUR STUFF.
GO ON.
LOOK, LU'S NOT THERE. SHE WENT BACK
TO HER OLD JOB BACK IN RENO.
AND ANDY'S NOT GONNA BE COMIN' AROUND
ANYMORE, 'CAUSE I DON'T WANT HIM THERE.
WHEN HE GETS OLD AND I'M NOT THERE ANYMORE
AND YOU WANT HIM TO COME AROUND, THAT'S OKAY.
BUT I DON'T WANT HIM THERE NOW.
LU'S NOT THERE,AND ANDY'S NOT THERE.
I WANT YOU TO COME ON HOME WITH ME.
I'VE BEEN LONESOME.
I DON'T LIKE MY BEDROOM.
I WANNA SLEEP IN THE GUEST ROOM.
SURE, FINE. WHATEVER YOU WANT.
IT JUST AIN'T WHERE I SLEEP.
WHEN YOU WANNA COME HOME,
YOU GET YOUR STUFF, YOU GIVE ME A CALL.
I'LL COME GET YOU.
DADDY, YOU GOIN' UP
TO GET THE CALF?
DADDY?
DADDY,
THE CALF'S RIGHT THERE.
DADDY, IT'S CAUGHT.
DADDY?
JUST LET HER STAY HERE.
HELL WITH IT.
THE COYOTES WILL GET HER.
MAYBE IT JUST DON'T MATTER.
WHAT?
IT DON'T MATTER.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST GO ON
BACK DOWN THE HILL AND LEAVE ME BE?
IT DON'T MATTER.
DON'T MATTER.
¶ [Car Radio: Country Rock]
COME ON.
HEY, YOU NEED A RIDE?
YEP.
COME ON. GET IN.
¶ [Continues, Indistinct]
READY?
YEP.
WHERE YOU BOUND FOR?
RENO, NEVADA.
I'VE BEEN THERE.
PRETTY.
I'M NOT GOIN' THERE TODAY THOUGH.
I'M GOIN' TO A RODEO.
I'VE BEEN TO TWO.
TWO RODEOS?
I'M GARY MADDOX.
ARNOLD HILLERMAN.
HI, ARNOLD.
¶ LORD, I LOVE
THAT COUNTRY MUSIC ¶
¶ JAMBOREE IN THE HILLS
EVERY SUMMER IN JULY ¶
LOTS OF FUN AND COUNTRY MUSIC ¶
HERE. YOU WANT SOME?
GO AHEAD.
GIVE IT A SHOT.
¶ THAT'S WHERE I WANT TO DIE ¶
¶ JAMBOREE IN THE HILLS ¶
EW!
LIKE IT?
MM-MMM!
¶ JAMBOREE IN THE HILLS ¶
- [People Chattering]
- [Woman] YOU GENTS WANT ANY DRINKS?
[Woman] SCOTCH?
[Continues, Indistinct]
[Man Chattering On P.A.,
Muffled, Indistinct]
[Bus Departing]
[People Chattering]
EXCUSE ME, HONEY.
YOU'RE TOO YOUNG TO BE IN HERE.
IS THERE SOMETHING
I CAN HELP YOU WITH?
DOES LUCILLE JANSEN WORK HERE?
LUCILLE JANSEN?
OH, LU. SURE.
ARE YOU A FRIEND OF HERS?
YEAH.
TELL YOU WHAT. WAIT RIGHT HERE,
AND I'LL GO IN AND FIND HER, ALL RIGHT?
DON'T GO AWAY NOW.
HEY, LU, THIS REALLY CUTE GUY'S
LOOKIN' FOR YOU.
WHAT DOES HE LOOK LIKE?
HE'S GOT DARK HAIR, AND HE'S VERY SHORT.
WHERE IS HE?
HE'S OVER THERE.
SEE YOU LATER.
THANKS.
LU?
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN' HERE?
WHERE ARE YOUR FOLKS--
YOUR MOM AND DAD?
- THEY'RE NOT HERE.
- YOU CAME HERE ALL BY YOURSELF?
[Sighs]
[Traffic Noise,
People Chattering]
DAMN SHOES.
[Door Closes]
DO YOU WANT SOMETHIN' TO EAT?
IT'S OKAY.
I GOT APPLES.
"IT'S OKAY.
I GOT APPLES."
YOU KNOW, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO GROVEL, ARNOLD.
[Door Opens, Closes]
GO AHEAD. SIT DOWN.
GO ON.
[Sighs]
[Exhales]
WHAT AM I GONNA DO WITH YOU?
I SUPPOSE YOU CAME DOWN HERE
THINKIN' YOU COULD GET ME
TO APOLOGIZE FOR HURTIN' YOU.
GONNA GET ME TO SAY,
"OH, THE POOR KID.
POOR KID."
- IT AIN'T THAT.
- WELL, WHAT IS IT?
LU?
I DID HARM.
I DID HARM TO EUGENE.
AND AFTER HIM, I DID HARM TO YOU.
[Beer Can
Slides On Table]
I CAME TO SAY, LU,
I DIDN'T MEAN HARM.
NOBODY MEANT HARM, ARNOLD.
WELL, I GUESS YOU BETTER
GO ON HOME NOW.
THIS AIN'T NO PLACE FOR KIDS,
YOU KNOW.
I DON'T THINK I'LL BE UP
IN THE MORNIN' WHEN YOU LEAVE,
SO I'LL GIVE YOU SOME MONEY.
WHEN I GET UP, I'LL CALL YOUR MOM AND
TELL HER YOU'RE COMING HOME ON A BUS.
AND YOU MAKE SURE YOU USE THIS MONEY
TO GO HOME AND NOWHERE ELSE,
OR IT'S GONNA
BRING YOU BAD LUCK.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
I KNOW A LOT OF THINGS
YOU DON'T KNOW.
SO, UH, WHAT'S GOIN' ON HERE?
- OH, HI, BABE.
- HI.
UM, THIS IS ARNOLD.
HOW YA DOIN', ARNOLD?
WHAT'S HE DOIN' HERE?
I DON'T KNOW.
HE JUST SHOWED UP.
HE'S NOT IN TROUBLE AGAIN,
IS HE?
OH, NO.
OH. ACTUALLY, I'VE BEEN TELLING
HIM TO KEEP OUT OF TROUBLE.
GOOD. SO, HOW YOU DOIN',
ARNOLD?
HUH?
SO, UH--
I'LL JUST GO UPSTAIRS, HUH?
YOU ALL RIGHT?
OH, YEAH.
[Kisses]
OKAY.
I'LL BE UPSTAIRS.
SO, HOW'S OL' ANDY?
I GUESS HE'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU KNOW,
WHAT I THOUGHT WAS LOVE
REALLY WASN'T LOVE AT ALL.
IT WAS JUST WANTIN' TO BE LOVED.
[Sighs]
YEAH.
LIKE HIM.
HE SAYS HE LOVES ME.
HOW DO I KNOW?
[Laughs] HOW DOES ANYBODY KNOW?
OH.
[Voice Quavering] YOU KNOW, EVERY TIME
I START THINKIN' ABOUT ANDY,
MY HANDS START SHAKIN' AND--
[Sniffles]
I START DROPPIN' COINS
ALL OVER THE FLOOR AT WORK,
AND THEY'RE ROLLIN' AROUND,
AND I--
MY HEART STARTS POUNDIN'.
YEAH. YEAH, THEY GOT
THESE WINDOWS WHERE I WORK...
UP IN THE CEILING, AND-- AND THEY
LOOK DOWN ON EVERYBODY WORKIN' THERE...
TO MAKE SURE THAT NOBODY'S
STEALIN' FROM THEM.
AND I'M STANDING THERE,
MY HANDS ARE SHAKIN'--
[Laughing] AND THE COINS ARE ROLLING
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
AND THEY'RE LOOKIN' DOWN, AND I'M GOIN',
"OH, JESUS, THEY CAN SEE MY HANDS ARE SHAKIN'.
[Sniffles] AND THEN THEY'RE
GONNA FIRE ME."
I WOULDN'T FIRE YOU.
[Sniffles]
[Crying]
OH.
[Sighs]
[Laughing]
SILLY ME.
I'M GONNA BE OKAY.
[Baby Fussing]
[Woman Chattering]
DON'T CRY.
DO YOU WANNA
GO TO SLEEP NOW?
[Baby
Continues Fussing]
WHERE YOU BOUND FOR?
YOU NEVER HEARD OF IT.
WELL, RENO IS A GOOD PLACE TO LEAVE.
THE PLACE WHERE I'M GOIN' IS A GOOD PLACE
TO LEAVE. WHY YOU GOIN' THERE THEN?
YOU KNOW WHAT I DID?
WHAT, LOST ALL YOUR MONEY?
DID YOU GAMBLE IT ALL AWAY?
[Voice Quavering]
I WAS GOIN' HUNTIN',
GET SOME DUCKS.
GUN GOT CAUGHT ON THE WIRE.
I KILLED EUGENE.
[Crying]
I COULDN'T BELIEVE IT.
- HEY, GRANDPA.
- WELL, HELLO THERE.
YOU BACK FOR A WHILE?
YOU KNOW THAT NOTE YOU LEFT ME?
YOU SPELLED "RENO, NEVADA"
LIKE IT WAS ONE WORD.
IT'S TWO WORDS.
WHAT WAS I SUPPOSED TO THINK,
MAYBE YOU'D GONE TO CHINA?
I SAW LU.
- GRANDPA, I SAW LU.
- OH, I HEARD YOU.
YOU KNOW, YOU DIDN'T NEED TO GO CLEAR
TO RENO, NEVADA, TO SEE LU.
SON, ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW
IS WHAT I'VE BEEN TELLING YOU.
MAYBE YOU WANTED TO HEAR IT
FROM A WOMAN, THOUGH, HUH?
KIND OF SOFT AND SWEET
AND GENTLE.
- YOU HUNGRY?
- YEAH.
GOOD.
COME ON. I'LL FEED YOU.
I'LL FIX YOU SOMETHIN' TO EAT,
MAYBE TAKE YOU TO THE CARNIVAL.
MAYBE SHOW YOU THE FAT LADY
AND THE GEEK SHOW.
¶ [Carnival] ALL RIGHT. FIFTY CENTS.
FIFTY CENTS. STEP RIGHT UP.
COME ON UP. LADY, WHAT ARE YOU WAITIN' FOR?
WANNA BE SCARED OUTTA YOUR WITS?
GIVE ME ONE OF THEM.
WHAT FLAVOR, SIR?
SAME AS THAT, ONLY MORE JUICE.
¶ [Continues]
[Chattering]
WHAT DO YOU WANNA DO?
WHERE YOU WANNA GO FIRST?
MM. I WANNA TAKE YOU
ON THE FERRIS WHEEL.
WHOSE MONEY?
[Laughing]
MINE OR YOURS?
YOUR MONEY.
WHAT'S MINE IS YOURS. WHAT'S MINE
IS MY OWN, OKAY? THANK YOU.
IT'S A STUPID GAME.
HERE.
SEE IF YOU CAN FIND THE FREAK SHOW.
COME HERE.
HOW ARE YOU?
HOW HAVE YOU BEEN?
I HAVEN'T SEEN YOU.
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN
COMIN' AROUND LATELY.
WELL, YOU'VE HAD YOUR GRANDSON
THERE WITH YOU.
YOU DOIN' OKAY?
I'M FINE. HE'LL BE GOIN'
TO SCHOOL NOW SOON.
SO YOU COME AROUND, OKAY?
OKAY.
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Barker] COME ON IN,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
COME ON IN.
ALL RIGHT.
FIFTY CENTS. FIFTY CENTS.
STEP RIGHT UP
AND SEE THE PETRIFIED MAN.
THE PETRIFIED MAN.
ONLY 50 CENTS. COME ON IN.
YOU'VE NEVER SEEN NOTHIN' LIKE THIS
IN YOUR LIFE.
IF YOU WANNA BE SCARED,
IF YOU THINK YOU'VE BEEN SCARED,
OR YOU HAD NIGHTMARES--
HA!
COME UP HERE,
AND WE'LL SHOW YOU
WHAT SCARING IS ALL ABOUT.
YOUR MOTHER WILL SCARE YOU.
YOUR FATHER WILL SCARE YOU.
YOU THINK THAT'LL SCARE YOU?
COME ON IN HERE
AND LET ME SHOW YOU
WHAT'LL SCARE YOU.
COME ON UP!
ONLY 50 CENTS!
[People Shouting, Screaming]
[Crowd Exclaiming]
- [Fireworks Continue Bursting]
- [No Audible Dialogue]
[Fireworks Whistling,
Bursting]
[Exclaiming]
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
[No Audible Dialogue]
YOU OKAY?
YOU ALL RIGHT?
[Crying]
[Fireworks Whistling,
Bursting]
¶ [Carnival Fades, Ends]
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+ |T|h|e| |D|e|a|f| |B|o|y|s| |F|o|r| |B|o|y|s| |G|r|o|u|p|  +
E N J O Y   this   SRT   SUBTITLE   R e l e a s e
http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0088176
The Stone Boy (1984) English for hearing-impaired.srt
FPS: 29.976
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+ |T|h|e| |D|e|a|f| |B|o|y|s| |F|o|r| |B|o|y|s| |G|r|o|u|p|  +
We want more subtitles right NOW!
1) All DVDs to be subtitled
2) All VIDEO GAMES to be subtitled
3) All videos/DVDs used in lessons at school to be subtitled
4) More pre-recorded & live subtitles on TV
__       _             _            _        _            _
//_ _   / | _  _ _/|  /_)_      _  /_`_  _  /_)_      _  / `__     _
// //_' /_.'/_'/_|/   /_)/_//_/_\  /  /_//  /_)/_//_/_\  /_;//_//_//_/
_/                    _/              /