No one in need
who has ever approached you...
...the generous citizens
of Lake Forest, Illinois...
...has ever been refused.
Therefore, although
the United States...
...has not yet entered
the war in Europe...
...we of the American
Ambulance Service...
...have continued to donate men,
women and equipment...
...to aid our unfortunate wounded
French and British friends.
I want to thank this year's graduating
class of Lake Forest College...
...for this badly needed vehicle.
Hear, hear!
But more important,
I want to thank...
...the two brave members
of that class...
...who have volunteered to accompany
the ambulance overseas as drivers.
- Mr. Gray Maturin.
- Hey!
- That's my boy! That's my boy!
- Thanks, Pop.
And Mr. Larry Darrell.
Now, in order to raise funds
for this noble cause...
...Mr. Maturin is going to give
demonstration rides...
...around the village green...
...for the small donation
of 5 cents a person.
- The line forms to the right.
- You're first, ladies. Go on.
I do wish Mr. Darrell
had made his appearance.
I assure you, madam,
whatever Mr. Darrell is doing...
...he is servicing the needs
of your fine organisation.
I'm gonna take this whiskey,
okay? Got it?
Aren't you the cutest little
hat rack I've ever seen?
And don't scratch that pretty face.
Come on, let's go.
Kisses, 1 dollar?
I sure will, ma'am. Here you are.
One dollar.
It's amazing, isn't it?
I seem to have left my money
in my other uniform.
- You mean your Boy Scout uniform?
- Well, I just take what I want.
No! No!
Oh, you're getting heavy.
That hurt.
It's nice working for free.
Come on.
- Hey, Gray, can I get a ride?
- Jump in. All aboard.
Larry, I'm supposed to be
doing my patriotic duty.
Come on, your patriotic duty
my last night in town...
...is to leave me unable to walk.
- Come on. Seriously.
- Oh, no, no.
First the wedding,
then the honeymoon. Yeah.
Do it the other way around,
you end up like Bob and Sophie...
...stuck in that dumb old apartment.
I like that place.
How do you think they'll like it
when the baby comes?
- I don't know.
- No charge to boys in uniform.
Oh, well done. Very good.
Our baby's gonna have
its own room and a nanny...
Why don't you talk
to Gray about getting married.
He's got a million bucks.
He'll go for that nanny stuff.
Hey, look, I don't want a million bucks.
I just want you...
...and half a million bucks.
This is the singly
most disgusting concoction...
...in the culinary annals.
Well, that didn't stop you
eating a dozen of them...
...every Fourth of July
when you were a boy, Elliot.
This quaint little village may be
the place of my birth...
...but after 15 years in Paris...
...I've come to regard that as a most
unfortunate accident of genetics.
Oh, Elliot, you are the biggest snob
in the world.
I sincerely hope so.
Nice-looking dog you got there, Unc.
Oh, how I envy you, young man.
Off to Paris, the City of Light.
Oh, my God.
I really ought to provide you
with a few introductions.
I could put you in touch with some
of the most elite members...
...of the European aristocracy
while you're there.
- Sophie, Bob, where you guys been?
- Hi.
Oh, Bob had to work.
- On a holiday? Gee, what a shame.
- Yeah.
Yeah, I almost missed seeing you
and Gray off. They kept me late.
Well, you're late, but you're
not too late to come with us!
- Bobby boy! Bobby boy!
- Hey!
Put him down! He's a dad!
He's not going anywhere!
- Can Bob play on the ambulance, then?
- No!
I don't have any life insurance!
Soph, what?
Here.
I had these printed up for you.
Your poems.
This is great.
Now I'll have something to read
to the guys in the trenches at night.
You used to like them.
Well, they're good.
I always liked the poet.
I'm gonna miss you.
You know, when we were kids...
...I was always terrified you were
the guy I was gonna have to marry.
But you just couldn't control yourself,
could you?
"Oh, Bob. Oh, Bob. Bob, don't.
Oh, Bob, don't!
Stop. Whatever you do, Bob, don't!
Oh, Bob."
Larry, Sophie, come on,
the fireworks are gonna start!
- Can you hold this?
- Sure.
Thanks.
Thanks, Gray.
Hey, Bobby. Thank you.
Oh, God! More!
They're beautiful!
- Hey!
- Isn't that beautiful?
Hi.
This ambulance field headquarters?
Chicago. I know people in Chicago.
Jeez, you must be
the guys from Chicago.
Piedmont.
Fresh meat.
Fit them out, Malcolm.
I'm Piedmont.
I'm your leader.
That's Malcolm.
He's what's left of my followers.
We put three heaps to a squad.
There'll be you,
some dogmeat from Harvard...
...and our rig when it gets ready.
What the hell's the gun for?
America's not in the war.
Well, yes and no.
We don't get to kill anybody,
but they can kill us.
There's a big push on
tomorrow at Mons.
We leave the minute
this Harvard heap arrives.
Mr. Piedmont, I presume?
Doug Van Allen and Brian Ryan,
Harvard, '17.
- You must be Chicago.
- Lake Forest, actually.
- Larry Darrell.
- Doug Van Allen.
- Brian Ryan.
- Gray Maturin.
- How do you do?
- Larry Darrell.
- No trouble clearing this off the train?
- None, sir.
- Isn't she beautiful?
- Swellegant.
Hi, meat.
That paint job's
gonna make a great target.
Not the way we drive.
Doug and I did the six-mile course
at Harvard in six and a half.
Is that right?
Six and a half.
Piedmont and I did it at Yale
in six flat.
Okay, for now, I'll ride with Darrell.
Malcolm, you take Gray meat.
You two follow in Moby Dick.
Let's move!
- What is this foul stuff?
- Well, this definitely isn't chicken.
Oh, it's chicken.
Head, skin and feet.
Hey, Chicago, why don't you
finish this potted shrimp.
You betcha.
Thanks.
- Shrimp?
- Yes.
Shrimp?
God, what a car.
Thanks, Piedmont.
- Goddamn it! Are you crazy?
- You can't have headlights.
The heinies catch a flash of those
headlights, you guys are dead meat.
- Goddamn it, you're drunk!
- Drunk?
The liquor never even makes it
to my brain, Dougie boy.
You're educated men.
Let's get this over with.
You came over here for a little fun,
a little excitement...
...and to help your fellow man.
Well, you won't help anybody.
And you know why? Because you
can't even help yourselves.
And after the first good
mortar concussion...
...you'll be picking that windshield
right out of your face...
...so you might as well
get rid of it right now.
- Piedmont, what are you doing?
- I am helping my fellow man.
Gray, Darrell, come here!
The hospital is eight kilometres.
Don't stop for anything.
No matter what happens, don't stop!
Piedmont, there has got to be
something else.
- You got a driver's licence?
- Licence?
Don't stop, Larry.
- What's he saying?
- Didn't they teach French in college?
I was a baseball major.
What does he want?
He says his arm is shattered,
and it's pinned under the body...
...of another guy who won't move,
because he's already dead.
He's sure he's dying...
...and if you had the decency of half
a human being, you'd do something!
I don't know what he wants!
Don't stop, Larry!
All right, boys, everybody sing
or we aim for the ruts!
Oh, my God, I've been hit!
- What are you doing?
- Doug's been hit!
Hey, Doug Van Allen's
been hit. In his wrist.
Well, Piedmont says not to stop.
Darrell, Doug and I crewed together!
Doug Van Allen and Brian Ryan,
wasn't it?
Jeez, what a couple of liars, huh?
They loved to lie, those two.
They enjoyed it.
They never did any goddamn
six miles in six and a half.
Maybe you don't, but I hate liars.
I hated those two
when they told their little lies.
They won't be missed.
Green River at the sweetshop.
The first thing I'm gonna have
when we get home.
Could be any day now too...
...now that Uncle Sam's in the war.
You okay?
It's getting light.
Come on!
- How are you?
- I'm bad.
We need help.
- What now?
- Now we wait.
Hey, Piedmont.
- What was that?
- Grenade.
- Horseshit.
- Okay, it was some woman's tee shot.
Darrell, look out!
Nice going, Piedmont.
He was a slob.
Did you ever see him eat?
Starving children could
fill their bellies...
...on the food that ended up
on his beard and clothes.
Dogs would gather...
...to watch him eat.
I never understood gluttony.
But I hate it.
I hated that about you.
He enjoyed disgusting people...
...being disgusting,
the thrill of offending people...
...and making them uncomfortable.
He was despicable.
He will not be missed.
I'm very sorry. It was my fault.
It was my fault, really.
Now, let's try again.
More champagne! Fine.
Look out, here comes Frankie.
- What a generation.
- No, no, let them burn off some steam.
The war heroes have earned it.
But come next week, I'll work the two
of those boys ragged at the office.
Next week?
It's the first I've heard of it.
Larry's been so quiet about things
since he got back.
Hi. I think we need to talk.
Larry, this has been going on
for three weeks.
Did it ever occur to you
that I might be in training?
that you might be avoiding me?
- Okay, let's talk.
- No, Larry, you come out.
Larry! Damn it!
Okay, let's talk.
Seal talk.
Thank you.
We all believe in you, Larry.
I mean, Mother and myself
and Mr. Maturin.
And we all know that you've
had some kind of a...
...well, shock over there,
and that...
Well, that you just needed time
to kind of "loaf around"...
...as you put it.
But...
...doesn't it seem that it's time to...?
To get back on your feet again?
Yeah.
No.
What?
I wanna put off the wedding
for a while.
I wanna put off the job too.
For a while anyway.
I don't understand.
In your letter,
all you talked about was...
...coming back and getting married
and starting the job.
I lied.
I didn't know I was lying...
...but I guess I was.
I see.
I don't think I'm the guy
you wanna marry right now.
This isn't the old Mr. Sunshine.
I'm not happy.
I can't make myself happy.
I couldn't make you happy.
I just wanna think.
I need to think...
...and I don't have much
experience in that field.
Think?
Think about what?
I don't know.
Me, you, our lives.
I'll tell you when I start thinking.
So you want me and everyone else
to just go on and on...
...sitting here, waiting for you
to figure out the meaning of life?
- Well, sort of, yeah.
- Well, that's just great.
- Okay, well, we'll... We'll see.
- Yeah, you wait. You wait.
My money is in...
Your money's in my pocket.
Bob?
As long as he's on their team,
we're bound to win.
Right.
Bob?
I'm sorry. I'm afraid we should leave
now if you're gonna make it for work.
Come on, hon. One more scrum.
We're three goals behind.
You can't take him from us now.
I've got a bet on with Gray.
Oh, yes I can, Tyler.
What are you making
at that sweatbox anyway?
I'll buy them out for the night.
Thanks anyway, Tyler, but I think
you can manage without him.
All right.
We'll just have to play
five on six, then.
- See you, Gray.
- See you, Bobby.
- Is everything all right, dear?
- Mom, there's been a change of plans.
We're going to postpone
the wedding, just for a while.
- You're what?
- Now, don't start one of your things.
It's just for a while.
He wants to be by himself right now,
so he's going to Paris.
Paris.
I think he needs a little time by
himself. I'm gonna give him that.
Oh, Isabel, don't be so naive.
It's just an excuse.
It is not an excuse!
He loves me.
You know, if I may say so, Louisa...
...it makes perfect sense to me.
All Americans should avail
themselves...
...of at least one season in Paris...
...just prior to marriage.
It curbs the itches
which tend to rise...
...a year or two
down the connubial pike.
Elliot, don't be vulgar.
People think I'm being vulgar
when I'm being serious...
...and they think I'm being serious
when I'm being vulgar.
- Then you'll take care of him for me?
- Of course I will.
I'll arrange his passage for him.
You know, the people
you meet on the ship...
...often set the tone
for the entire tour.
I think the Mauretania for Larry.
Yes. Yes, the Mauretania.
He'll sit at the captain's table...
...and meet all the right people.
Then he'll need a first-class hotel
where he can entertain.
I think a suite at the Georges V
would be perfect.
Roland!
Don't worry, we'll have your boyfriend
back to you in no time.
Well, hello. Welcome to Paris.
- Louisa, my dear, at last.
- Elliot.
- It's so good to see you.
- And here she is.
Hi, Uncle Elliot.
Welcome to my humble abode.
Come in, my dear.
- Oh, thank you.
- How was your crossing?
- I read it was a little inclement.
- Well, it wasn't too good.
Come along, Cinderella.
Oh, Elliot.
This is a palace.
Why, thank you. I'm glad you like it.
Oh, my God.
This is my music room.
Oh, isn't that lovely?
Oh, what a beautiful piano.
Well, it's a spinet by Larande...
...late-18 th-century French.
- It must have cost a fortune.
- It did.
My poor dear friend the viscount
de Corvence had to part with it...
...at a slight reduction...
...but then, estates are so draining
on one these days, don't you find?
And are all these things for sale?
My dear Louisa, this isn't a shop.
I occasionally allow the odd piece
to be torn from my grasp.
You've got that
lovely picture of Mother.
This room...
I never dreamed anyone
could ever live like this.
Why, it's not difficult
if you know what you want.
This outfit looks really
ridiculous, doesn't it?
Especially over here.
- I'm such a mess.
- The dress is.
We'll get you a new one.
You, yourself, are exquisite.
You belong in a room like this.
It and everything in it
will be yours someday.
I had hoped that you might
grow up in this house.
You're the only family I have.
But your mother preferred to remain
in the cow pastures of Illinois.
No worry, I realise why you finally
deigned to visit your old uncle.
Larry's stayed here longer
than you expected, hasn't he?
I assure you I did
everything I promised you.
I invited him to parties, he claimed
he didn't have a dinner jacket.
I asked him to lunch,
he said he didn't eat lunch.
Elliot Templeton gets the message.
Nice catch.
Be careful, my dear.
That one plate is worth more...
...than your young man has earned
in a whole year.
Hello, Mr. Templeton.
- Hello, Mrs. Bradley.
- Hello, Larry.
I'm sorry that I'm late,
but I had to pick up the band.
I hope you'll forgive me.
In case you get the chill.
We cross the fingers.
- Who are they?
- They're from Les Halles.
I work with them in the stalls.
Work?
I thought you came over here
to think.
Well, I did. But I learned too much.
I'd read so many books,
you could smell wood burning.
So I took a job packing fish.
Packing fish?
Yeah, it's a good job.
I like it.
Well, that's great.
I mean, that you like it.
Is that what you're gonna tell
Mr. Maturin when you see him?
That you kept him waiting six months
because you like to pack fish?
I'm not going back.
I'm not going to be a stockbroker.
Marry me. We can raise a family.
We can travel.
I have $3000 . That is more
than most people live on.
Larry...
...we are not most people.
- We're special people.
- Iz, nobody is special.
I'm special.
I am not gonna spend my whole life
tagging along behind you...
...making both ends meet.
- Come on.
- No, Larry. Come on.
It's not fair.
I've lived up to my half of the bargain.
You haven't lived up to yours.
I should just give this back to you.
Don't give it back.
Wear it on another finger.
It will mean...
...that there is one man somewhere...
...who will always love you.
- What does that mean?
- Look, I got a second chance at life.
I am not gonna waste it on a big house,
a new car every year...
...and a bunch of friends who want
a big house and a new car every year!
I can't turn back now.
I want you to come with me.
Would you like
a chilled glass of Chablis?
Yeah.
So, what do you do
when it's hot outside?
Drink red.
Did you read all these books?
I skimmed them.
To think I used to help you
with your homework.
Yeah, you got me
through grade school.
It wasn't that hard, really, you know.
All you had to do was...
Was what they told you to do.
Well, I'm doing my own thinking now.
- I want to speak with Isabel.
- But she's not here, Monsieur Larry.
You're not doing butler stuff
on me, are you?
Isabel?
Isabel?!
Joseph.
Isabel has gone. She and her mother
have taken the boat train.
Joseph, I appear to have been
crashing about again...
...without my spectacles.
I'm really very, very sorry.
Bob, hurry up, they're coming.
Here, they're coming now.
Thank you.
Goodbye. Thank you.
- You're a lucky man.
- Thank you.
Sally.
Be back in the office by Monday.
Let's have a drink.
Hello, Mary, Shirley.
I wonder if we'll ever see him again.
He'll come back, but he'll
be a little late, won't he?
I wonder if she'll still let Gray
give him that job.
Oh, God, Bob,
Larry doesn't want that job.
That's refreshing.
Who do you think you're saving?
- Have a drink with me.
- What for?
I owe you my life.
My life's worth one drink.
How about some cards?
Well, I've watched you play.
I think you must cheat.
I've watched you read.
You read funny books
for a coal miner.
Oh, yes, that. There's a god of light
and a god of darkness.
Heaven for good people and hell
for bad ones. You believe that?
I believe...
...that you're saving nines.
What else do you read?
The Apocalypse, Essenes,
Aristotle, Plato?
What about Znachar,
the Russian sorcerer?
The Upanishads?
You've never read the Upanishads?
You don't know so much.
You really don't know anything,
do you?
Lend me your copy.
I never lend books to coal miners.
They've got dirty hands.
- Have you been to India?
- What's in India?
Hundreds of millions of people
that pray three times a day.
There are answers there.
India's a lonely place.
If I'd stayed...
...I never would have known
this little one.
Very good.
I'm a good cheater.
Here. The Upanishads.
But you won't find
the answers in a book.
You'll have to go there.
What about her husband
and her son?
They were killed instantly.
A drunken driver. Head-on.
Oh, Sophie.
Izzy.
Baby.
My baby's gone.
Bob, he's gone.
Oh, my God!
At least...
...they didn't suffer.
Get out of here.
- Izzy, get her out of here!
- Please, please.
This is a sad time, Mrs. MacDonald...
...but it is also a day for rejoicing.
Our Lord has promised to call us
all home to him in heaven.
And today he has called home
your husband and child.
You're like idiots.
They're dead, you freak!
They're dead!
Dead! Get away from me
with that thing!
Are you gonna be here in a week
when I wake up?
In a month? In a year?
For the rest of my life?
Mrs. MacDonald,
I know you're upset.
What do you know?
I had that baby inside of me!
I had that man inside of me!
You, you've never had
anyone inside of you!
- Oh, lzzy! No!
- Please!
- All right. You'll have to leave.
- No!
- Izzy, don't leave me! Don't go!
- Please.
- Izzy, don't leave me, please!
- Sister.
- Sister, hold her.
- No! What happens now?
No, lzzy, don't go!
All right. All right, it's all right.
Izzy!
You need guide, sahib?
No, my friend. Thank you. Here.
- More rupees. More rupees.
- How are you?
More rupees.
Is this your sister?
Here.
Here's 2 rupees.
Give one to your sister now.
Okay. All right, there's 5.
Split them up, okay?
Help me out here, pal!
Come here! Come in here!
Okay, thank you.
I like it. I like it. I'll take it.
- Cigarette?
- No, thank you.
You must find it pleasant to be rich.
I'm not rich.
I'm often mistaken.
I worked in a coal mine
to come over here.
A coal mine?
What was the intention?
- To make money to come over here.
- That was the reason.
What was the intention?
Because if work has no intention,
it's not work at all.
It's an empty motion.
Well, what would you call
washing dishes?
For me, this is
a religious experience.
Hey, let me try that.
Yeah, I feel it.
Kind of like being in church.
Pass me the soap, will you, bishop?
I could take you to a better church.
In the mountains.
I've been there
many times before to work.
It's a difficult place to reach.
- It's a difficult place to work.
- Who washes the dishes up there?
- Could you leave at dawn?
- Want me to talk to your boss?
Boss? I have no boss.
I own this boat.
And a few more.
Ta-da!
- Too much?
- Very good.
Smashing, in fact.
What do you think, honey?
Too much? Not enough?
Is this gonna help?
Is this gonna get me anything?
What do you think?
No?
Well, gee, I know
what this one here is...
...but shouldn't this one
be walking by now?
I mean, did you ever think of giving it
a cold shower or an aspirin?
I could do pretty well
up here, I think.
They see few Westerners up here.
They see none
where we are heading.
Our guides.
That's the church, Larry.
Now, let's hurry.
Must get back to my boats.
I have been waiting for you. Welcome.
You are welcome.
Fabulous, fabulous, fabulous.
Excuse me.
Are you having a good time?
Well, I thought I told you two
it was time for bed.
- I'm sorry, Mrs. Maturin.
- It's all right, Barbara.
I'll take them up.
Come on, angel face.
I hear you bond boys are losing
a lot of your clients' money.
Yeah. What does your old man
think of that, Gray?
Well, think what you like
about my old man, Tyler.
Believe me, I know
how difficult he is to live with.
But the fact is, he's a good man.
A damn good man.
Excuse me, sir. Telephone.
- They have their baths?
- They did. Yes.
We'll tell a nice story.
How are you?
Hello. Yes.
I'm telling you, there's 12 percent
unemployment out there.
And we're really feeling it.
I think Roosevelt's right.
We got a depression on our hands.
Gray!
Did you see that?
It was a nice service for your dad.
- Yeah, short and sweet.
- Yeah?
Hey, nice tic you got there, Gray.
Here. Have a shot.
It'll go faster for a minute,
and then it'll stop.
- No, thanks.
- No?
Hey, look at that freak. Why didn't he
jump in the grave with your dad?
Oh, Sophie, please.
Let's not fall apart, okay?
Gee, lzzy...
...to tell you the truth,
I fell apart a while ago.
So, what did the monsignor say?
I told him that Pop always kept
a gun in his office...
...and he kept large amounts of cash.
And while he was cleaning the gun...
...it accidentally went off.
Hey.
Easy, Gray.
You sound like
you're starting to believe that.
It is time to go.
The lama is waiting for you.
There is a hut in the mountain.
The lama likes you to go there.
I packed your books.
I am sad...
...because I am losing my cook.
Yes, I'm leaving.
Isn't it true...
...it is easy to be a holy man
on the top of a mountain?
You are closer than you think.
The path to salvation is narrow
and as difficult to walk...
...as a razor's edge.
Good God, Romulus and Remus.
Now, Joseph, you see...
...this is not fit for a gerbil.
That, on the other hand,
minus an outer leaf or two...
...is positively Rousseauvian
in its beauty, and at half the price.
Pay the man. Half what he asks you.
Hello, boys.
Good God, Darrell, I was under
the impression that you'd vanished.
You know that Isabel
is here in Paris with me?
This wretched Depression
cleaned them out.
Poor old Gray lost everything.
Gray? Gray Maturin and Isabel?
And they have two children.
Gray hasn't worked
for two-and-a-half years.
But I can see you're busy.
I'll give your best to everyone.
Come, Joseph.
Look, why don't you...
...take a wash and drop by sometime.
Thank you.
Would you tell your mother
Uncle Larry is here?
- Okay.
- Yeah.
Mama, Mama, Uncle Larry's here!
Thanks, girls.
You go out and play, all right?
I was hoping you might stop by.
Well, I had to make sure the children
didn't look too much like Gray.
- Where is he?
- He's upstairs.
Honey?
Larry.
- Good to see you.
- How you doing?
I was downstairs this morning.
Wish you'd caught me then.
Got another one
of my damn headaches.
Sometimes they're so bad...
...I feel like I'm gonna die.
Sometimes I wish I was dead.
Gray, sometimes all of us
wish you were dead.
What are you doing here?
This is guy talk.
We're gonna talk about girls.
We don't want you around. Bye.
Bye.
How are you doing?
Not bad, for me.
You haven't tried aspirin
for these headaches?
I've got something that might work.
Here.
Hold it in your hand.
Clasp your fingers tightly around it.
Hand out, palm down.
No big deal. I'm gonna count to 10.
And before I get to 10,
you're gonna drop the coin.
One, two, three, four...
...five, six...
...seven, eight...
- How did you do that?
- I didn't do it. You did it.
Here's what you're gonna do next.
Hold the coin in your hand again.
Gently, this time.
Let your hand rest on your lap.
Lie back.
Relax.
Relax your whole body.
Your eyelids are gonna get heavy.
They're going to close.
You're going to sleep...
...for three minutes.
And when you wake up...
...your headache will be gone.
Where'd it go?
God, it's good
to see her smile again.
- It's good to have you back.
Nice being here.
Okay, now we go here.
Oh, hey, go and tickle
Uncle Larry like crazy.
Oh, children, children,
Monsieur Larry is not ticklish.
You traitor.
- Oh, mama. Your mommy's ticklish.
- No!
Mama is very ticklish.
Thank you, Joseph.
There's a lot of energy
in this place. I feel it.
A little less than there was
a minute ago.
Oh, Larry.
This is good. You're gonna like this.
Well, for chrissake.
Sophie.
Larry.
Goddamn.
I thought you were dead
or something worse.
- What are you doing in Paris?
- Our old friends didn't tell you?
I guess it must have
slipped their minds.
Been trying to call you lately.
I even came around to the house
the other night, but I guess...
...it was a little late for you.
- How have you been, Sophie?
- I've been having a regular riot, lzzy.
My loving in-laws ran me
out of Chicago.
They didn't care for my behaviour.
Our old friends here don't care
for my behaviour either, but...
...that's okay.
I got lots of new friends.
How's Bob?
Bob?
Oh, Bob...
Been having a regular riot too,
isn't he, Gray?
There was an accident.
Bob and Matthew were killed.
Sophie's been under
a lot of strain lately.
I've been under a lot of strain?
Honey, you looked in a mirror lately?
You will excuse my little friend.
Sometimes she smokes too much
of the Chinaman's pipe.
Perhaps you find her amusing.
Would you like a private room
upstairs? Forty francs.
- Twenty for her, 20 for the linen.
- How dare you!
You bastard, why don't you just
get the hell out of here.
- But see, we're old friends of Sophie's.
- For you, 30 francs.
- Okay, deal.
- For 30 minutes.
Don't kid with Coco. He doesn't
have much of a sense of humour.
Got a clock, Coco?
In my head, monsieur.
Doesn't leave room
for much else, does it?
Gee, you were right.
You just can't kid with Coco.
Let's call it an evening. Okay?
We'd like to go home, Joseph.
Not so fast, you're our ride home.
It occurred to me that I wouldn't
have to pay for the linen at my place.
You sure you both don't wanna
come to our house?
- We'll be fine.
- Good night.
Come on, let's run.
You think I can't run.
Here, here, go ahead.
Come on. Come on.
Where the hell do you live anyway?
It's this set of steps and one other.
Hey! I didn't tell you about
the incredible view that I have.
You've never seen anything like it.
Larry, you don't know
where I've been.
Get up these stairs! Get up there!
Come on, come on.
It's kind of a bachelor's place,
but I'll go straighten up.
What a dump.
Are we there...? Are we there yet?
Almost. Bring that up
for me, will you?
Lance Romance, huh?
Would you care to dance?
- You know...
- Get me out of here!
...It's getting hard to find an apartment
that doesn't have hot water...
...but I found this fabulous landlord.
That is refreshing, isn't it?
You bastard!
Larry?
Oh, thanks. Big trouble.
The landlord's making me paint the
place. You're gonna have to help.
- Paint?
- Yeah.
Oh, yeah, okay,
I'll be back in about an hour.
Who do you think you're talking to?
Mr. Coco? "I'll be back in an hour"?
"See you in 60, Coc," huh?
Larry, goddamn it, I've got to go!
What about last night, princess?
You think that was for free?
You're on the painting team. Get it?
You don't think I would give you
your freedom...
...if this painting thing
hadn't come up?
What do you think of white?
Right.
Pretty good.
No.
Yes or no? Yes or no?
You're not gonna like this either,
are you? You don't like this, do you?
Now, that I like.
You like exercise?
You're gonna love our place.
Hey, honey.
I thought I'd whip you up some lunch.
Aren't I the thoughtful,
domestic type?
You smell nice.
Squaw, fix dinner.
- Okay.
- Nice job on canoe.
Just one thing, chief.
That's wet paint you're sitting on.
When Bob and the baby died, I...
I went to such a black place.
It was almost like...
Like I felt I deserved it or something.
I don't know why.
And then I was trying
to justify it somehow.
Like, by proving to myself
that I was a really bad person.
I did deserve it.
Jeez.
You've given me so much, Larry.
It's very easy to love
someone like you.
Yeah.
I think we should have used
the back door.
We'll probably have to use it
to get out.
I think the market's doing very well.
Darling, your hand is perspiring.
- Larry.
- You can drink if you want to.
- Hi.
- Hi, Sophie.
- Sophie, my dear, it's been far too long.
- Mr. Templeton...
...you haven't changed a bit.
Well, you certainly have.
I just mean that I don't recall you
being such a fibber...
...about an old man's looks.
Cocktail, Mr. Templeton?
No, thank you, Albert.
I fear my drinking days are over.
Surely, a tear of Zubrwka
could do monsieur no harm.
Zubrwka!
We used to drink it at the Radziwill's
when I stayed there for the shooting.
I don't suppose a drop will hurt me.
Oh, we must all try some.
- Oh, not for me. Thanks.
- Oh, my dear, you must.
No. Thanks anyway.
The herbs.
It's like newly mown lavender.
Well, what shall we drink to?
We could drink to Sophie's
and my wedding.
That's swell!
Congratulations!
Golly! Imagine that!
When is the happy occasion?
We're going to do it Friday.
Friday?
Oh, I think that's wonderful.
I'd like to...
...take you to Molyneux's after lunch
and pick out your dress.
Gray and I would love to give it to you
as a wedding present, wouldn't we?
- You don't have to do that.
- Oh, don't be silly.
I mean, after all,
you two are our oldest friends.
Well, I really don't think
it's gonna be that kind of wedding...
...where I'll need a new dress, right?
- So thanks anyway.
- Don't be stupid, Sophie!
You've gotta wear something!
You can't wear that!
Honey.
Honey...
...maybe Sophie
doesn't want a new dress.
Okay.
That'll be nice.
Good.
We'll go after lunch.
- Great.
- Well...
Cheers.
Uncle Elliot, you were right.
That's the best thing I've ever tasted.
I don't mind simply looking at it.
I'll have Albert order up a bottle
for the house. You can take it with you.
Albert, have them place a bottle
of this ambrosia in my car, please.
It's like listening to music
by moonlight.
- Pretty nice place.
- Oh, thank you.
Make yourself at home.
I'm gonna check on the kids.
It's really Uncle Elliot.
He's been incredible.
I don't know what we would have
done without him.
Afraid I rearranged
your knickknacks.
You wanna break
anything else, Soph?
Okay. Let's get this over with, huh?
- I know all you really want is Larry.
- That's ridiculous.
I think it's actually quite fitting
that you two found each other...
...after all these years.
Isabel, I know
you're in love with him.
You've always been in love with him.
I wonder who else has always
been in love with him.
And what if I am in love with him?
And what if I can't see...
...how you're going to be able to
stand by him when things get tough?
How would you know?
When he wanted you,
you walked out on him.
I walked out on him? Oh, no,
I sacrificed myself for him.
Oh, come on, honey.
Honey.
You sacrificed yourself
for a mink-fucking-coat...
...and a set of monogrammed towels.
I wanted to be a wife,
and I wanted children.
Now, maybe that's something
that you can't understand.
That's not true, Isabel.
Larry wanted to give you that.
I was a good wife.
I was a good mother.
I'm gonna be one again.
Bob got you pregnant.
You made the best of the situation.
Do you really think he was happy?
Oh, Sophie.
What can I say?
I just do not believe that you
will not drag him down eventually.
Your drinking alone.
I haven't...
...had a drink in three months.
That's great.
But you've wanted one, haven't you?
Haven't you?
And you will again and again.
And again. What about the drugs?
And what about everything else?
Larry helps me.
I know Larry helps you.
I can see him devoting
the rest of his life to helping you...
...and never whispering
one word of regret ever.
Can't you?
Telephone, Mrs. Maturin.
Hello? Oh, yes.
This is Mrs. Maturin.
Oh, yes.
Oh, that's wonderful.
That was the children's dentist.
There's been a cancellation...
...and I've been trying
to get an appointment for weeks.
Wait for me, please.
Joseph will bring you
some tea, and...
And when I get back, we'll go.
Maybe some other time, huh?
No, Sophie.
If you're going to get married, then...
...I'm going to buy you the dress.
Yes, madam?
Nothing.
Come on, Sophie.
Leave me alone.
Can't you see?
I'm listening to music by moonlight.
Oh, Isabel...
...you were so right.
She was right about
everything, you know.
Let's go, Sophie.
Don't you hear the music?
No, I guess not.
All you ever hear
are choirs of angels.
Well...
...Coco here is my angel.
Aren't you, mon chri?
Don't you wanna go home?
Home?
This is my home.
I like it here.
Right here in Coco's lap.
It's the biggest...
...warmest...
...lap in town.
Wanna feel it?
Why don't you just run along, Larry.
We don't need you here.
Nobody wants you here.
We just...
...wanna listen to music
by moonlight.
Larry!
No! Larry!
Monsieur Darrell, we are the police.
Yeah, I noticed your shoes.
We dragged her body from the river.
What?
Her throat was cut with a razor.
It could have been
any one of her friends.
They are the vermin of the city.
What was your relationship
to the deceased?
She was my fiance.
Good, Larry's here.
Thank you, Your Grace.
Elliot's had a stroke.
The bishop just gave him
the last rites.
Isabel's in pretty bad shape.
Oh, Larry, he's going fast...
...and I don't want him to die sad.
All his friends have forgotten him.
He waited for weeks for an invitation
to Princess Novemali's party.
I knew it wouldn't come.
People think him a silly man, Larry...
...but he's a good man...
...and a generous one.
I'm gonna miss him so much.
I wish I'd been a better friend to him.
- Like you were to Sophie?
- Is she okay?
When I came back yesterday
afternoon, she'd gone.
- What happened to your face?
- She's gone for good.
- What?
- She met up with some old friends.
They got her drinking, slit her throat
and dropped her in the Seine.
Oh, my God!
I don't give a damn
if they catch who killed her.
What I wanna know is how you
got her to take the first drink.
What'd you do, get her going
on Bob and the baby?
Did you get her down
and keep her there?
I broke this chair once...
...because I couldn't spend
the rest of my life with you.
Sooner or later,
she would have let you down.
I wanted you to see that.
I've never stopped
thinking about you.
I love you.
I just wanted you to be happy.
I didn't want anyone else to hurt you.
So you killed my fiance for me?
Just like you killed my fianc.
I was in love with Larry Darrell,
but you had to take him away...
...to go and find the meaning
of his goddamn life.
Honey...
I'm afraid you'd better come.
How you doing, Unc?
Life is full of ironies,
isn't it, Darrell?
You know...
...I spent my whole life...
...among the great names of Europe.
Now I'm dying...
...and who comes to see me but a...
Well, I mean...
An itinerant...
- Fish packer?
- Fish packer.
Oh, I got some mail for you.
Some old buzzard came to the door...
...while I was downstairs
raiding your icebox.
Who's Novemali?
"Princess Novemali...
...kindly requests the..."
Costume party?
You're not gonna get out that old
rabbit outfit of yours, are you?
R.S.V.P. The princess's palace,
I guess, Joe.
Get your pad, Joseph.
We must reply.
Oh, not now, Uncle Elliot.
My dear, I've always been
a man of the world...
...and I see no reason to forget
my manners now that I'm leaving it.
Are you ready, Joseph?
Monsieur Elliot Templeton...
...regrets he is unable...
...to accept Princess Novemali's
kind invitation...
...due to a previous engagement
with his blessed Lord.
The old bitch.
The children.
When Piedmont died...
...I had to pay him back for my life.
I found out there's
another debt to pay...
...for the privilege of being alive.
I thought Sophie...
...was my reward for trying
to live a good life.
There is no payoff.
Not now.
Am I ever gonna see you again?
Isabel...
...you just don't get it.
It doesn't matter.
- Is she okay?
- She will be as soon as you go up.
What happened, Larry?
Isabel's gonna tell you.
You know something?
You two are the best friends
I've ever had.
Gray, that's just the luck of the draw.
Oh, I tell you...
- See you.
- Yeah.
Hey, pal, that's my coat.
Don't worry, I'm leaving.
Where are you going now, Larry?
I'm going home.
But where is your home, Larry?
America.
Subtitles by SDI Media Group