Heavy rain continues to
batter the tri-state area.
Severe thunderstorms have dumped 8.6
inches of rain in the last 12 hours.
Flooding is reported in Fulton,
Rolling Fork and Osborne.
Watch out, Tom!
Beth, get in
the truck.
Tom!
Are you hurt?
I'm all right.
My leg's caught.
Which one?
The left one.
I'll tell you what.
Both of you hold me under the
shoulders and pull like hell.
It should come out.
Dad, it's going!
Lewis,
grab his leg! Pull!
Try again.
Daddy.
Tom,
you okay?
I'm fine.
I'll get Beth.
We'll get
the animals.
Come on, honey.
I have to save Ernie.
We'll get him.
Hang onto me.
Tight. Okay.
You get behind
Jessica.
Hey, up!
Come on, get up!
Take this quilt upstairs,
Beth. Put it in my room.
Ya! Get out!
Stay close to me.
Oh, Lord.
Be careful.
Welcome back,
Senator.
Thank you, son.
Hop in, Senator.
Morning, Joe.
Morning.
Where's
your regular pilot?
He's not feeling
too good, Ed.
But don't worry. I'm sure I can
figure out how this thing works.
All this bottom land used to be
duck marsh back 200 years ago.
Natural springs all
over it. Real fine water.
How many farms
flooded, Joe?
What do you figure,
Harve?
Maybe eight, nine all told.
It's the same
as always.
They'll all be at my
bank asking for money.
Those are the Garveys
down there.
Hard-working guy,
Tom Garvey.
Stubborn son of a bitch.
That's Joe Wade.
The flying farmer.
What's he doing here?
Showing off.
Why did you
show me that, Joe?
I'm sitting on 11,000 acres
of good, productive farmland
and I'm running out
of water.
My aquifer's going dry. I'm too
far from the river to irrigate.
We've got to
build us a dam.
Wait a minute.
You flood that valley,
what happens to the farmers?
They'll get a fair price
for their land.
It's not just irrigation
for myself.
I'm talking about enough
hydroelectric power for the county.
I'm talking about jobs.
Could mean a lot
to everybody.
Including yourself.
I'll look into it.
You're a smart man, Joe.
So are you, Senator.
That's why we put you
in the state house.
No loafing
in front of the bank.
Move on. Won't get no work sitting here.
Can I have
some ice cream?
When Daddy's
finished.
When will he
be finished?
When he's done.
He'll be finished
soon.
Good morning, Mae.
Joe.
Hi, kids.
Saw you took
some water.
Could have
been worse.
Anything I can do?
We'll manage.
Okay.
You need $9,700?
I got to plant a new crop
and fix the 'dozer.
It's all there
on the list.
Three hundred
and twenty acres.
Borrowed $60,000 in 1970,
a second for $18,500 in '76.
$214,000 worth of
farm equipment
on which you have paid
only $16,300.
Yeah.
You owe us
a lot of money, Tom.
I'd like to help you.
If we give you another loan,
how will you make the payments?
I'm a good customer...
I know that.
I've made payments
for 12 years.
That's not
the point.
That's the point.
Ten years ago, you begged
me to borrow the money.
It's different now.
Land values are down.
You owe us more
than your place is worth.
You turning me down?
Take it easy.
You're putting me
out of business.
Lower your voice.
I need that loan.
I earned it.
Leutzcorp might give you
a good price for your land.
Talk to Joe Wade.
I'm not looking to sell.
I'm looking to stay.
I don't know what
we can do for you, Tom.
We can roll
your notes over.
Just talk to Wade.
What did you
come in for?
Wanted him to
see us.
Don't guess
it helped.
It sure didn't.
Neither did this.
Can I have
my ice cream now?
No, honey.
She said when
Dad was finished.
Aren't you
finished, Dad?
No, Beth,
I'm not finished!
Come on out.
Go get yourself
an ice cream.
Hold her hand,
Lewis.
You look real handsome.
I gave you
a great haircut.
It itches.
It's time to eat.
That's great, honey.
Put it up
on the rolling pin.
Like this.
That's great.
That's
a beautiful crust.
Cut the edges off.
Wade didn't waste
any time, did he?
Howard must have called him
as soon as I left the bank.
We'd come away clean
with about $25,000.
It's more like $28,000.
How many times
did you read this?
Sometimes I think we'd
do better someplace else.
Away from the river.
I'm not interested.
Because the offer
came from him?
This is
our home place, Mae.
My people
are buried here.
Beth, what do you
got there?
Take that
back inside.
It's only a quilt.
It's not for sale.
What do you got?
Pears, applesauce,
blackberry jam.
Lewis, come here.
Put the jam back
in the kitchen.
Like my jam, huh?
Yeah.
There's more of
them every day.
Where are
they coming from?
A lot of them
look like farmers.
I got three, now four, four.
Anybody got four,
now, five, six?
Looking for seven, seven?
Over here!
Seven and a half.
Eight.
Anybody go eight and a half?
Anybody go nine,
nine, nine, nine?
Did you tie this?
It's a tough one.
Morning, Tom.
Morning, Dave.
How are you?
Need a hand?
No, thanks.
We can handle it.
Don't mind Tom.
You know how he is.
Just like
his daddy.
Look.
I hate being
a farmer's wife.
Your attention,
please.
The next item
for auction
is the John Deere model
7000 four-row corn planter.
It's owned by
the Garveys.
What am I bid?
Who started the bidding?
Who'll give me a six?
A $5,000 bid.
Anybody got five?
Anybody got four, four?
$500.
Gentlemen, we have a $6,000
piece of farm machinery here.
We only have $500
bid on it.
We got $500,
now six, six, go seven.
$50!
I got $550, now $600.
Six-and-a-half?
$700! Who'll go seven?
Eight!
Eight, eight, nine?
Bid ten, ten, ten?
$1, 100.
Bid 11 and a quarter?
Who'll bid 11
and a quarter?
I sold an $1, 100 bid.
Number 13.
I'm sorry, son.
That's all right.
Ladies and gentlemen,
your attention, please.
Could I have
your attention, please?
Move on down.
Form a circle.
We're going to have
an auction.
You people in the rear
come over on this side.
You people,
come on around.
Farmers, come in.
We're having an auction.
I'd like to present to you
Dan Gaumer and his family.
The merchandise we're selling
this afternoon belongs to them.
We're going to be selling the
personal property, farm equipment,
machinery,
and livestock.
If you want to know anything
about this equipment,
livestock, machinery,
step up and ask Dan.
He's worked it,
he knows it.
You all just ask him.
Everything is to be sold.
They're going to
sell his farm.
He's five miles
down the river.
His land must
be gone, too.
Looks that way.
The first item
we'll be selling...
We won't stand
for this shit!
You ain't
selling him out.
You tell him!
No sale, no sale!
Hold on just a minute, please.
No sale!
I agree with Smoot.
No sale.
We're conducting
a professional auction.
No sale!
Hold on just a minute.
Are we gonna
let him sell?
Stop this sale!
No sale!
Ain't gonna be
no farm selling.
No sale!
No sale! No sale!
Hold it, everybody.
Hold it!
Everybody hold it!
Please!
Hold it,
everybody, please!
Will you listen
to me, please?
It's too late.
They already took it.
Do you understand?
My farm's gone.
They already
foreclosed on me.
See there?
We aren't selling
his farm.
We're just selling property,
machinery and livestock.
So just move back.
Earl, Charlie, everybody, I
appreciate what you're doing.
I really do and
I understand,
but my place
is already gone.
This stuff here is
all that's left.
We'll need the money
to clear on out.
I just want to
thank you.
God bless you.
Mr. Richardson,
just go on.
Thank you, Dan. The
first item to be auctioned
will be the Farmall
model 100 tractor.
Who'll make
a $2,000 bid?
Billy, where are
you going?
To tell Lewis
good-bye.
Don't take
too long.
My dad says they got
Little League in the city.
Uniforms and
everything.
That's great.
Billy,
Billy!
Billy, Daddy says
we got to hurry.
Bye, Lewis.
Got to go.
They're all here.
You ready?
Yeah, let's go.
Okay, everybody
listen up!
Who's first?
Garvey!
Say, Tom, did you get
the water off your land?
It's going.
Why didn't you
answer my letter?
Didn't know I had to.
You want to contract?
Yep.
Another crop, huh?
It's a habit.
Three hundred twenty acres?
How many bushels?
Hundred and thirty
an acre.
That many, huh?
That's $3.45.
$3.45?
It says $3.50 there.
Them's morning prices.
It's gone down.
Who sets the prices?
The free market.
I thought it was you.
You set everything else.
You don't like the price,
haul your crop to the city.
You've got options,
Tom.
Well, I need the seed.
I haven't got the cash,
so I don't have any options.
Load him up.
Load him up!
Garvey!
Next, Youngdall.
Here.
How many acres?
Hundred and twenty.
How many bushels?
Hundred and ten.
Mama, she don't
look too good.
Don't worry, honey. This
medicine will make her better.
It's real strong.
Hear that, Jessica?
You just rest.
I'll come see you
before bedtime.
Keep it steady.
Keep them feathers
just off the cutting edge.
Don't be afraid of it.
Go ahead.
I'm going to take a nap.
Dad, don't go to sleep.
Maybe you better do it.
You're doing fine.
Go on.
Hi, Eldridge.
That's not fair, Joe.
I got Gaumer
to sell out.
One out of eight.
Tessley has a big payment he can't meet.
Youngdall's
ready to fold.
You could've
bankrupted Garvey.
Instead, you rolled
his notes over.
He's a good
customer, Joe.
Haven't I been
a good customer?
I'd hate to
change banks.
No, sir, Joe,
I wouldn't want you
to do that.
Then you start squeezing
like you said you would.
Thanks for coming by,
Howard.
Are those Oreos?
Yes.
You got pretty hair,
just like your mama's.
Thank you.
Look at that face.
Let's get rid of
that mustache.
Turn your head.
You know, Oreos are just about my
favorite cookie in the whole world.
Yours, too?
Mama said
don't talk to strangers.
Your mama's right,
but I'm no stranger.
There's no answer, Beth.
I guess we'll have to wait.
Hi, Joe.
Hello, Mae.
I was just talking your
daughter out of a cookie.
How'd you do?
No luck yet.
If you're stuck,
I can give you a lift.
I'm going right by
your place.
Well...
If Tom's coming,
he'll pass us.
I guess it's okay.
Great.
Give me that bag.
Come on, sport.
Let's get in the Jeep.
How many cookies
did you eat?
I don't know.
You want a soda
or anything,
reach in that fridge
behind you.
Now you're corrupting
my daughter.
Well, if she's your
daughter, she can handle it.
We got your letter.
Tom's not interested
in selling.
How do you feel about it?
It must be hard
trying to hang on.
Not for Tom Garvey.
Thanks for the ride.
It was a pleasure.
Hi, Tom.
Thanks, sweetie.
We thought
you forgot us.
Sorry.
That roof took longer
than I thought.
What's wrong
with it?
Old age,
I guess.
Beth, honey,
go feed the chickens.
I fed them this morning.
Well,
feed them again.
Okay.
It's the middle
of the afternoon.
My favorite time of day.
Okay, try it, Dad.
Be careful,
Lewis.
Son of a bitch.
I just bought
this hose.
Who's desperate?
You got it.
Tom,
we needed you.
You seen Harley?
Around the back.
Tom, your buddies
could have used you.
Seen Harley?
He's down there.
Excuse me, Dave.
Tom.
Harley,
I need a new hose.
Look at this thing
you gave me.
It's Sunday.
I ain't open.
I'm not asking you
to open.
Just get me a new one.
No way I'm opening
on Sunday.
I'm a Christian. There's
just no way I'm opening.
If I don't have
a hose in five minutes,
you'll have
a Christian burial.
Got your attention,
didn't he?
Let's go.
Bye, Harley!
Nobody stocks parts on that
old hunk of junk you drive.
I'll sell you a new tractor.
Just get the hose, Harley.
Harley, as long as you're
open, I'll pump myself some gas.
Got the keys?
Thank you.
"Just get the hose,
Harley. "
Nice machine, huh?
It's okay.
All right, here it is.
That will be $4.25.
Forget it.
No business on Sunday.
Thank you, Harley.
You can plow and
listen to a cassette
while the air conditioner
keeps you cool.
Hey, Lewis.
Why don't you
play ball anymore?
Haven't got time.
There's a game next Sunday.
Nobody in the valley
can touch my fastball.
Hit a homer!
Hit a homer, Daddy!
Ball one.
Foul! You cheater!
Come on, Harve.
Do it again, Joe!
Ball two!
I'll talk to him.
No, I'll talk to him.
Go get him, Dad!
You having a little
control problem?
I guess so.
Get a hold on yourself.
Try putting one there
and see what happens.
Let's play ball.
Way to tell him, Dad!
All right!
Come on, Tom!
Bring it home!
You're out!
Mom!
Daddy hit a homer!
It stinks in here.
Mom's not home.
Is Jessica dead?
Yes, she is.
I'm sorry, Beth.
I tried.
I should have called the vet,
but we owe him so much.
I just couldn't face him.
I'm sorry.
Lewis, take her
into the house.
Wait. I have to say
good-bye to her.
I don't know
what to do about Sears.
I sold the quilt.
I paid the FHA.
Power company sent
a final notice.
I've got a money order
for that.
I found an old pair
of Lewis' sneakers.
I can give those to Beth.
But I don't know
what to do about Sears.
Corn will be ready to
pick in about 90 days.
Can you hold on
till then?
I don't know. We got
nothing else to sell
but the land.
Spring. You'd think
it would warm up.
The city gets
colder every year.
Bitter.
You noticed my marriage
ain't so good, huh?
Now I'm working, maybe
things will get better.
Swick, there's
the guy, Swick.
He's the boss.
Take your hat off.
Next two.
What do
you say?
Shut up!
How's it going?
How's your sister?
Oh, she's fine,
just fine.
This is the fellow
I mentioned.
Hi.
Hi. How are you?
He needs the work.
What can you handle?
Oh, whatever you got.
Cut and weld,
both oxy and arc.
I can do layout.
I can braze.
He's my cousin,
and he's good.
All right. He's on.
But you fucking
better be good.
You get $4.50 an hour, 50-hour week.
You get a flop.
Shut up!
Get him
on the truck.
Appreciate it.
What's a flop?
It's an on-site job.
Didn't I tell you?
It's all shut down.
It's all gone to hell.
Stay away from the edge!
What is this?
It's a strike.
We're scabs.
Okay, boys,
party's over.
Everybody off.
Come on.
Get off there.
Come on, boys.
Let's go. Keep moving.
Watch where
you're going, you asshole!
We're taking their jobs.
It's the only jobs
there are.
Everybody, listen up!
I'm going to say this once.
Now, the tool shed
is down there.
You get number tags.
Don't lose them.
If you break a tool,
you pay for it.
You ruin the work,
You get a piss break
every two hours.
We'll give you a cot.
You eat what's in the canteen.
No booze and no dope.
Anybody that wants to
leave here,
you're crossing that picket
line on your fucking own.
Got it?
Good. Let's go, boys.
Move it out!
You look like girls.
Make sure the cut
is real clean, okay?
If not, it's my ass.
Your ass, too, Jim.
Tom.
Nice meeting you, Jim.
What are
we making?
I don't know, pipes.
Boilers for ships.
Power plants.
Sewers to
wash away shit.
It's work.
Get to it.
Go like that
and squeeze.
Get it up and
slide down.
Go up, slide down,
and then squeeze.
Good!
Thank you.
Lewis.
Earth that gave us this food,
sun that made it ripe and good,
dearest earth, dearest sun, we'll
not forget what you have done.
Amen. Beth.
Come on, Beth.
Mommy!
What?
Come on, Beth.
Oh, damn.
Mrs. Garvey!
Help me!
Here!
Mrs. Garvey.
Bram.
Move this thing.
Help me move it.
Move this.
Move this thing, Bram.
I'm going to have
to get Judy.
Damn it!
Hit it!
Hit me!
Hit me, Bram.
Be home, Judy.
Let Tom do the cooking.
Keep off your feet.
These should help.
I'll be okay.
Thanks, Tom.
Easy.
Take it easy.
Don't.
I'm saying it.
I don't want to
hear it.
I can't stop
thinking about you.
I try.
I try, but
I can't help myself.
It's too late.
You chose Emily.
I chose Tom.
It's too late.
Lives can change.
I can make them change easy.
This kind of life is
over. Can't you see that?
Old Man Leutz isn't going
to be around forever.
Think about what that
could mean to your kids.
Life doesn't have
to be so hard.
That's my kids.
Go home, Joe.
Please, go home.
Did you get her?
Yeah. I just
talked to her.
She don't
sound good.
This your first one?
Yeah.
What month is she in?
Seventh.
I don't like her
working the farm alone.
Don't worry, kid.
It'll go
smooth as silk.
Can we get music
out of this?
Don't touch that.
I need the weather.
You going on a picnic?
No. He's a farmer.
Working in
this shithole,
he can't be
doing so good.
It smells like
something
crawled up in you
and died!
Maybe it's your mama.
I need some air.
Hey, farmer, you into air, ain't you?
Come on, Baines.
How come
you grow all that food
and people
are still hungry?
I don't know. There's
something wrong somewhere.
You're a farmer,
ain't you?
I got no answers.
I don't get it, Jim.
Look at this!
How much
you weigh, Jim?
I don't know.
Hundred and
sixty-five, 170.
What about you?
How much you weigh?
Hundred and sixty.
Hundred and sixty?
You mothers are staring at 205
pounds of USDA prime nigger.
How about you, kid?
How much you weigh?
I don't know.
Hey. Where you going?
I'm going home.
Dumb bastard.
Get back here.
Hey! Wait!
Get back over here!
Scab son of a bitch!
Get him, Rick!
Stinking scab!
Take my job!
I'll kill you!
Roy, come on.
Let's get out of here.
I'll kill you!
Don't, Truck!
Stop! Stop it!
Stop!
You'll kill him!
Let's go.
Come on, mothers!
Get up! Come on.
You okay?
Terrific.
Crazy frigging farmers.
You all right, kid?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Chickenshits.
Mommy, Daddy's
on the telephone!
Mommy!
What?
Daddy's on the phone!
Tom?
Yes.
How is he?
We are.
He's fine.
I got it into my head
that maybe you and the kids
could come up here next weekend.
I'll send
the bus tickets to you.
Mom, what is it?
We're going to the city
to see your dad.
All right, everybody,
listen up.
You meet this truck
Sunday at midnight.
Now, if you don't show,
you don't get back in.
Take them out
through the dump.
Poachers.
They've been in there all
summer. Everybody's hungry.
Look.
Whitetail are getting
pushed out.
When's hunting
season start?
Two adults.
Four adults and two...
Five adults and one child.
Two adults.
Lewis.
Me and Roy's going deer
hunting in two weeks.
We'd like you
to come.
I can? Really?
Yeah.
I said yes.
Beth, did you hear?
Dad and Roy's
taking me hunting.
Mae.
After the show, the kids
can stay with Ida and Roy.
I'm sorry.
I can't.
Maybe I want you
too bad.
I know.
Me, too.
The snore
that ate Birmingham.
You should hear the barracks
at 3:00 in the morning.
Sounds like
a damn sawmill.
The crops okay?
They're fine.
Can you do all of it?
I can handle it.
Nothing wrong?
No.
Wade been around?
You don't always
tell me everything.
You want me to
make something up?
We've got weevils
in the corn.
You don't always
tell me everything either.
The plant is
noisy.
The noise.
It's hot.
It's hard to breathe.
When I go out for air,
I see the strikers.
Even when you can't see them,
you know that they're there.
I can't sleep.
If you sleep, you dream.
I dreamt about the river
last night.
Only it wasn't a river.
It was a big snake.
I couldn't find the head
or the tail of it.
It had me wrapped up so tight
I just couldn't breathe.
What's this?
The machinery's hot.
And this?
People aren't so neighborly
in there.
I know what this is.
I gave it to you.
Some nights
I miss you so bad.
I ache for you so bad.
Look at that deer.
Hey! Look at that!
It's a deer.
What the hell?
Hey.
It's a goddamn deer.
Barbecue!
Get him in!
Lock it up!
All right.
Everybody, listen.
Pick up your money
at the window.
I want you all out of here
in one hour.
The strike is over.
It's settled.
All right. Move it out.
Come on, boys.
The party's over.
Keep moving.
Keep walking.
Come on. Speed it up.
Come on.
Don't start bunching up.
Damn it, didn't you hear me? Move!
Where are the trucks?
There's no trucks.
As part of their deal, you've
got to walk out of here.
Damn it.
I said there's no trucks.
You heard me. There's no
trucks. It's part of their deal.
You no-good pimp!
You've got to walk out.
Open the gate!
Goddamn scabs,
get out of here.
Scabs!
Go home, scabs!
Go home where you belong!
Get out of here.
You dirty scabs!
Go home!
Go home, scabs!
You scum.
Dad!
Mom! Beth! Dad's home!
Hey, boy!
Dad!
Look at this.
Come and see.
That's a good crop.
I'm proud of you.
All of you. Come here.
They're finished
kissing now.
Now they're just talking.
Daddy said
a lady spit on him.
Are daddies allowed to cry?
Want to sleep with me?
Yeah.
Lie down.
It's still pretty wet,
Tom. It ain't ready.
What are you talking
about? It ain't ready.
Feel it.
It's dry.
I don't want to argue.
You should have
planted it sooner.
The flood held us up,
but it's dry.
Lord, I hear
fiddle music.
We got a contract.
If the corn's no good,
neither is the contract.
It'll cost us to dry this out.
I'll give you $2.75.
$2.75?
Take it or leave it.
It cost more than that
to grow it!
Next time you got crops to raise,
don't leave it to a pretty little thing.
Where's Wade?
He ought to be inside.
You seen Wade?
Where is he?
Excuse me.
Where's Wade?
You must see
Mr. Stanley.
I already have.
It's Wade's turn.
Come with me.
We'll make an appointment.
You can't go in there.
Wade, tell me
that corn's no good.
We're in a meeting.
Don't send some flunky
to do me in.
I want to hear it from you.
Gentlemen,
I'll be right back.
Okay, bonehead,
you want it, you got it.
Go on. Take a look at
the future.
You're going to flood
the valley?
That's right.
My people are buried there.
So are yours.
I need that water.
Everybody needs work,
and you're in the way.
What are you hanging on for? Your kids?
Mae?
She deserves
a lot better.
I don't buy it.
And I ain't leaving
except in a box.
Mommy, will you dry my hair?
This towel's wet.
Get me a dry one.
Another cold front
is building.
It's spreading thunderstorms, hail
and high winds through the plains.
This moisture,
with the already soggy ground,
will increase local flooding.
Mom, we're going to
get rocks for the levee.
Wait, honey.
I'm fixing sandwiches.
There's no time.
Lewis, you missed lunch.
So did your father.
Hurry.
I'll get in trouble.
Put them under your coat!
Damn it!
Lewis, get me
the other ratchet set.
Beth, come and
hold the light.
I can't leave Alice.
She's sad.
Beth. Bring
the stool with you.
Hold it there,
will you?
What are you doing?
Don't move a damn muscle, all right?
Just hold it there.
Don't move.
You hold it there.
Don't move a damn muscle.
I need to talk
to you, Tom.
Lewis! Wake Lewis up.
I need to talk to you, Tom.
Not now. Lewis, get up!
You're pushing him
too hard.
He's just a kid.
Get in the cab.
I'm not letting you
do this.
If we don't stop the river,
it will finish us.
Let it end.
Let it finish us
before you do.
I can't live like this.
Then clear out and
go live with Joe Wade!
Go outside.
I don't want to
live with Joe Wade.
I want to live with you, but
you can't hold back the river.
Why won't you get any help?
I don't need help.
You don't need anybody,
do you?
Nobody needs anybody else.
You stupid, goddamned farmer!
Fill me a pile of them.
Make them lighter.
It's going to get worse.
See the floodline?
Yeah.
Hey, Mae! Mae!
Joe Wade!
Tom! Joe Wade!
They ain't
going to make it.
Well, they might.
They just might.
Come on over here
a minute! Listen up!
Come on over
and listen up!
Come on over! Listen up!
I got some work.
Listen up here!
I know you're cold,
wet, and hungry
and your unemployment
and welfare's run out
and you're looking
for something to happen!
I need men
who can handle a shovel
and aren't afraid to
work in this weather.
Who wants to work
for $100 a day?
It stopped.
We did it!
Lewis, go and
get my shotgun.
Get off my land.
I'll give you all
one last chance!
$10,000 more
to each of you!
You can harvest
your crops.
I'll give you
what we contracted for.
But then you got to clear out.
I want your answers now.
Okay, boys.
Tear it down.
Dad!
Get off the levee!
Hold on! You don't get paid if you run.
He won't shoot anybody.
Get down!
Baines?
What the hell are you doing up
there? I damn near killed you.
They took my farm.
I don't want to shoot you,
but I'll do it.
You're on the wrong side.
We've been on
the wrong side before.
Tell them.
What are you doing
his dirty work for?
I'm hungry.
We're all hungry.
Come on,
goddamn it!
Do what
I'm paying you for!
Don't tear me down.
All I got is what's
growing in these fields.
Look out!
My God! We did it!
Sooner or later, there's
going to be too much rain
or too much drought
or too much corn.
I can wait.
Lewis, are we going to
get rich now?
Don't be dumb.
Who are you calling dumb?
I bet we get a million dollars
for this corn.
Dad! Beth says
we're going to get
a million dollars
for all this corn.