What did you do that for?
The guy's insecure enough already.
The Cambodians have
to leave the embassy.
They want all our passports
and everybody downstairs...
...and the Cambodians out.
If you have papers,
you have a name.
If we have a name,
we can find the mother.
Look, I fight for five years.
Useless war.
Fuck!
You know, Pran is not gonna last
five minutes out there.
The Khmer Rouge have killed every
journalist they've ever caught.
Does Syd know how serious this is?
- Of course he bloody knows!
- We can't let him walk out of here.
Look, two passports. This one's
out-of-date, but the visa's valid.
Jon Ankertill Brewer Swain.
Knock out the Jon, knock out the Swain,
and you're left with Ankertill Brewer.
Change my photograph for one of Pran,
and he's a British subject.
It's worth a try.
I hope he's got a photo because
I don't have any fucking film.
I try to escape to Thailand right now.
Give me two or three weeks.
If you get there first, let me know.
And leave message for me
at Reuters. Okay?
Just give me an hour.
I need some time to think.
I got no time to give you.
Swain's got an idea.
Ankertill Brewer.
That's the new name.
- Ankertill Brewer.
- Right. Now, my photograph.
- Change my photograph for yours.
- Do you have an old photo?
I don't think so.
Give him your passport.
Your old passport,
a family snapshot, anything.
Khmer Rouge took everything.
- What about your press card?
- Everything!
Fuck!
- Didn't give it back.
- We'll go and find some film.
There's film here. We'll get it.
Polaroid, any kind, any speed.
We're gonna get it,
and I'll shoot it, okay?
We'll find the film.
Do you have a Polaroid camera?
Do you have film?
No, I haven't got any film!
I've also got no metronidazole, and
this child has got amebic dysentery!
We've gotta get sulfide
and a developer.
If we can get that,
I can make the photo.
Shit!
Listen, I know where we can get
some water. We can drain...
...the air conditioning vent.
I've seen it done. Come on.
Excuse me, you're Mr. Schanberg?
I've been told that you're
in charge of bed covers.
What?
Blankets. We've just arrived.
We want some blankets.
Come on down here.
Go to the end of the hall there.
Turn to the right,
go up the stairs.
If there are any, they'll be
at the top of the stairs.
Syd, I have got the camera...
...I have got the film...
...and I have got
the fucking darkroom!
All right. Don't smile.
- You're smiling.
- Very serious. You are smiling.
Stop, please.
- Very serious.
- Very serious, very American.
Okay, cover it.
This fucking paper, I don't know.
That was the stuff you found
in the coatroom.
Ankertill Brewer.
Getting an image.
Look at it.
Look, the bugger's face.
It sure is. Come on.
Come on.
Now fix it.
That's good.
Oh, no. Fuck, it's fogging.
Goddamn it.
Goddamn this paper!
Goddamn it!
We're gonna have to start again.
Okay, now we gotta fix it.
I did it.
Let me have that.
It's fading.
Take it out.
No, it's already gone. The solution's
too strong. It's fading.
Take it out now.
I mean, if it's...
Fuck!
Goddamn it!
Man, this fucking room is killing me.
Could I just...?
I'll just do it myself, okay?
Let me just have a few feet
in here by myself.
Fuck.
Sorry.
That's it.
It's perfect.
Perfect.
Welcome to New York. We got it.
Perfect. Rockoff, perfect!
Ankertill Brewer. Ankertill Brewer.
All right, you jokers, would you like
to bring your passports over to me?
This is the last call for passports.
Can I have your passports, please?
Thank you.
Passports, ladies and gents.
All right, you jokers, this is your
last chance to get your passports in.
Your passports, please.
On this passport depend my life.
Thank you.
Passports, ladies. This is for
the big tour, the big package.
From Thursday Island right down
to Mount Macedon...
...to see the famous Hanging Rock.
Come on, passports, please.
Ladies and gentlemen, last call.
Going...
...going...
...gone.
Is this lunch?
What?
It seems certain
that the majority...
...of Phnom Penh's population has
been evacuated to the countryside.
The population is swollen
with thousands of refugees.
Hello again.
It'll be argued by some that this is
a way of coping with postwar chaos.
Dennis, can you turn
that down, please?
Now, listen, everybody.
The trucks which we've seen arriving
are for our evacuation.
Probably in the next 24 hours.
Now, listen. That's to be confirmed.
It's almost certainly for Thailand.
These so-called journalists
have no right...
You're not biased? You haven't
seen any atrocities in Cambodia?
- It's just an emotional spasm!
- Yes, it is, yes. So just shut up!
You have to break eggs
to make an omelet!
Sydney, Ankertill Brewer.
- Thank you. Goodbye.
- Good luck.
- Give me these back in Paris.
- Goodbye.
Don't forget. All right?
Why didn't you get him out
when you had the chance?
You had no right to keep him here!
You've got a funny
sense of priorities.
I'm a reporter too, Morgan.
I know his heart.
- I love him like my brother.
- Sure.
And I do anything for him.
Anything.
Goodbye, Rockoff.
Tell my wife I love her...
...and look after all my children.
She doesn't speak any English.
Please...
...I don't want anyone
to be bad to my wife.
Dith Pran.
P-R-A-N.
He disappeared in Phnom Penh in 1975.
Pran is his first name.
Any information you can give.
Well, we're hoping
for any information at all.
He was last seen in '75.
Can you get me that number again?
In April 1975.
4144-5364...
Pran is a resourceful man.
He will wait until he knows
that it's safe...
...and then he'll make his move.
Thank you for coming...
...and taking care of her
and her family.
But she knows that
her husband is dead.
That's not true.
That's absolutely not true.
It's not true. It's not.
She doesn't believe you...
...because she knows
her husband is dead.
You're a good man.
If your mother needs anything,
make sure she gets in touch with me.
You better go.
For the past 5 years...
...as indicated on this map
that you see here...
...North Vietnam has occupied
military sanctuaries...
...all along the Cambodian frontier
with South Vietnam.
As the President spoke...
...American troops were preparing
to move into Cambodia.
The decision to invade, like
the earlier secret decision to bomb...
...was withheld from
the Cambodian people.
We will yell at the top of our lungs.
We will move.
It's the fear that makes a man
so scared, you know?
There are no American
combat advisors in Cambodia.
There will be no American
combat troops or advisors in Cambodia.
We will aid Cambodia.
Cambodia is the Nixon doctrine
in its purest form.
Sydney...
...I think of you often
and often my family.
They tell us that God is dead.
And now the party they call
the Angka...
...will provide everything for us.
He says Angka has identified...
...and proclaims the existence...
...of a bad new disease...
...a memory sickness diagnosed
as thinking too much about life...
...in prerevolutionary Cambodia.
He says we are surrounded by enemies.
The enemy is inside us.
No one can be trusted.
We must be like the ox...
...and have no thought
except for the Party.
No love but for the Angka.
People starve...
...but we must not grow food.
We must honor the comrade children...
...whose minds are not corrupted
by the past.
Is anybody of us...
...a doctor...
...professor...
...and student?
Angka needs you.
Angka has forgiven all the past.
Sydney...
...Angka says that those
who were guilty of soft living...
...in the years
of the great struggle...
...and did not care for the sufferings
of the peasant must confess...
...because now is the year zero...
...and everything is to start anew.
I'm full of fear, Sydney.
I must show no understanding.
Not of French or English.
I must have no past, Sydney.
This is the year zero...
...and nothing has gone before.
The wind whispers of fear and hate.
The war has killed love, Sydney.
And those who confess
to the Angka vanish.
And no one dare ask where they go.
Here, only the silent survive.
Mercedes, number one!
Anyone who knows my work will know
that half of this belongs to Dith Pran.
Without Pran, I wouldn't have been able
to file half the stories I did.
It's nice to congratulate ourselves
on occasions like this.
But I can't stand here tonight...
...without thinking
of those innocent people...
...Pran dedicated himself to helping
me bring to the notice of the public.
As they pondered their options
in the White House...
...the men who decided to bomb
and then to invade Cambodia...
...concerned themselves
with many things:
Great power conflicts
and collapsing dominoes...
...looking tough and dangerous
to the North Vietnamese...
...relieving pressure on the American
troop withdrawal from the South.
They had domestic concerns as well...
...which helps explain why they kept
the bombing of Cambodia a secret.
And they may be assumed not to have
ignored self-interest...
...in their own careers.
What they specifically were not
concerned with...
...were the Cambodians themselves.
Not the people...
...not the society...
...not the country.
Except in the abstract
as instruments of policy.
Dith Pran and I...
...tried to record and bring home...
...the concrete consequences
of these decisions to real people.
To human beings...
...the people left out
of the Administration's plans...
...but who paid the price...
...and took the beating for them.
I'm very pleased to accept this
on behalf of Dith Pran and myself.
I'm very honored...
...and I know that Pran would be
very proud.
Do you plan to continue
with that theme in the future?
Congratulations, Ernie.
Do it again next year!
I'm sorry.
- That was great, really good.
- Better than last year.
Abe, meet my sister.
I'm very happy to meet you.
That's my dad.
Would you hold this for me?
One second.
I hoped you could recommend
a good school for journalism.
I told my daughter I'd be
seeing you today.
Just one minute, okay?
I'll be right back.
Could I have your autograph?
I'm a great admirer of yours.
Congratulations on your award,
it was well-deserved.
Very impressive.
I was hoping you'd burst into song.
- What are you doing here?
- You know what bothers me?
What?
It bothers me that you let Pran
stay in Cambodia...
...because you wanted to win,
and you knew you needed him...
- I didn't have any idea what...
- The fuck you didn't!
The fuck you didn't.
I did everything I could,
and I'm doing everything I can.
Nice to see you.
I'm on my way to Florida.
I'm doing everything I can.
I'm sure. I didn't realize
you'd been out there to see him.
Don't play games with me, Al.
Don't play stupid games.
Nobody gets to go in there.
If I thought I could, I would.
I've sent out hundreds of photographs.
Every relief organization
on the Thai-Kampuchean border...
...has got his picture. If I saw
one glimmer of hope, I'd go today.
Life isn't a '40s movie.
You can't just get on a plane and
make the whole world come out right!
And I can't believe
I'm hearing this from you!
Congrats.
Do you keep in touch
with Dith Pran's family?
Yes. They're living in San Francisco.
How do you respond to accusations
that journalists...
...underestimated the brutality
of the Khmer Rouge...
...and so share responsibility for
what happened in Cambodia afterwards?
We made a mistake.
Maybe we underestimated
the kind of insanity...
...that $ 7 billion worth
of bombing could produce.
That is provocative...
There have been a lot of refugee
stories in Reader's Digest...
...about Cambodia.
Do you believe them?
Don't you believe them?
Maybe in this instance the
Reader's Digest happens to be correct.
Do you apply the same disbelief
to stories...
...that come out of Iran
or Palestine or Chile?
Are refugees your next area
of interest?
Will you be covering the boat people?
No, I will not.
Do you want a cup of tea?
Are you looking around for some kind
of more salable suffering?
I must have sent 500 letters.
I wrote the International Red Cross,
the World Health Organization.
I know you did, Syd.
You told me.
I don't know who I didn't write to.
I never really gave him any choice.
One time we tried to discuss leaving.
I talked to him about it,
but we never really discussed it.
I discussed it with Swain and Rockoff.
But I never discussed it with him.
He stayed because
I wanted him to stay.
And I stayed because...
I'm trapped, Sydney.
I know he suspects me,
and yet he treats me well.
There are many different groups
over here, Sydney.
I must take much care.
Now Angka says we have new enemies.
They say we must regain
our old lands from the Vietnamese.
And now they say we must fight them.
I miss you, my wife, my children.
And my heart hungers for news of you.
New China Radio reports...
...that fighting between Vietnam
and Democratic Kampuchea...
...has broken out
on a number of fronts.
This is in retaliation,
according to the Vietnamese...
...for a number of attacks
on border villages...
Taxi driver, huh?
I think you speak English.
Sit down.
You know, I love this country.
I sacrificed everything for it.
My wife died for the revolution.
But the leaders of Angka
no longer trust the people.
Therefore, I can no longer trust them.
And they don't trust me.
I fear...
...really fear for the future.
I think you love my son.
For his sake...
...look after him.
The fighting is close by, Sydney.
If the Vietnamese get here...
...Angka will destroy everything...
...and the Vietnamese,
they will find only ashes.
I must try to stop the killing.
Good luck.
Yeah, I'll be right there, Brian.
Ann, get me 415-555-6421.
Abe, I've got some great news!
Twenty minutes ago, I get
a phone call from Paris.
I get Andreas Freund.
He talked to Henry.
He told him how to get in touch
with me.
Freund says, "I have got
some great news for you."
- San Francisco's on the line.
- "It's about Pran!"
Is your mother there?
When?
All right,
I want you to get this down.
No, write it down. Write it down.
I've got a message from your dad!
How you been?
Do you forgive me?
Nothing to forgive, Sydney.
Nothing.