CAPTIONING FUNDING BY
WARNER BROS., INC.
¶ I THINK YOU'VE
BECOME THE ONE I NEED ¶
¶ IT'S STILL LIKE
A DREAM TO ME ¶
¶ YOU CAME AND
YOU CHANGED MY LIFE ¶
¶ IN FRONT OF ME ¶
¶ IT'S STILL
LIKE A DREAM... ¶
[DOORBELL BUZZES]
YES?
ELKE?
NO.
MR. BEN AMI,
DOES ELKE LINDSTROM
WORK THERE?
THIS IS A FRIEND.
YES, BUT--
A FRIEND
FROM STOCKHOLM.
SHE'S ON VACATION.
LEFT THIS MORNING.
OH, DEAR.
HER MOTHER ASKED
ME TO BRING
THESE CLOTHES
AND RECORDS
FOR HER.
[BUZZ]
¶ ALWAYS IN LOVE ¶
¶ YOU'LL ALWAYS
BE A PART OF ME ¶
¶ ALWAYS IN LOVE ¶
¶ ALWAYS IN LOVE... ¶
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE
VERY KIND.
WON'T YOU COME IN?
I HAVE
A CAR WAITING.
MAYBE
ANOTHER TIME?
MAYBE.
WHEN ELKE GETS BACK,
PLEASE ASK HER
TO CALL ME.
KATRIN FROM
STOCKHOLM.
OK.
YOU MUST BE
GABRIEL.
JA.
ELKE'S TOLD ME
ALL ABOUT YOU.
SEE YOU
WHEN ELKE'S BACK.
OK.
GOOD-BYE.
BYE.
¶ ALWAYS IN LOVE... ¶
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
¶ ALWAYS IN LOVE ¶
YOU FOLLOWED YOUR
REGULAR ROUTE?
YES.
THE SAME EVERY DAY.
YOU KNEW
GABRIEL?
I'VE TOLD THE POLICE--
WE WISH TO HEAR
IT OURSELVES.
YES, I KNEW HIM.
THAT HIS FATHER WAS
AN ISRAELI DIPLOMAT?
YES.
YOU WERE GIVEN
NO SECURITY
INSTRUCTIONS?
THE INSPECTOR IS HERE
WITH THE RECONSTRUCTION.
WAIT HERE.
AH, MR. LITVAK,
THIS RECONSTRUCTION
WAS MADE
BY OUR MOST SENIOR
BOMB TECHNICIAN
WITH HIS OWN HANDS.
PERSONALLY.
GENIUS.
THEY CALLING THIS
THE BIKINI BOMB.
THE BARE MINIMUM.
LIKE ON THE BEACH
IN ISRAEL.
YOU GOT FRAGMENTS
OF THE ORIGINAL BOMB?
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
YOU ARE CALLING THIS
LIAISON, MR. LITVAK?
WE GIVE AND YOU TAKE.
IS THIS LIAISON?
AFTER ALL,
BETWEEN GERMANS AND JEWS,
WE ARE NORMALIZED.
MIND IF WE
BORROW THIS?
IT'S NOT OUR FAULT
THEY HAVE PROBLEMS
WITH THE ARABS.
WITH EVERYONE.
ALWAYS.
HAVE YOU
GOT JERUSALEM?
YES.
GET KURTZ FOR ME. NOW.
ON SHABBAT?
IF NECESSARY,
DRAG HIM FROM THE SYNAGOGUE.
HE'S BEEN
WAITING FOR THIS.
KHALIL?
KHALIL.
KHALIL'S BOMB,
KHALIL'S SIGNATURE,
AND MARTY KURTZ'S
LUCKY DAY.
THEY CALL US
TERRORISTS.
WHY?
BECAUSE WE DELIVER
BOMBS BY HAND.
WE HAVE NO
AMERICAN PLANES.
NO TANKS
TO SHELL THEIR TOWNS.
THIS
ISRAELI COMMANDER
WHO FIRES
INTO OUR CAMPS,
SO OUR WOMEN
AND CHILDREN ARE BURNED,
THIS ISRAELI
IS CALLED A HERO.
BUT WHEN
WE STRIKE BACK
WITH OUR HANDS,
WE ARE CALLED
TERRORISTS.
IF THE ISRAELIS
GIVE US AIRPLANES,
WE'LL GIVE THEM
SUITCASES.
WAIT.
YOU PALESTINIANS
RUN HISTORY'S
RICHEST REVOLUTION.
THAT'S A QUESTION?
A GOOD QUESTION.
WHO'S RIGHT
AND WHO'S WRONG?
PLEASE!
THE PALESTINIANS
HAVE BEEN WRONGED.
THEY'VE BEEN
DRIVEN OFF LAND
THEY'VE OWNED
FOR CENTURIES.
SIT DOWN!
PLEASE.
IF HE SOLD
HIS CLOTHES,
HE COULD
AFFORD HIS OWN
BLOODY PLANE.
EVEN WITH ONE
PALESTINIAN LEFT,
WE WILL FIGHT.
WE WILL
FIGHT WITH WHAT
WEAPONS WE HAVE.
WE ASK THE RETURN
OF LANDS TAKEN BY
FORCE AND TERROR.
WE ASK FOR JUSTICE.
THAT'S ALL.
I'M SURE
WE APPRECIATE
THAT OUR SPEAKER
NAMED MICHEL,
HAS COME AT GREAT RISK.
HE WON'T ATTEND
SUNDAY'S SEMINAR,
BUT WE HOPE ONE DAY,
HE CAN RETURN FREELY
AND WITHOUT SUBTERFUGE.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
MICHEL.
THANK YOU.
THE REVOLUTION
THANKS YOU.
AND I THANK YOU.
AND A HORNY
BLOODY TERRORIST AT THAT.
WE HAVE HAD HIM
UNDER SURVEILLANCE
SINCE HE RETURNED
FROM ENGLAND.
HE IS KHALIL'S
YOUNGEST BROTHER, MICHEL.
KHALIL MAKES THE BOMBS.
MICHEL DELIVERS THEM.
WE KNOW HE
AND THE BLOND GIRL
BLEW UP THE HOUSE
IN BAD GODESBERG.
HE'S A HANDSOME BOY.
GIRLS? YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE
HOW MANY IN ONE WEEK.
HE STUDIES,
LIKES TO SMILE.
IT'S HARD BELIEVING
THIS OTHER SIDE OF HIM.
YOU MUST
TELL KURTZ.
HE PICKS UP
EXPLOSIVES
IN ISTANBUL
AND BRINGS THEM
BACK TO GERMANY.
WE SHOULD
KILL HIM NOW.
"ARAB PIG
KILLS ARAB PIG."
HAPPENS EVERY DAY.
TO CATCH A LION--
FIRST TETHER
THE GOAT.
THAT BOY
IS OUR GOAT.
IT'S HIS BROTHER
KHALIL WE WANT.
COME,
TAKE A LOOK.
HE'S
ON THE PHONE.
HE'S TALKING
TO A GIRL. NO NAME.
WE'LL LET HIM
GET THE EXPLOSIVES
AND THEN GET HIM.
HAVE WE
GOT THE GIRL?
WE'RE WORKING ON IT.
MR. JEFFRIES, MR. HUMPHRIES,
YOUR CALLS, PLEASE.
THREE MINUTES.
HOW'S
THE HOUSE?
IS NED
OUT THERE?
USELESS NED HAS
YOUR COMMERCIAL
PRODUCER IN TOW.
HE GOT ME
A WINE COMMERCIAL.
SELL OUT, GIRL.
HAWK YOURSELF ROTTEN.
YOU CAN'T EAT
PRINCIPLES.
GIELGUD DOES
COMMERCIALS.
SO DOES
OLIVIER.
JESUS CHRIST.
WHAT?
LOOK. IN
THE SECOND ROW,
IN HIS RED BLAZER.
IT'S MICHEL.
THE GUCCI
TERRORIST HIMSELF.
RINGS ON HIS FINGERS
AND BOMBS
IN HIS POCKETS.
WHAT'S HE DOING HERE?
NOT TO SEE ME.
ACT I BEGINNERS,
PLEASE, ON-STAGE.
CHARLIE!
ALL RIGHT. OK.
STAND BY.
TAPE'S GOING.
MY ONE FAITHFUL,
WHAT COMFORT HAVE
YOU FOR ST. JOAN?
WHAT DO
THEY AMOUNT TO,
THESE KINGS,
CAPTAINS, BISHOPS,
LAWYERS,
AND SUCH LIKE?
THEY'LL LEAVE YOU
BLEEDING TO DEATH,
THEN YOU'LL MEET
THEM DOWN THERE.
ON CUE 20, GO.
[CHIMES]
EXCUSE ME.
A PRESSING APPOINTMENT.
O GOD THAT MADETH
THIS BEAUTIFUL EARTH,
WHEN WILL IT BE READY
TO RECEIVE THY SAINTS?
HOW LONG, O LORD?
HOW LONG?
WILL YOU GET THAT
BLOODY BELL CUE RIGHT?
CHARLIE.
YEAH?
THESE JUST CAME.
OH, MY GOD!
THANKS.
THANKS, PAM.
HEY, ORCHIDS!
YEAH.
THEY'RE GORGEOUS.
FROM WHO?
I DON'T KNOW.
CHARLIE.
JUST ONE
MOMENT, PLEASE.
YOU'VE GOT THE JOB.
HE'S RIGHT OUTSIDE.
5,000 POUNDS
FOR A WEEK ON
A GREEK ISLAND.
NOW, NO
POLITICS, NO
DISARMAMENT SERMONS.
WHO SENT THOSE?
I DON'T KNOW.
I'M SORRY.
CHARLIE!
MAY I CALL
YOU CHARLIE?
I'M LESLIE GOLD.
HE TOLD YOU
ABOUT MYKONOS?
YES, HE DID.
I HOPE
APOLLO WINE
IS AS APPEALING
AS
OUR APOLLO GIRL.
THANK YOU.
I MUST LEAVE.
I'M VERY
PLEASED THAT
YOU ARE OUR GIRL.
THANK YOU.
HE'S GOT THE MONEY,
AND IT'S WINE,
NOT LAXATIVES.
I'LL CALL IN
THE MORNING WITH DETAILS.
CONGRATS!
THANK YOU.
PAM, WHO BROUGHT
THE ORCHIDS?
A LAD
FROM THE FLORIST.
NO ONE ELSE?
NOT THAT I SAW.
¶ EYES OF FIRE ¶
¶ HELPS ME DRINK THE WINE ¶
¶ YOUR DESIRE ¶
¶ FLOWS RIGHT THROUGH
TO MINE ¶
¶ OH, YOUR EYES OF FIRE ¶
YOU'RE WALKING ALL
THE WAY TO MARIPOU?
I'M HEADING FOR
THESSALONIKI.
JUMP IN.
APOLLO WINE FOR LOVERS...
D-DA, D-DA,
D-DA, D-DA, D-DA...
CUT!
IS THAT MAN
IN THE SHOT?
YEAH, MAYBE SO.
GET HIM AWAY.
PHILIP, TALK TO HIM.
NO, I'LL GO.
I HAVE
PEOPLE FOR THAT.
MICHEL.
MICHEL?
AREN'T YOU MICHEL?
I'M AFRAID NOT.
I'M SORRY.
THEN YOU
MUST BE JOSEPH.
JOSEPH?
WITH THE COAT
OF MANY COLORS?
OK, THEN I
MUST BE JOSEPH.
I'D LIKE YOU
TO CALL ME CHARLIE.
HELLO, CHARLIE.
HELLO.
HEY, WE'RE READY.
BACK OFF THAT WAY.
YOU'RE IN OUR SHOT.
WE'RE FILMING,
SO IF YOU COULD MOVE...
WATCH THAT MAN.
OF COURSE
I WILL.
I'M SORRY.
IS THE REVOLUTION
TAKING TIME OFF
FOR A TAN?
I'M NOT SURE
I UNDERSTAND.
WHERE'S
THAT RED BLAZER?
RED BLAZER?
IN NOTTINGHAM?
THE WEEK BEFORE LAST?
I THINK YOU MUST
CONFUSE ME WITH
SOMEBODY ELSE.
I DON'T MISTAKE FACES.
I'VE NEVER BEEN
IN NOTTINGHAM.
I'M
NOT AN ACTOR.
I'VE MODELED
FOR FASHION ADS
IN ITALY.
NO ACTOR.
AFTER TWO YEARS
AT THE ACADEMY,
WE'RE PLAYING EVEN.
YOU'RE
A TRUE ACTRESS.
JUST LOOK
AS IF THE WINE
WAS MAKING US
WANT TO SCREW.
THAT DOESN'T
TAKE MUCH ACTING,
DOES IT?
SOME WINE.
CHEERS.
EXCUSE ME.
I'LL BE BACK.
OF COURSE,
BUT...
I'LL BE BACK.
I HAVE TO
APOLOGIZE TO YOU.
YOU GAVE ME
MY NAME.
PLEASE
HAVE A SEAT.
WOULD YOU
LIKE A GLASS?
WHAT IS IT?
PUTARI WINE.
WHITE AND COLD.
AS LONG
AS IT'S NOT APOLLO.
UH...
I HEARD YOU SPEAK
SEVERAL WEEKS AGO
IN DORSET.
I WAS IMPRESSED.
IT WAS STUPID
TO THINK YOU'D
REVEAL YOUR IDENTITY.
I SHOULDN'T
HAVE CHALLENGED YOU.
I WON'T DO IT AGAIN.
I SHOULD CALL
YOU CHARLIE?
YES.
IS THIS FILMING
FOR A TELEVISION
COMMERCIAL?
YEAH, BUT THE BOTTLE
GETS THE GOOD ANGLES.
TOMORROW, MAYBE
YOU'D LIKE TO RUIN
ANOTHER SHOT
OR JUST WATCH.
I'D LOVE TO.
THANK YOU.
CHARLIE!
CHARLIE, COME ON!
I'LL
SEE YOU TOMORROW?
GOOD NIGHT.
READY.
ROLL 'EM.
APOLLO WINE.
SCENE THREE,
TAKE EIGHT.
ACTION.
APOLLO WINE...
GIVE HER
A LOOK.
CUT. CUT!
MAKE SURE
THE BOTTLE
IS TURNED
TOWARD THE CAMERA.
OK, LET'S GO AGAIN.
IT'S AFTER 1:00.
ALL RIGHT.
BREAK FOR LUNCH.
LUNCH, EVERYBODY.
CHARLIE, BE BACK
BY 2:00.
ALL RIGHT.
DO YOU WANT
TO JOIN THEM?
DO YOU WALK?
YES, IN SEVERAL
DIRECTIONS
AT ONCE.
I WALK,
RIDE, EVEN HUNT...
UNTIL I REALIZED
HOW AWFUL IT WAS.
I WENT TO FOXCROFT,
THIS VIRGINIA SCHOOL
WHERE GIRLS HAVE HORSES.
VERY SOCIAL.
YOU'RE AMERICAN.
CAN'T YOU TELL?
WHERE DID YOU
GROW UP?
IN THE
MIDDLE EAST.
BROKE MY PROMISE
BY ASKING.
JUST SEEING IF
THE PAINT'S STILL WET.
I'VE PLAYED LAURA IN
THE GLASS MENAGERIE,
JO IN
A TASTE OF HONEY,
LADY BRIGHTON IN
THE IMPORTANCE
OF BEING EARNEST.
I'VE DONE
SHAKESPEARE, AND NOW...
UGH...
MISS APOLLO WINE.
ALL
DIFFERENT LIVES.
WITH ALL YOUR
DIFFERENT LIVES,
WHICH IS
THE REAL YOU?
ACTORS DON'T
HAVE MUCH CENTER.
WE'RE
BITS OF PEOPLE.
LIKE MY
MOTHER'S RAG BAG.
WE STEAL FROM
EVERYBODY,
SO WATCH OUT.
SO WHO
HAVE YOU GOT?
BROTHERS, SISTERS,
SIX BOUNCING BABIES?
I DON'T MIND.
I JUST
WANT TO KNOW.
I'M BY MYSELF.
I GUESS YOU HAVE
TO BE, DON'T YOU?
IN A WAY.
LET'S CUT
THE BULLSHIT.
WE BOTH KNOW
WHO YOU ARE.
RIGHT?
YES.
YOU'RE HERE FOR ME,
AREN'T YOU?
THE REVOLUTION
DOESN'T JUST SUNBATHE.
NO, IT REALLY DOESN'T.
CHARLIE!
THEY'RE
WAITING ON YOU.
YOU'VE TWO MORE
DAYS FILMING.
I'M GOING TO
ATHENS ON BUSINESS.
AFTERWARDS I'M
DRIVING TO THESSALONIKI.
MEET ME IN ATHENS
AND DRIVE WITH ME.
WHO ARE YOU?
AT THE HOTEL THERE'S
A TICKET, MONEY,
AND INSTRUCTIONS
ON CONTACTING ME.
CHARLIE,
IT'S MY JOB!
DID I SAY YES?
YES! YES!
GET HIM UP.
AND TAKE
THOSE CHAINS OFF.
YOU CAN'T
DO THIS!
TREAT A HUMAN
BEING THIS WAY!
TAKE HIS HOOD OFF.
GIVE US SOME LIGHT.
I'M WILHEIM KOLMER.
THESE ARE
MY CREDIENTIALS.
INTERNATIONAL RED CROSS.
PAUL TOREN.
NEVER PUT THESE
ON HIM AGAIN.
NOW LEAVE US.
MAKE A COMPLAINT
AND WE'LL GET ACTION.
WHAT HAPPENED TO
YOU AT THE WALL?
YOU CAN ANSWER.
WE'RE INTERNATIONAL RED CROSS.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
IT'S NOT
GOING TO WORK.
GIVE HIM A CHANCE.
HE'S NOT
BUYING THEM.
THEY WON'T
GET ANYTHING.
I NEED JUST
30 MINUTES
WITH MY HANDS.
I'VE FOUR DAYS
TO COMPOSE SIX
WEEKS OF LOVE LETTERS.
SCHVILI MUST
HANDWRITE THEM.
YOU'VE GOT
THEIR DIARIES.
HE CAN COPY
THE HANDWRITING.
BUT I NEED MORE.
HIS ENGLISH EXPRESSION,
HIS IDIOM USE.
DRUGS?
ON DRUGS HIS HANDWRITING
WON'T BE TYPICAL.
I NEED HIS
NATURAL SCRIPT.
IS THERE A NAME
YOU WANT US TO NOTIFY?
ARE YOU CERTAIN?
WE'RE ONLY HERE
FOR YOUR PROTECTION.
HE'S MAKING
FOOLS OF THEM!
ARE THEY
GIVING YOU FOOD?
DO YOU HAVE
ANY COMPLAINT
OF PERSONAL
TREATMENT?
YOU CAN SAY.
CAN I LOOK?
NOT YET.
WAIT, WHERE
ARE WE GOING?
SOMEPLACE
VERY SPECIAL...
ALL TO OURSELVES.
OK.
SLOWLY.
A FEW MORE STEPS.
WE'RE ALMOST THERE.
NOW, STOP.
OPEN YOUR EYES.
GOD!
OH, MY GOD!
I'VE SEEN PICTURES OF IT
BEFORE, BUT I NEVER--
IT'S INCREDIBLE!
IT'S GREAT!
THOSE COLUMNS
LOOK STRAIGHT,
BUT ACTUALLY
THEY'RE NOT.
THEY'RE EACH
SLIGHTLY CURVED
TO LOOK
AS IF THEY'RE
STRAIGHT.
DID YOU LEARN THAT
TO IMPRESS ME?
I READ IT TODAY.
IT'S A WONDERFUL
PRESENT.
SHOULD I THANK YOU?
THANK YOU.
I LIKE THANKING YOU.
SHOULD I THANK YOU AGAIN?
AND AGAIN?
AND AGAIN.
[HORN HONKS]
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
WE MUST GO.
WE JUST GOT HERE.
WE HAVE
VERY LITTLE TIME.
HOW LONG CAN IT TAKE?
COME ALONG.
QUICKLY, NOW.
CHARLIE,
THIS IS DIMITRI.
HE HAS PERMISSION
TO STAY UP LATE TONIGHT.
HI, CHARLIE.
WHERE'S OUR TAXI?
WHERE'S MY SUITCASE?
IT'S IN THE TRUNK.
COME ON.
YOU DON'T
CARE FOR IT?
SHALL I ORDER
ANOTHER?
IT'S HIRED THEN?
IT'S BORROWED
FROM A FRIEND.
SOME FAT FRIEND.
FORGIVE US NOSY GIRLS.
IF I'M BEING RECRUITED,
THIS IS A HELL
OF A WAY TO DO IT.
YOU ARE WITH US
FOR A GOOD REASON.
YEAH, WHO'S "US"?
THE PALESTINIANS?
HEY, SLOW DOWN!
SLOW DOWN!
GUNS FOR SOME SMALL WAR?
NO, CHARLIE.
WHAT? WHITE SLAVES?
NO.
WELL, YOU JUST
STOP THIS CAR!
I'M GETTING CARSICK!
I WANT OUT!
YOU CAN GET OUT NOW.
I'M NOT GETTING OUT
OF THIS CAR!
HELLO, CHARLIE.
WHO ARE YOU?
MY NAME IS TOBY.
HEY, WHERE ARE YOU
TAKING THOSE?
DIMITRI0!
WHATEVER
YOUR NAME IS!
PUT THOSE DOWN!
PUT...
PUT THEM DOWN!
DAMN IT!
THAT'S MINE!
HEY, MY PASSPORT'S
IN THERE!
CHARLIE.
HI, CHARLIE.
YOU'RE FINALLY HERE
SAFELY AMONG US.
WHAT IS THIS?
MY NAME IS MARTY,
NOT LESLIE GOLD.
I TOOK ADVANTAGE
OF YOU.
THE WINE COMMERCIAL
WAS A TRICK,
AND WE APOLOGIZE.
YOU LYING BASTARD!
CHARLIE, JOSEPH
IS THE MOST LOVED
AND LEGITIMATE SON
OF HIS COUNTRY.
WHAT COUNTRY?
YES, WELL, CHARLIE...
I'LL ADMIT THAT
IS A LITTLE PROBLEM.
LET US SAY FIRST
WE ARE DECENT PEOPLE,
CONCERNED LIKE YOURSELF
IN THE DIRECTIONS
THE WORLD IS TAKING.
DON'T FOAM AT THE MOUTH
IF I ADD THAT
WE ARE ISRAELI CITIZENS.
ISRAELIS?
IS IT YOUR CONVICTION
THAT ISRAEL SHOULD
BE SWEPT UNDER THE SEA?
DO YOU FEEL
YOU ARE AMONG ENEMIES?
ANYBODY
WHO KIDNAPS ME
IS A FRIEND!
YOU JUST
WAIT A MINUTE!
YOU'VE GOT
THE WRONG GIRL.
I'M NOT A JEW!
I AM
PRO-PALESTINIAN!
WE RESPECT
YOUR POLITICS.
GIVE THE ARABS BACK
THE LAND
YOU STOLE FROM THEM.
WHERE WOULD
YOU HAVE US GO, CHARLIE?
MAYBE CENTRAL AFRICA
OR URUGUAY?
NOT EGYPT, THANK YOU.
WE TRIED IT ONCE
UNSUCCESSFULLY.
OR BACK TO THE GHETTOS.
I JUST WANT PEACE.
SO DO WE.
THAT'S WHY WE CHOSE YOU.
FOR WHAT?
TO OFFER YOU
AN ACTING JOB.
IN WHAT?
IT'S THE BIGGEST PART
YOU'VE EVER HAD.
THE MOST DEMANDING
AND IMPORTANT.
AM I SUPPOSED
TO KILL ARABS?
WE WOULD NEVER
ASK THAT.
CHARLIE...
HEAR US OUT.
IF AFTER THAT
YOU WANT TO GO,
YOU'RE FREE.
DO I HAVE A CHOICE?
AFTER THE AUDITION.
WHAT SORT OF AUDITION?
YOU WILL ANSWER
A STRING OF QUESTIONS
VERY FRANKLY,
VERY TRUTHFULLY.
DON'T EVALUATE.
IF YOU STILL WANT
TO LEAVE AFTER THAT,
AS JOSEPH INDICATED,
YOU WILL HAVE THAT OPTION.
UH-HUH.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GET ON WITH IT.
WE BEGIN WITH A LITTLE
FAMILY HISTORY.
YOUR FATHER
BORN, WHEN?
MY FATHER?
OH, GOD.
UH...
1925.
THE HEADMISTRESS
SENT FOR YOU.
SO, WHAT DID SHE SAY?
WAIT A MINUTE.
"PACK YOUR THINGS,
GOOD-BYE, GOOD LUCK,"
AS FAR AS I REMEMBER.
NO EXPLANATION OF WHY
THEY ASKED YOU TO LEAVE?
IT WAS A SCANDAL.
THE TUITION
HADN'T BEEN PAID.
THEY'RE IN BUSINESS.
LET'S CALL THIS
A DAY OR A NIGHT.
YOU SAID YOU
RETURNED HOME TO...
CHAOS. POLICE
SWARMING THE HOUSE,
MY MOTHER CRYING.
WHERE WAS
YOUR SISTER?
SHE WAS
PREGNANT, AS USUAL.
SHE WASN'T
PREGNANT THAT YEAR.
I DON'T REMEMBER!
IT WAS TEN YEARS AGO!
MAYBE SHE
COULDN'T FACE IT.
THE DISGRACE OF
YOUR FATHER'S TRIAL?
WHAT ELSE
WAS THERE?
CONTINUE IN
YOUR OWN WORDS.
WHAT ELSE DO WE SEE?
MY PONY. THEY
TOOK MY PONY.
WHERE'S YOUR FATHER?
IN PRISON.
I TOLD YOU.
YES. OF COURSE,
YOU TOLD ME.
LET'S SEE...UM...
THE VISIT.
WHO TOOK YOU
ON VISITING DAY?
I NEVER WENT.
I TOOK CARE
OF MY MOTHER.
THE PRISON...
CHRIST, I
COULD NEVER VISIT.
I REMEMBER...
WHEN HE
SHOWED UP...
WE'D MOVED
TO BALTIMORE.
WE WERE ON WELFARE,
AND HE JUST SHOWED UP
A MONTH EARLY.
HE LOOKED
SLIMMER, YOUNGER,
HE GAVE ME A HUG
AND WEPT.
MOTHER WAS UPSTAIRS,
TOO SCARED TO COME DOWN.
I REMEMBER.
HE WAS FUNNY
ABOUT THE DOORS.
HE COULDN'T
OPEN THEM.
HE'D JUST...
HE'D GO UP TO THEM
AND THEN HE'D...
STAND AT ATTENTION
WITH HIS FEET TOGETHER,
HIS HEAD HELD DOWN,
AND HE'D WAIT FOR
THE GUARD TO UNLOCK THE DOOR.
THE FIRST
TIME I SAW IT,
I SCREAMED AT HIM
TO OPEN THE GODDAMN DOOR.
YOU GAVE
AN INTERVIEW,
THE IPSWICH PAPER,
DESCRIBING STANDING OUTSIDE HIS
CELL BLOCK, WAVING TO HIM.
I WAS...
SAUCING IT UP.
YOUR AGENT SAID
YOUR FATHER DIED
IN PRISON, NOT AT HOME.
MORE SAUCING IT UP.
THAT'S NED TALKING,
NOT ME.
HOW AM I DOING?
SO? WHAT?
DOESN'T ANYBODY
SLEEP AROUND HERE?
NO, HUH?
[TELETYPE PRINTING]
THAT WEEKEND
FORUM IN DORSET--
YOU MENTIONED KHALIL.
IT WASN'T
THAT SERIOUS.
HOW MANY TIMES
DID YOU SEE HIM?
ONCE, A COUPLE?
WOULD YOU REVISE IT?
FOUR?
A COUPLE.
THAT'S WHAT I SAID.
SIGN ANYTHING?
STATEMENTS? PETITIONS?
NO.
THERE'S ALWAYS
A RESOLUTION TO SIGN.
BE REASONABLE.
UH, I...
TELL US, WHAT
WAS DISCUSSED?
I DON'T REMEMBER.
HER DIARY
DESCRIBES FOUR.
WHERE'D YOU GET THAT?
FOUR? CHARLIE'S LOSING
MY CONFIDENCE.
HE HAS NO RIGHT
TO TAKE MY DIARY!
I DON'T WANT THIS!
I HATE THIS
AND I HATE YOU!
I'M GETTING OUT!
YOU TOLD ME
I COULD LISTEN AND LEAVE.
I WANT OUT NOW!
YOUR OPTIONS OPERATE
ONLY WHEN WE INVITE YOU.
YOU'VE KEPT ME
THE WHOLE GODDAMN NIGHT!
THERE'S DISCREPANCIES.
YOUR FATHER NEVER
WENT TO PRISON.
NO DEPUTIES, NO PONY
TAKEN FROM YOU.
YOU ATTENDED
PUBLIC SCHOOL IN IOWA,
NOT A FANCY PRIVATE SCHOOL
IN VIRGINIA.
YOUR FATHER WORKED UNTIL
HE DIED IN A MORTGAGE OFFICE.
YOUR ONLY SCANDAL WAS
A SCHOOL SUSPENSION
FOR BEING TOO AVAILABLE
TO THE LOCAL BOYS.
WHY DO YOU LIE TO US?
WHY NOT TRUST US?
TRUST? YOU BASTARD!
YOU'RE THE ONE!
YOU FUCK, YOU!
YOU BASTARD!
THREE MINUTES,
NOT MORE.
SHE DOESN'T PUT ON
SOME NEW IDENTITY,
SHE COMES BACK IN!
CHARLIE,
STOP FOR A MINUTE.
WAIT!
I SAID, STOP!
YOU DID WELL.
CONGRATULATIONS.
YOU TOOK A DIVE,
BUT YOU RECOVERED.
YOU LOST YOUR WAY,
BUT YOU HUNG IN THERE.
WHEN THE LINE BROKE,
YOU BLAMED THE WORLD.
WE'RE PROUD OF YOU.
NEXT TIME,
YOU'LL TELL
A BETTER STORY.
HURRY BACK.
TIME IS SHORT.
MONTY.
YES?
THE ATHENS EMBASSY
HEARD FROM JERUSALEM.
FOR YOUR EYES ONLY.
SHE'S EVERYTHING
WE WANT--
BRIGHT, CREATIVE,
UNDERUSED, ROMANTIC...
AND A LIAR.
TONIGHT SHE LIES
FOR HERSELF.
TOMORROW
SHE LIES FOR US.
DO WE WANT
AN ANGEL SUDDENLY?
NOW LISTEN TO THIS.
MISHA GAVON SAYS WE ARE
TO POSE AS AMERICANS.
ISN'T THAT NICE?
"ON NO ACCOUNT
WILL YOU ADMIT TO HER
"THAT YOU
ARE ISRAELI SUBJECTS
ACTING IN OFFICAL
OR NEAR OFFICAL CAPACITY."
I LOVE IT.
THAT'S HELPFUL, HUH?
AND SO TIMELY.
CABLE THEM "YES"--
REPEAT "NO!"
TIME FOR YOU
TO TAKE OVER.
HE HAS LOST IT.
I KNOW THE SIGNS.
HE'S A GREAT FIGHTER.
I NEVER KNEW
ANYONE BETTER
FOR DARK NIGHTS
EXCEPT YOU.
WE SHOULD'VE USED
THE JEWISH GIRL.
SURELY, THEY'LL
CHECK HER PAST.
WE NEED THE
GENUINE ARTICLE,
NOT AN
IMPERSONATION.
SHE WON'T
TOW THE LINE.
THEY BOTH WILL.
BOYS, GIRLS, GIVE HER
MORE SUPPORT.
MORE WARMTH NOW...
A FAMILY SHE CAN JOIN.
SO, CHARLIE?
SO?
I LIED.
THAT MAKES US EVEN.
HOW DOES THAT AFFECT
MY POLITICS?
THEY MIGHT
ALSO BE LIES.
GODDAMN IT!
I BELIEVE IN THINGS.
I BELIEVE
IN ENDING SUFFERING.
WHAT HAVE
YOU DONE, REALLY?
GOTTEN
YOURSELF FILMED
IN ONE DEMONSTRATION
OR ANOTHER
IN TRAFALGAR SQUARE.
YOU MADE
THE EVENING NEWS,
SITTING
IN FRONT OF A BUS,
READING ALOUD
FROM CHE GUEVARA.
WHAT HAVE YOU
DONE BESIDES TALK?
NOT A THING.
YOU WANTED
TO STOP THE KILLING.
FINE, SO DO WE.
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE?
WHAT WOULD YOU DO?
TELL ME.
CHARLIE.
LISTEN TO ME,
BOTH SIDES
HAVE THEIR MADMEN,
THEIR EXTREMISTS.
THEIRS
WOULD DRIVE US
INTO THE SEA.
OURS WOULD
WIPE THEM OUT.
THEY HAVE
THE WEAPONS.
SOME ON BOTH SIDES
WANT TO COME
TOGETHER,
WANT A
PALESTINIAN
HOMELAND BESIDE US.
I DO.
THE KILLINGS
MADE ME LEAVE.
I'M BACK BECAUSE
I DON'T WANT
MADMEN IN CHARGE.
DO YOU?
NO.
DO YOU WANT
TO BLOCK TRAFFIC
IN TRAFALGAR SQUARE,
OR DO YOU
REALLY WANT TO HELP?
SO THAT
ROMANTIC TOUR OF GREECE
WAS JUST A COME-ON,
WASN'T IT?
I WANT VERY MUCH
TO MAKE THAT TOUR
WITH YOU, CHARLIE.
THE AUDITION'S
OVER, CHARLIE.
THE PART IS YOURS,
IF YOU WANT IT.
OR YOU'RE
FREE TO LEAVE NOW.
WHO DO I PLAY?
YOURSELF.
WE TAKE CARE
OF THE PLOT.
JOSEPH PLAYS
MICHEL AND
WRITES DIALOGUE
WITH HELP
FROM YOU.
YOU HAVE
A FEW HOURS TO SLEEP
AND A BIG PART
TO LEARN.
SO, GO TO BED.
RACHEL WILL WAKE YOU
WHEN IT'S TIME.
WHO'S THE REAL MICHEL?
YOU MET HIM.
HE WORE A SKI MASK
AND LECTURED TO YOU
IN DORSET.
YOU'LL MEET HIM AGAIN.
SO, GOOD NIGHT.
SO, GOOD NIGHT
TO YOU, TOO.
YOU HAVEN'T
LOST YOUR TOUCH.
SHE'S GOING TO
DO IT FOR YOU.
YOU DECIDE
HOW TO PLAY
WITH HER EMOTIONS.
YOU MIGHT GET CLOSE.
YOU MIGHT
PLAY DISTANCE.
THIS ONE IS DISTANCE.
GOOD LUCK TO YOU.
GOOD LUCK, EH?
CHARLIE.
HUH?
WAKE UP, CHARLIE.
IT'S TIME.
OHH.
WHAT TIME IS IT?
IT'S 11:00.
YOU'VE
HAD FOUR HOURS.
I BOUGHT YOU
A DRESS. ALSO
NEW UNDERCLOTHES.
LOOK AROUND.
REMEMBER THIS ROOM.
WE HAD
A WONDERFUL
DINNER LAST NIGHT.
PUTARI WINE,
WHITE AND COLD.
LOBSTER.
WHO ARE YOU?
FROM NOW ON,
I'M MICHEL.
YOU'LL BE
PLAYING YOURSELF.
WE'RE ACTING
OUT A LOVE AFFAIR.
THIS IS WHERE
WE SPENT THE NIGHT.
WE VISITED
THE ACROPOLIS.
WE HAD IT
TO OURSELVES.
THEN WE CAME HERE.
WE MADE VERY
PASSIONATE LOVE,
VERY FRENZIED.
HOW DO YOU RATE?
I'M IMPRESSIVE.
LACKING IN
IMAGINATION, BUT
VERY ENTHUSIASTIC.
SORRY
I SWIPED YOU, JOS.
FEEL
UNDER THE PILLOW.
THERE.
OH, MY GOD.
IT'S AN AUTOMATIC.
A GIFT FROM
MY BROTHER KHALIL,
WHO IS LIKE MY GOD.
IT SERVES
A BAD WISH SLEEPING.
WE CALL IT CHIVE.
IT'S THERE
DURING LOVEMAKING.
WE NEVER FORGET IT.
THAT'S HOW WE LIVE.
HURRY
AND GET DRESSED.
[DOORBELL BUZZES]
HAS HE TALKED YET?
NOT A PEEP.
NOT A SOUND?
SOUND, YES.
SPEECH, NO.
WHAT'S HIS CONDITION?
HE'S VERY TIRED.
FOR THREE DAYS
HE'S HAD SEVEN NIGHTS
AND FIVE HOURS
OF SLEEP.
HE ONLY TAKES WATER.
WE HAVE
CHARLIE'S LETTERS?
A FEW
WITH SOME
INFORMATION.
SCHVILI'S
WORKING
ON THEM.
YOU'RE CHECKING
THE MAIL AT HIS FLAT?
TWICE A DAY.
I CAN SHOW YOU
THEIR LOVE STORY--
ATHENS
TO THESSALONIKI,
BUT WHAT
ABOUT THE CAR
AND EXPLOSIVES?
WHO HE
WAS PLANNING
TO CONTACT, WHEN?
IT'S A PROBLEM
IF WE CAN'T
BREAK HIM.
YOU HAVE A TAPE
OF A BEATING?
YEAH.
A BAD ONE?
WE'LL USE IT TOMORROW.
GIVE HIM
MORE SLEEP TONIGHT.
LET HIM FEEL FORGOTTEN.
YOU PEOPLE
NEED PATIENCE, HUH?
LISTEN TO ME.
I AM MICHEL.
NO! NO, NOT AGAIN.
CHARLIE.
I'M TIRED OF MICHEL.
GIVE HIM A BREAK.
BE JOSEPH FOR TONIGHT.
THERE ISN'T TIME.
SOON OR LATER
YOU'LL BE QUESTIONED
ABOUT TONIGHT.
OK. ALL RIGHT.
SO YOU'RE MICHEL.
I'M MICHEL,
BUT MY ARAB
NAME IS SALIM.
I'M FROM
A SMALL VILLAGE
CLOSE TO
THE TOWN OF KHALIL,
WHICH THE JEWS
CALL HEBRON.
KHALIL--SAY IT.
KHALIL.
YOU'RE
BROTHER'S NAME.
MY FATHER
WAS THE CHIEF
OF THE VILLAGE,
WHERE OUR FAMILY
LIVED FOR CENTURIES.
MY FATHER
ADMIRED THE JEWS.
MY BROTHER AHMED
REMEMBERED WATERING
GRANDFATHER'S HORSE
AND HEARING
WONDERFUL STORIES
FROM
JEWISH TRAVELERS
AND PEDDLERS.
IN 1948
MY GRANDFATHER
SOLD HIS HORSE
TO BUY RIFLES
TO SHOOT ZIONISTS
WHEN THEY ATTACKED
OUR VILLAGES.
ZIONISTS SHOT MY
GRANDFATHER INSTEAD.
THEY MADE MY FATHER
WITNESS HIS DEATH.
MY FATHER, WHO
BELIEVED IN THEM.
IS THAT TRUE?
DO YOU KNOW
DAL YISSIN?
NO.
IN THAT VILLAGE
ON APRIL 9th, 1948,
254 WOMEN, OLD MEN,
AND CHILDREN
WERE BUTCHERED BY
ZIONIST TERRORISTS
WHILE THE MEN WORKED
IN THE FIELDS.
IN DAYS
500,000 PALESTINIANS
HAD FLED
THEIR OWN COUNTRY.
BUT
OUR VILLAGE STAYED
ON MY FATHER'S
COMMAND UNTIL 1967.
THAT'S WHEN
THE ISRAILI TANKS
CAME TO FLATTEN
OUR HOUSES,
MAKING ROOM FOR
THEIR SETTLEMENTS.
SO WE LEARN
TO FIGHT ZIONISTS.
DO YOU
KNOW WHO SAID,
"I FIGHT,
THEREFORE I EXIST?"
HE'S
A POLISH TERRORIST.
KILLED MANY BRITISH
AND PALENSTINIANS.
THIS PROUD WINNER
OF THE NOBEL
PRIZE FOR PEACE.
HE'S THE PRIME
MINISTER OF MY
COUNTRY PALESTINE,
WHICH THEY STOLE
AND NOW CALL ISRAEL.
I LOVE YOU.
SHARE MY CAUSE.
WHO ARE YOU?
DOES IT PLAY?
YES. IT PLAYS.
KEEP IT.
SOUVENIR OF THIS
WONDERFUL NIGHT.
WHERE WERE YOU
DURING ALL OF THIS?
YOU, JOSEPH.
I WAS IN THOSE
ISRAELI TANKS
IN 1967, CHARLIE.
AHH!
PLEASE!
STOP RIGHT HERE!
YOU'RE NOT
TAKING HIM ANYWHERE.
GET AWAY.
WE LEAVE NOW!
THE GENEVA PROTOCOL--
SHOVE GENEVA
PROTOCOL!
DO NOTHING
UNTIL I SEE
THE AUTHORITIES.
ALL RIGHT!
LET'S GO.
COLONEL HERSCH,
I WANT TO TALK TO YOU.
WE HAVE A COMPLAINT.
WHAT IS IT?
WE HAVE SEEN
THIS MAN'S BROTHER
KHALIL KASSAN.
THEY NEARLY
BEAT HIM TO DEATH.
LAST NIGHT
WAS AN ACCIDENT.
HE WAS
SAVAGELY TORTURED!
KHALIL KASSAB
IS A MURDERER!
I'VE NO SYMPATHY.
YOU WILL BE
RESPONSIBLE THEN
FOR A RED CROSS
PUBLIC CONDEMNATION!
MY NAME
IS COLONEL HERSCH.
I HAVE A FEW
QUESTIONS TO ASK YOU.
YOU ARE SALIM KASSAB?
YOU WERE SEIZED
BY THE IDF
FOR YOUR CRIMES
AGAINST ISRAELIS.
YOU WERE FOUND
POSSESSING THE AUTOMATIC
GIVEN TO YOU
BY YOUR BROTHER
KHALIL KASSAB.
WILL YOU CONFIRM
THAT YOU ARE
SALIM KASSAB?
OK. YOU HAVE BEEN
A BRAVE BOY.
11 DAYS
AND NOT A WORD.
MANY DON'T LAST
AN HOUR.
BUT YOU KNOW...
EVERYONE TALKS.
ARE YOU SALIM KASSAB?
PLEASE.
CAN I SEE
MY BROTHER, PLEASE?
GOT HIM!
I HOPE
WE CAN ARRANGE THAT.
MARTY'S
GETTING IT ALL.
THE BOY'S
A FOUNTAIN.
KHALIL'S PEOPLE
WILL GET THE CAR
IN LIVNITZ.
SHE'LL PUT THE KEYS
IN THE TAIL PIPE.
HE'S SIGNING OUT.
WILL THEY EXPECT
A GIRL TO BE DRIVING?
HE'S USED
THEM BEFORE.
TELL MARTY
TO STAND BY.
HERE'S SOME MORE.
PARK, PUT THE KEYS
IN THE TAIL PIPE,
GO TO MUNICH.
WHAT'S IN THE CAR?
IT'S NOT DANGEROUS.
EXPLOSIVES.
200 POUNDS OF RUSSIAN
PLASTIC EXPLOSIVES.
WHERE DID
THEY HIDE IT?
IT'S BEEN THERE
ALL ALONG.
OH, MY GOD!
WHERE?
UNDER SEATS,
IN THE ROOF...
WHAT'S IT FOR?
THE CAUSE.
DON'T USE THE RADIO.
YOU'RE JOKING.
YES, I AM.
WELL, DON'T!
SHE'S ALL YOURS, CHARLIE.
WHOSE ARE THESE?
THOSE WERE HIS.
I'LL BE EMBALMED
IN ARAMIS.
LOOK AT
THE PAPERS
ONCE MORE.
I KNOW THEM.
THE BORDER IS
FOUR KILOMETERS NORTH.
IT'S 700 MILES
THROUGH YUGOSLAVIA.
YOU'RE EXPECTED
IN TWO DAYS.
STATION ON
THE SQUARE,
KEYS IN
THE TAIL PIPE, MUNICH.
I DO HAVE A MIND.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I KNOW WHAT I'M DOING.
¶ WHEN YOU'RE ALONE... ¶
¶ YOU CAN ALWAYS GO ¶
¶ DOWNTOWN ¶
¶ WHEN YOU'VE
GOT WORRIES... ¶
TELL MEIR
THE PACKET'S POSTED.
HOW MUCH TIME
HAS SHE GOT?
SHE PASSED
THE BORDER
10 MINUTES AGO.
SHE MIGHT
MISS THE TRAIN.
GIVE AN ALERT.
KEEP IT IN GERMAN.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
JA.
SHE'S HERE.
GOOD.
SHE'S IN TIME
FOR THE TRAIN.
HAVE TOBY
MAKE SPACE.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
NEIN, NEIN, NEIN!
AMERICAN?
YEAH.
WHO IS THAT?
WHO IS HE?
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
AMERICANA.
HE'S AN AMERICAN.
JULIO, MOVE IN.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
JUST COME ON OUT.
BEN, COVER.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
BACK...
OK, NOW BACK.
FORWARD.
PARKING'S NEVER
BEEN MY STRONG SUIT.
I COULD TELL.
YOU'RE FROM AMERICA?
UH-HUH. FROM IOWA.
IOWA! NEBRASKA!
WE'RE ALMOST NEIGHBORS.
WE SHOULD CELEBRATE.
LET'S GET A DRINK.
I'VE GOT
A TRAIN TO CATCH.
HERE.
NO, NO, NO.
HEY, NO PROBLEM.
TO THE STATION?
YEAH.
THE KEYS.
SHE DIDN'T
LEAVE THE KEYS.
MY COAT.
I'LL BE BACK.
GOOD GIRL.
JULIO, STAY WITH HER.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
WHERE YOU HEADED?
ME? OH, GRASSE.
ODED, MIDDLE DISTANCE.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
IT'S A LONG STORY.
DON'T GET ME STARTED.
THERE'LL BE
A LATER ONE.
NOT FOR ME.
TOO BAD.
NO BRIEF ENCOUNTER.
I'M AFRAID THAT'S
JUST WHAT YOU GOT.
HERE.
BYE.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
PASSENGER ON BOARD.
THE CUSTOMER'S
JUST A PEDESTRIAN.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
A MOTORCYCLE JUST
CIRCLED AROUND TWICE.
THE LION MAYBE
TAKES A SNIFF.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
CUSTOMER'S BACK.
ANOTHER SNIFF.
ALBERT LUIGI ROSSINO.
BORN ROME, 1956.
I ALWAYS SAID
THE SON OF A BITCH
WAS RED BRIGADE.
SEND THAT TO JERUSALEM.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
THE DRIVER'S A GIRL.
SHE COULD
BE THE BLONDE
THAT BLEW UP THE HOUSE
IN BAD GODESBERG.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
TRAIN COMING.
ROSE, WHERE IS
YOUR CUSTOMER?
GO AFTER HER.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
SHE'S GONE.
GONE?
WHERE THE HELL'S HE GOING?
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
CUSTOMER'S LEAVING.
WHERE?
SHE'S IN THE CAR.
EVERYBODY GO.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
THEY SPLIT UP.
COMPANY FAVORS THE LADY.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
PICK HER UP AS
SOON AS IT'S SAFE.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
CHARLIE, WE OWE
YOU AN ORCHID.
WAIT A MINUTE.
LET ME FINISH THIS.
I HAD WINE IN A SACK.
WHEN I BENT OVER,
MY SKIRT
OPENED LIKE A BOOK.
I'LL LET THESE
POOR BORDER GUARDS
SEE A FLASH OF THIGH.
I THOUGHT I'D BEEN SHOT!
THIS BOY STAMPED ME
WITH HIS PASSPORT STAMPER!
I'LL SHOW YOU.
RIGHT?
OH, CHARLIE,
YOU ARE GREAT!
YOU ARE
INCREDIBLE!
SHALOM.
WE DO THE
LETTERS NOW.
TIME GOES.
DOESN'T A TRAINED SEAL
GET A SARDINE?
WE WROTE
THESE FOR YOU.
YOUR LETTERS
TO MICHEL.
HE SAVED THEM.
READ THEM.
YOU WANT MY
FINGERPRINTS?
YES. VERY SHARP.
THEY SHOW
YOU'VE WRITTEN HIM
SINCE NOTTINGHAM.
ALL RIGHT. OK.
HA HA!
OH, MY GOD.
OH, PLEASE.
OH, NO!
SHE'S A LUSTFUL BITCH,
ISN'T SHE?
IT'S MY HAND.
ABSOLUTELY MY HAND.
IT DID RAIN
IN NOTTINGHAM.
HOW'D YOU KNOW THAT?
OK. WAIT.
OH, NO.
OH, SHE'S SHAMELESS.
THIS IS AWFUL!
WHAT IS IT?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
IT'S TIME
TO MEET THE
REAL MICHEL.
JUST FOR PRECAUTIONS,
PUT THESE GLASSES ON.
IF YOU GET SEASICK,
REMEMBER HE KILLED
MANY INNOCENT HUMANS.
EVERYBODY HAS
A HUMAN FACE.
HE'S NO EXCEPTION.
GOOD LOOKS,
TALENT, POTENTIAL...
ALL WASTED.
DON'T TALK TO HIM.
WE'LL DO THAT.
LOOK AT HIS HANDS.
HE WAS GOING
TO BE A CARPENTER.
NOW HE'S A GREAT
INTELLECTUAL.
LOTS OF MONEY, GIRLS,
GOOD FOOD, SOFT HANDS...
YOU'RE A GREAT
INTELLECTUAL.
RIGHT, LITTLE FELLOW?
YOUR GIRLS
DO YOUR WORK.
ONE GIRL
HE USED AS A BOMB.
I GUESS SHE NEVER
KNEW SHE'D DONE IT.
YOU WANT TO SPEAK
TO THIS LADY?
WELCOME HER
TO OUR VILLA.
TELL HER
GOOD EVENING,
LITTLE FELLOW.
GOOD EVENING.
DON'T ANSWER.
GOOD EVENING, MA'AM!
GOOD EVENING, MADAM.
HAVE HIM
WRITE SOMETHING.
SEE HOW HE WRITES?
ARAB STYLE.
ARABS AND JEWS WRITE
FROM THE WRONG SIDE.
MAYBE ONCE YOU FOUND HIM
DOING HIS ACCOUNTS.
SO THAT'S
HOW HE LOOKS.
CHARLIE.
DEAR.
WE HAVE ONE FURTHER
STAGE OF THIS THING.
WE MUST GO
THROUGH WITH IT NOW,
EVEN IF IT COSTS
A LITTLE EFFORT.
COME ON. GET UP.
PLEASE...
BIRTHMARK.
KNIFE WOUND.
TURN HIM
AROUND.
PLEASE, SIR.
APPENDIX SCAR.
PLEASE.
FEET.
JORDANIANS DID THIS
TO HIM AS A BOY.
TORTURE BY
WHIPPING SOLES.
ARAB SPECIALTY.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
GET HIM DRESSED.
YOUR LETTERS TO MICHEL
WILL BE PLANTED
IN HIS APARTMENT.
THEY WILL LEAD
HIS FRIENDS TO YOU.
MAYBE A WEEK,
A MONTH, OR MORE.
WHENEVER THEY
MAKE CONTACT,
PUT ON THIS
RED SCARF...
AND WE'LL GET TO YOU.
WILL YOU KILL HIM?
I'VE KILLED
ALL THE ARABS
I EVER WANT TO KILL.
KEEP THIS WITH YOU.
IT'S A RADIO.
IT'S IMPORTANT.
HIS LETTERS TO YOU
ARE IN YOUR DESK.
MICHEL SAID
TO HIDE THEM,
BUT CARRY
THEM WITH YOU.
EMERGENCY SIGNAL?
WHAT WAS THE QUESTION?
IF THERE IS
AN EMERGENCY...
THE RED SCARF.
AND I KNOW
THE HEMPSTEAD NUMBERS.
AND I LOVE YOU.
THOUGHT I'D MENTION IT
IN CASE ONE OF US DIED.
HER NAME IS LINSTROM,
SHE THINKS.
MICHEL PICKED HER UP
IN FRANKFORT, SHE THINKS.
SHE LOVES FUCKING
AND BLOWING PEOPLE UP.
SHE ADMITS GODESBERG.
SHE'S HOW OLD?
21 NEXT WEEK.
WHAT'S YOUR POINT?
WE HAVE TO
HAVE THE EVIDENCE
THAT NOBODY HAS HER
BUT GOD AND MICHEL.
ARE YOU DISAGREEING?
NO.
NO WHAT?
NO OPERATION?
WHAT IS NO?
IF SHE LIVES,
THEY'LL NEVER
ACCEPT CHARLIE.
IF WE'RE GOING ON,
THIS IS WHERE WE'LL DO IT.
IF?
ASK EACH KID
INDIVIDUALLY.
NO MARK AGAINST
ANYONE WHO WANTS OUT.
I ASKED THEM.
ASK THEM AGAIN!
GO AHEAD. DO IT.
I'M CALLING RUTH
FOR FAMILY NEWS.
HELLO, DARLING.
DID I WAKE YOU UP?
I'M ALONE.
CHECK THE TRAFFIC.
POST ONE, TRAFFIC.
POST TWO, TRAFFIC.
ALL CLEAR.
I'LL CALL GAVRON.
DO YOU WISH TO
TELL ME SOMETHING?
DO YOU HAVE
A MORAL POINT
THAT WILL EASE
YOU INTO A NICE
FRAME OF MIND?
SAM!
HELLO, CHARLIE!
WELCOME BACK.
HAVE A NICE TRIP?
WONDERFUL!
TALK TO YOU LATER.
I'LL BEGIN
WITH THE WOMEN.
I CHARGE YOU, O WOMEN,
FOR THE LOVE
YOU BEAR TO MEN,
TO LIKE AS MUCH
OF THIS PLAY--
OK. SKIP
TO THE END,
WHERE YOU DO
THE CURTSY THING.
WHEN I MAY CURTSY,
BID ME FAREWELL.
FOR THE
CURTAIN CALL--
THERE WASN'T TIME
FOR MY CHANGE.
WE'LL SETTLE THAT.
YOU TAKE
CENTER STAGE.
ORLANDO COME
TO ROSIE'S RIGHT.
SHOULDN'T
I BE CENTER
WITH ROSALIND?
SHE'S MY DAUGHTER,
FOR FUCK'S SAKE.
CHARLIE, THESE
ARE FOR YOU.
SOME LOVELY MAN
AWAITS YOU IN
THE GREEN ROOM.
OH, AREN'T YOU
THE LUCKY GIRL.
MISS CHARLIE?
I BRING YOU
GREETINGS
FROM MICHEL.
WHO'S SHE?
I DON'T KNOW
A MICHELLE.
HE ASKED ME TO
TAKE YOU TO DINNER.
HE INSISTED.
I DON'T KNOW MICHEL,
AND I DON'T KNOW YOU.
GOOD NIGHT,
CHARLIE.
GOOD NIGHT.
MICHEL ASKED ME
TO BUY YOU LOBSTER
AND WINE--
WHITE AND COLD.
I HAVE OTHER
MESSAGES ALSO.
HE'LL BE VERY
ANGRY YOU REFUSED
HIS HOSPITALITY.
WHERE IS HE?
I'LL TAKE YOU.
CHARLIE!
I'VE GOT
AN INTERVIEW.
HOW ABOUT A DRINK?
TOMORROW!
MICHEL.
ANTON, YOU'VE
BROUGHT ME CHARLIE.
THIS IS TOO NICE.
WELCOME.
WHERE IS HE?
SHOW ME HOW TO WORK
THIS RIDICULOUS MACHINE.
YOU CALL ME HELGA.
HOW WAS SHE?
WAS SHE FANTASTIC?
SHE WAS WONDERFUL.
I KNOW IT WAS
ONLY A REHEARSAL.
WHERE IS HE? MICHEL!
MICHEL!
WHERE IS HE?
SIT DOWN.
NO!
YOU SAID YOU
HAD MESSAGES.
WHEN DID
YOU SEE HIM?
NEVER MIND!
ANSWER.
GO TO HELL!
THE MOVEMENT
WANTS HIS LETTERS.
THEY BELONG TO US.
PLEASE SIT.
HE'S DEAD, ISN'T HE?
WE'RE SORRY.
YES, HE'S DEAD.
WHAT HAPPENED?
IS SHE IN DANGER?
I DON'T KNOW.
THOSE BASTARDS.
POOR, CHARLIE.
WE ALL SYMPATHIZE.
BUT CRYING
MEANS NOTHING.
ACTRESSES ARE
TRAINED TO CRY.
DRINK THIS NOW.
OHH!
YOU HAVE TO ANSWER
CERTAIN THINGS.
BUT YOU
KILLED HIM.
THE POLICE SAY
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
SHE'S PLAYING
HYSTERICS.
WHERE ARE
HIS LETTERS?
I BURNT THEM.
NO, NO, NO.
LOVE DOESN'T
BURN LETTERS.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
WHERE DID YOU
FIRST MEET?
IF YOU
DON'T ANSWER--
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
SEE? A LIE
FOUND OUT ALREADY.
NO MORE, PLEASE.
THIS IS A
REVOLUTIONARY MOVEMENT,
AND WE WILL DO EVERYTHING
TO PROTECT OURSELVES!
GREAT! YOU JUST
DO THAT. TERRIFIC.
WHEN DID YOU
MEET HIM FIRST?
WHEN?
IN DORSET.
LIE! HE WAS
NEVER IN DORSET.
NOTTINGHAM, YES?
IT WAS DORSET!
HE SPOKE THERE.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
WHAT'S THIS?
AN ASHTRAY.
WHAT ELSE?
ANSWER ME!
WHERE DID
YOU GET IT?
IT'S FROM THE NIGHT
IN THESSALONIKI.
WHEN HE TOLD ME
ABOUT HIS BROTHER.
AND ABOUT
DEAR USINE.
WHAT BROTHER?
DID HE MENTION
A NAME?
HIS BROTHER...
KHALIL.
HE LOVED HIM
MORE THAN ANYONE.
WHAT'S GOING ON
UP THERE?
YOU LIVE
AROUND HERE?
I WAS JUST CURIOUS.
THERE SHE IS.
CHARLIE!
HEY, CHARLIE!
I BELIEVE THAT
WAS THE GIRL.
YES, IT WAS.
SHE'S RUNNING...
IF THAT'S
WHAT YOU WANT.
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT WE WANT.
THANK YOU,
COMMANDER.
THANK YOU.
DID YOU CALL
THE PIGS ON ME?
MY FLAT.
THEY'RE THERE.
HOW CAN I DO
THIS PLAY?
THEY'LL TAKE ME
OFF THE STAGE.
WHAT AM I
SUPPOSED TO DO?
WHERE'S JOSEPH,
FOR GOD'S SAKE?
I PUT ON
THE RED SCARF.
HE SAID HE'D COME.
THEY WANT TO FLY ME
TO LEBANON TOMORROW.
YOU SON OF A BITCH!
YOU KILLED HIM!
YES.
YOU SAID YOU'D
STOP THE KILLING.
IT WAS NECESSARY.
I ASKED YOU.
I SAID WHAT YOU
WANTED TO HEAR.
TELL ME THE TRUTH.
I WANT TO KNOW
WHAT I MEAN TO YOU!
CHARLIE, COME ON.
NO! YOU NEVER
REALLY TOUCHED ME.
YOU MADE ME FEEL
LIKE I WAS NOTHING.
TELL ME
ABOUT THESE.
THE SCARS?
MM-HMM.
BURNS FROM
SITTING IN A TANK.
OH.
AND THESE?
BULLET HOLES FROM
GETTING OUT OF IT.
OH. AND THIS?
SINAI.
GOLAN HEIGHTS.
I'M A MAP OF
THE MIDDLE EAST.
I USED TO TAKE
PRIDE IN THAT.
WHEN DO YOU STOP?
WHEN DOES IT END?
THE END IS KHALIL.
WHAT'S HE LIKE?
HE'S VERY GOOD.
CLEVER.
HE ALWAYS MOVES.
HE HAS NOBODY
HE RELIES ON.
FEW SEE HIM.
HE'LL WANT
TO SEE YOU
BECAUSE
OF HIS BROTHER.
HOW WILL
I KNOW HIM?
WE DON'T HAVE
ANY PICTURES OF HIM.
JUST HIS SIGNATURE.
SIGNATURE?
A HABIT, REALLY.
EXTRA WIRE
OFF THE DETENATOR
THAT HE WINDS
AROUND ITSELF
AND THROWS IN
WITH THE BOMB.
CAN'T YOU GET
A PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION?
SOMEBODY MUST
HAVE SEEN HIM.
CHARLIE.
DON'T GO.
DON'T GO?
YOU'VE DONE ENOUGH.
YOU LIFTED THE LID
ON THE OPERATION.
WE CAN SEE IN.
YOU CAN STOP NOW.
WHY NOW?
UNTIL NOW,
WE'VE BEEN NEARBY.
WE COULD STEP IN
IF YOU NEEDED US.
IF YOU GO OVER,
YOU'RE OUT OF REACH
MAYBE FOR MONTHS.
WHAT DOES
MARTY SAY?
THAT YOU COULD STOP
WHEN YOU WANTED.
HE DIDN'T START ME OUT
TO HAVE IT END HERE.
CHARLIE.
I DON'T WANT
YOU TO GO.
I DON'T WANT TO BE
JUST WHAT I WAS.
DON'T SEND ME BACK
TO TRAFALGAR SQUARE.
PLEASE.
PLEASE, JOSEPH.
DO YOU SPEAK FRENCH?
I'M AFRAID NOT.
FORGIVE
MY ENGLISH.
YES. I FORGIVE
YOUR ENGLISH.
WHAT WAS THAT?
HOLIDAY INN.
USED TO WAS.
MISS CHARLIE.
CAPTAIN TAYEH.
I OFFER YOU
THE HOSPITALITY
OF OUR REVOLUTION.
WELCOME.
THANK YOU.
YOU FLEW THROUGH
THE BACK DOOR.
YES. FROM EAST
BERLIN TO HERE.
COFFEE, TEA?
TEA, PLEASE.
YOU WANT
TO KILL ZIONISTS?
YES.
MOST ENTHUSIASTS
WE GET
WANT TO BLOW UP
THE WHOLE WORLD.
ARE YOU
LIKE THAT?
NO.
THESE ARE SCUM,
THESE PEOPLE.
HELGA,
MASTERBEIN...
NECESSARY SCUM.
YES?
I HAVEN'T HAD
TIME TO FIND OUT.
ARE YOU SCUM?
NO.
I DON'T THINK SO.
YOU WRITE
BEAUTIFUL LETTERS.
THEY WERE MEANT
TO BE PRIVATE.
TEA.
GO HOME.
YOU'VE DONE NOTHING
CRIMINAL YET.
YOU HAVE CIVIL
RIGHTS, DEMOCRACY.
WHY GIVE THEM UP
FOR A BUNCH OF
STATELESS SAVAGES?
I BELIEVE
WHAT HE BELIEVED.
WHAT KHALIL BELIEVES.
MICHEL
CHANGED MY LIFE.
HE TAUGHT
YOU TO HATE?
HATE IS
FOR ZIONISTS.
TO FIGHT,
WE MUST LOVE.
ANTISEMITISM IS
A CHRISTIAN INVENTION.
HE TAUGHT YOU
THAT IN BED?
SORRY, SORRY.
SORRY.
WHAT HE TAUGHT
YOU IS TRUE.
I'M READY.
MAYBE I BELIEVE YOU.
MAYBE I DON'T.
MAYBE IT WON'T
MATTER TOO MUCH.
THEY HAVE
CLOTHES FOR YOU.
[SINGING DOWNTOWN]
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
GO.
10 SECONDS.
I CAN DO IT FASTER.
ONCE AGAIN.
ARABIC.
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
1...
2...
3...
4...
5...
6...
7...
8...
9...
10...
11...
12...
13.
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
WHO IS THE TARGET?
A PROFESSOR FROM
HEBREW UNIVERSITY.
A PEACEMAKER.
HIS NAME IS
ASHA MINKEL.
HE'S SPEAKING
IN FREIBURG.
WHEN?
IN SIX DAYS.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
THEY'LL USE CHARLIE?
ONCE SHE HAS KILLED,
SHE'S COMMITTED.
SHE'LL BE MARRIED
TO KHALIL FOR LIFE.
SHE DOESN'T
SPEAK GERMAN.
SHE CAN PULL A TRIGGER.
THEY WON'T TRUST HER
UNTIL SHE HAS KILLED.
THE NEXT KILLING
IS SET FOR FREIBURG.
IN YOUR LETTER,
YOU MENTIONED
A CHILD.
WHAT CHILD?
THE GUN.
WE SLEPT WITH IT.
WHERE DID
HE GET IT?
KHALIL.
WHO IS JOSEPH?
JOSEPH WHO?
DO I KNOW
A JOSEPH?
HE WROTE A CARD
TO A FRIEND OF OURS.
OH, THAT JOSEPH.
A GREASY JEW
WHO LIKED GIRLS.
DON'T, DON'T.
DON'T TALK ABOUT
JEWS LIKE THAT.
WE AREN'T ANTISEMETIC.
WE'RE ANTIZIONIST.
TELL ME ANOTHER.
I WANT TO PRESENT
A FIELD PROBLEM.
YOU ARE TRAINED TO
HANDLE FIELD PROBLEMS.
THIS YOUNG FELLOW
WAS FOUND LESS THAN
A KILOMETER FROM HERE
YESTERDAY AFTERNOON.
FOR AN ARAB WANDERER,
HE IS WELL-EQUIPPED.
NIGHT VISION GLASSES,
RADIO TRANSMITTER,
A VERY OLD MOTORBIKE
WITH A VERY NEW ENGINE.
HE SAYS HE IS MUSLIM.
WE SAY HE IS JEW.
WE'RE UNABLE TO AGREE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
HE'S A ZIONIST SPY,
OBVIOUSLY.
THAT'S WHAT WE THINK.
WOULD YOU KILL HIM?
HAVE YOU THOROUGHLY
QUESTIONED HIM?
SINCE HE WON'T SPEAK
BEYOND HIS NAME, YES.
I THOUGHT OF
SHOOTING HIM.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WELL?
PLEASE YOURSELF.
I WILL.
WE HAVE A MISSION
FOR YOU.
GET YOUR POSSESSIONS
AND RETURN HER IMMEDIATELY.
DANKE.
HELLO.
I'M YANO.
COULD I KNOW
YOUR NAME?
IMOGENE.
HI.
COME ON.
YOU MIGHT LOOK
AROUND.
SEE IF ANYONE'S
BOTHERING YOU.
YOU LIKE MUSIC?
HUH?
SURE.
GOOD.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYS]
I LIKE MUSIC.
IMOGENE?
TAKE CARE
OF THE ROOF.
PIECES FALL OFF
ALL THE TIME.
IT'S GREAT.
IT'S TERRIFIC.
IMOGENE, THIS
IS LUIGI.
LUIGI, TAKE
HER BAG.
WE HAVE TO CALL
YOU IMOGENE.
WHO CHOOSES THESE
RIDICULOUS NAMES?
DID YANO HAVE
DIFFICULTY
FINDING YOU?
NO, NONE AT ALL.
NO, WE DON'T KNOW
THEIR PLAN YET.
CERTAINLY, WE'LL
KEEP YOU CURRENT
ON ALL DEVELOPMENTS.
THANK YOU,
INSPECTOR.
THESE GERMAN
SECURITY ARE
VERY INSECURE.
WHAT SHOULD
THEY PREPARE FOR?
CAR BOMBS?
AUTOMATIC WEAPONS?
AND WHERE?
THE AUDITORIUM?
HOTEL?
GERMANY MAKES
YOU JUMPY?
WE'LL KNOW
SOON ENOUGH.
WHERE THE HELL
IS DIMITRI?
SUPPOSE SHE GAVE
HIM AWAY.
SO WHAT'S YOUR
SOLUTION?
KHALIL IS
SOMEWHERE CLOSE.
SEAL EVERYTHING
AND SEARCH.
GERMANY'S NOT
THE WEST BANK.
WHAT DO WE DO
WITH HIM?
KILL HIM.
WHO KILLS CHARLIE?
SHE'S A WHORE,
AND SHE'S
A COMMUNIST,
AN ARAB LOVER!
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
COFFEE.
YES.
NO, HE'S BUSY.
THIS IS HELMUT
BOOTH SPEAKING.
YES.
YOU ARE
A NICE BOY.
CHARLIE ARRIVED
AT THE HOTEL FIVE
MINUTES AGO.
ROSSINO'S WITH HER
HAVING BREAKFAST.
DO WE HAVE
COVERAGE?
UDI, ZEV.
DON'T BE NERVOUS.
YOU'RE GOING TO DO
JUST FINE.
MANCHESTER UNITED
LAST WEEKEND.
POOR OLD EMPIRE.
THE PEUGEOT.
GOOD. HE'S CARRYING
THE BRIEFCASE.
DON'T FORCE IT.
IF IT DOESN'T WORK,
THERE'S LOTS
OF OTHER WAYS.
GO.
IT'S TOO MUCH.
IT'S NOT TOO MUCH.
NO, YOU SHOULDN'T.
ANYWAY, I'LL SEE
YOU LATER. GOOD-BYE.
A ROOM IN THE BACK
WOULD BE PERFECT.
PROFESSOR MINKEL?
YES? WHY?
PROFESSOR, MY NAME'S
IMOGENE BOSTRUP.
I'M FROM TORONTO.
I'M A GRADUATE IN
SOCIAL ANTHROPOLOGY.
I HAD THE GOOD
FORTUNE
TO HEAR YOUR
CENTENARY LECTURE,
AND IT
CHANGED MY LIFE.
DO YOU MIND IF
I SHAKE YOUR HAND?
YOU'RE MRS. MINKEL?
[RING]
YES.
YES!
YES, GOOD.
ROSSINO LIFTED
THE BRIEFCASE.
THEY'LL BRING
IT TO KHALIL
TO WIRE.
CHARLIE WILL
DELIVER IT
TO MINKEL.
PROBABLY THE
LECTURE HALL.
CALL YOUR GERMAN.
TELL HIM YOU
WANT TO DEFUSE
THE BRIEFCASE
AND SET OFF OUR
OWN EXPLOSION.
AND NOBODY
GETS HURT.
SHE'S A FINE GIRL.
I CONGRATULATE YOU.
WAIT.
WAIT?
COME ON.
BYE-BYE, CHARLIE.
GIVE HIM MY LOVE.
HOW WILL I
KNOW KHAHIL?
HE'LL KNOW YOU.
HURRY, NOW.
YANO WILL TAKE
YOU TO HIM.
IMOGENE, HI!
HI.
YOU LIKE FRIEBURG?
BEAUTIFUL, HUH?
I KNOW. I KNOW.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYS]
THIS IS IT.
WAIT, NOW.
TAKE THIS.
WHAT?
HE LIKES ONIONS.
TURN AROUND.
GIVE ME YOUR BAG.
WE ALL DO THIS.
ALL THESE RULES.
BUT IT'S A JOB.
YOU HAVE TO DO IT.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
NICE MUSIC.
I'M SORRY
TO DO THIS.
THOSE ARE ORDERS.
OK.
I APOLOGIZE.
RULES AGAIN.
OK, THAT'S IT.
LET'S GO.
HE'S WAITING FOR US.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
WHERE IS HE?
HE SAID IF HE
WAS DELAYED,
TO START
WITHOUT HIM.
CLOSE THE DOOR.
SIT THERE.
YOU WERE IN TRAINING
CAMP IN LEBANON.
UH-HUH.
YOU KNOW THIS
TYPE OF BOMB?
DID TAYEH TEACH YOU?
YEAH.
YOU WERE
MICHEL'S WOMAN,
WEREN'T YOU?
YES.
I KNEW HIM.
HE WAS A GOOD MAN.
KHALIL'S DIFFERENT,
A LONER.
ALWAYS MOVING.
NEVER IN ONE PLACE.
YOU NEVER
CAN PLAN ON
WHEN HE'S GOING
TO BE ANYPLACE.
GO AHEAD.
LIKE THIS TONIGHT.
MAYBE HE WON'T
EVEN SHOW UP.
WHERE DID YOU
GET THE BRACELET?
MICHEL.
HOW MUCH
DID IT COST?
I DON'T KNOW.
IT WAS GIVEN
TO ME FOR LOVE.
I'VE GOT A CHAIN
THAT'S SACRED.
OK, THE
CIRCUIT'S GOOD.
TAYEH SAYS YOU WERE
VERY MODEST AT CAMP.
NO BOYS.
NOBODY.
WHY DO YOU STARE
AT ME? PLEASE.
WHY DON'T YOU
TRUST ME ENOUGH
TO SAY
YOU'RE KHALIL?
HABIT. HABITS ARE
NOT ALWAYS POLITE.
YOU UNDERSTAND THAT.
HMM?
MY BROTHER WAS
A VERY LUCKY MAN.
LUIGI WILL BRING
YOU BACK TO ME
AFTERWARDS, YES?
GO NOW.
GO.
HELLO?
HELLO!
DO YOU SPEAK
ENGLISH?
YES, I DO.
WOULD YOU
GIVE THIS TO
PROFESSOR MINKEL
WITH IMOGENE
BOSTRUP'S
COMPLIMENTS?
COME WITH ME.
BUT I HAVEN'T
GOTTEN MY TICKET.
COME WITH ME.
NO, YOU HAVE
TO GIVE THIS TO
PROFESSOR MINKEL.
IT HAS HIS LECTURE
NOTES IN IT.
IS THERE A TIMER?
IT EXPLODES
WHEN IT'S OPENED.
GOOD.
THE EXPLOSIVES
ARE SET.
THEY'RE READY
TO GO.
SAY WHAT YOU
WOULD SAY.
IGNORE THE OTHERS.
SO YOU'LL REMEMBER
IF HE QUESTIONS
YOU LATER.
NO, NO, I CAN'T.
GO AHEAD, NOW.
UM...
UM, PROFESSOR MINKEL,
A TERRIBLE THING HAPPENED.
THE HOTEL PEOPLE SENT
YOUR BRIEFCASE TO MY ROOM.
THEY THOUGHT
IT WAS MY CASE.
GIVE IT TO
THE PROFESSOR.
GO ON, CONTINUE.
I DIDN'T SEE IT
TILL HALF AN HOUR AGO.
I'M TERRIBLY SORRY.
HAVE A GREAT SPEECH.
I RESENT THIS.
PEOPLE LIKE YOU WILL
END JEWISH CULTURE.
I WON'T DO IT.
I CAN'T. I WON'T.
PLEASE.
GIVE ME YOUR RADIO.
WHAT ARE YOUR ORDERS?
I'M MEETING ROSSINO.
HE'S WAITING
FOR ME.
THIS RADIO
TRANSMITS A SIGNAL
WE CAN HOME IN ON.
WILL YOU COME?
ARE YOU LISTENING?
IF YOU PRESS
THE VOLUME CONTROL,
IT MEANS
HE'S ASLEEP.
HE WON'T SLEEP.
HE'S LIKE YOU.
I CAN'T DO IT.
HE WANTS ME
FOR A WEDDING NIGHT.
GO BACK NOW.
IT'S A TRAVESTY!
THANKS FOR YOUR
COOPERATION.
YOU HAVE NO RIGHT
TO TELL ME WHAT
RISKS I TAKE.
WE'RE ABOUT SET.
WHAT ABOUT
THE MEDIA?
WE'LL FEED THEM
OUR OWN REPORT.
YOU AND JULIO STAY.
EVERYBODY ELSE OUT.
LEAVE NOW, EVERYBODY!
COME ON, OUT, OUT!
HAVE YOU HEARD
ANYTHING?
NOT YET.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
WHAT HAPPENED?
A GREAT VICTORY.
MINKEL DIED
OPENING THE CASE.
MANY ZIONIST
SUPPORTERS
ARE WOUNDED.
MANY, MANY
SEVERELY. THEY'RE
STILL COUNTING.
TOMORROW
THE WHOLE WORLD
WILL READ
THAT THE PALESTINIANS
WILL NOT WAIT
2,000 YEARS.
75 METERS.
70...
65 METERS.
60...
55 METERS.
STOP. TELL ALL
UNITS TO STAY
WHERE THEY ARE.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
HE'S TALKING
ABOUT ME?
HE'S DESCRIBING YOU.
DON'T WORRY.
WE'LL LOOK
AFTER YOU.
I PROMISE.
TOMORROW,
WE...WE START
YOU TO BEIRUT.
YOU HAVE DONE
A GREAT THING
FOR US.
WE PROTECT YOU
WITH OUR LIVES.
DON'T BE ASHAMED.
WHEN OTHERS KILL,
THEY LAUGH.
BETTER YOU WEEP.
KEEPS YOUR HEART
ALIVE.
BLOCK THE ACCESS
AND STAND BY.
NOBODY MOVES UNTIL
WE GIVE YOU SIGNAL.
TED, GO AROUND THE BACK.
ZEV, TAKE THIS SIDE.
HEY, WAKE UP.
YOU...
HMM?
WAKE UP.
BETTER TO SLEEP.
COME ON.
TALK TO ME.
LOVE ME.
I WILL.
YEAH?
YEAH.
SO WHAT DID THIS...
DID THIS TO YOU?
THIS?
YEAH.
ONE DAY IN BEIRUT,
I'M A LITTLE STUPID
LIKE SALIM.
I RUN THE OFFICE,
THE POSTCOM.
I EXPECTING
A CERTAIN PARCEL.
I OPEN IT.
THIS WAS
A BIG MISTAKE.
WHEN I WOKE UP
IN A HOSPITAL,
THERE WAS SALIM.
HE WAS VERY PLEASED
THAT I SHOWED
MYSELF STUPID.
"BEFORE YOU OPEN
A PARCEL," HE SAID,
"READ THE POSTMARK FIRST.
IF IT COMES FROM TEL AVIV,
BETTER RETURN IT."
I LOVED HIM.
YOU LOVED HIM.
WE LOVED
A STUPID FELLOW...
MAYBE.
WHY NOT?
LOOKS LIKE
THEY'RE IN THE
GROUND-FLOOR BEDROOM.
I COULD TRY
GETTING CLOSER.
NO, NO.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
HOW COULD THEY NOT
SLEEP ALL NIGHT?
WE MUST GO
BEFORE DAYLIGHT.
NO, WE WAIT.
[SPEAKING HEBREW.
NO COWS.
WHAT DO YOU SEE?
NO COWS AND
NO FISHERMEN.
THEY MILK COWS
AT SUNRISE.
NOT FOR TWO HOURS
DO THEY MILK.
NO CARS,
NO PASSING LIGHTS.
NOT ONE LABORER
ON HIS WAY TO WORK.
THEY KEEP COWS
INDOORS.
WHO WANTS TO DRIVE
CARS AT THIS HOUR?
SO...
WHY DO YOU
APOLOGIZE
FOR THEM?
I DON'T WANT YOU
TO BE AFRAID.
I'LL COMFORT YOU.
WHY COMFORT ME?
WHAT?
YOU'RE SEARCHED FOR
BY THE POLICE, BUT
YOU DON'T FEAR.
PLEASE LOVE ME--
WHERE IS YOUR
RADIO, CHARLIE?
WHERE
IS THE RADIO?
WHERE?
IN MY BAG!
TURN IT ON.
LET'S HEAR
SOME MUSIC.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
WHEN DID YOU BUY
NEW BATTERIES?
I DIDN'T.
BUT IT'S WORKING.
IT'S THE
LONG-LIFE ONES.
WE'LL MAKE
AN EXPERIMENT
OF HIGH FREQUENCY.
NO!
[HIGH-PITCHED SQUEAL]
THE HOMING
SIGNAL STOPPED.
SEND ALL UNITS
IN NOW!
YOU WORK FOR
THE GERMANS?
FOR THE ZIONISTS?
ARE YOU JEWISH?
NO.
DO YOU BELIEVE
IN ISRAEL?
WHAT ARE YOU?
NOTHING.
I AM NOTHING.
DID YOU BETRAY
MY BROTHER?
I...NEVER KNEW HIM.
THEY SHOWED HIM TO ME
BEFORE THEY KILLED HIM,
AND THE REST
WAS INVENTED.
OUR LOVE AFFAIR,
EVERYTHING.
I FELL IN LOVE
WITH A MAN WHO
LOOKED AFTER ME,
BUT THAT'S
ALL THERE IS.
YOU BELIEVE
IN NOTHING?
YOU HAVE
NO BELIEFS?
GET IN.
CHECK THE HOUSE.
HOW RIPE IS JOSHUA?
JOSHUA IS GREEN.
ROGER.
COME ON.
[RING]
HELLO.
WHO IS THIS, PLEASE?
YES.
NO PROBLEM.
CHARLIE,
IT'S ALL OVER.
[JET ENGINE ROARS]
START FROM
THE TOP.
DIRECTIONS.
ALL RIGHT.
I THOUGHT OF
TROTTING UP THERE,
BUT THE SKY
LOOKED IMPENDING.
CHRIST, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT IMPENDING MEANS.
I THINK INSTEAD
WE OUGHT--
I DON'T...I DON'T KNOW
WHAT THAT MEANS.
IT'S JUST A WORD.
HE DOESN'T
PICK THEM WELL.
IMPENDING RAIN?
RIGHT.
LET'S GO AGAIN.
SAME PLACE.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S
HEAR IT FROM
THE BEGINNING.
I, UH...
I THOUGHT OF
TROTTING UP THERE,
BUT THE SKY
LOOKS IMPENDING.
YEAH, I HAVE IT.
I THINK INSTEAD--
CHARLIE.
YEAH?
DON'T CAMP IT UP.
KEEP IT REAL.
REAL?
YEAH.
I CAN'T DO IT.
GO ON.
YOU CAN DO IT.
DO IT AGAIN,
FROM THE ENTRANCE.
OK.
OK, ALL RIGHT.
I...I...
I THOUGHT OF
TROTTING UP...
TROTTING UP THERE...
CAN WE HELP
IN SOME WAY?
GO HELP HIM.
NO. UH,
MM-MMM.
NO, I'LL
TAKE CARE OF IT.
UH, IT'S BEST.
I CAN'T.
I CAN'T DO THIS.
I'M SORRY.
YOU GOT SOMEBODY
ELSE YOU WANT ME
TO KILL, JOSE?
CHARLIE! CHARLIE!
MY NAME ISN'T JOSE.
IT'S SCOTT BECKER.
I DON'T KNOW
MUCH ANYMORE
ABOUT WHAT'S RIGHT
AND WHAT'S WRONG.
I'M HERE
BECAUSE I LOVE YOU...
IF YOU'LL LET ME.
I'M DEAD, JOSE.
YOU KILLED ME,
REMEMBER?
I'M DEAD.
CAPTIONING FUNDING BY
WARNER BROS., INC.
CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC.
CAPTIONS COPYRIGHT 1984
WARNER BROS., INC.