(CROWD CHATTERING AND LAUGHING)
- WOMAN 1: Come on!
- WOMAN 2: You can blow better than that!
WOMAN 3: Blow it!
You all right, miss?
I thought someone was following me.
Would you like me to walk you home?
I live right there.
Could you watch to
make sure I get in?
Sure.
Hey, Dad.
Is he all right?
Well, I don't know.
He hasn't got a collar.
Looks like he's kind of hungry.
Oh, can we keep him?
I don't know, honey. Maybe we
ought to take him to the pound.
They'll find him a good home.
What happens if they don't?
MAN (ON TV): There's a big turnout for
Monday Night Football at the Superdome.
New Orleans...
Hey, you know who should
be quarterbacking tonight?
- Stabler.
- WES: Me.
We'll be ready to
go in two minutes.
MAN: Stabler, still suffering from bruised
ribs and coming off a big game...
in a losing effort against
the Buccaneers last week.
The Saints outgained Tampa
Bay by 100 yards...
Here you are, partner.
(PHONE RINGS)
Damn it.
Yeah?
Right.
Sorry, girls.
- WES: Any ID?
- A purse.
(SIREN WAILING)
- What do you think?
- I think she died on the bed.
She couldn't have been killed
in here and dragged in there?
Possible, but not likely.
What time, about?
Well, from the rigor mortis and body
temp, about, uh, oh, 18 to 20 hours ago.
(MACHINE BEEPING)
WOMAN (ON MACHINE): Hi, honey. We just
wanted to wish you a happy birthday.
Dad yelled to say he loves you.
We're excited you'll be home
for the weekend. Bye, dear.
He says she died 18
to 20 hours ago.
That would've made it no
sooner than midnight.
So what?
That clock looked like it was broke
in the struggle. If it says 9:15...
why wasn't she killed
until midnight?
Maybe someone wanted three
hours with her first.
WES: I want everybody on
this block interviewed.
That's the neighbors,
mailmen, garbage people.
In fact, I want every garbage can and every
sewer looked into for a five-block radius.
MOLINARI: You think it
brings the crazies out?
They're always out.
Good evening, Mrs. Holstein.
How are those kids?
Oh, fine, they're asleep.
(POP MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
(WES GRUNTS)
Jesus.
Death came from strangulation.
Ligature marks on her throat...
and hemorrhages around her neck.
There are also two parallel slightly
indented marks on her wrists.
- From what?
- Handcuffs, possibly.
There are bruises on her arms and shoulder
blades from being pinned to the floor.
And what looks like a
knee bruise on her chest.
Before she died, she was penetrated
both vaginally and anally.
- What time did she die?
- Close to midnight.
- You sure?
- She ate a piece of banana cake at 7:00...
then, over the next hour and a half,
consumed eight ounces of white wine.
Chardonnay, I believe.
Then finished at 9 with a small amount
of Swiss vanilla-almond ice cream.
Anything else, detective?
Take a look.
First one is a human scalp hair.
The bulbous portion of the root is still
attached, meaning it was wrenched out.
The next one, the tapered
one, is an eyebrow hair.
And the one at the
bottom is a pubic hair.
- All from the same person?
- Dark-haired Caucasian.
- Probably male, probably in his 40s.
- You're really nailing him down for me.
- Heh. What more do you want?
- His phone number and address.
- Heh. His semen.
- Oh.
- What blood type?
- O. Just like the night before last.
This is a common everyday
rayon-and-acetate fiber.
I found it sticking to the
back of Melanie Silber's neck.
And I found this one under
Yvonne Larkin's fingernail.
You know, the killer didn't leave
any prints this time either.
Every print in the bedroom matched Melanie
Silber's. But there's one thing I don't get.
What?
There was a cup on the dresser
with traces of coffee.
- There weren't any prints on it.
- I saw it. So what?
Well, why would he take the
time to drink a cup of coffee?
He was starting to enjoy himself.
Wes, Beryl Thibodeaux from the rape
something-or-other wants to see you.
- Where is she?
- The reception room.
- Tell her I'm out.
- MAN: I did. She said she'd wait.
Good. Tell her I'm out of town.
Welcome back.
Thanks.
I've tried calling you five times.
Sorry.
Look, I'm not particularly eager...
to talk to women who go around
with chips on their shoulders...
tell everybody I'm doing a lousy job
and get everybody pissed off at me.
I wouldn't be eager to
talk to them either.
I'm really not eager to talk to cops
who have a chip on their shoulders...
stereotype women from rape centers and
then go to any length to avoid them.
I'm sure you don't care for
those kinds of cops either.
Another woman was
strangled last night.
Now, we're concerned it
could be the same killer.
- Why?
- Because she was killed in the same way.
And also because we heard a rumor
the murders might be connected.
- Well, you know how it is with rumors.
- But it could be the same person.
- That possibility always exists.
- Do you have any evidence?
I'm not at liberty to discuss
evidence in this case.
Have you been able to establish
a link between the victims?
I can't discuss that
either. I'm sorry.
Look, all I'm asking is to be involved
in the investigation, all right?
Maybe we could put up
some warning posters.
That say what? That some nut's going
around the city strangling women?
- Yeah, why not?
- Because we're not sure it's true.
All it would do is terrify
women all over this city.
Well, maybe it should.
- Did you brush your teeth?
- Mm-hm.
(HORN HONKS)
Well, you better get going.
Give your dad a smack.
Bye-bye, baby.
MAN:
Come on, kids. We got a big day.
(ENGINE STARTS)
- You want some honey?
- I don't eat sweets.
Do you eat drumsticks, mister?
- MAN: Need any help?
- WES: Not on this one.
WOMAN: Who is it?
WES: May I come in?
I heard you two, uh,
worked together.
Doing what?
As a sandwich.
One on the top and the
other on the bottom.
Well, what else did you hear?
That you liked it.
That you liked her,
but she split on you.
She developed a taste for cops.
She get close to any?
Cops don't get close to anybody.
Any of them come on to her?
They kept coming...
and coming. That's the
funny thing about cops.
Hmm?
You take a cop...
whose wife splits, hmm...
sooner..
Or later...
that cop...
will react like anybody else.
Hmm?
He'll start doing things...
he wouldn't have done before.
Hmm?
So, Block...
what happened to the
rest of the sandwich?
Somebody ate it.
You're 10 minutes late.
Yeah. Ten minutes after
he's down there...
he won't know the difference between
the big hand and the little hand.
Promise?
Trust me.
(FUNK MUSIC PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
WES: You're still awake.
- What's the matter?
- Can't sleep.
Oh. Well.
- Where did you go?
- To his house.
Oh.
- What's it like?
- Big.
- She ask about me?
- No, but I told her about you anyway.
Where did you go tonight?
Out to look for something.
Did you find it?
I found out one thing.
You know what it is?
That you should be in
bed, getting some sleep.
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello?
- It looks like the same method.
- Go ahead.
So how old is this one?
He found her.
- WES: Do you filter on that drain?
- Yeah.
Empty it.
How long has she been in here?
MAN: About an hour.
- Anybody in here with her?
- Not that I saw.
LUTHER: From the hot tub's drain.
And this is the brownie found
in Melanie Silber's apartment.
This is the mold I
made from her teeth.
The mold doesn't match
the impression.
I'll coat the bite-mark pattern on the
brownie and run it under the SEM.
We might get a reading that'll
match the killer's teeth.
Thirty calls already, three from a
Beryl Thibodeaux at the Rape Center.
Oh. Check on the specific days of the crimes,
meteorological reports, phases of the moon.
Would you check CID and find out if there's
similar m.o.'s? And check all 42s in the area.
Get a tail on that
hot-tub guy, would you?
Check out all sexual arrests in
the town for the last two weeks.
That goes for somebody who's been humping
sheep to some guy who's swinging his dick.
- MAN: You got it.
- Here's the file.
Here he comes, Tim.
Detective Block, are
the murders connected?
Yes, we believe that the murders
were committed by the same killer.
So far, the victims have all been women linked
to unusual or aberrant sexual activity.
We recommend, however, that all
women exercise extreme caution...
until this killer is apprehended.
Thank you.
- REPORTER: Do you have any clues?
- WES: I can't talk about it.
What's a hard-on, Daddy?
I heard Amanda say it, and she
won't tell me what it means.
Well, darling, it's...
It's, uh...
When a man is attracted
to a woman...
he, uh, likes her.
- Understand?
- No.
Well, he likes her
in a certain way.
Why?
Well, sweetheart, male bears
like female bears and...
male bees like female bees...
and, uh, occasionally
they get together...
Dad...
forget it.
(DOOR OPENS & BELL DINGS)
(KNOCKING ON TABLE)
You recognize this?
- Why should I?
- You drew it.
- So what?
- Well, tell me about it.
Uh, Jamie Cory, she come here one day
saying this hot-tub guy beat her up.
She wanted a tattoo, so I did it.
Well, the hot-tub guy says she came
down here and you beat her up.
Do I look like the kind of guy
who'd do something like that?
Yeah.
You ever heard of a girl
named Melanie Silber?
Yeah, I like to beat her up too.
(PHONE RINGING)
You know, everybody's
looking to get beat up.
- What's your name?
- Block.
You're hanging out with the
wrong kind of people, Block.
What kind would you
suggest I hang out with?
Someone who's more...
up your alley.
Maybe I'll take you
up on that sometime.
And do what?
Take you bowling?
I don't like bowling.
Neither do I.
(SAXOPHONIST PLAYING "WHEN
THE SAINTS GO MARCHING IN")
(DISCO MUSIC PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
Tequila.
(BLOWING WHISTLE)
- How you doing, Shorty?
- Hello.
- You know Jamie Cory?
- SHORTY: Sure, she wrestled here last night.
You know much about her?
Not as much as I'd have liked to.
Try the blond with
the big bazookas.
- Ice?
- What for?
You didn't mention you knew her.
You didn't ask.
Besides, I thought you came here...
to bowl.
You recall seeing her
with anyone last night?
- Yeah. There were a couple of guys.
- Who?
Customers. You know, guys
trying to hit on her.
She let any of them?
- No. She thought they were creeps.
- What about other nights?
If she liked someone, she
might've done something about it.
But by and large,
just one-night stands?
Are there any other kind?
And you two knew each
other very well?
Well enough.
Did she ever mention anything about
anybody using handcuffs on her?
I think so. She liked
to get pretty kinky.
Remember who it might've been?
I think it was a cop.
Who knows? Maybe it was you.
(DOOR CLOSES)
- WES: Can I help with anything?
- Uh-uh.
Dad, how come you have to
work so late every night?
Well, there's been
three murders, hon.
Couldn't you just
work during the day?
Some people I can
only see at night.
What kind of people?
People that don't have day jobs.
- Dad?
- Mm-hm?
Could you get hurt?
Tell me, Wes, how's things at home?
What do you mean?
I mean, I'm not sure yet you're
ready to run this task force.
Beryl Thibodeaux talked to the
mayor about you, and he called me.
He said if I don't come up with something
soon, he's gonna start shitting all over me.
Shit runs downhill, Wes.
Yeah.
ALL: No!
Louder.
Again.
ALL: No! Stop!
- BERYL: Again.
- WOMEN: Stop! No!
BERYL: One more time.
- WOMEN: Stop!
- BERYL: All right.
Now, in most of the situations
you'll encounter...
you will have several options.
Most important, don't stop thinking.
He's counting on you going catatonic and
being petrified with fear and surrendering.
Keep thinking.
First you could try
and reason with him.
Now, if that doesn't work, blow
your whistle. Start yelling.
The yell we've just
learned, yell it out.
I mean, don't forget, he's
got his adrenaline going.
You make sure you pump up yours.
At this point, our goal is
to disable your attacker.
Now, several ways of
sending him a message are:
Stomping on his toes.
Scratching his eyes.
Hitting this vital point
here in the throat.
Kicking into his kneecaps.
Striking his solar plexus.
And if he still keeps
on acting tacky...
well, then you can always
drop back and punt.
(DUMMY GROANING)
Hi.
(BALL BOUNCING)
I'll bet you were
just about to knock.
Actually, I was just gonna
hang out here and be tacky.
Tell me, um, Detective Blot...
Block.
Wes Block.
- How do you like the Rape Center?
- I love it.
Would you care to make
a charitable donation?
- Any reason I should?
- Yeah.
Maybe...
Maybe I'll talk about the mayor.
Yeah, I hear you go out with him.
Once in a while.
I hear he's gay.
You like a date with him?
Well, I would like him off my back.
Oh, don't tell me he's
interrupted your busy schedule.
Awful, ain't it?
Yeah, well, maybe you should've
told him you were out of town.
Listen, I called him...
because I'm playing by your rules. Now,
if you'd help me, I'd like to help you.
The killer's a Caucasian,
blood type O...
about in his mid-40s. We found traces
of a red fiber on all the victims.
From what?
WES: We don't know.
- Any suspects?
- About 120,000 of them.
Anything you'd like
me to tell the mayor?
Yeah. He's one of them.
Daddy!
WES: Hi, pumpkin.
- Am I heavy?
- Not to me, you're not.
- I weigh 50 now.
- Oh, ha, ha.
- I missed you.
- Well, I missed you too, sweetheart.
I tried to call a lot, but the phone's been
busy. You and your sister sure are gabby.
Did your mother call?
- Hi.
- Mind if I have one?
- Uh-uh.
I heard you had a phone call.
She's getting married.
She wants us to come
to the wedding.
She also said something about
having us come live with her.
- Could she do that?
- I don't know, baby.
I used to make these for her.
- I know.
- But I like making them for you better.
(LOCK BUZZES)
WES: Seen any of these?
No.
No. Too bad.
Yeah. I've seen her in here before.
Anybody ever get violent with her?
That's part of the
turn-on, isn't it?
You know who it was?
No.
Hey, what about you? You
ever see her in here before?
No.
You recognize her?
Uh...
Why don't you come on in?
Close the door.
(WHIRRING)
(THUD)
- When did they find it?
- About 20 minutes ago.
What's up?
Smudge marks from Melanie
Silber's bedroom.
- Can you tell anything?
- Yeah, heh. It's mostly good old dirt.
- What about this morning?
- There were cuff marks on her wrists.
Anything else?
This.
Struck out with the hot-tub
guy. Wrong blood type.
- Maybe we should...
- What was her name?
Who?
The girl at the river.
Judy Harper, a nurse.
Every mass murderer
has a motive, Wes.
It could be as bizarre as
voices commanding him to kill.
The voices could come from God
or from the refrigerator.
Or it could be as simple as
anger, frustration, revenge.
That's why he uses
handcuffs on the women.
- Has he contacted you?
- No.
- I wouldn't be surprised if he did.
- Why?
Once you started going after him, you
became closer to him than anyone else.
Unless there's another psychopath
out doing the same thing.
I'm not sure how close I wanna get.
There's a darkness
inside all of us, Wes.
You, me and the man
down the street.
Some have it under control.
Others act it out.
The rest of us try to walk a
tightrope between the two.
Wanna go hoist some oysters?
BERYL: I've never seen you
work out there before.
I came there looking for you.
- They found another body.
- I know.
- Sorry about it.
- Well, why tell me?
I didn't know who else to tell.
(BAND PLAYING JAZZ MUSIC)
You didn't have to bring
me here to tell me that.
No.
- Thank you.
- So why did you?
Well, I saw you working
out in that gym.
I was wondering what you'd be like.
Why the, uh, sudden interest?
I was wondering if you came alone.
What else were you wondering?
You really wanna know?
Yeah.
What it would be like...
to lick the sweat off your body.
(CHUCKLES)
Do you...?
Do you always say exactly
what's on your mind?
You don't like it?
It could be a little more subtle.
What I said?
More the way you said it.
How would you like me to say it?
As if you're not saying it
to somebody every night.
What else would you like?
I'd like to find out what's
underneath the front you put on.
- Maybe you wouldn't like what you'd find.
- Maybe you're scared I would.
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
- You're not married, are you?
- What makes you say that?
Just a hunch.
You hear the one about the cop
whose wife left him a note...
saying she'd fallen in
love with anyone else?
- Your wife leave you a note?
- No, she left me two kids.
- Where is she now?
- Still here in New Orleans.
You ever thought of moving away?
No. Twenty-eight years ago,
I borrowed $40 from my father...
packed up an old beat-up suitcase,
took a bus and came here.
I was 17 at the time.
I walked down through the French quarter,
looked out over the Mississippi...
and swore I'd never leave.
- Ever come close?
- Only once.
When I looked down and saw
that suitcase missing.
(BERYL CHUCKLES)
Have you ever been married?
- Nope.
- How come?
I guess I haven't
met the right man.
Maybe I scared him away.
Then he definitely
wasn't the right man.
- My mother thinks it's my job.
- What do you think?
- Doesn't matter. I like what I do.
- Helping women?
Oh, men too.
What makes you so
sure they need it?
We all need it.
(ENGINE STARTS)
WES: Okay, gals, come on. Wake up.
(AMANDA GRUNTS)
Come on. We're gonna go
back to our own beds now.
- AMANDA: Hi, Dad.
- PENNY: Where you been?
WES:
Get Dad. Come on. Get on my back.
Unh. Your dad had a date tonight.
- Who with?
- Uh, somebody he met.
- Where'd you go?
- Out on the river.
- PENNY: Is she nice?
- WES: Oh, yeah.
- AMANDA: Do you like her?
- Yeah, she's nice.
- AMANDA: Did you kiss her?
- Hey, come on. Give me a break, will you?
(PHONE RINGING)
PENNY: I bet that's her right now.
And she wants to see you again.
- And you can have a hard-on anytime you want.
- AMANDA: Ha-ha-ha.
"Another one will soon be dead.
You could stop it if you
knew what was ahead."
Think it's from a crank?
No.
Sam's. What's that?
I'm Sam.
Ooh, you're strong.
I love being punished
by a strong man.
Ahem. He said, uh, you'd want this.
- What for?
- Me.
He's wrong.
He said you were just like him.
Who's he?
Use the whip.
You're, uh...
You're to wear this to Praline's.
I don't know who he is.
(GRUNTING)
(R & B MUSIC PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
Dixie.
Looking for something...
Alice?
He said this was your first time.
- Who?
- MAN: You don't know?
- He bought me for you.
- You've seen him?
When was he supposed to pay you?
Right after this, at the old
warehouse across the street.
Well, you go on over to that
warehouse and collect your money.
- You don't want it?
- No.
He said you did. You
just don't know it yet.
Well, he's wrong.
How do you know if you
haven't tried it?
Maybe I have.
I'm at a warehouse at 1460 Water.
- We searched the whole warehouse. He's gone.
- Hmm.
- The saliva on the stamps tested...
- Blood type O.
Right.
The notes are from...
a '72 Olivetti. The letters
E and S are worn down.
The K is misaligned.
That's all I can tell.
- What about the red ribbon?
- Same as the fibers from the other victims.
"... if you knew what's ahead."
(GASPS)
Becky?
(SHRIEKS)
She could still be alive.
Couldn't she?
Still no sign?
It won't be long.
Any luck with him?
No.
You're letting him go?
Yeah.
I heard you knew her too.
That's right.
Just out of curiosity, Wes, did you
happen to know any of the other victims?
No.
Alex?
Do you have someone
who could drive by my house?
Your kids?
- Yeah.
- Sure.
(PHONE RINGING)
(SIREN WAILING)
You remember the smudge marks
in Melanie Silber's bedroom?
Yeah.
- The killer made them.
- How do you know?
Because they have the same chemical
composition as particles on that doll.
- Any idea what they are?
- Some kind of glass fragments...
coated with a barley residue.
- Where could they come from?
- Who knows? Maybe a grain storage bin.
He must've picked up the fragments
in the treads of his tennis shoes.
- He wore tennis shoes?
- Heh.
By tomorrow, I might
even know the make.
(PHONE RINGS)
- Hello?
- Hi. Can I see you tonight?
- I've got some work.
- Can it wait?
Are you okay?
I don't know.
(BAND PLAYING JAZZ MUSIC)
They found one of the
bodies near here.
I know.
- They're getting closer.
- Closer to what?
To me.
Boo!
Do you investigate
many sexual crimes?
Why?
I was wondering if they've
had any effect on you.
Well, they did make me want to treat
my wife a little more tenderly.
How did she respond?
She said she wasn't
interested in tenderness.
They're nice kids.
Yeah, they're about the only thing
in my life I haven't screwed up.
Well, some people
don't even have that.
Why didn't your wife
take them when she left?
Because they're a part
of what she left.
What did you tell them?
I didn't tell them anything.
They already knew.
Do they get jealous when
you bring a woman over?
I don't bring a woman home.
How about that woman
you just bumped into?
She's just sort of a friend.
That kind of friend have anything
to do with your wife leaving?
I made those kind of
friends after she left.
Can we come back
tomorrow night, Daddy?
We'll talk about that later.
PENNY: I want a balloon.
AMANDA: Here, I got it.
Here you are.
(COIN CLINKS)
Yeah.
AMANDA: Come on.
(BERYL & PENNY CHUCKLING)
- Dad?
- Mm-hm?
Beryl's nice. She's pretty
too, don't you think?
Yeah.
I can tell she wants
to see you again.
WES: Oh, you can, can you?
If I were you, I'd ask
her out this weekend.
Oh, you would, would you?
Dad...
- ...find out if she likes dogs.
- Oh, of course.
You'll have to excuse the mess.
Well, you should see
my place sometimes.
I don't exactly have a
lot of help around here.
Uh-huh.
Now, why do you think
he uses handcuffs?
Control?
Do you use them very often?
Well, that depends.
On what?
The situation.
When you feel you are threatened?
Yeah, you could say that.
With these, no one
can get to you, huh?
They'll stop just about anyone.
(BERYL GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
From Jamie Cory's clothing.
We traced the serial numbers.
It is...
It's payroll money Louisiana
Bank sent to 2401 Tulane Avenue.
Even if the killer saw her earlier,
who's to say he gave her the money?
- It could've been some drunk.
- Uh-uh.
Luther said he found minute glass fragments
on them just like the fragments on the doll.
He also found a barley residue he says
resembles the smudge marks on the carpet.
- Barley?
- MOLINARI: Mm-hm.
- What's at 2401 Tulane?
- Dixie Brewery.
(GASPS)
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
- WES: How many employees?
- Almost 1000.
- All of them have medical files?
- Sure.
Well, start checking the blood type O's,
and then we'll work our way from there.
Isn't it possible she could have
got them from someone else?
No.
(PHONE RINGS)
Amanda's kitchen.
- Hi. What's doing?
- Dinner.
Sorry I won't be there.
I've gotta work late.
You save some for me.
There'll be plenty. Don't worry.
Tell Mrs. Holstein to lock up. You
look after your sister, will you?
Gotcha, Dad.
Bye.
You'd like another car
to check on them?
Yeah.
Ruth?
Mrs. Holstein?
- Penny.
- Daddy.
WES: Wake up.
I want you to get in the closet. Don't
come out until your dad says so, okay?
Stay right there.
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(GUNSHOT)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Daddy.
It's all right.
MOLINARI: She's ready, Wes.
We checked everywhere.
No sign of him.
- Joe?
- Yeah.
- Was she...?
- No, no, no.
MAN (OVER RADIO):
Squad 15, how do you read?
WOMAN (OVER RADIO):
Squad 15. You're loud and clear.
Car 32, 17-50.
(POP MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
You...
I'll get you, motherfucker.
Then I'm gonna break
your motherfucking head!
We talked a bit.
She felt better.
She'll be able to rest now.
It wasn't your fault.
No one could have
known what he'd do.
No one but me.
There are 255 male Caucasians
with blood type O at Dixie.
Uh-huh.
MOLINARI: Fifty of them were working
the night shift during the murders.
Check and see if any of
the others have records.
And check the hair colors
of those samples...
that we've got, would you? And
the dental records along with...
- Ask their personnel about a Leander Rolfe.
- Leander Rolfe?
How is she today?
Better.
- WES: Penny would like to spend the night.
- That's all right.
You wait out here, sweetie.
My mother used to wear this.
Maybe you'd like to wear it too.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Telephone.
- Yeah?
- Bingo.
(TIRES SCREECH)
Leander Rolfe just finished doing
11 years at Angola State Prison...
- for going nuts one night...
- And raping two teenagers.
You remember him?
Yeah. He was a cop.
You knew him?
I arrested him.
He just left Dixie
Brewery a half-hour ago.
- What room is he in?
- 316.
WES: Let's go.
WES: You try in there.
I'm gonna tell you right now, I
could've just blown my stack.
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(GRUNTING)
How long has it been?
About an hour.
Do you think he saw us?
I don't know. Maybe.
WES (OVER RADIO): Jake?
I just called and no one answers.
Well, she's in there,
and so is Restic.
Vic, anything?
Vic?
Jake, Vic's not answering.
Jake?
(FLOORBOARDS CREAKING)
(GRUNTS)
I'm okay.
Get inside, will you, Joe?
(SIREN WAILING)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(GROWLS)
(HORN BLARING)
(SIREN WAILING)
MAN: You all right, Wes?
(English - US - SDH)