[WOMAN ANNOUNCING IN FRENCH
ON PA]
Hey.
Take a whiff of this.
Mmm. That's nice.
Ah! It's ringing.
I'm going to go.
Damn it. I keep getting this
dumb recording in French.
Look, I'll meet you
on the plane. Gate 7.
Don't cut it too close.
I'm just going
to try one more time.
WOMAN ON PA:  Last call for passengers
on flight TE flight 222
to Warsaw.
Please proceed to Satellite
number 7 for immediate
boarding.
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING
IN FRENCH]
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
[CONVERSING IN FRENCH]
WOMAN ON PA:
Your attention, please.
Miss Alexander.
Miss Alexander?
You must proceed
immediately to Satellite
number 7 for
immediate boarding.
[PANTING]
[ENGINE STARTING]
That's my plane!
That's my plane.
Monsieur,that's my plane!
Monsieur, s'il vous plait,
that's my plane.
Yes.
Uh... My plane.
[SPEAKING BROKEN FRENCH]
That's not possible, yes?
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
Uh...
Chile.
Santiago.
[CONGRATULATING IN FRENCH]
Peru.
[MOUTHING]
Lima.
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
Afghanistan.
[IN FRENCH]
Look, regardless of the details,
I have to get on a flight andback with the rest of my group.
MAN: Okay. Just a minute.
Yes, I can confirm you on a
flight to Warsaw on Friday.
Friday?
Yes. Friday.
Who else flies to Warsaw?
Air France.
No, no. You don't understand.
I have to change these now.
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
But that's two hours.
Well, I can't wait...
Thanks a lot!
[SIGHS]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[BUZZES]
Chantal?
Hello!
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
Um...
[SPEAKING BROKEN FRENCH]
No, she lives there.
[EXHALES]
Thank God, you speak English.
But he's on vacation. She'll
be back in September.
Are you her boyfriend?
No, I live right here.
Oh, I'm sorry.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
I found myself in Paris.
I thought maybe I could stay
with her for a few nights.
Well, she didn't say
anything to me.
Oh, she wasn't expecting me.
Ah!
How do you know Chantal?
We went to school together
in Saint Louis.
Ah, Saint Louis.
Yeah. Yes.
Well, I'm sorry.
[PHONE RINGING]
I guess I'll just
stay in a hotel.
As you wish.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
Are there any hotels
around here?
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
Are there any hotels
around here?
I'm sorry. Je ne
parle pas l'anglais.
Hotel. That's H-O-T-E-L.
You spell it the same.
I know. I've seen it written.
Are there any hotels
around here?
Yes, there's one at
the end of the street.
I'm going in that
direction, if you want...
Thank you.
Is this typical summer
weather you're having?
Certainly not, but I'm not
usually here in August.
I don't blame you.
Oh, by the way, my name is la
Perouse. Xavier de la Perouse.
What?
Xavier de la Perouse.
Mo.
Mo Alexander.
You know, I don't
understand the French.
They're rude, arrogant,
totally unhelpful.
They act as if the
inability to speak French
is a kind of disease.
You know, I can't figure it out.
Do you hate all foreigners?
Is it particularly Americans?
Or is it some sort
of deep-seated
cultural insecurity?
Why are you here?
Oh, God.
A friend lured me intochaperoning a group of students.
We had a layover in Paris.
I got lost in the airport
and missed the plane.
How did you do that?
It's a lousy airport.
I couldn't find the gate.
No, you're completely wrong.
Charles de Gaulle is one of thebest airports in the world.
Well, I did miss it.
And now I'm here with no
luggage, no clothes, no shoes,
just these ridiculous things.
I'm walking down on probably one
of the chicest streets in Paris.
Yes, it is.
Figures.
[EXHALES]
Here's the hotel.
And I hope your stay
will become more pleasant.
Oh, it really hasn't
been that bad.
I tend to exaggerate at times.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
You have the most beautiful
eyes I've ever seen.
[PLAYING HARMONICA]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
Saint Louis, Missouri.
Hey, Carol, your
sister's on the phone,
she's calling long distance.
Whoo-hoo!
JENNY: Mom, it's Aunt Mo.
Hurry up.
Mo, hi! Did you arrive okay?
You're where?
Well, I got off the
plane to call you.
I forgot to tell you
about the delivery tomorrow.
Emoo's bringing in 20 newseedlings and I promised them...
You did tell me,
you wrote it down.
I did?
Yes! Will you stop worrying?
Everything is fine here,
except that it's a 107 degrees.
Let me talk to her.
Look, if Marcia calls,
tell her that she should leave amessage and phone number for me
at the travel agency here.
She knows which one.
Look, I have to hang up.
This must be
costing a fortune.
Okay. Listen, I love you
very much, darling.
Ooh, me, too.
Okay. Bye-bye.
Bye.
Where is she?
Paris.
Where's that?
Well, it's where
they make rabbit stew,
like what we're going
to do with Harvey tonight.
Oh, Mom.
[KNOCKING]
Come in.
[KNOCKING CONTINUES]
[CONVERSING IN FRENCH]
I called Chantal.
The place is yours.
She insists.
Oh, that was very kind of you.
She says you're very good
with plants and I am not.
Uh...
Would you like to have
dinner with me tonight?
Unless you have other plans?
Oh, no.
No?
I mean, yes.
It's a yes or a no?
Yes.
Great.
By the way,
you have the most
beautiful blanket
I've ever seen in my life.
Thanks.
I'm waiting for you downstairs.
Okay. Okay.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, no.
This is ridiculous.
It's already closed
for the summer.
Oh, that's funny.
They'll miss the tourist trade.
Yes, precisely.
Those are the very clients
they wish to avoid.
Really?
This place is open.
Oh, it's... No, no.
I think we'd better
try somewhere else.
Oh, it's real pretty inside.
It'll be my treat.
Oh, it's not a
question of money. No.
I didn't mean to imply
you couldn't afford it.
I just meant since it's my
choice.
You'd be my guest
I'm...
I'm not used to women
paying for me.
It makes me feel uncomfortable.
Okay, you pay.
[CHUCKLES] Yes.
The point is, I don't think
we are dressed properly.
What do you mean?
You're wearing a suit and...
Oh, you mean
I'm not dressed properly.
I don't think you'd
feel comfortable there.
Or maybe you wouldn't
feel comfortable?
Do you always turn around
the things that people say?
Only when people say
what they don't really mean.
Look, I'm too tired for this.
You go ahead, I'm gonna go
get a sandwich or something.
Come on.
Why are you being so sensitive?
Where are you going?
[CHUCKLES]
Oh!
Look, what's wrong with you?
I don't understand you.
You're very rude, you know.
I invited you to dinner
and you behave like a child.
Just because you...
Look, I'm sorry.
I haven't slept in two days.
I'm tired, I'm hungry. I
don't even want to be here.
All in all, I'd say I've
had a pretty rotten day.
Have a heart.
You're very pretty
when you're angry.
How do you like your spaghetti?
Al dente?
Tomato sauce?
Parmesan?
[SOFT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING]
[DISHES CLATTERING]
Can I help with something?
No, I'm fine.
Is Nescafe all right with you?
I'm afraid we're out
of real coffee.
Sure. It's fine.
[SOFTLY] I thought
Nescafe was real coffee.
Is this your family?
Yes.
Your wife's lovely.
She looks very... French.
When are you going to join them?
Oh, you already told me,
didn't you?
So, you're a horpi... Hort...
A plant person?
Yes, a horticulturist.
Horticulture. Yeah.
I have a nursery in Saint
Louis with my sister Carol.
You sure you don't need help?
I'm looking for the cups.
Cups.
I'll bet they're here.
No. I've already... Oh.
You sure you live here?
No. I live in there.
This enterprise
is run by our maid.
This was taken in Portofino, my father-in-law owns a house
there.
We fly over every summer
for vacation.
[DOORBELL RINGING]
I'd love to.
[THANKING XAVIER IN FRENCH]
So, we have requested a newvisa from the Polish consulate.
That will take two weeks.
That won't work.
According to this telex
my friend sent me,
they'll be in Moscow by then.
A visa to Moscow
might not take as long.
We could get it
in a week to 10 days.
In 10 days, they'll
still be in Prague.
Look, give me your itinerary
and we'll see what we can do.
Maybe I'll just go back home.
Ma'am, you could be stuck
in a worse place than Paris.
Is that
a Southern accent I hear?
Yes, ma'am. [CHUCKLES]
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello?
Ah! Chantal! Hi!
Oh, thanks so much for the
apartment. It is so wonderful.
Yeah.
Who? Oh, Mr. de la Perouse.
Yeah, no, he's great.
He's really a good
sport, believe me.
[DOORBELL RINGING]
I'll just be a minute.
I... got the message.
Even in French clothes
you still look American.
Thank you.
Now, I'll tell you a good
way to recognize wine.
Bordeaux wines always
come in bottles like this.
And Burgundy's...
[THANKING IN FRENCH]
in bottles like that.
And then the Rhine wines
always come
in bottles like this,
you know. This...
And now, I'll tell you a secret.
Very few people know that.
If it has a star in it
on the bottom, you know,
you can return it and get your
money back on the empties.
It's French.
Now taste this one. It's a
much more complex wine.
How did you learn
how to speak English?
English is the language
of money.
I'm a banker,
so I speak English.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
Mrs. Becker's fifth grade class.
You are very beautiful.
Are we home?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
I did it again, didn't I?
I'm just so exhausted.
No.
Don't.
Why?
Look,
regardless of the reasons,
it all adds up to the same.
No.
[SIGHS]
How do I open this?
You're not attracted to me?
Look, let's make it simple.
How about, you're married?
Oh.
I wasn't proposing marriage.
[SCOFFS]
[RATTLING KNOW VIOLENTLY]
How do I open this thing?
[DOOR UNLOCKS]
Tell me,
why did you go out
with me tonight?
To hear about
the history of wine?
Xavier, I don't
necessarily associate
eating, drinking,
and talking with...
[SIGHING] making love.
I don't even know
what to call it anymore.
Fucking, screwing,
fooling around.
That's yours.
Thank you.
Anyway, what makes you think itwas included with the evening?
You accepted
my invitation, right?
You mean if...
If I wasn't going to go
to bed with you,
I should've accepted
the invitation?
That's right.
Because if I hadn't
thought you'd go to
bed with me, I wouldn't
have invited you.
Oh, that's good.
Those are interesting rules.
Are they particularly French?
[KNOCKING AT DOOR]
Lower your voice, please.
There are
people trying to sleep in there.
You're talking louder than I am.
You wanted to go out with me.
So don't tell me you didn't
have the same thing in mind.
I wanted to go out with you.
I wanted very much
to go out with you.
From the very first
moment when I
saw you standing on this landing
with that watering can
in your hand.
But I'm not a little
girl anymore.
And I feel things differently now.
Okay.
I do understand.
Thank you.
And thank you for a beautiful
evening I'll never forget.
Goodnight.
[DOOR CLOSING]
Oh.
[CHUCKLES]
[SIGHS]
[KNOCK AT DOOR]
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
They are still in Riyadh.
Still in Riyadh?
So how much longer
are we going to have
to hang around here
waiting for them?
Look, he's got to
give us some idea.
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
It's going to be a week.
Better go and tell them.
[IN FRENCH]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
They've been delayed. We have
to adjourn it for a week.
Why the delay?
Mr. Moriaki's trying
to convince the Saudis
to cover the loan
for a half a billion.
So what do we do?
Just sit and wait?
Wait, yes.
Sit, no.
Relax, Carry.
Learn how to enjoy yourself.
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
[MEN CHATTERING]
Everybody move in.
Come on. Hit it to Kansas.
MO: Come on. Come on.
All right!
[ALL CHEERING]
Go on to second! Go to second!
Go! Come on! Come on!
Come on! All right! Come
on, come on! Come here!
All right!
Yeah!
I knew you had it in you.
Paris in August
is really at the pits.
Nobody's here
to answer the phone.
My secretary's on vacation.
And her replacement can't
fix a decent Bloody Mary.
You poor old grass widow.
Now, the way I see it, your wifeand children are on holiday
and you've just negotiated
yourself a free week,
presumably to be spent
in bed with Nathalie.
My heart bleeds for you.
Nathalie left me.
Her timing was
always rather good.
I can't even find a date
for dinner tonight.
Do you want to have
dinner with me tonight?
Sorry, old boy.
But I prefer bacon and eggs
at home with my wife.
But you know, you're
very welcome to join us.
Oh, no, thank you very much.
No?
Okay.
Good night.
[CONVERSING IN FRENCH]
MO: Taxi!
Oh, Xavier.
I was hoping you'd get
home before I left.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
I had to work late.
I'm going to a concert.
It's an American
I met the other day.
Should be good.
Would you like to come?
No, thank you.
I had a difficult day.
Well, look,
here's the address
if you change your mind.
No, no. I never do that.
No, here take it.
[CONVERSING IN FRENCH]
Okay.
Oh!
Hey, wait...
Thanks for the wine book!
[PLAYS CLASSICAL TUNE]
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
I confess, this wasn't what I
expected when you invited me.
No?
What were you expecting?
I don't know. Green
hair, I suppose.
Xavier, you are pompous.
Oh, I'm sorry.
If you say so.
It might have been just as
good if it was a rock concert.
I'm sure you're right.
I didn't come for the music.
ANDREW: Mo.
We're making a mass exit
to the Apocalypse.
It's just down the street.
You want to come?
I'd love to.
Okay.
Aren't you coming?
Hmm?
No, thank you. Thank you
very much. I'm very... No.
[EVERY BREATH YOU
TAKE PLAYING]
♪ Every bond you break
♪ Every step you take
♪ I'll be watching you
♪ Every single day
♪ And every word you say
♪ Every game you play
♪ Every night you stay
♪ I'll be watching you
♪ Oh, can't you see
♪ You belong to me?
♪ How my poor heart aches
♪ With every
step you take
♪ Every move you make
♪ And every vow you break
♪ Every smile you fake
♪ Every claim you stake
♪ I'll be watching you
♪ Since you've gone  I been lost without a trace
♪ I dream at night
I can only see your face
♪ I look around  but it's you I can't replace
♪ I feel so cold  and I long for your embrace
♪ And I keep crying,
"Baby, baby, please!" ♪
[LAUGHING]
Was it that Pakistani?
[LAUGHS] No, it's a Frenchman.
He kept saying, "You know, the
famous English poet
Lord Bee-ron?"
"Lord Bee-ron?"
And I kept saying, "Who?"
[LAUGHING HYSTERICALLY]
Oh.
Good evening.
You missed a wonderful evening.You should have come.
No, I had to pack. I leave for
Deauville early in
the morning, so...
You're going away?
Yes. I'm...
You remember Andrew?
Oh, of course.
You gave a splendid performance.
Thank you.
Good night. Thank you.
[CONVERSING IN FRENCH]
Good luck.
I hope you make it to Budapest
or wherever you're going.
And thank you for
your charming company.
Goodbye.
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
Good night.
Perhaps I should have
told you earlier
what a truly charming
companion you were.
Forgive me.
Good night.
[BOTH WISHING GOOD EVENING
IN FRENCH]
Good night.
That was him?
Look, come around to Rome
with me just for a few days.
I'm sorry to bother you, but areyou going to water the plants?
Plants. Yes, sure.
I replanted the
croton in a special
kind of pot so it
won't need watering.
And I'll water the
others before I leave.
Okay.
I'm sure that will be fine.
And...
Andrew is...
Oh, he went back to the hotel.
Oh.
Yeah.
Good night. Good night.
Oh, where should I
leave the key?
Ah, I'll show you.
Right here. You put
it across here. Here.
Since the concierge
isn't here...
Isn't here. Right.
Yes.
I think that's best.
Oh, yeah. Okay.
Good night.
Yes? Good night.
[KNOCK AT DOOR]
[MO EXHALES DEEPLY]
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
Why are you so difficult?
Things just aren't as
simple as they used to be.
No, things are simple.
You complicate them.
[SIGHS]
Oh!
Wait!
Oh! "Wait?"
But I've been waiting all week.
You're not sure. You're
still playing with me.
You're not a woman,
you're a little
girl. You play games with men.
No.
You came to the club,
didn't you?
Which club?
I saw you.
I saw you leaving.
Why did you leave?
No. I came home to pack.
So proud.
You're so beautiful.
Beautiful?
Yes. [MOUTHING] Beautiful.
[WOMAN SPEAKS FRENCH]
You left the door open.
Damn.
[CONVERSING IN FRENCH]
[MO GIGGLING]
You've ruined my
reputation, you know that?
[CLICKING TONGUE]
[MO LAUGHING]
[EXHALES]
Mmm.
You have beautiful breasts.
Too small.
Oh, no!
No.
They are small, but they
have beautiful proportion.
My husband liked big breasts.
What could he possibly know
about breasts? Tell me.
If he were smart,
he'd still be with you.
Well, look at them. They're
round. They're high.
There are two of them.
And they're perfect.
What's this you got here?
Oh.
It's a scar from a firecracker.
I got it when
I was a little girl.
Oh! No!
It's only a little firecracker.
Oh.
Do you have any scars?
Yes.
Got a huge one on my back.
A lion bit me.
Where?
In Africa.
[LAUGHS] Yeah.
On a safari.
Where?
No. No! No, don't move!
It was just a little lion.
A little lion?
[XAVIER ROARING]
[BOTH MOANING]
[INHALES]
What are you doing?
Mmm. I'm smelling you.
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
Smelling me?
You smell just like
another Frenchman I know.
What? You mean, I'm not
your first Frenchman?
Mmm-mmm.
Oh! Oh, no.
Oh.
Is it true
that all Frenchmen
have mistresses?
No, not all.
Do you?
What?
You do, don't you?
Once.
What's she like?
She's 89-years-old with a woodenleg and warts on her ass.
Mmm, I'll bet.
But she understands me.
Oh, good.
She's really vicious.
How can you remember?
What?
The smell of that French...
Man.
I have a very good memory
for smells.
Everything. People,
places, flowers, plants.
And what was he like?
Who?
Come on, the French... Yeah.
The... This one. Yeah.
Handsome.
Charming.
Funny.
But now that I think about it,
he was sort of a... jerk.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
You smell wonderful.
Your skin, your
mouth, your hair.
Oh!
[MOANING]
[ALARM BEEPING]
[GROANING]
I have to get up. I'll come
back to kiss you goodbye.
Oh!
Oh, you fixed breakfast.
You're very quick.
Mmm, do you have to go?
It's business, you know.
Why don't you go back to bed?
No, I have to get up, too.
Why?
[SIGHS]
I'm leaving today.
Oh! You've got your visa?
No, no, no, not yet.
They're still working on it.
Yeah?
Andrew and his friends
asked me to go to Rome.
Guess I will.
Great.
[SIGHS]
Well...
It's business, but I might
be able to get back tomorrow
if you wait.
If you stay, I'll stay.
But I won't wait for you.
Okay.
That's for you.
Okay, I actually bought
it for someone else,
but I'd rather give it to you.
Do I smell French now?
Goodbye. Goodbye.
Nice meeting you.
Come here.
What?
Oh.
Thank you. Bye.
Bye.
[SIGHS]
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
Oh, shit.
[APOLOGIZING IN FRENCH]
I've changed my mind.
[EXCLAIMS IN RELIEF]
[EXHALES]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
Hey. Mo!
Are you okay?
[GROANING] Yeah, fine. I'm fine.
[EXHALES]
Did you forget something?
Hey, you didn't go to Rome?
What's wrong?
[SOBBING]
Aw! Why are you crying?
Because I...
[CHUCKLING]
Broke my hand.
Oh! No. No.
[LAUGHING]
You're such a child.
So are you. You just weigh more.
Now, tell me, what happened
to your guitarist, huh?
I decided to stay in Paris.
Good.
What about Deauville?
Which Deauville?
I hate Deauville.
Now that we are here,
will you stay with me?
Right here?
No, no, not exactly here. No.
Until when?
Until September.
Okay.
Ha! Ta-da!
Wonderful.
[PLAYS HARMONICA]
[GARGLING TO TUNE]
Is this a real cowboy song?
Yeah. It's my grandfather's
favorite song.
Where's your family from?
Saint Louis.
Saint Louis. No.
Yeah, but I mean your roots.
Your ancestors.
Little bit of everything.
My family's been in the
Midwest for generations.
My great-grandfather
was a sheriff in Oklahoma
and my great-great-grandmother
was a full-blooded
Cherokee Indian.
Wow. You are the real thing.
Mmm.
Do you often come
to United States?
Oh, often enough.
But you've never
been to the Midwest?
I'm sorry. I didn't
know you were there.
Oh, God.
Until you've been
in the Midwest,
you haven't really seen America.
It is so beautiful.
It's just cornfields
and wheat fields
that's spread out
as far as the eye can see.
And the sky goes on forever.
And at night, the sky
is so filled with stars.
My grandmother used to sit
out at night with her dog
and look up at the sky for
hours and hours and hours.
She never got a stiff neck?
[LAUGHS]
No, but her dog did.
[SPITS]
Of course I can do it.
You're cheating. It's very easy.
All the way to the mouth.
You sure you're not hungry?
No, no. How could I be
at this time of night?
What the hell is that?
French toast.
It's the only French thing
I know how to make.
Mmm.
But it's not French at all.
It's not?
No!
What about French fries?
That's very different.
French fries
are very French and delicious.
No. No, no.
You really want
to have a lecture
about the history
of French fries?
No.
Okay.
You sure have a very
funny way of eating.
What do you mean?
Look.
Try this.
Hold your fork like this
and use your knife like that.
I do.
Yes. But then,
you don't have to fumble around.
[SCOFFS] I don't fumble.
Take it easy. I just say it's
a truly superior technique.
Look.
One.
Two.
Three.
I think you're just in such a
hurry to get it to your mouth,
you don't want to do it
the proper way.
I'm not in a hurry. Look.
One.
Two.
Three.
Tell me something.
Are you ever wrong?
No.
I may not always be right,
but I'm never wrong.
Definitely, it's not
French at all.
Not hungry, huh?
Oh, yeah. I've got to show
you something wonderful.
Yeah? Yeah.
You see all this water?
It's a river called the Seine.
Yeah.
And it goes directly
into the sea.
I'm sorry. It throws
itself into the sea.
You know that?
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
XAVIER: Shit.
What's the matter?
I'll be right back.
[CONVERSING IN FRENCH]
[SIGHS]
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
Hurray! You made it.
Hi, Philip. Hi.
Hello. Hello. Oh!
This is Mo. And I'm Philip.
Philip. Hi.
Well, I think my wife's
around here somewhere.
Never mind. I'll show you
to your room. Come on in.
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
So how was the drive?
Oh, wonderful.
Come on in.
I have got something
for you. Go ahead.
Well, you know your way.
Come on in.
And here we are.
What a beautiful old house.
Well, I hope you'll be
comfortable here.
Yeah, the nights have been
rather chilly recently.
I think you may well
need one of these.
Ah, let me see
what else is there.
Oh, yes. Bathroom's
through that door there.
It's all rather rustic,
I'm afraid.
Now, this is France.
[SOFTLY] You've done
well for a banker.
Oh. Oh!
Oh, wonderful. Thank you.
Well, I'll leave you
to sort yourselves out.
Oh, oh, by the way, we'll begoing into the village later on,
if anybody wants to come.
There's a big dance
there, on Sunday,
and we're helping
them set it up.
Well, I'll see you later.
[BOY SHOUTING]
Is that Philip's wife?
Yes.
Hi, Sylvia. Hi.
Are they friends with Isabelle?
No, Sylvia and Isabelle
are worlds apart.
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING]
Mum and Daddy.
[CHATTERING IN FRENCH]
[CONVERSING IN FRENCH]
I like her.
So does Xavier.
[LAUGHS] I can see that.
[BAND RESUMES PLAYING]
[CONVERSING IN FRENCH]
Oh, yes.
See you.
[WOMAN SINGING FRENCH SONG]
[SLOW MUSIC PLAYING]
Do you love Isabelle?
Ah! She's an exceptional woman.
I know. I know.
But do you love her?
We're very good together,
we're just like that?
You're not answering
my question.
Look.
Drop it.
You don't understand.
It's none of your business.
Come on now.
Let's dance.
Tell me.
Were you always in love
with your husband?
Yes. Very much so.
Then why did you divorce him?
I didn't divorce him.
He divorced me.
He didn't love me anymore.
That's not a valid reason.
All right.
Perhaps I don't love my wife.
But I need her,
and she needs me.
And it was in both our interests
to get married
and to stay married.
And then you have others for
love affairs like this...
What's her name?
Nathalie.
How long have you
been seeing her?
On and off for three years.
And there were
others before her?
A few.
That's horrible.
You're being naive, Mo.
And Isabelle doesn't care?
Or doesn't she know?
I make sure she doesn't.
You must put on some
really good shows.
I try to be diplomatic.
Diplomatic?
That's not diplomacy.
That's duplicity.
It's pathetic.
All of you.
You, your wife, your mistresses.
Wait a second!
You are one of my mistresses.
You know it.
And you knew I was
married when you met me.
You reason like a child!
Grow up!
Mo.
Go away.
What are you doing?
I'm digging holes.
[VOICE BREAKING]
For the lavender.
You can't see a thing.
I don't need to see.
I do it by touch.
[SIGHING]
You don't take me
seriously, do you?
Of course I do.
No, you don't.
You take your wife seriously.
And you take your
mistresses seriously.
But I'm just a
odd girl
to fill up an odd month
that you really didn't
know what to do with.
But, Mo,
that was our agreement,
wasn't it?
Everything's been so beautiful.
Let's not ruin it.
Don't spoil the memories.
[SIGHS]
Memories?
I have to get up in four hours.
If you want to stay
here with Sylvia,
while Philip and I are in Paris?
You're strange sometimes.
[SIGHS]
SOPHIE: And then, he had
to go and catch him.
And then, afterwards, he turns
him over and he became black.
Then he became...
Oh, thank you.
She's so cute.
SYLVIA: Yeah, I think so, too.
Look. Don't be so upset.
You fell in love
with a married man.
I know. I did it myself.
It always hurts.
You understand?
Yes.
I understand.
And it wasn't so bad, was it?
No, I guess not.
SOPHIE: Oh, the ball
fell in the water.
[SOPHIE SCREAMS]
[WATER SPLASHES]
Sophie! [DOG BARKING]
Oh, my God.
Sophie!
Sophie! Sophie!
Look under the boat!
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
Colonel Viola has assured me
that the national
deficit will be
substantially less
than what we expected.
How's she doing?
[SOBBING] I don't know.
She's going to be
all right. Okay?
As will you see,
these guidelines
conform to IMF standards.
We will cut imports
to $17 billion
from $20.5 billion.
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
SYLVIA: Mo, please hurry.
Oh, shit. Where do we go?
Watch out!
[HONKING]
These changes will be
particularly effective
in the agricultural
infrastructure.
When are we gonna stop
behaving like gamblers
and start behaving like bankers?
Oh, Carry. Please,
let's hear him out.
We all know that
the consequences are...
Philip, it's Sylvia.
We have to go.
Come on!
[PEOPLE MURMURING]
[BABY CRYING]
Hello, darling. Yes, you are.
[THANKING IN FRENCH]
There they are.
Sylvia!
I know it.
Is she all right?
Hi, Daddy. I'm in the hospital.PHILIP: You are.
You got here so quickly.
PHILIP: Come to Daddy.
XAVIER: We're so worried.
I wanna go home now.
Are you okay?
The car's in the car park.
PHILIP: Come on, little one.
Let's get you home.
SOPHIE: It's very funny here.
Thank God you're here.
She's going to be okay.
[LIGHTNING CRACKING]
How long have we
known each other?
Almost three weeks.
I feel like I've lived
a lifetime with you.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
The weather changes so quickly.
[MAN CHATTERING ON TV]
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello? MO: Hi, it's me.
Mo! What time is it there?
Are you okay?
Oh, I just wanted
to hear your voice.
I guess I'm getting
kind of homesick.
Oh, Mo. Why don't you come home?
We're all here waiting
for you and we miss you.
Oh, and the damn rabbit got
lost. Jenny was so upset.
She's sleeping right
here, beside me.
Do you want to speak
to her? Jenny.
Oh, no, no, no. Don't wake her.
Oh, okay.
Hi, Jenny. No. Don't you
worry about Harvey.
He'll be fine.
That's what Mommy said, but
who's gonna take care of him?
Take care?
You know wabbits.
They're a lot like people.
It's hard for them to be alone.
He probably went
looking for a wife.
[CHATTERING IN FRENCH]
[MAID CHATTERING IN ITALIAN]
[THANKING IN ITALIAN]
Xavier?
[CHATTERING IN FRENCH]
[DOOR CLOSING]
I'm looking for my keys.
Jenny's rabbit ran away.
She was real upset.
Oh. Too bad.
[KEYS JANGLING]
Can I talk to you for a second?
Not now, I'm late.
I have to make
my reservation today.
Okay, do it.
We'll have to decide on a date.
If I went there last minute,
the flights will be full.
It's up to you.
[LAURENCE SPEAKS FRENCH]
[BIRDS SQUAWKING]
[CONVERSING IN FRENCH]
"Tomorrow"...
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
We go in avion a America.
[CHUCKLES]
[THANKING IN FRENCH]
Hello.
[DOOR OPENING]
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
Oh, no, it's not working.
Oh, I'll go up the stairs.
Can I help you?
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
It's heavy.
What's in there?
Oh, it's a little rabbit. It's
for my niece in Missouri.
[CHUCKLES] He's very sweet.
Are you going to the top floor?
Yes. Are you
a friend of Chantal?
Oh, no.
MO: Oh.
[BIDDING FAREWELL IN FRENCH]
Xavier. Uh...
This is for Mo. From Sophie.
That's very sweet. Thank you.
Look, I...
I hope you come down to the
country and see us again soon.
And I know that
Sophie and Sylvia
would both love to see Mo again
before she leaves.
And, thank you.
[ELEVATOR BELL DINGS]
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
[OPENING DOOR]
[THANKING IN FRENCH]
GUIDE ON PA: We
are now passing
under the oldest
of the 37 bridges
that links the left bank
to the right bank.
Every stone is
hand-carved.
On your left, you will see
the famous Cathedral of Notre
Dame.
The man who designed it never  lived to see its completion.
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
[SCREAMING]
WOMAN: Stop him! Hey!
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING]
[SIREN WAILING]
[CONVERSING IN FRENCH]
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
[CHUCKLES] What happened to you?
I fell in the river.
[CHUCKLES] How did you do that?
I went on the Bateaux-Mouches.
Mo, I warned you about that.
Xavier, you really piss me off.
I'm going to bed.
Goodbye and good night.
Why do you always run away?
Why do you always lie?
Every time you get upset,
you run away.
Answer me, damn it!
Answer what?
Where were you?
You know where I was.
Say it!
I was with Nathalie.
Doesn't matter anyway.
This time tomorrow,
I'll be in New York.
I was afraid.
Did you
make love to her?
I couldn't.
You know, my life,
it was
a fine, good structure.
And I worked hard
to keep it that way.
And now,
it's falling apart.
Don't go away.
Please.
Maybe I'm not very clear.
I'm trying to tell you
I'm love with you.
[MOUTHING]
[LAUGHING]
Ah!
I love you. I love you.
I'm starving.
Are you?
Okay, I'll cook today.
You?
Yeah, surprise you.
This I got to see.
Oh, we don't have any bread.
Oh, who needs bread?
I do.
You don't really need bread.
Okay, forget it.
[SPEAKS FRENCH FLUENTLY]
Oh. Okay. I'll take this
upstairs and start lunch.
Do we need some wine?
No, I'll get some from my place.
And, Mo! Don't run
away this time.
Go learn how to cook.
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
Xavier?
Xavier, are you here?
Guess what I found?
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
[QUESTIONING IN FRENCH]
ISABELLE: Are you American?
MO: Yes.
Chantal lives right...
over there.
But she is on vacation now.
She'll be back in September.
Well, thank you.
Please,
use the lift. It works now.
Everything's back to normal.
No, thank you. I'd rather walk.
[DOOR CLOSING]
[SIGHING]
[CRYING]
Where to?
Charles de Gaulle Airport,
please.
[SHOUTING] [CAR HONKING]
WOMAN ON PA:  Last call for passengers
on TWA flight number 803
to New York.
Please proceed to
gate number...
[THANKING IN FRENCH]
[EXCLAIMING]
Mo! Mo! Mo!
[INAUDIBLE] [PLANE WHOOSHING]
Mo!
[PEOPLE COMPLAINING]
[WOMAN ANNOUNCING IN FRENCH
ON PA]
WOMAN: Your boarding pass?
[KNOCKS]
[CONVERSING IN FRENCH]
WOMAN ON PA:
Your attention, please.
Passengers to New
York are awaited at
gate number 2 for
immediate boarding.
[ANNOUNCING IN FRENCH]
I need a ticket to the next
flight to New York now!
I'm sorry.
It's fully booked today.
And you're being
too late anyways.
Okay, give me a ticket
to anywhere, but now!
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
[SCANNER BEEPING]
[SPEAKS FRENCH] Oh!
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
Mo!
Wait for me!
[CHUCKLES]